<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Limbird Real Estate Group - your professional Northwest Arkansas Real Estate Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://limbirdteamblog.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://limbirdteamblog.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 09:28:22 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 09:28:22 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Holidays Are Great for 2 Things: Listing and Fun</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/LLnHt5j4XlM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m coming to you today from Toyland in Bentonville, Arkansas to discuss a few reasons why selling your home during the holiday season can be a great idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the spirit of the season, I also want to bring you a list of some great things to do around this time of year here in Northwest Arkansas. But first, let’s talk real estate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what are the top reasons to sell your home during the holidays?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reduced inventory.&lt;/strong&gt; There is a common misconception that the fall and winter markets aren’t a good time to list. As a result, there is significantly less inventory on the market during the holiday season. This translates to less competition for you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buyers are more serious.&lt;/strong&gt; During this time of year, the buyers who are still looking on the market are truly committed to finding a home. So, the holidays are a great opportunity to capture serious buyers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Financial incentives.&lt;/strong&gt;Some buyers may be looking to purchase a home by the end of the fiscal year because of certain financial opportunities. This will drive further interest to your property.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These aren’t the only reasons to sell this season, though. There are actually about seven more that my team and I would love to share with you. To find out what they are, email us at &lt;a href=&quot;javascript:void(location.href='mailto:'+String.fromCharCode(105,110,102,111,64,108,105,109,98,105,114,100,116,101,97,109,46,99,111,109))&quot;&gt;info@limbirdteam.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Some may think you shouldn’t list during the holidays, but this simply isn’t true.%20http://limbirdteamblog.com/the-holidays-are-great-for-2-things-listing-and-fun.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Some may think you shouldn’t list during the holidays, but this simply isn’t true.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now, I’d like to jump back into the holiday fun I mentioned earlier. There are a lot of great events coming up in our area this holiday season, so you won’t want to miss out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here is a list of everything that’s going on&lt;/strong&gt;. You can click on the links to find out more about each event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;November 9: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eurekasprings.org/foodandwine/&quot;&gt;Eureka Springs Food and Wine Weekend&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;November 17: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.experiencefayetteville.com/lights-of-the-ozarks&quot;&gt;Fayetteville Lights of the Ozarks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;November 18: &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.regwiz.io/register/sstt/292&quot;&gt;Siloam Springs 5K Turkey Trot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;November 18: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.arkansas.com/event/lighting-of-the-bentonville-square/149476&quot;&gt;Bentonville Lighting of the Square&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;November 23: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.turkeytrotar.com/&quot;&gt;Don Gammie Turkey Trot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;December 1: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mainstreetrogers.com/event/christmas-parade-2/&quot;&gt;Rogers Christmas Parade&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;December 1: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eurekaspringschamber.com/events/details/2017-eureka-springs-chamber-of-commerce-parade-of-lights-460&quot;&gt;Eureka Springs Chamber of Commerce Parade of Lights&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;December 2: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hlofss.com/christmas-parade.html&quot;&gt;“Red, White, and Who” Siloam Springs Christmas Parade&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;December 9: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.arkansas.com/event/bentonville-christmas-parade/149480&quot;&gt;Bentonville Christmas Parade&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;December 9: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eurekasprings.org/event/night-1000-santas/&quot;&gt;Night of 1,000 Santas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last but not least, don’t forget to meet and take a photo with Santa himself at Pinnacle Hills Promenade. You can find dates and information for that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pinnaclehillspromenade.com/en/events/photos-with-santa-15907.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 10:37:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://limbirdteamblog.com/the-holidays-are-great-for-2-things-listing-and-fun.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://limbirdteamblog.com/the-holidays-are-great-for-2-things-listing-and-fun.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Don't Miss Our Annual Thanksgiving Pie or Wine Giveaway</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/os07Jn_vqzA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s almost Thanksgiving, so you know what that means: our annual client appreciation event is coming up. Our Pie or Wine Giveaway is just around the corner, and you won’t want to miss it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure you join us on Tuesday, November 21 from 9 a.m. to 6 p.m. to receive your choice of either pie or wine. The event will be at our office, which is located at 5247 W Metro Park Crossing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Our Pie or Wine Giveaway is just around the corner.%20http://limbirdteamblog.com/dont-miss-our-annual-thanksgiving-pie-or-wine-giveaway.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Our Pie or Wine Giveaway is just around the corner.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can register to reserve your free pie or wine &lt;a href=&quot;http://limbirdloyaltyclub.com&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/versions/client-appreciation-giveaway-3---x----672-480x---.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 07:20:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://limbirdteamblog.com/dont-miss-our-annual-thanksgiving-pie-or-wine-giveaway.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://limbirdteamblog.com/dont-miss-our-annual-thanksgiving-pie-or-wine-giveaway.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>You're Invited to The Team Tara Fundraising Kickoff Party</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/w4HYQW3VojY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would like to invite you the Limbird Real Estate Group’s kickoff party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the party isn’t for Limbird Real Estate Group, though—it’s for Kiss A Pig.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Kiss A Pig Gala is the biggest charity event in Arkansas and helps the American Diabetes Association.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to be a candidate helping to raise money and awareness for diabetes from now until March 10th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Diabetes affects almost 30 million people in our country, so we need your help and your support.%20http://limbirdteamblog.com/youre-invited-to-the-team-tara-fundraising-kickoff-party.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Diabetes affects almost 30 million people in our country, so we need your help and your support.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Diabetes affects almost 30 million people in our country, so we need your help and your support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Team Tara fundraising kickoff party will be held &lt;strong&gt;Thursday, October 19th, from 5 to 7 p.m. at Landers Toyota in Rogers, Arkansas.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have never done anything like this before, and I’m so out of my element, but I really need your support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bring a friend with you and show us some love and support. We really appreciate it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll have drinks, hors d’oeuvres, and door prizes. It’s sure to be a lot of fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope to see you October 19th!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 08:40:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://limbirdteamblog.com/youre-invited-to-the-team-tara-fundraising-kickoff-party.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://limbirdteamblog.com/youre-invited-to-the-team-tara-fundraising-kickoff-party.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We’re Back in the Running for the 5th Straight Year</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Y8NB38CyXcU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s that time of year once again. We’ve been fortunate enough to win the honor of “Best real estate team in  Northwest Arkansas” for the last five years. With your help, we’d like to make it six in a row.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few different ways that you can vote for us, and it’s super easy. One option is to simply head on over to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nwadg.com/best&quot;&gt;Northwest Arkansas Democrat Gazette&lt;/a&gt;, locate the “Business service and retail” section and vote for The Limbird Team as the “Best real estate team.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Thanks in advance for your support.%20http://limbirdteamblog.com/were-back-in-the-running-for-the-5th-straight-year.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Thanks in advance for your support.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also vote for us via text. Text “nwabest” to 313-131 and wait for a response. Once you’ve received one, reply back with the code “FM265” and you’re all done!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks in advance for your support. If you have any questions for us or real estate needs we can assist you with in the meantime, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;www.nwadg.com/best&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/Limbird_500-&amp;#40;2&amp;#41;.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Click Here to VOTE!&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 07:08:23 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://limbirdteamblog.com/were-back-in-the-running-for-the-5th-straight-year.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://limbirdteamblog.com/were-back-in-the-running-for-the-5th-straight-year.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The 5 Things You Need Before Purchasing a Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/H4PyoyrjS74?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you purchase a home, there are five key things you’ll need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, obtaining a pre-approval letter will be essential to your success as a homebuyer. Meeting with a loan officer who will ask you basic questions about your income, credit, and eligibility is the first step in getting a pre-approval letter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A pre-approval letter is a fantastic thing to attach to any offer. Additionally, a loan officer will be able to help you with other things throughout the home buying process, as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, while some have moved away from suggesting this tip, I like to recommend putting down earnest money. Earnest money is money put down in good faith to show the seller that you are serious about the purchase. It can also give you a big advantage in multiple offer situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main concern people tend to raise about earnest money is the fear of not getting it back. However, if for some reason the financing falls through or the inspection isn’t satisfactory, you do get this money back. &lt;strong&gt;Earnest money can be written into an agreement or contract in a way that ensures it will be refundable.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third thing you’ll need is to sort out your down payment. In many cases, the more you put down, the better your interest rate will be. Also, in cases where you’re able to put down 20%, you then don’t need to pay for mortgage insurance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A pre-approval letter is a fantastic thing to attach to any offer.%20http://limbirdteamblog.com/the-5-things-you-need-before-purchasing-a-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A pre-approval letter is a fantastic thing to attach to any offer.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, paying 20% isn’t necessary. &lt;strong&gt;There are many loan programs out there, so it will be important that you find one that works best for your needs.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is especially important because your down payment isn’t the only money required in the transaction. You will also need money for your closing costs. These closing costs include several different fees associated with buying a home, but the good news is that you can negotiate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, this will depend on circumstance. &lt;strong&gt;If you are in a multiple offer situation, the seller will feel less of an obligation to negotiate in your favor.&lt;/strong&gt; Ultimately, your loan officer and agent will be able to help you determine the right way to navigate this situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the fifth thing you’ll need to buy a home is money for the home inspector. This cost will depend on the size of the home and be taken out of pocket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind that if you are dissatisfied with the results of the inspection or with the home itself, you won’t get a refund. However, the hundreds of dollars you will pay for an inspection will be a worthwhile investment to make sure everything is sound with the home before you spend thousands on a purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 05:39:11 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://limbirdteamblog.com/the-5-things-you-need-before-purchasing-a-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://limbirdteamblog.com/the-5-things-you-need-before-purchasing-a-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What to Do When You’re up Against Multiple Offers</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8LbPdP9MSAI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real estate market is crazy right now, especially in certain areas and price points. It can be difficult to find a home in our area that meets your criteria, and once you do, you’ll probably notice that many other buyers are looking for the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you end up in a multiple offer situation, there are a few things you should take into consideration in order to make sure your offer stands out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Of course, the first thing everyone thinks about is the price.&lt;/strong&gt; Price is important, but it’s not the only factor to pay attention to. If you are at a price point with a lot of buyers, go in with your highest and best offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can be tough because everyone wants to negotiate and try to get the best deal. Think about it this way, though: How upset would you be if you lost out on this home? Some people may have another home in mind and may not panic if they lose out on this home. If it’s the only house on the market that you like, though, I’d hate for you to get beat out by $500. So, you may wind up paying more than you plan, but at least you’ll get the house you wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of overpaying, remember that if you use financing to purchase your home, then &lt;strong&gt;your lender will order an appraisal.&lt;/strong&gt; If the home doesn’t appraise, you can always negotiate with the seller or walk away from the deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if you can pay out of pocket over the list price, you can make your offer not contingent on the appraisal. That way, the seller doesn’t have to worry about the home failing to appraise and going back on the market—and your offer looks more appealing to the seller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Keep your offer as clean as possible.%20http://limbirdteamblog.com/what-to-do-when-youre-up-against-multiple-offers.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Keep your offer as clean as possible.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, if you have enough money for your share of the closing costs—that’s great. It is okay to ask the seller to cover closing costs, but keep in mind that the seller will look at the price and the concessions you ask for before deciding which offer to work with. Some concessions may include things like the refrigerator, patio furniture, rugs, and bar stools. The cleaner you keep the offer, the better.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually, you would ask the seller to cover the home warranty. Home warranties run about $500 to $700, so if you can, go ahead and pay for it instead of asking the seller to. The seller will look at how your offer affects their bottom line versus competing offers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finally, consider the closing date.&lt;/strong&gt; Be as flexible as you can. If you absolutely have to close on a specific date, then maybe your price has to be more competitive. If the seller is building a home, be flexible with the closing date or when the seller has to move out. Maybe you agree to close in 30 days but give the seller an additional month or two to move out of the property. That way the seller doesn’t have to move twice, which could put your offer over the edge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, these tips will help you win the home of your dreams. Our team also has some unique ideas that have helped our clients in multiple offer situations, so if you have any other questions, give us a call. We would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 05:37:51 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://limbirdteamblog.com/what-to-do-when-youre-up-against-multiple-offers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://limbirdteamblog.com/what-to-do-when-youre-up-against-multiple-offers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Best Time to Lower the Price on Your Listing</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8UnHG23MlqE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you first list your home something magical happens. Like a new kid at a high school dance, all eyes are going to be upon your listing. Buyers and agents alike are going to make some rapid judgments about your home: is it over priced, is the condition of your home in good shape, and is the location an ideal location for the buyer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first impression of your home in the first few weeks of it being listed is going to determine whether or not people come to see it. If you’re not getting very many showings or no showings at all, you’ve got a problem. It means that the market as a whole is rejecting your value proposition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The sooner you lower the price, the better.%20http://limbirdteamblog.com/the-best-time-to-lower-the-price-on-your-listing.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The sooner you lower the price, the better.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At that point, the only thing that can typically be done is to lower the price and the sooner, the better. You may be thinking, “Why in such a short time? Why not keep the price as it is for a few more weeks?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think of the real estate market as an audience in a movie theater. When the movie first hits the screen, the audience members are going to make a determination about whether they like the movie or not. More time isn’t going to change their minds. At that point, you’re just waiting for new audience members to trickle in and against all odds, they love it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More than likely, the best decision when you aren’t getting showings is to edit the price and get it back up on the MLS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this topic or you’re looking to buy or sell a home, give me a call. I’d be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://limbirdteamblog.com/the-best-time-to-lower-the-price-on-your-listing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://limbirdteamblog.com/the-best-time-to-lower-the-price-on-your-listing.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Northwest Arkansas Market Update</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-76mqYTPvJ8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot going on in the Northwest Arkansas market this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The market is booming and there are a lot of great things happening.&lt;/strong&gt; According to the Northwest Arkansas Council, there are 31 people moving in every day and research from the University of Arkansas shows that the average age of residents here is 33.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for market activity, I wanted to look at things in terms of Benton County and Washington County.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are currently about 1,500 homes for sale in Benton County and roughly a quarter are new builds. In Washington County, there are 738 homes for sale with 149 being new builds. Through the first five months of the year in Benton County, 2,375 homes have sold compared to 2,279 during the same period last year. In Washington County, 1,406 homes sold in the first five months of 2017. That number last year was 1,341.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Prices are definitely up.%20http://limbirdteamblog.com/northwest-arkansas-market-update.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Prices are definitely up.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, prices are definitely up. In Benton County, price per square foot rose about $8. The number of days it takes to sell a home on average has held steady in Benton County, but in Washington County, homes are selling in an average of about 30 days faster than last year. Prices in Washington County are also up by about $7 per square foot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New construction home sales are up by about 80 this year in Benton County and up by about 60 in Washington County. Prices are also up about $8 a square foot for such homes. If you thought about buying a home last year but waited until this year, it will cost you about $20,000 more on average.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interest rates are still low for homes, making it still a great time to buy. March marked the 31st consecutive quarter of incline in the economy, tying for third-longest in the history of the U.S. economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in buying a home or you have any other questions, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We’re here to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 07:57:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://limbirdteamblog.com/northwest-arkansas-market-update.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://limbirdteamblog.com/northwest-arkansas-market-update.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Are The Core Values that Define Our Company?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wo89dWV70OI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste present-before-paste&quot;&gt;Our core values are what define us as a team, and they’re very important to us. These six values represent who we are and what we stand for:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. A positive outlook:&lt;/strong&gt; Nobody ever walks into a company and wants to hang around negative people. This business is somewhat of a roller coaster and there are a lot of emotions involved in buying and/or selling a home, so we try to keep a positive outlook and be solution-oriented with no excuses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Being your best:&lt;/strong&gt; We believe in taking pride in your position and doing everything to the best of your ability. To me, anything worth doing is worth doing right. There are a lot of things that happen in a real estate transaction, and putting our best foot forward and being the best we can be for both our clients and each other is extremely important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Appreciation:&lt;/strong&gt; We take the time to appreciate our clients and our team. We like to have client appreciation parties a few times a year. We get busy with the day-to-day hustle and grind, and sometimes we forget to thank our clients and northwest Arkansas for choosing us as your real estate team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We take the time to appreciate our clients and our team.%20http://limbirdteamblog.com/what-are-the-core-values-that-define-our-company.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We take the time to appreciate our clients and our team.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Being silly:&lt;/strong&gt; This is a very stressful business, so we take the time to be silly and happy. You have to take time out of the day to laugh. As the expression goes, “If you don’t laugh, you’ll cry,” and sometimes we feel like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Abundance:&lt;/strong&gt;When living in a world of abundance, you have to give in order to get. One of the things I’m most proud of with our team is the fact that we’re a giving team. We like to give back to our community, and we help sponsor several different organizations across Arkansas. We also have our Compassion Campaign, where every time we sell a home we put money into an account that helps with urgent needs within our community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Being coachable:&lt;/strong&gt; I’ve been in this business since 2004, and I still learn something new every day. We’re never going to know it all, and that’s what I love about real estate. It’s always changing, and there’s something new to learn each and every day. We can all learn something new, and if I ever felt like I knew it all, it wouldn’t be as much fun to be in this business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;If you have any questions about our core values or you’re thinking about buying or selling a home, feel free to reach out to us. We’d be happy to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://limbirdteamblog.com/what-are-the-core-values-that-define-our-company.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://limbirdteamblog.com/what-are-the-core-values-that-define-our-company.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Limbird Real Estate Group Is Investing in the Future</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/yJ22zgyxyeQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the Limbird Real Estate Group, we are proud to always be on the cutting edge of technology. This is why we are thrilled to announce our adoption of 3-D home tours. Buying a home can be a taxing process, especially for out-of-town buyers. Typically, Realtors use still photos and some use video to market their homes to buyers. This is only a 2-D experience, however.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are investing in a three-dimensional experience for our buyers and sellers. Open houses are usually only held for a few hours each week. With our easy-to-navigate 3-D tours, however, your home can be open 24/7, 365 days a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=With these tours, you have a 360-degree view of each room.%20http://limbirdteamblog.com/the-limbird-real-estate-group-is.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“With these tours, you have a 360-degree view of each room.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We take you beyond the real world with a complete digital scan that gives buyers an unprecedented insight into your home like never before. With the use of lasers and high-tech cameras, potential buyers can select any room to view and instantly place themselves inside that space with the ability to maneuver inside the room and view it in 360 degrees. Buyers will be able to virtually walk through your home, get a feel for its layout, and notice details and features that they typically wouldn’t with still images.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you combine the fact that the majority of homebuyers start their search online with the power of photos being shared on social media, this is an amazing tool for a seller like yourself to take advantage of. Our team currently advertises on more than 100 websites and we’re ready to put our state-of-the-art technology to work for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for us, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We would love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 13:50:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://limbirdteamblog.com/the-limbird-real-estate-group-is.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://limbirdteamblog.com/the-limbird-real-estate-group-is.html</guid>
        
        <category>Best Northwest Arkansas Real Estate Team</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
