<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Career Advancement Video Blog</title>
    <description>Govig &amp; Associates is one of the largest privately held firms in the Executive Search industry. With more than three decades in staffing and recruiting, we have the knowledge, the network and the speed to provide unparalleled service to our clients.</description>
    <link>http://govigblog.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://govigblog.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 14:19:04 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 14:19:04 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Do ‘Can’t Ask Salary’ Laws Work?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/6veXxUkRp0E&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently had a conversation with one of my clients about can’t ask salary laws which made me realize that many of you might not be aware of how they work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A few areas across the country have recently passed can’t ask salary laws.&lt;/strong&gt; Like any new law, it can be a little complicated, so let me simplify it for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three states and one city have these laws in effect: California, Massachusetts, Delaware, and New York City. Oregon has passed a can’t ask salary law that will go into effect in January of 2019. Philadelphia also passed a can’t ask salary law, but that has been delayed due to some court actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You cannot ask potential candidates about their salary.%20http://govigblog.com/how-do-cant-ask-salary-laws-work.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You cannot ask potential candidates about their salary.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Basically, the law prevents you from asking potential candidates applying for a position about their previous or current salary.&lt;/strong&gt; When I say salary, that encompasses the entire compensation package. You are allowed to ask what their salary expectations are if they were to make a move or accept a position within your organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now remember, this is not just for companies headquartered in that state; if you are filling any positions for your company within that state, these laws apply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can’t ask salary laws are all-encompassing for companies and agencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do not follow these laws, you will get sued.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been studying this for quite some time. If you would like more information, just give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/how-do-cant-ask-salary-laws-work.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://govigblog.com/how-do-cant-ask-salary-laws-work.html</guid>
        
        <category>Building Products</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Can Millennials Enhance Your Business and Leadership?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/szD10KP6MAE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I want to talk about millennials and leadership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Millennials grew up with structure. I can’t speak for anyone except myself, but I can tell you that I’ve never seen someone with structure and an understanding of appropriate expectations fail, unless the business just wasn’t for them, and sometimes that happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Millennials grew up with structure, but &lt;strong&gt;they also grew up with a strong desire to work autonomously and know that they can mess up and learn.&lt;/strong&gt; I too would like to work autonomously, and sometimes that means we as managers have to redefine what it is that we want from millennials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I grew up in an environment where SOS (show, observe, shape) was the most effective way to coach people. I would challenge to many people that it’s still a very effective way of coaching individuals. First, you show them. Then, you observe them. Finally, you shape them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interesting thing about millennials, however, is &lt;strong&gt;that they may want you to show them and then jump straight to having you shape them.&lt;/strong&gt; They want to be in an environment where it’s allowed and encouraged to jump in, learn, try, make mistakes, and learn from those mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I understand that won’t make sense for businesses in all industries, but if you’re in an environment where you can allow millennials to jump in and start however they see fit, it’s beneficial to both them and your business. You would be amazed at some of the questions you have to answer because of their inquisitive minds and their need to know the “why.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Millennials need strong leaders—not just leaders who will tell them what to do, but also why and how. If you can show that to them and then allow them to jump in, you will be amazed at how quickly and how much they thrive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Millennials think differently, and they’ll be able to enhance your business.%20http://govigblog.com/how-can-millennials-enhance-your-business-and-leadership.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Millennials think differently, and they’ll be able to enhance your business.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last point I want to address concerning millennials is their creativity. This doesn’t mean that every millennial can pick up a paintbrush and paint a Monet picture, but it does mean that they think differently. They think outside the box, so I encourage you—if you’re not sure how to take your business to the next level or you’re not sure what to do in a certain situation—to ask a millennial. They think differently, and they’re able to enhance your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hear so often that it’s no longer a top-down approach in business, but rather a bottom-up approach. That bottom-up approach is asking for the insights and initiatives that you want to see from your millennials as they become the new leadership generation. They have such creativity that flows through them—not necessarily from an artistic standpoint, but they’re disruptors. They want to challenge the status quo, be more efficient, and thrive and learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I encourage you to embrace that and allow your millennials to let you understand where we should go instead of you telling them where they need to go. It will make a world of difference, and I’m so excited to hear how it has been impactful for you for the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there is anything myself or my team can do for you or you have any questions about this topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/how-can-millennials-enhance-your-business-and-leadership.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://govigblog.com/how-can-millennials-enhance-your-business-and-leadership.html</guid>
        
        <category>BioPharma</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are You Moving to Another Organization? If So, Consider This</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/vQ46LBxGFDY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I want to speak briefly about the things you should research and take into consideration when moving to another organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, ask yourself: “What is the company’s primary service or product?” Once you’ve answered this, &lt;strong&gt;ask yourself if it is something you have the ability to stand behind and get excited about. &lt;/strong&gt;If it’s not, it could be a challenge for you to work with this service or product on a daily basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, you should think about the company’s target market. Who are they trying to serve and impact? This factor will impact the things you’ll do on a daily basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of who the company is trying to reach, another thing to think about is what the company wants to be known for. Along with considering who the company wants to impact, it’s also important to know how they want to make that impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The age of the company will also matter. If a company just started, you may have the opportunity to come in and give some real input on how to improve or change certain aspects of the operation.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Think about who the company wants to reach and how they want to make that impact.%20http://govigblog.com/are-you-moving-to-another-organization-if-so-consider-this.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Think about who the company wants to reach and how they want to make that impact.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well-established companies also have benefits. When a company has been around for a while, you can feel certain about their track record of success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However long a company has been in business, leadership matters. &lt;strong&gt;Before moving to an organization, determine who is on the leadership team and what experience they have. &lt;/strong&gt;When you figure this out, you may even find common ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another question you should be asking is, how much revenue have they generated? Also, who is their biggest competitor? Having this information from the beginning will be greatly beneficial to you as a potential member of any organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should also know what strengths and weaknesses the organization may have. This information can be found through press releases and even social media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all of this information in mind, the final question to ask yourself is this: &lt;strong&gt;Why could you see yourself working for this organization?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This question will undoubtedly be asked of you in the interview process, so it may be a good idea to have your answer prepared ahead of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/are-you-moving-to-another-organization-if-so-consider-this.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://govigblog.com/are-you-moving-to-another-organization-if-so-consider-this.html</guid>
        
        <category>Building Products</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Decide Between 2 Job Offers</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2q2il5GGBpQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you’ve gone through the interview process and have received multiple job offers. First off, let me say congratulations. Once the celebration is over, you’ll need to make a decision. Here are five key factors to consider when determining which choice is going to be the best for you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Your long-term career goals.&lt;/strong&gt; You not only want to focus on what the job gives you today, but also where it puts you down the road. Don’t just think about those immediate results. Think about where you’ll be five or 10 years from now if you accept the job. Ultimately, you want to find more than a job. You want to find a career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Salary. &lt;/strong&gt;The simple answer here is to take the job that pays the most, but it can be more complex than that. Salary isn’t everything. Weigh the salary with the position itself and keep in mind that you can always negotiate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=People don’t quit companies, they quit managers.%20http://govigblog.com/how-to-decide-between-2-job-offers.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“People don’t quit companies, they quit managers.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. The workplace culture.&lt;/strong&gt; If you’ve ever worked with a recruiter before, then you know about the importance of company culture in your decision. Not only is a good culture fit beneficial to you, but it’s also a benefit to the company you choose to work for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Compare the prospective managers&lt;/strong&gt;. Most of the time, people don’t quit companies – they quit managers. Is the person you’re going to be working for somebody that you can learn and grow from? This person should definitely be a factor in your decision process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Trust your gut.&lt;/strong&gt; You’ll hear a lot from outside sources that tell you to take a certain job just because it pays more or because you get X or Y benefit. At the end of the day, it’s your decision. If you feel like it’s not the right one or you’re making it for someone else, take a step back and listen to what your gut is telling you. It’s usually right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deciding between two job offers can be tough, but it’s a much better problem to have than no job offers at all. If you have any questions for me in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/how-to-decide-between-2-job-offers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://govigblog.com/how-to-decide-between-2-job-offers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Healthcare</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Challenge Yourself to Think Like a Millennial</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/zsrP5Q0oZkc&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the second of a three-part series about millennials and how they can be beneficial to your business. Last week, I discussed misconceptions about millennials, so this week I’d like to talk about rebranding our initiatives for them.
&lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finding Your &amp;ldquo;Why&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We should all have a “why” but to be honest, before I worked with millennials, I frankly hadn’t given it much thought. I went to college, got a degree, and I wanted to be successful. But when people asked me why, all I could really give them was a blanket statement. I wanted to do well in work, make good money, be able to support myself and my future family, and that was it. &lt;strong&gt;It was when a millennial really challenged me that I had to change my thinking and recognize that I needed to be able to offer them more as a manager.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One millennial asked, “Why do you get up in the morning?” I hadn’t even thought about it. &lt;strong&gt;Millennials want to know that they have purpose&lt;/strong&gt;, to be able to see themselves progress into a career, and to understand the “why” to what we do and how they can do it so they can be successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s part of their career journey, part of their development, which has been very, very different from my own developing years. Many of us didn’t have to answer that question and we hadn’t really given it much thought. Today, I can confidently tell anyone I work with—millennial or otherwise—that I get up in the morning because I like to help personally and professionally develop my team. I like to help them reach their goals and succeed with the goals that I set for them. I want to see them grow and achieve levels they may never have thought they could. It’s my job, my duty, and my passion to get up every morning to help them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Millennials want to know that they have purpose%20http://govigblog.com/challenge-yourself-to-think-like-a-millennial.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Millennials want to know that they have purpose”&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fun in the Workplace&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It’s often said that millennials just want to have fun. Don’t we all? We work more than we do anything else in this life, and my thought is that if people really aren’t having any fun, then they already are, or could become, pretty miserable. &lt;strong&gt;Really understanding what “fun” means, especially to this newer generation entering the workforce, is so extremely important.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It used to be that “happy hours” were where people would go to have fun, blow off some steam, and talk about the week and the challenges we faced. Honestly, millennials may not find happy hours fun. Yes, happy hours are great for networking and camaraderie, but millennials are looking for something different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I challenge you to really challenge the status quo by &lt;strong&gt;asking them what they want to do for fun.&lt;/strong&gt;Don’t be surprised if their answer is something like an escape room, where they have to think, or giving back to a nonprofit or volunteering. Remember that millennials want a purpose and to know that what they’re doing is making an impact in the world today. By you changing your initiatives and understanding what fun is for them, &lt;strong&gt;it will prove to those millennials that you care as much about the bottom line as you do about impacting and benefiting the world.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you so much for your time. If you have any other questions about this or other topics, please feel free to contact me. I’d love to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/challenge-yourself-to-think-like-a-millennial.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://govigblog.com/challenge-yourself-to-think-like-a-millennial.html</guid>
        
        <category>BioPharma</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ace Your Next Interview With the STAR Method</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/BkGR1lzDTmw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In today’s marketplace, more and more employers are using behavioral-based interviews. This style of interview is designed to examine applicants based on past behavior and performances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A behavior-based interview might start off with questions like “Tell me about a time when . . .” or “Give me an example of . . .” Sometimes, people can be tempted to ramble when answering these questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, there is a way to add structure to your answers. Today, I’d like to go over something called the STAR Method. Here’s how it works:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“S” stands for “situation.”&lt;/strong&gt; The first part of your answer should explain the context of the situation you’re describing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“T” stands for “task.”&lt;/strong&gt; After you explain the situation, explain your role in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“A” stands for “action.”&lt;/strong&gt; Describe what you did to overcome, fix, or address the situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“R” stands for “results.”&lt;/strong&gt; What was the outcome of the situation?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Following the STAR method creates a streamlined response instead of a rambling one.%20http://govigblog.com/ace-your-next-interview-with-the-star-method.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Following the STAR method creates a streamlined response instead of a rambling one.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you understand the STAR Method, let’s review an example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine you’re in an interview and are asked to recount a challenge you experienced at work. You might answer by saying something like, “I was hired on as a director of sales for an assisted living center, they were at 74% occupancy.” This portion of your response constitutes the “s”—the situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, you might continue with a phrase like, “It was my role to develop their referral lead base.” Now you’ve covered the “t” portion of your answer—your task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that you may tell them “I went into the marketplace and developed relationships with hospital systems and physician groups. I led marketing events and really became the face of the community. I developed long-standing relationships.” With this response, you’ve established your “a”—your action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, it’s time for your “r”—your results. In this scenario, you might finish by saying, “As a result, we grew to 95% occupancy within nine months of my tenure.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the STAR Method creates a streamlined response instead of a rambling one. However, you still won’t know what questions you’re going to be asked when you’re going into the interview. My advice is to pull up qualifications, pull out hot buttons, pull out some skill sets, and get with the recruiter you’re working with. &lt;strong&gt;Have some stories relating to your qualifications and skill sets in mind as you enter the interview.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/ace-your-next-interview-with-the-star-method.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://govigblog.com/ace-your-next-interview-with-the-star-method.html</guid>
        
        <category>Healthcare</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Are Millennial Employees Different?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/x-w9mPxfVyk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the past 15 years, I’ve been lucky enough to hire, train, and engage with Millennials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a lot of negativity surrounding the subject of Millennials entering the workforce, but today I want to focus on some positives. Actually, millennials can bring a lot of benefits to a work place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, &lt;strong&gt;M&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;illennials speak up about questions and concerns that past generations did not. &lt;/strong&gt;This doesn’t mean they’re entitled, it just means they understand what they need in order to perform and be successful. Many times, Millennials simply want to understand the “why” of what they’re being told to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first joined the workforce, I wasn’t given that “why.” When I was assigned tasks, I was told to just do them, often without clear reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Millennials won’t just “go do” things. They want to understand why a given task is being asked of them, so that they can perform towards the best result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Millennials challenge the status quo because they’re always seeking out better alternatives.%20http://govigblog.com/how-are-millennial-employees-different.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Millennials challenge the status quo because they’re always seeking out better alternatives.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second point I’d like to make is that &lt;strong&gt;millennials are disruptors. But, why is this a good thing?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I once had a supervisor tell me that it’s just because something had always been done one way, it doesn’t mean that the right way. That was a game changer for me. Millennials understand this. They challenge the status quo because they’re seeking out better alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, &lt;strong&gt;M&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;illennials are tech-savvy.&lt;/strong&gt; In today’s technology-driven society, this is a great thing. Embracing the knowledge and skills of Millennial employees can be greatly beneficial to any business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/how-are-millennial-employees-different.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://govigblog.com/how-are-millennial-employees-different.html</guid>
        
        <category>BioPharma</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Structuring Your Sales Team to Meet or Exceed Your Sales Goals</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qJ_2QWIsVzI&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With 2017 quickly coming to a close, companies are looking at their infrastructure and deciding how they want to enter 2018 in order to meet or exceed their sales goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s common in the building products industry, both commercial and residential, for companies to have a go-to market strategy with either independent agents, direct salespeople, or a combination of both. With the companies we deal with, we’re realizing that &lt;strong&gt;even the smaller ones need to make the transition from independent agents to direct salespeople in a lot of markets across the country.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Independent agents don’t fully represent your product.%20http://govigblog.com/structuring-your-sales-team-to-meet-or-exceed-your-sales-goals.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Independent agents don’t fully represent your product.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will obviously be smaller markets where it makes more sense to have independent agents because there is a fixed cost with direct salespeople that you don’t have with independent agents—you only pay them if they sell your product. However, the downside is they don’t fully represent your product specifically in the marketplace. Your time is split between the other products they sell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of companies are looking at the major markets, but they’re also bringing their focus down into the B-level markets where they’re transitioning from independent agents to direct salespeople in order to have a bigger and stronger breakthrough in that marketplace. &lt;strong&gt;They believe the growth in sales in those markets will heavily outweigh the small fixed costs involved.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any more questions about this topic or you’d like to discuss it further, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We’d love to speak with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/structuring-your-sales-team-to-meet-or-exceed-your-sales-goals.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://govigblog.com/structuring-your-sales-team-to-meet-or-exceed-your-sales-goals.html</guid>
        
        <category>Building Products</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Dating Game: How Interviewing for a Job and Finding Love Are Similar</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/SLHJMDhU46s&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I began my career at Govig &amp;amp; Associates, I was an executive recruiter on our Biopharma team. I noticed that a lot of tenured executives would compare interviewing to dating. This was a curious comparison to me, but as I learned more, I realized that they were correct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it’s time to make a change, whether it be in your dating life or in your career, the steps are actually rather similar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First, you’re going to prospect.&lt;/strong&gt; You might join an online dating service, access your network, and agree to be set up on some blind dates. Before even agreeing to these, you’ll probably research that person on social media or ask your family and friends about them. You’ll want to learn more before agreeing to the setup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In interviews, it’s the same thing&lt;/strong&gt;. You’ll go to online job boards to search for jobs or companies that interest you. Before applying, you’d check a site like Glassdoor, look at stock information, or read news about the company trends they’ve gone through to provide more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, once you’ve decided to go on the date, &lt;strong&gt;it’s time for the first meeting.&lt;/strong&gt; Most people don’t go on a first date with the intention of a marriage proposal at the end of it. It’s just a time to get to know one another. &lt;strong&gt;You ask questions, learn about each other, and decide if your interests and goals are similar.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is very similar to the interview process. I stress to a lot of candidates that agreeing to go on &lt;strong&gt;a first interview is not a commitment to that job&lt;/strong&gt;; it’s just a commitment to learning more about the company and for them to learn more about you. Use this to your advantage—ask good questions that will give you more serious information about the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third, &lt;strong&gt;if the first date or interview went well, you’ll enter into a relationship.&lt;/strong&gt; Sometimes this could lead to meeting family and friends, which I also call the team interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Most people don’t go on a first date with the intention of a marriage proposal at the end of it.%20http://govigblog.com/the-dating-game-how-interviewing-for-a-job-and-finding-love-are-similar.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Most people don’t go on a first date with the intention of a marriage proposal at the end of it.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if that all continues to go well, it could lead to the final stages. In dating, this would mean a marriage proposal. With a marriage proposal, there are a lot of logistical aspects that need to be organized: the timing, the ring, the delivery, and so on. &lt;strong&gt;Typically, a lot of things have been discussed with your partner before extending this proposal&lt;/strong&gt;, so the likelihood of acceptance is rather high.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the same in the interview process when you get to the point of the job offer being extended. Like the proposal, many logistical aspects need to be put together: start date, compensation, title, etc. &lt;strong&gt;A lot of these will have already been discussed in the interview(s)&lt;/strong&gt;, so the expectations are managed appropriately and the likelihood of having the offer be accepted is high.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, dating and interviewing can be very similar. Both can be stressful and emotional, but we do them because the outcome for our personal and professional growth is positive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, please feel free to email me directly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/the-dating-game-how-interviewing-for-a-job-and-finding-love-are-similar.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://govigblog.com/the-dating-game-how-interviewing-for-a-job-and-finding-love-are-similar.html</guid>
        
        <category>BioPharma</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bring These 7 Things to Any Job Interview</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/9H7KAZIYkLI&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m going to be talking to you about seven things you ought to bring to every job interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Directions and contact information.&lt;/strong&gt; If you’ve never been to the location of your interview before, it’s important to have directions to your interview ahead of time and also have the contact information of your interviewer. In the event that you run late, you can let them know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Identification.&lt;/strong&gt; Just in case, you should bring a form of identification to the interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Notepad and pen.&lt;/strong&gt; During your interview, you may want to take notes, record addresses, and/or write some questions. You’ll look more prepared if you bring your own materials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Resume.&lt;/strong&gt; I would suggest bringing at least 3 copies of your most updated resume. If you’ve made any changes, you can let them know what changes you’ve made. Bring extra copies in case other interviewers decide to join the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. References.&lt;/strong&gt; Have 3 professional references to provide to your interviewer, including your relation to the reference and their contact information, such as a cell phone number or email address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. A portfolio.&lt;/strong&gt; This can depend on the type of job you’re after, but it may be good to bring a portfolio of your past work. This can be in a folder, a binder, or a tablet-friendly website. It should be very organized and easily referenced during your interview. The contents will depend on the profession, but &lt;strong&gt;it should have quality examples of your work and accomplishments&lt;/strong&gt; regardless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Questions. &lt;/strong&gt;After every job interview, you’re going to be asked if you have any questions. You should be prepared with at least two or three specific questions to ask, whether they’re about the culture of the company, the hiring process, expectations of the position, and so on. If you have questions ready, &lt;strong&gt;it’ll show that you’re both prepared for and interested in the position.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you have questions for your interviewer ready, it’ll show that you’re both prepared for and interested in the position%20http://govigblog.com/bring-these-7-things-to-any-job-interview.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you have questions for your interviewer ready, it’ll show that you’re both prepared for and interested in the position”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of things go through your head on the day of your interview; it’s important not to forget the small things because they could end up costing you the job or getting you the job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me, please reach out to me. I’d be glad to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/bring-these-7-things-to-any-job-interview.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://govigblog.com/bring-these-7-things-to-any-job-interview.html</guid>
        
        <category>Healthcare</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
