<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>What's Working Now!</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from 240-731-8079 - your professional Cleveland Park Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 13:51:03 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 13:51:03 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>What's Working Now! - How an Under-the-Radar Strategy Can Sell Your Home Now</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/OeE5upoA5cM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the latest episode of “What’s Working Now!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I want to share a successful under-the-radar strategy for selling a home that worked in the middle of the holidays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, if you are thinking of selling your home in 2018, I have something special to share with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, we recently sold a home about a week before Christmas. When I met with the homeowner to talk about cleaning, sorting, staging, and making the house market-ready, she looked like she was going to cry. So, we decided on a different strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We decided to show the home before it was ready for the market.&lt;/strong&gt; The market is full of buyers, interest rates are low, and inventory is so low that there is practically nothing for sale. In the last couple of weeks, we’ve had eight buyers that wanted to buy two houses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Inventory is incredibly low right now, which means there is almost no competition for sellers.%20http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/whats-working-now-how-an-under-the-radar-strategy-can-sell-your-home-now.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Inventory is incredibly low right now, which means there is almost no competition for sellers.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went ahead and advertised this particular property under the radar to my network of prospects, agents, and the neighborhood. One of the neighbors had a friend who wanted to look at the house. This was the only person we showed the property to, and they turned out to be the right buyer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are thinking of selling your home in 2018, there is no need to wait for the azaleas to be in bloom. The seller I just told you about entered the market in the middle of the holiday season. The market is hot right now. &lt;strong&gt;Inventory is incredibly low, so there is almost no competition.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find an agent who can take advantage of current market conditions to make it easy for you to get top dollar fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you plan on selling your house in 2018, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dchomeblog.com/freebook&quot;&gt;check out my new book&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, “Selling Secrets You Can’t Afford to Miss.” To get your free copy, visit &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dchomeblog.com/freebook&quot;&gt;DCHomeblog.com/FreeBook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for watching &lt;em&gt;“What’s Working Now!”&lt;/em&gt; Be on the lookout for our next video, where I’ll look back on the 2017 market and go over what you can expect in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, if you have any other questions in the meantime, please don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 07:06:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/whats-working-now-how-an-under-the-radar-strategy-can-sell-your-home-now.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/whats-working-now-how-an-under-the-radar-strategy-can-sell-your-home-now.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What's Working Now! - Hire a Real Estate Agent With Negotiating Expertise</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/H_19mDnLENE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to another episode of &lt;em&gt;“What’s Working Now!” &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I want to talk about the value of negotiating experience and expertise, especially when sellers get multiple offers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me give you an example. We recently put a house on the market on a Friday. By Sunday, it had five offers, and we sold the house Sunday evening. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your agent needs to be able to talk to the buyer agents about how to write a good offer in the first place.&lt;/strong&gt; Once the house is on the market and has had a couple of showings, the agents start calling me and asking, “When are you presenting offers? How are you doing this or that?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At that time, I take the opportunity to discuss with those agents how I would like them to write their offer. I say, “The seller would really appreciate a settlement date of X. The seller would really appreciate a short home inspection contingency or none at all. If your offer is going to have a financing contingency, the seller would appreciate seeing a financial information sheet, not just a lender letter.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I give the agents instructions to bring us what we want: a big number, a short settlement date, and a big, fat deposit from a well-qualified buyer. If possible, we want that from five different buyers if we can get it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So last weekend, I put the word out to these agents and told them exactly what we wanted. I even said, “I know there will be other offers on this property. Rather than doing an escalation clause, which says ‘If someone makes me pay more, I’ll pay more,’ just come in and say ‘I will pay more. I will give you this and take out that contingency.’ That way, your buyer will have a better chance of winning the home, so please make your offer like that.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I talked to these five agents, I got two offers that were really low and had all kinds of contingencies. Those two offers were no good. I got three offers with really big numbers, so I called those three agents and coached them on how to make their offers better while I was sitting with the seller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=I reach out and coach the agents on what the seller wants in an offer.%20http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/whats-working-now-hire-a-real-estate-agent-with-negotiating-expertise.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“I reach out and coach the agents on what the seller wants in an offer.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any other real estate agent might have looked at those three offers, picked the best one, and sent it over for you to sign. They would probably say something like, “We got five offers! Look at what someone was willing to pay for your home! Here, sign this one.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me and my clients, that’s not good enough. I take it the extra step. Once I get the offers, I take the best ones and &lt;strong&gt;have a conversation with the agents about how they can improve the offers if they want a better chance at winning.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this case, two of the buyers increased their price, while the other took out the financing contingency and the appraisal contingency. I was able to get one buyer and one back-up buyer for my seller. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first buyer called their home inspector, came into the property, and immediately got cold feet. That buyer wound up walking away from the transaction. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, we had a backup buyer in place. I didn’t have to change the status of the property and say, “This deal fell apart and the house is now back on the market.” Instead, the home remained under contract, and the second buyer got the chance to slip in and get the house without renegotiating. It was a win-win for that buyer and for my seller. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We just had the inspection today, and everything looks good so far. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you sell your home, make sure that you work with a listing agent who will price the home correctly and make it look good enough to get all those people in the door. That agent will be able to create the opportunity for multiple offers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your agent also needs to be good enough to coach the buyer agents on how to make those offers into something that will get a better outcome for you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your home is priced well, looks good, and you have an agent who is an excellent negotiator, &lt;strong&gt;you will end up with a win.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To learn more about selling your home, make sure to watch the Home Seller Half Hour this week. &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.webinarjam.net/register/40860/ffb94e1c2b&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Sign up here&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to learn everything you need to know in less than 30 minutes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for watching &lt;em&gt;“What’s Working Now!”&lt;/em&gt; Next time, I’ll cover some of the coolest things happening in our red-hot real estate market. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, if you have any other real estate questions, just give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 09:59:20 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/whats-working-now-hire-a-real-estate-agent-with-negotiating-expertise.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/whats-working-now-hire-a-real-estate-agent-with-negotiating-expertise.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What's Working Now - Creative Ways to Generate More Interest in Your Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/mKfjXQ5VbT0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the latest episode of &lt;em&gt;“What’s Working Now!”&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I want to talk to you about &lt;strong&gt;an innovative way to generate additional buyer activity when selling your home.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, we have a new listing that is getting market-ready. The seller is moving boxes around, packing, cleaning, and gardening so that the house is ready to hit the market in the next couple of weeks. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The seller had the idea that they would like to invite their friends over to say goodbye to the house. We picked a day on the weekend and invited them over in the middle of the day while the sun was out and the friends all got to take a look at the house. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought it was a really good idea. Then we started talking about other ideas we’ve used on past properties to market the home to the seller’s community. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes time to market your home, I have a network of 3,500 real estate agents, 2,000 prospects, and a neighborhood listserv of 20,000 of my closest friends. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past, I’ve also had the sellers send my ad with the video tour of their home out to their own listservs. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about it. You may have a network of fellow college alumni, other parents from your kid’s high school, or you may belong to a church, synagogue, or music group. You may have your own “listserv” right on your own street. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Do you know anyone who might have a buyer for your house?%20http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/whats-working-now-creative-ways-to-generate-more-interest-in-your-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Do you know anyone who might have a buyer for your house?”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you take this ad and send it out to your friends, &lt;strong&gt;you can tap into a whole new pool of people.&lt;/strong&gt; As a seller, your friends might know someone who would be interested in purchasing your house. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also had past sellers send the ad to their Facebook friends. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, I show my sellers the examples of the ad and tell them about the networks and publications that I will send the ad to. Then, I say, “If you have a group of people or friends who might know someone interested in your property, why don’t we tap into those people as well? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the seller isn’t sure, then I let it go. If they think it’s a great idea, we talk about their Facebook, their neighborhood listserv, or any newsletters they may send out as part of their job or other organizations they may belong to. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By sending out the ad to the seller’s network, we are tapping into even more people than I would ever have access to, which is great. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I also have the seller make a video showing off their home.&lt;/strong&gt; The seller walks around and talks about family dinners, the wedding in the front yard, and the attic the kids used to play hide and seek in. I make the video look like a really nice home video. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, before I could even offer, the owner said to me, “How about I send this video to my friends?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought, what a great idea! We are doing just that with a new listing this week. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When getting ready to sell your house, make sure that you work with an agent who has some of these creative ideas. Think about who you know who may know a buyer for your house. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn more about the value of getting your home ready for the real estate market. Be sure to watch the Home Seller Half Hour this week. &lt;u&gt;Sign up here&lt;/u&gt; to learn everything you need to know about selling your home in less than 30 minutes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for watching &lt;em&gt;“What’s Working Now!”&lt;/em&gt; In my next video, I’ll talk about some of the coolest things that are happening in our red-hot real estate market. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, if you have any other questions about real estate, please don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 05:13:43 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/whats-working-now-creative-ways-to-generate-more-interest-in-your-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/whats-working-now-creative-ways-to-generate-more-interest-in-your-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What's Working Now! - How Backup Contracts Help Homebuyers &amp; Sellers</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/AyJbIjrDPro?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the latest episode of &lt;em&gt;“What’s Working Now!”&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m recording live from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/place/4550+Klingle+St+NW,+Washington,+DC+20016/@38.9313404,-77.0904095,3a,75y,185.8h,89.36t/data=!3m6!1e1!3m4!1spUUOxJ9umn0d14MaVUfEWQ!2e0!7i13312!8i6656!4m5!3m4!1s0x89b7b61d305faadb:0xea5abefb28b270f7!8m2!3d38.9311572!4d-77.0903391&quot;&gt;4550 Klingle Street NW&lt;/a&gt; in Wesley Heights. Today, I want to discuss the value of backup contracts for both buyers and sellers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, what is a backup contract? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say you have accepted an offer from a buyer already but there is another buyer who wanted the house. Maybe they were too late to make an offer or they lost out in a multiple offer situation. &lt;strong&gt;This buyer can write a backup offer. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, the backup offer says that if the first buyer backs out, you will agree to be the buyer at this price and these terms. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How does the backup offer benefit you as a seller? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say you have a buyer already. They do the home inspection and decide not to purchase the house after all and get a release signed. If you have a backup offer in place, then you can automatically start working with that buyer. You don’t have to put the home back on the market and spend time advertising the property again—you just move on to the next buyer. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If the seller has to relist the home, the buyer will face more competition again.%20http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/whats-working-now-how-backup-contracts-help-homebuyers-sellers.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If the seller has to relist the home, the buyer will face more competition again.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How does the backup offer benefit you as a buyer? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you really want this house but it already went under contract, you can submit a backup offer in case the deal falls through. Without a backup offer, the house will go back on the market and advertised to more buyers, which gives you more competition. You may lose the house a second time if you wait for it to come back on the market. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you submit a backup offer and the deal falls through, then the house will automatically go to you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may also end up paying less for the property. Let’s say you didn’t get the house in the first place due to multiple offers. You had to escalate your price and you still lost. &lt;strong&gt;As a backup offer, you might have a different contract at a different price.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you are buying or selling a home, make sure that you work with an agent who understands the value of the backup contract. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can learn more about the value of getting your home market ready by watching the Home Seller Half Hour this week. &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.webinarjam.net/register/40860/ffb94e1c2b&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Sign up here&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to learn everything you need to know about selling your home in less than 30 minutes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My listing here at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/place/4550+Klingle+St+NW,+Washington,+DC+20016/@38.9313404,-77.0904095,3a,75y,185.8h,89.36t/data=!3m6!1e1!3m4!1spUUOxJ9umn0d14MaVUfEWQ!2e0!7i13312!8i6656!4m5!3m4!1s0x89b7b61d305faadb:0xea5abefb28b270f7!8m2!3d38.9311572!4d-77.0903391&quot;&gt;4550 Klingle Street NW&lt;/a&gt; at Wesley Heights SOLD for full price! &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://spws.homevisit.com/hvid/201973&quot;&gt;Take a look at the virtual tour here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;. Let me know if you’d like me to find you a house like it. I’m here to help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for watching &lt;em&gt;“What’s Working Now!”&lt;/em&gt; Be on the lookout for our next video, where I’ll go over some of the coolest things happening in our local market. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about real estate in the meantime, please don’t hesitate to reach out to me by phone or email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 09:23:40 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/whats-working-now-how-backup-contracts-help-homebuyers-sellers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/whats-working-now-how-backup-contracts-help-homebuyers-sellers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What's Working Now! - How Do You Know If You Need A New Price?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/LWx-va3aZDQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to another episode of “What’s Working Now!” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m recording live from our new listing at 4550 Klingle St. NW at Wesley Heights. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also want to discuss one of the smartest things a seller can do: price reductions.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you know if you need a price reduction?&lt;/strong&gt; There are two main things to look for. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, let’s say you have a brand-new listing in a hot market. If no one calls and there are no showings, what’s wrong? Is the market bad? Is the market slow? No. Buyers respond to price, condition, and location. If the price of your home isn’t right for its condition or location, then the phone isn’t going to ring. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, one of the signs that you may need a price reduction is when no one calls or asks questions about your brand-new listing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, you may have 20 or 25 people come in for a showing. They look at your house, say that it looks great, but no one makes an offer. This tells you that &lt;strong&gt;there is no urgency to make an offer on this product in this location at the current price.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If no one calls to ask about your home, you may want to consider a price reduction.%20http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/whats-working-now-how-do-you-know-if-you-need-a-new-price.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If no one calls to ask about your home, you may want to consider a price reduction.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what do you do?  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It usually falls to the agent to recommend a price reduction. Go to the computer to take some notes. Pay attention to what has sold over the last two weeks while your house has been sitting on the market. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, call your seller to let them know what you’ve found. Show that no one is looking at the home even though four listings in the area have sold in the last two weeks. Use the statistics to make the case that they need to have the price reduction. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the seller doesn’t believe you, look to a partner, manager, or someone else in the office to back you up. Find a CEO or president—someone who will understand that the price needs to be reduced. Give them the statistics and have them write a letter for you to pass along to your client. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve done this with my partner, and it’s been very effective. In fact, I just did this a week ago. My partner wrote a letter to the seller backing up my recommendation for a price reduction. The sellers agreed. &lt;strong&gt;Soon after the price reduction, they got two offers and sold the house.&lt;/strong&gt; The inspection went through and they are heading to the closing table next week. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to learn more about selling your home in the current market, &lt;a href=&quot;www.homesellerhalfhour.tv&quot;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt; to sign up for the Seller Half Hour Seminar online. I’ll cover everything you need to know in less than 30 minutes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in my listing at 4550 Klingle St. NW at Wesley Heights, take a &lt;a href=&quot;www.4550Klingle.com&quot;&gt;virtual tour here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for watching “What’s Working Now!” Stay tuned for our next video, where I’ll discuss one of the latest market strategies that can make a big difference for both buyers and sellers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, if you have any other questions about real estate, just give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to speaking with you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 08:34:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/whats-working-now-how-do-you-know-if-you-need-a-new-price.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/whats-working-now-how-do-you-know-if-you-need-a-new-price.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What's Working Now! - What’s Wrong With Virtual Home Staging?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/UcOutsJCggI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the latest episode of &lt;em&gt;“What’s Working Now!”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m recording live from 3540 39th Street in McLean Gardens, which recently sold over its listing price of $545,000. The house opened on a Sunday afternoon and sold the next day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to talk about how high touch still beats this high tech deal killer known as virtual staging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know how I feel about home staging and how important it is to my sellers. In some cases, staging has helped my sellers net an extra $100,000 or $200,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what’s wrong with virtual staging? After all, it’s easier and cheaper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is that virtual staging is a &lt;strong&gt;recipe for disaster.&lt;/strong&gt; You may dazzle prospective buyers online only to disappoint them in person. It’s like going to an online dating site, finding an appealing partner, and upon meeting them in person, discover that their online photo must have been taken 25 years ago on a really good day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Virtual staging is a recipe for disaster.%20http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/whats-working-now-whats-wrong-with-virtual-home-staging.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Virtual staging is a recipe for disaster.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Staging is all about how you make the buyer feel the moment they step inside your home. You don’t want them to feel deceived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, virtual staging is penny wise and pound foolish, with one notable exception.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say you can’t afford to stage your home to get top dollar and your home doesn’t look like a million bucks. If some buyers are interested but not jumping, that’s when you unveil the possibilities for your home with virtual staging. Only do this after the buyers have already seen the house. &lt;strong&gt;In this instance, they just need a little nudge.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I’ve never tried virtual staging. If the right occasion arose, I would give it a shot. That said, I really want my clients to focus on what’s working now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are thinking about selling your home, &lt;a href=&quot;www.homesellerhalfhour.tv&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;sign up&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for our Seller Half Hour seminar online, where you’ll learn everything you need to know about selling a home in just 30 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can take a quick tour of our sold listing at 3540 39th Street &lt;a href=&quot;www.354039th.com&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;here&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for watching &lt;em&gt;“What’s Working Now!”&lt;/em&gt; Stay tuned for our next video. In the meantime, if you have any other questions about real estate, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 11:20:44 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/whats-working-now-whats-wrong-with-virtual-home-staging.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/whats-working-now-whats-wrong-with-virtual-home-staging.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What's Working Now! - Why Home Staging Works for Home Sellers</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/H27lZhj6Vn0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste present-before-paste&quot;&gt;Welcome to another episode of “What’s Working Now!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;Today, I’m reporting to you live from my new listing at 3201 Garfield Street NW on the edge of Cleveland Park. This home is on the market for $1.695 million.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;You all know how I feel about staging, and something happened at the Garfield house that demonstrates exactly how important staging is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;In many cases, home staging has helped my sellers net an extra $100,000. Sometimes, though, a motivated buyer will get a sneak preview before the house is ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;I invited an agent and her prospective buyers over to the Garfield house. She was working with a family of four. They came into the dining room. The sellers had their wedding guest list on the wall. The agent noticed it and couldn’t take her eyes off of it, and she told her buyers, “Come over here and see who’s invited to the wedding.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Make sure you pack away personal items before listing your home for sale.%20http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/whats-working-now-why-home-staging-works-for-home-sellers.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Make sure you pack away personal items before listing your home for sale.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;There were also a number of personal photos and other wedding memorabilia in the dining room. It turns out that the buyers were so distracted by all of these personal items that they never really looked at the house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;After that, we came in and made sure to pack away all personal photos that were in that dining room. The kitchen walls were brown and covered in pictures as well, so we cleared everything away, opened up the windows, and made the house clean and shiny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;As you can see, staging your home makes a huge difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;To learn more about the value of preparing your home for the market, you can &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.homesellerhalfhour.tv/&quot;&gt;sign up here&lt;/a&gt; to watch our Seller Half Hour seminar online. Remember, you can learn everything you need to know about selling a home in just 30 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;If you would like a tour of my new listing, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.3201garfield.com/&quot;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;for a tour from the seller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;Thank you for watching “What’s Working Now!”Be sure to tune in next time, when I’ll discuss a breakthrough in technology that may actually be a step backward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;In the meantime, if you have any other questions about real estate or the current market, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 11:24:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/whats-working-now-why-home-staging-works-for-home-sellers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/whats-working-now-why-home-staging-works-for-home-sellers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What's Working Now! - Learn How to Sell Your Home in Half an Hour</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/3OzRPUiPnBk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi this is Marjorie Dick Stuart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for watching, ‘What’s Working Now!’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ve probably noticed, I’m not at my desk. We’re doing something DIFFERENT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to record LIVE from my new listing at 4550 Klingle Street in Wesley Heights. It’s on the market for $1,799,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The staging is complete… It looks terriﬁc and I can’t wait for you to see it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m going to talk to you about How To Sell Your House For Top Dollar, Fast This Summer… No matter what your family, friends, neighbors &amp;amp; the “so-called” experts say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to tell you about… a brand new, exclusive resource for you if you’re thinking about selling your house now, or in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been over 35 years in the making, but takes you less than 30 minutes to cover everything online!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m really excited to announce my just-released webinar for neighborhood homeowners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a step-by-step…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Home Selling Guide To Get Top Dollar in Any Market… and how to eliminate your feeling of overwhelm, so you can focus on your future!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=In less than 30 minutes, you’ll learn the secrets to our proven home-selling system!%20http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/whats-working-now-learn-how-to-sell-your-home-in-half-an-hour.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“In less than 30 minutes, you’ll learn the secrets to our proven home-selling system!”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just go to my brand NEW online “Home Seller Half Hour” and discover a simple, market-proven, “home selling” system in just [ONE SHORT SESSION].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll ﬁnd out…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Everything you always wanted to know about selling your house, but nobody bothered to teach you, until now!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The one thing you must NEVER forget.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How to avoid the single BIGGEST mistake you could possibly make.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What you should and should NOT do to your home to get it “market-ready.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The best NEW strategy to get more buyers ﬁghting over your house!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ready to take a peek? Go ahead, check it out &amp;amp; let me know what you think!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watch the Home Seller “Half Hour” this week, click here! (REMEMBER: I cover everything in less than 30 minutes)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you’d like to take a quick tour of my new listing here at 4550 Klingle Street, just click here and take a virtual tour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll be amazed at the expanded spaces!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So thanks for watching ‘What’s Working Now!’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be on the lookout for my next video…we’ll talk about an important aspect of staging that most agents miss!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 05:29:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/whats-working-now-learn-how-to-sell-your-home-in-half-an-hour.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/whats-working-now-learn-how-to-sell-your-home-in-half-an-hour.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What's Working Now! - The Power of Pinpoint Pricing in Today’s Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jf9nWVdIutc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to another episode of &lt;em&gt;“What’s Working Now!”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our market is crazy right now. There’s practically no supply and demand is skyrocketing. It seems like everyone wants to buy a house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a seller, how do you get the most money for your home in this kind of market?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may think that since your house is the only one for sale in your neighborhood, you can price it as high as you want. After all, someone has to buy it if it’s the only home available, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Actually, I recommend using pinpoint pricing if you want to get top dollar for your home.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently sold a house in North Cleveland Park. The seller wanted to get at least $1.2 million for the home, but I wasn’t sure that buyers would be willing to pay $1.2 million for the home. I told the seller that we should use pinpoint pricing and price the home just under $1.2 million. That way, buyers would be excited about the property and overbid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of going right to pinpoint pricing, we decided to play with it for a couple of weeks. We sent the house out to my network of 3,500 local real estate agents and 2,000 prospects. We also placed a couple of ads in neighborhood listservs and some local publications. The home was advertised at $1.2 million.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Pricing the home slightly under market value will help you sell for top dollar.%20http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/whats-working-now-the-power-of-pinpoint-pricing-in-todays-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Pricing the home slightly under market value will help you sell for top dollar.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, nobody jumped up and expressed interest for the home. At that point, we decided to pinpoint that number in order to get a lot of people in the door and excited about the property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We put the listing on the MLS at $1.15 million on the first day and the seller wound up accepting an offer of $1.29 million, which is way above that first number we advertised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Advertising the home at $1.2 million put the home above comparable properties, which is why buyers didn’t make an offer. &lt;strong&gt;Once we pinpointed the pricing, the seller was able to net more than they expected in the first place.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for watching “What’s Working Now!” Stay tuned for our next video, where I’ll go over creative solutions for challenges in today’s market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;P.S. If you’d like to learn more about how to put the most money in your pocket, &lt;a href=&quot;http://a30441.actonsoftware.com/acton/media/30441/overpricing-guide&quot;&gt;[CLICK HERE]&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2017 06:28:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/whats-working-now-the-power-of-pinpoint-pricing-in-todays-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/whats-working-now-the-power-of-pinpoint-pricing-in-todays-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What's Working Now! - How to Use the Power of Deadlines to Your Advantage</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7BQYXVMkAPs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the latest episode of &lt;em&gt;“What’s Working Now!”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Homebuyers and real estate agents alike often misunderstand the power of deadlines. Today, I’ll go over the pros and cons of including a deadline with your offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, one of my buyers settled on a house that was brand new to the market. The house went up for sale on a Thursday, and the agent asked for offers by next week. My buyer really wanted this house, so I said, “&lt;strong&gt;If you write a compelling offer that is too good to be true, we can include a deadline&lt;/strong&gt; and make them answer us tonight before midnight.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The offer was all cash with no contingencies. The buyer offered to settle in four days and even included a rent-back that allowed the seller to stay in the home, rent-free, until August.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The seller had four hours to make a decision. The agent wasn’t prepared to accept offers so early and the sellers were traveling. Still, we required an answer by 11:30. They answered with thirty seconds to spare and we had a ratified contract!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the deadline certainly helped this buyer, deadlines aren’t always a good idea. I had another buyer who wanted to make a full-price offer with a 24-hour deadline. I explained that the 24-hour deadline was not a good idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Only use a deadline if you have a truly compelling offer.%20http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/whats-working-now-how-to-use-the-power-of-deadlines-to-your-advantage.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Only use a deadline if you have a truly compelling offer.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, this buyer was giving the seller 24 hours to call every prospective buyer that had been through the house and find a better offer. Deadlines are best used when you are making a compelling offer that’s too good to be true. In this market, a full-price offer is simply not that compelling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s very important that you &lt;strong&gt;work with an agent who understands when to harness the power of deadlines.&lt;/strong&gt; After all, this market is very competitive, and you don’t want to give other buyers the chance to sneak in and get the house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for watching “What’s Working Now!” Next time, I will have some advice for home sellers. Even though this is a hot market, you do need a strategy to sell your house for more than its market value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, if you have any other questions about deadlines or writing a compelling offer, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 08:54:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/whats-working-now-how-to-use-the-power-of-deadlines-to-your-advantage.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/whats-working-now-how-to-use-the-power-of-deadlines-to-your-advantage.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
