<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Michigan 401k under Financial Independence</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Financial Independence, LLC - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 12:46:04 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 12:46:04 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>We Can Help You and Your Employees Save for Retirement</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ugIdyq07aXg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine you’re getting ready to go on a great vacation and as your plane gets ready for takeoff, the flight attendant says, “Ladies and gentlemen, the captain would like me to inform you that there is an 85% chance that we will not get you to your destination on time and safely.” Are you going to stay on that flight? No way! Not with an 85% chance of failure!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we have learned in our 30 years of experience working with 401ks is that 85% of your employees have an &lt;strong&gt;85% chance of not making it to retirement on time and safely. &lt;/strong&gt;That’s what this series is going to be all about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have written a book called “Tracking Retirement” where we used our experience to put all the secrets to creating a successful 401k plan together in one place for both you and your participants. Our goal is to help you help them to create paychecks for life for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We have put all our expert advice in one place.%20localhost:4000/we-can-help-you-and-your-employees-save-for-retirement.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We have put all our expert advice in one place.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Over the course of the next year, we’ll discuss topics surrounding your 401k and ways you can improve it for yourself and your participants. &lt;/strong&gt;We will be sending a video out every other week covering a 401k topic, including how to reverse engineer your 401k expenses to reduce plan costs and how to get uncle Sam to pick up 30% or 40% of the bill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Pension Protection Act says that if you use specific automatic features in your 401k, you can get complete fiduciary liability. Guess what? Those same features improve the quality of the plan for those participants trying to create those paychecks for life. If you like what you’ve heard so far, stay tuned for our next post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/we-can-help-you-and-your-employees-save-for-retirement.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/we-can-help-you-and-your-employees-save-for-retirement.html</guid>
        
        <category>401K</category>
        
        <category>Financial Consultant</category>
        
        <category>Retirement Plans</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
