<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Greater Spokane Real Estate Video Blog with Alejandro Ventura</title>
    <description>Our mission at Alejandro Ventura Real Estate is to be your best resource for Greater Spokane real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Alejandro Ventura Real Estate, your professional Greater Spokane Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 15:36:42 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 15:36:42 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Whats the Cost of Selling Your Home?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/lzr1QTeoCT0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buyers aren’t the only ones who have to pay closing costs. Sellers can expect to pay 9% of their sale price on closing costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
**Want to sell your home?** &lt;a href=&quot;http://alejandrov.kwrealty.com/sell/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a FREE home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
**Want to buy a home?** &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all homes for sale&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all know there are costs associated with buying a home, but were you aware that there are also several costs of selling a home to consider before going through with listing it for sale?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Typically, a seller has to deal with eight different selling costs here in Spokane.&lt;/strong&gt; They include:
- Title insurance
- Escrow fees
- Excise tax
- Commissions
The more expensive your home is, the higher these costs will be. When you add them all up, they typically equate to about 9% of the sale price. So, when calculating your bottom line, you will be safe by assigning 9% of your asking price to closing costs and then subtracting any loans you have pending on your home. &lt;strong&gt;Doing this will give you a pretty solid idea of how much money you can expect to walk away with when the sale is finalized.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=SELLING A HOME ISN’T CHEAP.%20localhost:4000/whats-cost-of-selling-your-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“SELLING A HOME ISN’T CHEAP.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if you’re selling a home at $250,000, you can expect your closing costs to be anywhere from $20,000 to $25,000. Subtract that from your mortgage balance and you will get your bottom line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you found this helpful. If you have any questions in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 15:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/whats-cost-of-selling-your-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/whats-cost-of-selling-your-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Selling Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>6 Secrets to Selling for Top Dollar in Our Spring Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/y_zeqTEmDMw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have six secrets to share with you that can help your home sale generate maximum price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
**Want to sell your home?** &lt;a href=&quot;http://alejandrov.kwrealty.com/sell/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a FREE home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
**Want to buy a home?** &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all homes for sale&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking to sell your home in our spring market and are wondering how you can maximize your sale price, here are my six selling secrets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Don’t overprice the home.&lt;/strong&gt; Overpricing it is a poor strategy for making more money when you sell it. For example, last year in Spokane, 20% of the homes that entered the market failed to sell. That’s 1,800 homes in total. We know that the No. 1 reason a home doesn’t sell is pricing. Don’t be a part of that 20% and position your home to sell from the get-go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=THE NO. 1 REASON A HOME DOESN’T SELL IS PRICING.%20localhost:4000/6-secrets-to-selling-for-top-dollar-in.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“THE NO. 1 REASON A HOME DOESN’T SELL IS PRICING.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Clear your closet.&lt;/strong&gt; Storage is something every buyer is looking for in this market. Clear your closet as much as you can and then neatly organize whatever is left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Light it up.&lt;/strong&gt; New lighting in a new home ranks fairly high on most buyers’ priority lists. When showing your home, open the drapes, clean the windows, and replace any light bulbs where needed. Essentially, do all you can to ensure that your home shows brightly and cheerfully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Hire the right agent.&lt;/strong&gt; Working with a good agent will make you money. Hiring the wrong agent will cost you money. Hire someone who has marketing expertise and has systems and processes in place to ensure you have a successful transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. The kitchen comes first.&lt;/strong&gt; In many cases, you’re not selling your home—you’re selling your kitchen. That’s how important your kitchen is. If you’re planning on spending money preparing your home for sale, start there. That will give you the biggest bang for your buck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. First impressions are the only impression.&lt;/strong&gt; Buyers will make a value judgment about your house the moment they pull in front of it. Based on the curb appeal, they’ll decide to either go inside or drive away. Spend some time improving the curb appeal of your home. Take a minute and stand in front of your house and look at it from the eye of a buyer. Address any issues you need to fix to convey a great first impression. This could be the difference between selling and not selling your home for the price you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this topic or you’re looking to sell your home, feel free to give me a call. In the meantime, make it a great day!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 13:31:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/6-secrets-to-selling-for-top-dollar-in.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/6-secrets-to-selling-for-top-dollar-in.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Selling Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
