<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tools &amp; Training for Central Iowa Real Estate Professionals</title>
    <description>A Video Blog about Central Iowa Real Estate; It's industry, and the people working in it. Whether you're just starting out, aspiring to begin, or been working in the field for a few years, tune in to get updates, tips, tricks and more!</description>
    <link>http://bebetterdsm.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://bebetterdsm.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 15:06:27 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 15:06:27 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sellers, Beware of These 3 Myths</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/3Ntcm1SYTio?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a seller, there are three main real estate myths that you need to ignore when putting your home on the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Myth #1: You need to raise your listing price to leave room for negotiation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a tough one because it’s been reinforced time and time again, but just because people say it doesn’t mean it’s true. In our Central Iowa market, homes typically sell very close to their list price when they’re priced for today’s market. Depending on your home’s location and what type of home it is, it’s easy to anticipate getting anywhere from 98% to 100% of your list price. When we prepare a market analysis for our sellers, we give them an idea of what to anticipate and structure their pricing strategy based on those two factors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Myth #2: All homes sell in springtime, so it’s the only time to put your home on the market.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it’s true that a lot of people are fond of how their home looks in the springtime when everything’s in bloom, the truth is that homes sell every month of the year in our market. There are pros and cons to listing at any time of the year, so don’t worry about timing the market perfectly—worry about what’s best for your needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Don’t follow these myths—follow our tips instead.%20http://bebetterdsm.com/sellers-beware-of-these-3-myths.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Don’t follow these myths—follow our tips instead.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Myth #3: You don’t need to make any changes to your home because the buyer will just want to change it anyway.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though buyers love the idea of making renovations and improvements to their future home, the homes that sell the fastest and for top dollar the ones that are already neutralized in stylish, current colors. For carpeting and floor coverings, there are only so many different shades of gray and beige you can use. As a rule of thumb, we always suggest to our sellers to use carpeting that’s very in-style in new construction homes because that’s market-proven to be what buyers desire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So remember, price your home correctly and don’t artificially inflate it thinking you’re giving yourself room for negotiation. Also, remember that spring isn’t the only time homes sell—strategize your listing according to your family’s needs. Lastly, don’t leave it up to buyers to upgrade your home—make those changes yourself to make your home market-appealing so it sells for top dollar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you follow these tips instead of the myths, you’ll have a successful sale. If you’re curious about what’s happening in our market or you have any other real estate needs I can assist you with, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be glad to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 11:26:29 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://bebetterdsm.com/sellers-beware-of-these-3-myths.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://bebetterdsm.com/sellers-beware-of-these-3-myths.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Ways to Use Zillow Leads to Your Advantage</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/QhkyhaohPp4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few days ago, we had a fantastic new agent mastermind where we collaborated with agents from different companies in the Des Moines market that had been in the business for 18 months or less. We talked about which things have been successful for them, what kind of challenges they are facing, and then we had a great question and answer session about what’s brought me success in my 18 years in real estate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that really surprised me was the number of agents who said that their brokers had discouraged them from buying any sort of internet leads, particularly from Zillow. They asked me if I bought Zillow leads and, if so, how do I work with them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you’ve paid to find out that a lead is a serious buyer, don’t give up on the first try.%20http://bebetterdsm.com/3-ways-to-use-zillow-leads-to-your-advantage.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you’ve paid to find out that a lead is a serious buyer, don’t give up on the first try.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all know that agents love to hate Zillow, but the truth is that Zillow is an extremely consumer friendly tool. You need to decide if you are going to collaborate with them or work against them. I think it’s important to collaborate with a tool that consumers love. Just make sure that you know as much about it as possible so that if you do decide to play Zillow’s game, you are playing to win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are three important things that you need to know about working with Zillow leads.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The first is that the rules are always changing.&lt;/strong&gt; Constantly follow how they are selling and distributing leads, because it could change. They do give notice somehow, but it’s in a very subtle way, so it’s up to you to understand how the lead flow process works and how they are showcasing your listings so that you know what’s going on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Zillow, if you get a lead, you’re likely not the only person who got that lead. Being quick, friendly, and effective is the key to converting that lead into something. Follow up with that Zillow lead is just as important as being quick with your initial response.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many agents fall into the trap of getting a lead, calling them, and maybe not being the first one to call them. The person says, “No thanks! I’ve already been helped.” The agent then gives up, thinking the opportunity is gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth is that they are still not obligated to anyone. Where you’re going to shine as an agent is in following up, so check in with them. Say, “Hey, I saw another home in that neighborhood pop up on the market. Would you like that information?” or even a simple, “How is your home search going?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t just follow up with them once or twice; follow up with them again and again.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you know that they are a real buyer and you’ve paid to get the information that they are a buyer, don’t give up on the first try. Be consistent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third thing you need to do really well is to leverage the effectiveness of reviews. Zillow reviews are special in that they are moderated by actual people. Looking at the reviews, they check the IP address and other information submitted to determine if it really is a genuine review. Having a good number of reviews can set you apart from other agents very quickly. The number of reviews you have also affects the algorithm for who pops up in different areas and how agent searches are sorted. &lt;strong&gt;Having a large number of great reviews can really set you apart.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about Zillow leads or would like more tips about how to be effective as a real estate agent, just give me a call or send me an email. Let us know if you would like to attend our next Be Better Des Moines mastermind. We look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 13:52:51 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://bebetterdsm.com/3-ways-to-use-zillow-leads-to-your-advantage.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://bebetterdsm.com/3-ways-to-use-zillow-leads-to-your-advantage.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>January Central Iowa Market Update</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/fGmopF7J7Zk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like to take a few minutes today to look back at how the market was in December 2017, and that will help us going forward as we begin the new year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the month of December, we had 793 new homes come on the market in the Des Moines MLS. &lt;strong&gt;The amazing fact is that 33% of those 793 homes sold in the month of December&lt;/strong&gt;—that’s 262 homes that sold in December alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;average days on market for those homes that sold was five days&lt;/strong&gt; on the market before they got an offer. Homes coming on the market that are priced right are selling right away, which is great news for our sellers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Homes coming on the market that are priced right are selling right away, which is great news for our sellers.%20http://bebetterdsm.com/january-central-iowa-market-update.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Homes coming on the market that are priced right are selling right away, which is great news for our sellers.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of January 1, there are 3,201 homes for sale in the Des Moines MLS. That’s down by about 185 homes from December 1 of last year, which is normal this time of year. &lt;strong&gt;We’ll see the inventory ramp back up as we hit the springtime.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a look at the new construction home sales for 2017. Here are the top five home builders in our Des Moines MLS as of January 1:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Genesis Homes.&lt;/strong&gt; They sold 126 new homes, including pending sales, closings, and offers made in 2017.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Greenland Homes.&lt;/strong&gt; Greenland sold 182 homes, including condos, townhomes, and single-family homes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hubbell Homes.&lt;/strong&gt; They’ve been in the area for over 150 years, and last year, they sold 203 homes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jerry’s Homes.&lt;/strong&gt; They’ve been in the metro area for over 50 years and came out of 2017 with 207 closings and pending sales.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Classic Builders.&lt;/strong&gt; Located up in Ankeny, they sold 346 new homes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are big numbers for all these builders individually, but &lt;strong&gt;in terms of the entire market, we sold 2,455 new homes.&lt;/strong&gt; That’s a great number; we’re finally starting to come back from the pre-recession levels of new home sales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had 262 builders build at least one house in our metro area in the past year. This is an increase of 60 homes from four years prior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to know more about the market or any real estate topic, you can always feel free to give us a call, send an email, or message us on Facebook. We’ll be back soon with more information. Until then, have a great day!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://bebetterdsm.com/january-central-iowa-market-update.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://bebetterdsm.com/january-central-iowa-market-update.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Need to Meet Your Continuing Education Requirements? This Resource Can Help</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/YG2WnVZ4bNE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Toward the end of the year, I always notice that many agents are scrambling to get their continuing education requirements in for their license renewal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the state of Iowa, agents are required to take 36 hours of continuing education every three years,&lt;/strong&gt; with those hours due by December 31 of the year your license expires.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This education includes eight hours of law updates, four hours of ethics, and 24 hours of electives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Real estate is a complex industry, so continuing education is extremely important. Knowing industry standards, new laws, and other information helps us, as agents, be the best professionals we can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But let’s be honest: it can be difficult to find time for that education when you’re keeping such a busy schedule yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As real estate professionals, we’ve got very unpredictable schedules. Fortunately, there is an alternative in Iowa to in-classroom learning. &lt;strong&gt;In Iowa, up to 24 hours of your continuing education can be done online.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=I was able to schedule my continuing education around my life, instead of scheduling my life around my continuing education.%20http://bebetterdsm.com/need-to-meet-your-continuing-education-requirements-this-resource-can-help.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“I was able to schedule my continuing education around my life, instead of scheduling my life around my continuing education.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why I’ve found &lt;a href=&quot;https://realestatece.com/a/misty-soldwisch&quot;&gt;www.RealEstateCE.com&lt;/a&gt; to be an amazing resource. It’s very easy to sign up and is full of informational classes relevant to things I experience in my business. Also, it’s inexpensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best part of taking classes through this website, though, is that it helped me control my time. I was able to schedule my continuing education around my life, instead of scheduling my life around my continuing education.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, there is an amazing &lt;strong&gt;discount available to Iowa licensees through &lt;a href=&quot;https://realestatece.com/a/misty-soldwisch&quot;&gt;RealEstateCE.com/a/Misty-Soldwisch&lt;/a&gt; that you can find &lt;a href=&quot;https://realestatece.com/a/misty-soldwisch&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you’re busy, want to learn, and would like to save money, I definitely recommend checking it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 11:37:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://bebetterdsm.com/need-to-meet-your-continuing-education-requirements-this-resource-can-help.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://bebetterdsm.com/need-to-meet-your-continuing-education-requirements-this-resource-can-help.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
