<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Greater Spokane Real Estate Video Blog with Alejandro Ventura</title>
    <description>Our mission at Alejandro Ventura Real Estate is to be your best resource for Greater Spokane real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Alejandro Ventura Real Estate, your professional Greater Spokane Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://blog.avspokane.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.avspokane.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 16:56:23 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 16:56:23 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Staging Is So Important to Home Sellers</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/bncSvkahSvc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sylvia Dunn, the best professional stager in town, is here to explain why staging is so important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sylvia has staged all of our listings for the past two years and has helped us sell our listings above asking price in less than a week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Sylvia, &lt;strong&gt;that’s why it’s so important to stage your home: so you can sell faster and for more money.&lt;/strong&gt; This is a really good market, so you probably could sell your house for something eventually, but don’t you want to make the most money possible for your investment?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the time, a home is someone’s most valuable asset. Sylvia says that staging can help you retain as much money as possible so that you can invest it in your next home, rather than just taking whatever you can get. When you stage your home, you can make money on your home sale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, the condo unit we’re filming at was staged. Because of that, we were able to get $30,000 above asking price in less than two days. We’ve seen this happen again and again with the listings that Sylvia stages for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do plan on selling your home, what can you do to improve the condition of your property?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sylvia says that it’s mostly about decluttering.&lt;/strong&gt; Most of us have way too much stuff, and you want the buyer to see themselves living in the house. Pack things away; you’ll have to pack anyway, so why not do it earlier? You should also get a storage unit rather than storing boxes in the garage or spare room. You might spend a couple hundred dollars on the storage unit, but it’s worth it in the end to get a good price on your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You want potential buyers to be able to picture themselves living in the home.%20http://blog.avspokane.com/why-staging-is-so-important-to-home-sellers.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You want potential buyers to be able to picture themselves living in the home.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should also depersonalize your home. Everyone has pictures of their family up in their homes, which is fine when you’re living there. When you’re selling your home, though, you need to make it appeal to someone else and their family. Take personal photos down, especially in main living areas. It may be okay to leave some small photos or black and white photos to show your family happy in the home. That way, you tell potential buyers, “This is the lifestyle that you can have.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can even swap out furniture for more luxurious items, update the bedspread, or change other things to show buyers how they could live in the home, even if you’re not necessarily living that way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking big pieces of furniture out of your house can make your home feel more spacious. It’s important that the furniture in your home points toward the focal point of the room, whether that is a great fireplace or a beautiful view. Sylvia also recommends moving the TV out of the living room and downstairs into the family room; the TV is not a great focal point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, it’s important to create a flow throughout the house. Keep the colors light so the house feels airy and appeals to a broader market. Always be thinking about what most people will like, and keep up on trends that appeal to the broadest market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Identify amenities that you want to highlight and market that to buyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Staging has changed. Sylvia said that they used to put out place settings on the dining room table to make everything look perfect, but people don’t want to be tricked anymore. They want the home to feel natural. You may leave a book and some glasses on the table as if you were reading and just got up. If you have a pool table, take the cover off and rack up the balls so it looks like you are about to play a game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Natural things are important, but hide away everyday thing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;s,&lt;/strong&gt;like the soap on the sink or the shampoo bottles in your updated shower. Will your colorful shampoo bottles distract from the tile you paid all that money for? Accentuate what you want buyers to look at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, Sylvia says that organization is one of the most important things for the master bedroom and master closet. Just because the door is closed doesn’t mean you shouldn’t pay attention to it. Take some clothes out and make sure there is 20% empty space to put things in. Get hangers that are the same color to make your closet feel more upscale. Pay extra attention to that space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for Sylvia or would like a private consultation on how to stage your home, you can call Home Staging Works at 509.868.4187 or visit their website, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.homestagingworks.com/&quot;&gt;www.HomeStagingWorks.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any questions about buying or selling a home, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 14:23:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.avspokane.com/why-staging-is-so-important-to-home-sellers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.avspokane.com/why-staging-is-so-important-to-home-sellers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Steps to Take When Transitioning Between Homes</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/HqdDmFUJYBI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When transitioning between two homes, should you buy and then sell, or sell and then buy? Today, I’ve got three steps to help you decide which route is best for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Know the market.&lt;/strong&gt; Before you make your final decision, be sure that you fully understand the market in your area and in the area you’re moving to. Inventory and average prices will give you an idea of how much you can sell your home for, and also how much you should expect to pay when you buy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Know your options.&lt;/strong&gt; If you happen to receive an offer before you’ve found your next home, what do you do? There are a couple of things you can do. Your first option is to negotiate a rent-back agreement, where the buyer would allow you to stay in your home after closing for a designated period of time in exchange for giving them a reduced price or rental payments. Your second option is to ask for a longer escrow time. Instead of closing on the sale in 30 days, you can ask for a 60-day closing. This will give you more time to find your home while you complete the sale of your current property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Before you make your final decision, be sure that you fully understand the market in your area and in the area you’re moving to.%20http://blog.avspokane.com/3-steps-to-take-when-transitioning-between-homes.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Before you make your final decision, be sure that you fully understand the market in your area and in the area you’re moving to.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Don’t let fear rush you.&lt;/strong&gt; If your home has sold and you haven’t found a new place to live, don’t let anxiety push you into a bad decision. I recommend that you preemptively plan on temporarily living in a short-term rental during your transition. This way, you have adequate time to sell your home and find your next one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 09:29:01 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.avspokane.com/3-steps-to-take-when-transitioning-between-homes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.avspokane.com/3-steps-to-take-when-transitioning-between-homes.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Whats the Cost of Selling Your Home?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/lzr1QTeoCT0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buyers aren’t the only ones who have to pay closing costs. Sellers can expect to pay 9% of their sale price on closing costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
**Want to sell your home?** &lt;a href=&quot;http://alejandrov.kwrealty.com/sell/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a FREE home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
**Want to buy a home?** &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all homes for sale&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all know there are costs associated with buying a home, but were you aware that there are also several costs of selling a home to consider before going through with listing it for sale?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Typically, a seller has to deal with eight different selling costs here in Spokane.&lt;/strong&gt; They include:
- Title insurance
- Escrow fees
- Excise tax
- Commissions
The more expensive your home is, the higher these costs will be. When you add them all up, they typically equate to about 9% of the sale price. So, when calculating your bottom line, you will be safe by assigning 9% of your asking price to closing costs and then subtracting any loans you have pending on your home. &lt;strong&gt;Doing this will give you a pretty solid idea of how much money you can expect to walk away with when the sale is finalized.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=SELLING A HOME ISN’T CHEAP.%20http://blog.avspokane.com/whats-cost-of-selling-your-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“SELLING A HOME ISN’T CHEAP.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if you’re selling a home at $250,000, you can expect your closing costs to be anywhere from $20,000 to $25,000. Subtract that from your mortgage balance and you will get your bottom line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you found this helpful. If you have any questions in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 15:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.avspokane.com/whats-cost-of-selling-your-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.avspokane.com/whats-cost-of-selling-your-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Selling Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>6 Secrets to Selling for Top Dollar in Our Spring Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/y_zeqTEmDMw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have six secrets to share with you that can help your home sale generate maximum price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
**Want to sell your home?** &lt;a href=&quot;http://alejandrov.kwrealty.com/sell/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a FREE home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
**Want to buy a home?** &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all homes for sale&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking to sell your home in our spring market and are wondering how you can maximize your sale price, here are my six selling secrets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Don’t overprice the home.&lt;/strong&gt; Overpricing it is a poor strategy for making more money when you sell it. For example, last year in Spokane, 20% of the homes that entered the market failed to sell. That’s 1,800 homes in total. We know that the No. 1 reason a home doesn’t sell is pricing. Don’t be a part of that 20% and position your home to sell from the get-go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=THE NO. 1 REASON A HOME DOESN’T SELL IS PRICING.%20http://blog.avspokane.com/6-secrets-to-selling-for-top-dollar-in.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“THE NO. 1 REASON A HOME DOESN’T SELL IS PRICING.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Clear your closet.&lt;/strong&gt; Storage is something every buyer is looking for in this market. Clear your closet as much as you can and then neatly organize whatever is left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Light it up.&lt;/strong&gt; New lighting in a new home ranks fairly high on most buyers’ priority lists. When showing your home, open the drapes, clean the windows, and replace any light bulbs where needed. Essentially, do all you can to ensure that your home shows brightly and cheerfully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Hire the right agent.&lt;/strong&gt; Working with a good agent will make you money. Hiring the wrong agent will cost you money. Hire someone who has marketing expertise and has systems and processes in place to ensure you have a successful transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. The kitchen comes first.&lt;/strong&gt; In many cases, you’re not selling your home—you’re selling your kitchen. That’s how important your kitchen is. If you’re planning on spending money preparing your home for sale, start there. That will give you the biggest bang for your buck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. First impressions are the only impression.&lt;/strong&gt; Buyers will make a value judgment about your house the moment they pull in front of it. Based on the curb appeal, they’ll decide to either go inside or drive away. Spend some time improving the curb appeal of your home. Take a minute and stand in front of your house and look at it from the eye of a buyer. Address any issues you need to fix to convey a great first impression. This could be the difference between selling and not selling your home for the price you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this topic or you’re looking to sell your home, feel free to give me a call. In the meantime, make it a great day!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 13:31:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.avspokane.com/6-secrets-to-selling-for-top-dollar-in.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.avspokane.com/6-secrets-to-selling-for-top-dollar-in.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Selling Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
