<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Real Estate Pros Video Blog</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Real Estate Pros - your professional Pendleton Area Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://therealestateprosvideoblog.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://therealestateprosvideoblog.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2016 15:51:56 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2016 15:51:56 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>What’s Happening in the  Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/cKEQq0pefNs&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s going on in the real estate market right now?
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;First, &lt;strong&gt;we are currently in a seller’s market.&lt;/strong&gt;This means that there are fewer houses listed on the market than there are buyers to purchase those homes.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Due to the low number of homes on the market for sale, the prices for the properties available have increased. Home sellers can sell their house right now for top dollar and get full asking price for their home. In some cases, they’ll even get above asking price.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;What should you do if you’re a home buyer in a hot seller’s market like this one? &lt;strong&gt;First of all, you’ll need to act fast.&lt;/strong&gt; If or when you see a property on the market that you’re interested in, make sure you’re ready to make a decision.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Due to the limited inventory, &lt;strong&gt;you’ll also probably have less negotiating power than you would in a balanced market.&lt;/strong&gt; This means that you’ll probably have to pay full price for the home you want. If you’re in a multiple offer situation, you may even need to pay above asking price.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Interest rates are still very low, however, which has a positive effect on your buying power. Even if you end up paying full asking price or above for a home, it’s still likely that your monthly mortgage payment for the home will be affordable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Low interest rates mean that homes are still very affordable.%20http://therealestateprosvideoblog.com/whats-happening-in-the-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Low interest rates mean that homes are still very affordable.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you’re thinking about buying or selling a home in the our market or you have any questions about buying or selling real estate in the area, give me a call or send me an email. I’d be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://therealestateprosvideoblog.com/whats-happening-in-the-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://therealestateprosvideoblog.com/whats-happening-in-the-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
