<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>Our mission at Damon Gettier &amp; Associates is to be your best resource for Roanoke real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Damon Gettier &amp; Associates, your professional Roanoke Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://damongettierblog.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://damongettierblog.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 14:47:37 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 14:47:37 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>When Is the Best Time to Prepare Your Listing?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wuK3thsl-Ow?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, we’ll be continuing our series on things to do when preparing to sell your home. The tip I’d like to share this time is: Just do it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are so many things in life that we tend to put off for another day instead of taking care of them as soon as possible. I’m not going to lie to you. &lt;strong&gt;Putting your home on the market certainly isn’t the most fun experience. However, it is rewarding.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Even small changes can really add up and pay off.%20http://damongettierblog.com/when-is-the-best-time-to-prepare-your-listing.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Even small changes can really add up and pay off.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s take the example of selling a car for $10,000. Most people in this situation will spend $200 on getting the car detailed, having its tires filled or replaced, or getting it waxed. But when these same people sell a $200,000, they hesitate to spend even $500 on these kinds of upgrades and finishing touches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, little changes can really add up and pay off. &lt;strong&gt;Before you bring in a Realtor, start clearing out the clutter and doing everything else you can to prepare your home for the market.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right before you’re ready to list, hire professional cleaners to make your home really shine. The time to start preparing your home for the market is today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2018 11:51:22 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://damongettierblog.com/when-is-the-best-time-to-prepare-your-listing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://damongettierblog.com/when-is-the-best-time-to-prepare-your-listing.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Unexpected Costs of Buying a Home, Part 5: Homeowners Insurance</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/6A9mswjwUyQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is homeowners insurance? Why should you consider obtaining it when purchasing a home?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Homeowners insurance is something that’s required by the lender. &lt;/strong&gt;If you get a loan to purchase a house, the lender will require that you insure their asset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you obtain homeowners insurance, you want to make sure of a couple of things. First, you want to make sure it covers the structure of the house—not just what you pay for it, but what it would cost for you to rebuild it. You also need to make sure it covers the contents of the house. Just because the TV you bought four years ago is now worth $100 doesn’t mean you can replace it for $100, so make sure you get replacements costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=There’s nothing that will fix a flooded house if you don’t have flood insurance.%20http://damongettierblog.com/the-unexpected-costs-of-buying-a-home-part-5-homeowners-insurance.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“There’s nothing that will fix a flooded house if you don’t have flood insurance.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Another thing to consider is if you’re buying in an area that requires flood insurance.&lt;/strong&gt; Flood insurance is required in flood zone AE areas, but it’s not required in zone X areas. If you look at what happened in Houston last year and West Virginia the year before, those areas didn’t require flood insurance—they were flood zone X areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Living in flood zone X areas doesn’t cost nearly as much as living in flood zone AE areas, but I still recommend getting flood insurance. Remember—insurance is not for the expected. If we woke up one day and knew our car was going to crash, we wouldn’t drive it that day. We have insurance to be insured against the unexpected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s nothing that will fix a flooded house if you don’t have flood insurance. Those funds will have to come out of your back pocket, and most people don’t have an extra $100,000 or $200,000 lying around to repair a house that’s been destroyed by a flood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about homeowners insurance or any other unexpected costs when buying a home, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 09:01:51 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://damongettierblog.com/the-unexpected-costs-of-buying-a-home-part-5-homeowners-insurance.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://damongettierblog.com/the-unexpected-costs-of-buying-a-home-part-5-homeowners-insurance.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What to Do With Excess Paper in Your Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/QTHA5UgET-k?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I’d like to return to our series on things to do when selling your home. This time, let’s talk about paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some reason, many people feel the need to save away every little piece of paper they come across. Really, there’s only a couple of things you need to keep. &lt;strong&gt;Tax returns, bank statements, and some bills are essentially all you need to hold onto.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless it’s something like a birth certificate, wedding certificate, or another important document, you only need to keep most old mail and records for about three years. After that time, it’s usually okay to throw some things away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Unnecessary paper can really be the Achilles’ heel of a home you’re preparing to sell.%20http://damongettierblog.com/what-to-do-with-excess-paper-in-your-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Unnecessary paper can really be the Achilles’ heel of a home you’re preparing to sell.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you do get rid of important papers, though, don’t just toss them. &lt;strong&gt;Make sure you shred anything that could have your personal information on it.&lt;/strong&gt; If you don’t own a shredder, there are many places you can have this done. You can even come down to my office if you need something shredded badly and don’t know where else to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The bottom line is this: get rid of unnecessary paper when you clean your home. &lt;/strong&gt;Most of it isn’t important to keep, is a fire hazard, and is just taking up space. Paper causes a lot of clutter. It can really be the Achilles’ heel of a home you’re preparing to sell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 05:59:13 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://damongettierblog.com/what-to-do-with-excess-paper-in-your-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://damongettierblog.com/what-to-do-with-excess-paper-in-your-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Unexpected Buying Costs: Utilities</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/rOzpTrUUb44?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I’ve mentioned in the past, unexpected costs can arise during any home purchase. Today, I’d like to go over one type of cost in particular: utilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you were renting a property before you made your home purchase, things like your water or heat may have been included. However, as a homeowner, these costs must be accounted for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=When submitting an offer on a home, I highly encourage buyers to ask the property’s current owners about average monthly utility costs.%20http://damongettierblog.com/unexpected-buying-costs-utilities.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“When submitting an offer on a home, I highly encourage buyers to ask the property’s current owners about average monthly utility costs.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I highly encourage is for buyers to ask the home’s current owners about average monthly utility costs. &lt;strong&gt;These numbers won’t be ironclad, but they will help you understand what you should expect.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 08:48:15 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://damongettierblog.com/unexpected-buying-costs-utilities.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://damongettierblog.com/unexpected-buying-costs-utilities.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Smarter Way to Pack Up Your Belongings</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/lJoB9TH-hjs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m back with part three of our series on selling your home. Today I’d like to discuss the benefits of using clear plastic bins to store your belongings as opposed to cardboard boxes.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Not only are cardboard boxes fire hazards, insect attractors, and susceptible to mice and other rodents, but you can’t see anything either. You have to unpack the whole box just to find one thing. &lt;strong&gt;Oftentimes, those boxes don’t get repacked and just end up making a mess.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=It will help make the selling process easier.%20http://damongettierblog.com/a-smarter-way-to-pack-up-your-belongings.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“It will help make the selling process easier.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The use of clear plastic bins allows you to see if something is in there right away. Then you can reach in and grab it because you know exactly where it is.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Even if you only do it for a few weeks or while you’re selling your home, when you have a highly organized basement or garage with labeled bins like this, it will appear to potential buyers like you’ve been living like that the entire time. It will help make the selling process much easier and enjoyable. &lt;strong&gt;It will likely get you a higher price for your home, too.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you have any questions for me at all about selling your home, including where you can find these plastic bins, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 07:19:14 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://damongettierblog.com/a-smarter-way-to-pack-up-your-belongings.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://damongettierblog.com/a-smarter-way-to-pack-up-your-belongings.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Unexpected Home Purchasing Costs, Part III: Taxes</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/MLv9ign6Z2Y?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’re continuing our series about the unexpected costs of homeownership with a discussion of taxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When you buy a house, you are responsible for the property taxes.&lt;/strong&gt; Most of the time, that’s included in your payment unless you have an arrangement otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you’re not extremely responsible with money, it’s very important that you let the bank escrow your taxes so that you don’t have a huge bill come up that you won’t be able to pay.%20http://damongettierblog.com/unexpected-home-purchasing-costs-part-iii-taxes.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you’re not extremely responsible with money, it’s very important that you let the bank escrow your taxes so that you don’t have a huge bill come up that you won’t be able to pay.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, usually when you purchase your house, &lt;strong&gt;the bank takes money out at closing to establish an escrow account to pay your taxes.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As your taxes increase every year, &lt;strong&gt;the money that is required by the mortgage company will increase as well &lt;/strong&gt;so that they can pay your taxes for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re not extremely responsible with money, it’s very important that you let the bank escrow your taxes so that you don’t have a huge bill come up that you won’t be able to pay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any questions, please feel free to contact me. I’d be glad to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 09:28:33 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://damongettierblog.com/unexpected-home-purchasing-costs-part-iii-taxes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://damongettierblog.com/unexpected-home-purchasing-costs-part-iii-taxes.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Don’t Rush When It Comes to Selling Your Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2bF54v-aTQI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’re going to talk about giving yourself time as a seller to get everything prepared to move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So many people call us wanting to list their house, but they want the sign in their yard the next day. Their house at the time is usually in no way, shape, or form ready to sell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re going to sell your house and it’s not an emergency—such as a death in the family, or a job change in a different city—&lt;strong&gt;I highly encourage you to come meet with us.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you’re going to sell your house and it’s not an emergency—such as a death in the family, or a job change in a different city—I highly encourage you to come meet with us.%20http://damongettierblog.com/dont-rush-when-it-comes-to-selling-your-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you’re going to sell your house and it’s not an emergency—such as a death in the family, or a job change in a different city—I highly encourage you to come meet with us.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do something called a coming-soon period for two to six weeks. This gives you time to get your house ready for listing. &lt;strong&gt;The goal is to present your house in the best possible way that we can.&lt;/strong&gt; We can’t do that if you need to move in, say, 30 days, when you called us yesterday and expect it to be listed by tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your photos won’t look as good, your house won’t be staged properly, you’ll have items that need to be put into storage, your lawn/landscaping will need to be cleaned up, and so much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All those things and more besides will have to be done in order to present your house in its best light, which will get you the most return on the dollar. Few people want a fixer-upper; they want a house that’s move-in ready so they won’t have to do much with it. &lt;strong&gt;You’ll get more money for a home that is shown in optimal condition, and it will sell faster as well.&lt;/strong&gt; Overall, it will be a much more pleasurable selling experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If have any questions about coming-soon periods, selling your house, or getting on the market, please feel free to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 05:41:31 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://damongettierblog.com/dont-rush-when-it-comes-to-selling-your-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://damongettierblog.com/dont-rush-when-it-comes-to-selling-your-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Unexpected Home Purchasing Costs, Part II: Maintenance Costs</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-TkHvX6p8As?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the costs I mentioned last time, another unexpected cost you need to watch out for is the maintenance for your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you rent a house, you don’t have the same external and internal maintenance duties you have when you buy a house. Of course, you don’t have the tax advantages either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=When buying a home, budget accordingly.%20http://damongettierblog.com/unexpected-home-purchasing-costs-part-ii-maintenance-costs.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“When buying a home, budget accordingly.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When buying a home, you really need to budget accordingly, because nothing in a home lasts forever. One reason we always encourage home warranties among our buyers is that it acts as a maintenance plan for the house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When buying a house, look at items like the roof, the HVAC unit, and the water heater, because all of these things have expected lifespans.&lt;/strong&gt; Make sure you plan for the replacement, upkeep, and repair for these items.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about the maintenance costs of purchasing a home, don’t hesitate to give me a call or shoot me an email. I’d be glad to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 06:16:50 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://damongettierblog.com/unexpected-home-purchasing-costs-part-ii-maintenance-costs.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://damongettierblog.com/unexpected-home-purchasing-costs-part-ii-maintenance-costs.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What’s the First Step to Take When Selling Your Home?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wLldngkmq9E?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first task I want to talk about when it comes to things you must do when selling your home is sorting, or how to simplify your moving experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a couple ways you can do this. One way is to sort stuff into piles. This includes stuff you want to donate, stuff you want to trash, and stuff you want to keep. I generally suggest another way, though, and that way is something I call the “one-year rule.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one-year rule goes as follows: &lt;strong&gt;If you haven’t used it in the last year and you’re not going to use it in the next year, sell it or get rid of it because it’s cluttering your life.&lt;/strong&gt; From there, get rid of anything you consider trash. Take it to the dumpster or the landfill. Don’t let your kids or your spouse look at what it is—just get rid of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people who move are moving up, so if that’s the case for you, then your current house is too small. If your house is too small for you and appears to be too small for you, then it will appear to be too small for the next person, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Renting a storage unit will go a long way in getting your home sold.%20http://damongettierblog.com/whats-the-first-step-to-take-when-selling-your-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Renting a storage unit will go a long way in getting your home sold.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why my second tip is to &lt;strong&gt;rent a storage unit and store everything that’s not essential to your day-to-day life inside it.&lt;/strong&gt; This means removing all your extra clothes from your closets so they look big and roomy, all the storage boxes lying around in the basement or attic, and other stuff like that so there’s plenty of room in the house. Storage units aren’t cheap, but what they can do in terms of getting your home sold is incredible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t advise getting a pod instead of a storage unit. A pod just tells everyone you ran out of room in the house and what’s leftover is sitting in your driveway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about getting your house ready to sell, whether that involves staging, sorting, or throwing things away, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 10:17:35 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://damongettierblog.com/whats-the-first-step-to-take-when-selling-your-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://damongettierblog.com/whats-the-first-step-to-take-when-selling-your-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Unexpected Costs Could Leave You Reeling</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/pdqR-PcFhEk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t go into a transaction unprepared. There is a difference between closing costs and the total cost to close, and it could be thousands of dollars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to Sell Your Home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.damongettier.com/list/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get the Value of Your Central or Southwest Virginia Home&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Looking to Buy a Home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.damongettier.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search All Homes on the MLS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’re going to discuss some of the unexpected costs you may run into when purchasing a home, specifically regarding closing costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Closing costs are different from the cost to close.&lt;/strong&gt; A lot of people think closing costs are everything they’ll need to close on a home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=THE DIFFERENCE BETWEEN SPECIFIC CLOSING COSTS AND THE TOTAL COST TO CLOSE COULD BE THOUSANDS OF DOLLARS.%20http://damongettierblog.com/unexpected-costs-could-leave-you-reeling.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“THE DIFFERENCE BETWEEN SPECIFIC CLOSING COSTS AND THE TOTAL COST TO CLOSE COULD BE THOUSANDS OF DOLLARS.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our area, however, closing costs are strictly defined in the contract, so the difference between specific closing costs and the total cost to close could be thousands of dollars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your annual homeowners insurance is not a closing cost—it is a cost to close, as are property taxes. Things like that can run up your cost to close very quickly, so &lt;strong&gt;when you’re getting a quote for closing costs, make sure it’s not just for closing costs, but how much money you will actually need in total to be able to close on the home.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need any information about this or other topics, please feel free to contact us.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 15:54:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://damongettierblog.com/unexpected-costs-could-leave-you-reeling.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://damongettierblog.com/unexpected-costs-could-leave-you-reeling.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
