<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chicago Real Estate Video Blog with Ashley Carter</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Carter Property Group - your professional Chicago Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://chicagorealestatevideoblog.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://chicagorealestatevideoblog.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 16:35:42 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 16:35:42 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>What's Going On In Our Real Estate Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/5B2r96avwTg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I wanted to take a moment to compare the 2016 Chicago real estate market to that of 2015. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we left 2016, we found that we’re in a slight seller’s market here in Chicago; homes sold at a faster pace and for more money than in 2015. &lt;strong&gt;That’s all good news for sellers.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the buyer side, you’ll find that you have to be ready to make a decision once you find a property that’s the right fit. That’s because properties are selling faster than they typically would. However, there is good news for buyers. &lt;strong&gt;Interest rates are still incredible.&lt;/strong&gt; Due to low rates, buyers have a lot of buying power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Due to low rates, buyers have a lot of buying power.%20http://chicagorealestatevideoblog.com/whats-going-on-in-our-real-estate-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Due to low rates, buyers have a lot of buying power.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you been considering getting into the real estate investment market here in Chicago? Are you already the owner of an investment property? It continues to be a really strong market for us here in Chicago. Demand for rentals keeps going up as well. In fact, we’ve seen increases for the last four years in a row. The speed at which units re-rent is very fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you have any questions about the Chicago market or you’re thinking about selling your house or buying an investment property, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email with any questions at all. I’d be happy to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://chicagorealestatevideoblog.com/whats-going-on-in-our-real-estate-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://chicagorealestatevideoblog.com/whats-going-on-in-our-real-estate-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
