<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- MARKET -- Real Estate Video Blog with -- CLIENT NAME --</title>
    <description>Our mission at The Wolek Group is to be your best resource for  real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The The Wolek Group, your professional  Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 15:44:50 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 15:44:50 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Teaching Kids About Science and Teamwork Through Global Gardens </title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/zKhzubP828Q?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maryann Donahue from Global Gardens is here today to share how this wonderful organization helps empower children in high-poverty areas of Tulsa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Looking to sell your Tulsa area home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tulsahomevalue.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Looking to buy a Tulsa area home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thewolekgroup.com/search-for-homes/#/-1451235678&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to browse Tulsa homes for sale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something that’s really important to us as a real estate team is giving back to our community, which is why we like to spotlight our local nonprofits that are doing great things in the Tulsa area. Today, I’m talking to Maryann Donahue from Global Gardens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Global Gardens was created by a teacher from Tulsa named Heather Oakley [spelling?] in 2007. Heather had a background in urban science education and peace education. She also had a bachelors degree in botany. She combined all of those things to create Global Gardens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The purpose of Global Gardens is to help fight the cycle of poverty and empower kids&lt;/strong&gt; from high-poverty communities to be agents of change in their own lives and in their communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Heather came back to Tulsa in 2007, she started the first program at Eugene Field. She offered during and after-school programs. At that time, there was an empty lot next to Eugene Field that was bare, empty, and forgotten. She and that first group of students turned it into a beautiful, bountiful garden, and that’s what Global Gardens has done ever since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Since then, Global Gardens has added three more sites in addition to Eugene Field, including the one Maryann and I are filming from today.&lt;/strong&gt; This field services Union Middle School and Union High School. There are two other elementary schools in the program as well: Rosa Parks Elementary and McAuliffe Elementary in East Tulsa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=THE PURPOSE OF GLOBAL GARDENS IS TO HELP FIGHT THE CYCLE OF POVERTY AND EMPOWER KIDS.%20localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-community-spotlight-global-gardens.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“THE PURPOSE OF GLOBAL GARDENS IS TO HELP FIGHT THE CYCLE OF POVERTY AND EMPOWER KIDS.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We serve over 1,800 kids every week in this program,” says Maryann. “We’re helping about 2,500 people a year.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Global Gardens uses gardening as a vehicle for empowerment. They also use gardening to teach science and how to be peaceful. “In the during-school program, they have a class garden. They get to decide what to plant, and they have a harvest party at the end of the year,” says Maryann. “They do all of that together. It’s very intentional.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These programs teach science that addresses state science standards while also teaching teamwork. The students don’t have many opportunities outside of Global Gardens to do hands-on, real-world things and have to do them as a team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We really believe that Global Gardens is doing a great thing.&lt;/strong&gt; How can you help? Go to Global-Gardens.org to make an online donation. All of their funding is raised from community donations; they don’t have state contracts or charge fees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maryann says that Global Gardens hopes to add a fifth site at Jackson Elementary School in North Tulsa by 2019. This has been in the works for a while, so please consider helping them reach their goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would like to thank Maryann for taking the time to talk to me today. You can learn more details about Global Gardens at Global-Gardens.org.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any real estate questions or know another local nonprofit you think we should spotlight, give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 11:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-community-spotlight-global-gardens.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-community-spotlight-global-gardens.html</guid>
        
        <category>The Wolek Group</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Can Cleansing Rain Help You Clean and Organize Your Home?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/lDahCYGy7HE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I want to talk about Cleansing Rain, which is an incredible home cleaning business here in our town.To learn more about the business and how it began, I spoke with the owner, Lacie Partney.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Looking to sell your Tulsa area home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tulsahomevalue.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Looking to buy a Tulsa area home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thewolekgroup.com/search-for-homes/#/-1451235678&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to browse Tulsa homes for sale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I want to talk about an incredible home cleaning business here in our town: Cleansing Rain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I asked how she got the idea to begin her business, owner Lacie Partney told me she wasn’t always such a neat and organized person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Lacie, it all began when she returned to Tulsa after two years on the mission field. At that point in time, she was searching for something to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then, she’s found cleaning homes to be very fulfilling. She says it really helps her build relationships. On top of that, &lt;strong&gt;Lacie herself makes all of the natural cleaning products she uses.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=FROM YOUR ATTIC TO YOUR JUNK DRAWER, LACIE IS HAPPY TO HELP ANYONE DECLUTTER.%20localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-clean-your-home-with-cleansing-rain.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“FROM YOUR ATTIC TO YOUR JUNK DRAWER, LACIE IS HAPPY TO HELP ANYONE DECLUTTER.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just one of the things that help her stand out from other cleaning companies in town. She also loves to help people get more organized. From your attic to your junk drawer, Lacie is happy to help anyone declutter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, it doesn’t stop there. Once she helps her clients declutter their spaces, &lt;strong&gt;Lacie also helps them develop an organizational system that can be implemented into their specific lifestyle.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing Lacie highly recommends is to make use of vertical space. Instead of buying new furniture that takes up floor space, she suggests that people try to utilize their walls for storage, instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To learn more about Lacie and her business, you can visit her website at www.CleansingRain918.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 13:19:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-clean-your-home-with-cleansing-rain.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-clean-your-home-with-cleansing-rain.html</guid>
        
        <category>Jennie Wolek</category>
        
        <category>Tulsa Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How John Carter Bathrooms Can Help You </title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/LodG7j_AEbg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John Carter from John Carter Bathrooms is here today to answer a few questions about his business and some of the latest trends in bathroom remodels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Looking to sell your Tulsa area home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tulsahomevalue.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Looking to buy a Tulsa area home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thewolekgroup.com/search-for-homes/#/-1451235678&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to browse Tulsa homes for sale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I’m here with John Carter from John Carter Bathrooms. John has graciously agreed to answer some questions about his business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did you get into this business?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It started way back. I’m from Namibia and my father did remodeling. He taught me everything I know. I learned everything from scratch and got to love remodeling, which made me decide to make it a business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I moved to the United States a couple of years ago and got a job like everybody else. Then I realized that I wouldn’t be able to work on my dreams, so I decided to start a remodeling business. I can do kitchens, bathrooms, and even build homes, but I wanted to focus on something special, so I learned how to specialize in bathrooms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I love your story and that you are doing something you are passionate about, which is important to me as well. What makes you stand out from the competition?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a couple of things that make us different. First, we complete all projects on time and on budget. It is a top priority for us to work around your schedule and your finances. Second, all of our projects are designed to fit your size and your style. We don’t ask you to cut corners on the perfect remodel. Finally, we are the most available and we provide daily progress reports on what’s done, so you’re never left wondering what we did all day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=YOU WILL GET DAILY PROGRESS REPORTS SO YOU KNOW EXACTLY HOW MUCH WORK HAS BEEN DONE.%20localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-our-favorite-bathroom-remodel-specialist.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“YOU WILL GET DAILY PROGRESS REPORTS SO YOU KNOW EXACTLY HOW MUCH WORK HAS BEEN DONE.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s a new style or trend that you have noticed lately?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In kitchens, soapstone has been popular lately. We’ve been using it in bathrooms for a little bit. People do want to use quartz for their surfaces these days. There are a lot of new materials out there. People like wooden countertops as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For bathrooms, people stick to light, neutral colors. Those will last a long time. Back in the 80s, people made pink, green, and purple bathrooms. That doesn’t work. My job is to come into somebody’s home and put something in there with tile that will last. Technology has improved with tile and cement, so we can build up bathrooms that are mold-free and 100% waterproof, which is great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How can someone get in touch with you about a remodel or to ask any questions?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My phone number is 918-574-4610 or look at my website, JohnCarterBathrooms.com. You can enter your information and get a free 3-D model of what your bathroom could look like at no cost to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you to John for answering my questions. As always, if you have any real estate questions, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 13:03:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-our-favorite-bathroom-remodel-specialist.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-our-favorite-bathroom-remodel-specialist.html</guid>
        
        <category>tulsa ok real estate</category>
        
        <category>Tulsa Real Estate Other</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Does Luxe Furniture and Design Have to Offer?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/pLgQqROEbLI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m here with Tamara Noel, owner of Luxe Furniture and Design, to discuss the products and services her company provides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Looking to sell your Tulsa area home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tulsahomevalue.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Looking to buy a Tulsa area home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thewolekgroup.com/search-for-homes/#/-1451235678&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to browse Tulsa homes for sale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m here with Tamara Noel, owner of Luxe Furniture and Design, and I’m so excited for her to share with you all the great things they have here at Luxe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with beautiful furniture and decor, &lt;strong&gt;Luxe also offers a great design service&lt;/strong&gt; that’s complimentary with purchase. When you shop there, you get to work with a qualified, educated, and talented interior designer to help you every step of the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They’re not just salespeople who are knowledgeable about all the products Luxe offers; they are honestly legitimate design experts. The designers went to school to learn the skill and have spent their entire career honing the craft. They love what they do, and they’re very good at it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When somebody walks through the door with a need, what does the process of helping them look like?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It could be anything from one of the designers helping the client navigate the store to identify their wants and needs to schedule a house call where someone isn’t quite sure what they’re looking for or they have a larger project they don’t know how to start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=THE HELP OF A DESIGNER CAN MAKE ALL THE DIFFERENCE.%20localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-luxe-is-great-for-products-and-design.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“THE HELP OF A DESIGNER CAN MAKE ALL THE DIFFERENCE.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our designers make &lt;strong&gt;complimentary house calls&lt;/strong&gt; out to your home. They’ll do all the measuring, look at your paint colors, work with what pieces you already have, give guidance on space planning, give direction for new pieces, and more. It could be something as simple as window treatments, but whatever it is, the help of &lt;strong&gt;a designer can make all the difference.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do a lot in stages. It may just be planning for the big picture—doing a few changes now and a little bit more down the road to ultimately get the look that you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are you seeing in terms of design trends?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clean lines are still key here in Tulsa. It’s becoming a transitional market, but neutrals are still very popular, and a lot of the taupes of years past are coming back. Adding in a little bit of fun with texture or a pop of color is a good way to brighten up your space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How can people get in touch with you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find us in our showroom at 9922 Riverside Parkway in Tulsa, Oklahoma, in the King’s Landing Shopping Center. You can also visit our website www.luxetulsa.com, give us a call at (918) 459-8950, or like us on Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you need anything in terms of real estate from the Wolek Group, please feel free to reach out to us. Have a great day!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 11:36:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-luxe-is-great-for-products-and-design.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-luxe-is-great-for-products-and-design.html</guid>
        
        <category>tulsa ok real estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Will I See You at the Toyland Ball in January?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/DoB7fHiNPEA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mission of The Parent Child Center of Tulsa is to prevent child abuse and neglect through education, treatment, and advocacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Looking to sell your Tulsa area home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tulsahomevalue.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Looking to buy a Tulsa area home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thewolekgroup.com/search-for-homes/#/-1451235678&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to browse Tulsa homes for sale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m excited to be joined by special guest Carey Baker. I had the opportunity to ask Carey some questions about her involvement with The Parent Child Center of Tulsa. Her and her husband, Brett Baker, are Co-chairs for Toyland Ball 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Toyland Ball, held every January, is The Parent Child Center of Tulsa’s annual signature fundraising event.&lt;/strong&gt; This black tie gala featuring a whimsical theme offers an elegant evening of dinner and dancing, with a live auction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I caught up with Carey at the Toyland Ball Stock the Bar Party where attendees bring a bottle of wine valued at $50 or more to be auctioned off at the Toyland Ball 2018 in January. In past years, the wine auctioned off at the event in January has raised between $8,000 and $10,000 for The Parent Child Center of Tulsa. That is just the money raised from auctioning the wine. There are other items that are auctioned off that raise even more money for the cause.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those of you who may not know, the mission of The Parent Child Center of Tulsa is to prevent child abuse and neglect through education, treatment, and advocacy. People who have been &lt;strong&gt;victims of abuse or neglect are given education and counseling so that they are able to end the cycle.&lt;/strong&gt; Many people only know what they’ve been taught, so The Parent Child Center of Tulsa aims to reverse this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in attending, &lt;strong&gt;the Toyland Ball auction will take place on January 20th, 2018 at the Cox Business Center. For tickets, visit www.ParentChildCenter.org.&lt;/strong&gt; You can also become a patron sponsor by donating $1,000 for two people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the event, there will be raffles, an auction, and a live band. Also, all of the proceeds go directly to the counseling funds for The Parent Child Center of Tulsa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We hope you have a very Merry Christmas and a Happy New Year!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 12:10:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/will-i-see-you-at-toyland-ball-in.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/will-i-see-you-at-toyland-ball-in.html</guid>
        
        <category>tulsa ok real estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>This Time, Im the One Whos Buying</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Wdnm-6NqnLA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m on the hunt for an investment property in the TU/Midtown area. These kinds of properties are hard to find, so I’d love your help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Looking to sell your Tulsa area home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tulsahomevalue.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Looking to buy a Tulsa area home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thewolekgroup.com/search-for-homes/#/-1451235678&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to browse Tulsa homes for sale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually, I’m the one helping buyers. Today though, I’m the one who’s buying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I’m looking to buy an investment property around the TU/Midtown area for anywhere up to $125,000.&lt;/strong&gt; I would love one that has three bedrooms, but I’d be fine with two bedrooms as well. One or 1.5 bathrooms would be ideal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Midtown is a great place to live, so these kinds of properties are hard to find. If you’re thinking about selling your home and don’t have it on the market yet, I would love to talk to you and see if I could be your buyer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=I WOULD LOVE TO TALK TO YOU AND SEE IF I COULD BE YOUR BUYER.%20localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-im-looking-for-an-investment-property.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“I WOULD LOVE TO TALK TO YOU AND SEE IF I COULD BE YOUR BUYER.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you know of anyone else making a move from or selling an investment property that’s already being leased in that area, don’t hesitate to send them my way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, just give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call at (918) 712-2252 or send me an email at info@TheWolekGroup.com. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 09:51:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-im-looking-for-an-investment-property.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-im-looking-for-an-investment-property.html</guid>
        
        <category>real estate tulsa</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Holiday Gift Ideas and More with Candra at Saks</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZN98Wr_6gDM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking for some great holiday gift ideas? Look no further than Saks Fifth Avenue Tulsa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Looking to sell your Tulsa area home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tulsahomevalue.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Looking to buy a Tulsa area home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thewolekgroup.com/search-for-homes/#/-1451235678&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to browse Tulsa homes for sale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m back again to highlight another great business here in town. We’re getting into the holiday spirit today at Saks Fifth Avenue. Candra Monck joined me to discuss holiday gift ideas, style advisors, and some fun events they have coming up at the store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First, let’s take a look at some great holiday gift ideas, all of which are available in the store:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Artis makeup brushes. Not only is this set of brushes gorgeous, they are light and easy to use as well.
• Dyson hairdryer. This is a brand new product from Dyson. They have taken their air circulation and noise-canceling technology to the hairdryer market.
• Chanel skin regeneration set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have somebody on your list that’s a little bit harder to buy for, &lt;strong&gt;Candra recommends giving one of their style advisors a call.&lt;/strong&gt; They know the ins and outs of everything that the store carries. Candra even uses these advisors herself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=KEEP AN EYE OUT FOR ALL OF THEIR UPCOMING EVENTS ON THEIR FACEBOOK PAGE.%20localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-a-few-more-holiday-gift-ideas.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“KEEP AN EYE OUT FOR ALL OF THEIR UPCOMING EVENTS ON THEIR FACEBOOK PAGE.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a ton of great events coming up at Saks Fifth Avenue Tulsa. They include visits from national makeup artists, spa days, complimentary makeovers, makeup lessons, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best way to contact them is through their Facebook page, which they are constantly updating with events, deals, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call at (918) 706-9845 or send me an email at Info@TheWolekGroup.com. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 09:26:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-a-few-more-holiday-gift-ideas.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-a-few-more-holiday-gift-ideas.html</guid>
        
        <category>Tulsa Real Estate Agent Other</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Let Us Help You Find Your Dream Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/rv06WzAIIcc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve struggled to find your dream home by searching on your own, we have a proactive solution that may be the answer you need: buyer listings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Looking to sell your Tulsa area home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tulsahomevalue.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Looking to buy a Tulsa area home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thewolekgroup.com/search-for-homes/#/-1451235678&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to browse Tulsa homes for sale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I wanted to tell you about our buyer listings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve had many buying clients who have either exhausted the market because they just can’t find what they’re looking for, or they aren’t ready to move right this minute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We have come up with a plan to proactively search for listings for our buying clients.&lt;/strong&gt; We call this our buyer listings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just like we do for sellers, when we gather all the information on the property and market it on the MLS, our websites, and social media, &lt;strong&gt;we do the same thing for our buyer clients.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We have a website set up specifically to host all of these properties for our buyers,&lt;/strong&gt; and we definitely push those listings out to our social media avenues and networks as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=IT’S KIND OF LIKE A DATING GAME BUT FOR A HOME.%20localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-our-tool-to-help-you-find-that-dream-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“IT’S KIND OF LIKE A DATING GAME BUT FOR A HOME.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s kind of like a dating game but for a home. We are so excited to help match you up with a great home you’d be interested to move to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if you’re just starting to think about the buyer search or you’ve been searching online with no luck, go ahead and get with us. We’ll have a consultation where we talk about all your wants and dreams and get you set up on our website so we can help you find your perfect home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call at (918) 712-2252 or send me an email at info@TheWolekGroup.com. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 11:26:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-our-tool-to-help-you-find-that-dream-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-our-tool-to-help-you-find-that-dream-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Tulsa Real Estate Buyers Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Groggs Green Barn Is Unique to Tulsa</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/F57cwdqYovQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re out at Grogg’s Green Barn today with owner Carla Grogg. She’s going to talk to us a bit about what they do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Looking to sell your Tulsa area home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tulsahomevalue.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Looking to buy a Tulsa area home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thewolekgroup.com/search-for-homes/#/-1451235678&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to browse Tulsa homes for sale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m happy to be joined by Carla Grogg of Grogg’s Green Barn. This place is so cool, so I wanted to talk a little bit with Carla about all the things that are going on here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carla and her husband started Grogg’s Green Barn seven years ago. As far as I know, this business is the only one of its kind in Tulsa. Carla and her husband started Grogg’s Green Barn, an all-sustainable organic nursery, after a few of their family members were affected by cancer, causing them to take their own health more seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grogg’s Green Barn carries all kinds of perennials, trees, shrubs, and more.&lt;/strong&gt; Additionally, they have quite a selection of edibles, like berry bushes, fruit trees, vegetables, and herbs. They also have a ton of great pollination plants, which are becoming more and more important as bee and butterfly populations continue to dwindle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=YOU NEED TO COME DOWN AND CHECK THIS PLACE OUT.%20localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-groggs-green-barn.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“YOU NEED TO COME DOWN AND CHECK THIS PLACE OUT.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just this year, Grogg’s has added another component to their business. They are transitioning part of their facility to be a new dining facility: The Reserve at Grogg’s Green Barn. &lt;strong&gt;They will use their own produce as well as meat and dairy from other local farmers to prepare delicious meals from Chef Matt Owen.&lt;/strong&gt; You can RSVP to the next dinner right here on their site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I highly recommend that you come down here and check out Grogg’s Green Barn. To learn more about what they do, head on over to their website. If you have any questions, you can give Carla a call at (918) 994-4222.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any real estate questions or needs, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’re always here to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 11:26:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-groggs-green-barn.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-groggs-green-barn.html</guid>
        
        <category>Jennie Wolek</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Should You Handle a Low Offer?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/DYNGULW7HW8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you encounter an offer that is lower than asking price, it’s common to negotiate.
Do not take the low offer personally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Looking to sell your Tulsa area home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tulsahomevalue.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Looking to buy a Tulsa area home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thewolekgroup.com/search-for-homes/#/-1451235678&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to browse Tulsa homes for sale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I’m going to give my two cents on a topic that keeps coming up in our business. I know if you’ve watched my videos in the past, I say the same things over and over again. That just because we sell lots and lots of houses and we get to help lots and lots of people. We have a lot of experience with this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am still primarily the listing agent for our team, so I mostly work with sellers. I receive offers from agents that are working with buyers, and so many times these offers come in lower than the listing price, and sometimes with other concessions built in, such as closing costs and warranties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I will admit that sometimes, I’m a little shocked at some of the offers we get.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I remember that in a buyer’s mind, they are doing the best that they can for their family. &lt;strong&gt;Of course they want to make a lower offer, because they feel like it’s their job to negotiate.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, as an agent, that’s also part of our job: &lt;strong&gt;to best prepare our clients and to explain the market to them.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we receive these lower offers or offers that have different contingencies built in, it’s our job to settle the client (the seller) and explain to them that these are expected—low offers like these are the norm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=I WILL ADMIT THAT SOMETIMES, I’M A LITTLE SHOCKED AT SOME OF THE OFFERS WE GET.%20localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-dont-reject-low-offers-out-of-hand.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“I WILL ADMIT THAT SOMETIMES, I’M A LITTLE SHOCKED AT SOME OF THE OFFERS WE GET.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll admit it: I forget that you guys don’t do this every day like I do. &lt;strong&gt;I do need to slow down and understand where you’re coming from,&lt;/strong&gt; because as a seller, you are working to get your best deal and to put the most money in your pocket. &lt;strong&gt;That is my goal for you, too.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I do know that I’m studying the market all the time and monitoring the average list-to-sales price of the MLS, how we can put the most money in your pocket and at the same time, get your home sold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An offer early on may be a little lower than you were planning on, and yet, if it doesn’t sell, how much longer will you have it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remember that the process of selling is a negotiation.&lt;/strong&gt; Please do not ever reject an offer; you have to do a little bit of negotiating to show that you want to sell your house. The buyer is working to get their best number, and you’re working to get your best number, so sometimes you have to get together in the middle somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That’s our goal: to get you the most money, and for the buyers to get the best deal.&lt;/strong&gt; At the same time, we have to work together to achieve your real estate dreams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me know if this was helpful to you, and if you have any questions, give me call! I’d love to speak with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 13:29:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-dont-reject-low-offers-out-of-hand.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-dont-reject-low-offers-out-of-hand.html</guid>
        
        <category>Tulsa Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
