<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Donaldson Team - your professional Northern Virginia Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://jodydonaldson.tv/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://jodydonaldson.tv/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 13:56:22 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 13:56:22 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Has Our Market Changed Since Last January?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/fFSi2xLE4E4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The numbers for our January 2018 Northern Virginia market are in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we head into the spring market, Northern Virginia home purchase activity has changed. New pending home contracts are down 3.6% since last year and the number of closed sales also decreased, going down by 3.6% to 1,834 sales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New listings are down 3.4% from January of last year but are up 73.9% from what they were in December of 2017. The number of listings on our market is currently just below the five-year average for January.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The median sold price has increased 3.9% since January of last year, now sitting at $429,950.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Northern Virginia definitely has pocketed areas, but our market is still strong.%20http://jodydonaldson.tv/how-has-our-market-changed-since-last-january.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Northern Virginia definitely has pocketed areas, but our market is still strong.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as the average days on market, listings this January saw an average of 62 days. This is an improvement from last year and from the five-year average of 67 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To summarize, we entered the new year with low inventory but a steady buyer demand. Northern Virginia definitely has pocketed areas, but our market is still strong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if you’ve been thinking of listing your home, now is the time to start preparing. The spring market will be here before we know it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://jodydonaldson.tv/how-has-our-market-changed-since-last-january.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jodydonaldson.tv/how-has-our-market-changed-since-last-january.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Little Kindness Can Go a Long Way This Holiday Season</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/NhAEM_FlC64?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’d like to take a moment to wish each and every one of you a happy, safe, and healthy holiday season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time of year may be great for some, but it can be a very difficult time for others. I encourage you this year to spread some joy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider greeting a stranger in the grocery store, at the bank, or anywhere else. &lt;strong&gt;You can never be sure how much a small gesture might mean to someone who needs it&lt;/strong&gt;, since we never know what a person may be going through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We’re so grateful to help you achieve your real estate goals each and every day.%20http://jodydonaldson.tv/a-little-kindness-can-go-a-long-way-this-holiday-season.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We’re so grateful to help you achieve your real estate goals each and every day.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of support, we appreciate all of you who have made 2017 a record-breaking year for The Donaldson Team. Thank you to everyone who voted and made us the Top Real Estate Team for Northern Virginia for the third year in a row in the Virginia Living Magazine poll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re so grateful to help you achieve your real estate goals each and every day. &lt;strong&gt;My team and I look forward to connecting with you in the new year.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, feel free to give me a call or send me an email if you have any questions about real estate. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 07:10:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://jodydonaldson.tv/a-little-kindness-can-go-a-long-way-this-holiday-season.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jodydonaldson.tv/a-little-kindness-can-go-a-long-way-this-holiday-season.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Did the Northern Virginia Real Estate Market Do This October?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/T7LMAW6-UFA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s going on in the Northern Virginia real estate market?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latest numbers from October 2017 are in, so it’s time to highlight what’s happening as we head toward the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home purchase activity has changed a little year over year.&lt;/strong&gt; New pending contracts are up 4.1% from October of 2016, and the number of closed sales increased by 4.6% to 2,877.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New listings in October are up 4.2% year over year but down 16.6% from September of 2017. There were 3,502 new listings, which is below the five-year average of 3,808 new listings for October.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;October saw 7,108 active listings in Northern Virginia, which is also below the number active listings in October 2016 and the five-year average of 8,400 listings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If this winter is mild, the spring market can start at the beginning of the year.%20http://jodydonaldson.tv/how-did-the-northern-virginia-real-estate-market-do-this-october.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If this winter is mild, the spring market can start at the beginning of the year.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The median price is $426,500, which is a 1.8% increase from $419,000 last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The average days on market this October was 46&lt;/strong&gt;, which is just under the five-year average of 50 days on market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do all of these statistics mean for you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are entering the winter market with very low inventory and steady buyer demand, as is reflected in the number of closed sales and the reduction in the average days on market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Certain pockets of Northern Virginia are busier than others, but our market is still strong and continues to do better year after year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traditionally, the holidays are a tough time to sell your home. If you are thinking of selling, now is the time to get your home ready to go on the market at the beginning of the year. &lt;strong&gt;If we have a mild winter, the spring season can start as early as January 1, 2018.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about our current real estate market, please don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 05:44:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://jodydonaldson.tv/how-did-the-northern-virginia-real-estate-market-do-this-october.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jodydonaldson.tv/how-did-the-northern-virginia-real-estate-market-do-this-october.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The 8 Most Common Homebuyer Questions</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2nJq_nMa1fY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you have questions about the home buying process? If so, you’re in luck. Buying a home can be both thrilling and scary, but it’s never dull. You’re bound to have a lot of questions throughout the process. &lt;strong&gt;Here are the eight most common home buying questions that I receive, along with my answers.&lt;/strong&gt; Without further ado, let’s get to them:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. What kind of home can I afford?&lt;/strong&gt; Most of this depends on your income, but the first step is getting pre-approved. A pre-approval doesn’t cost you anything, but it will allow you to know exactly how much you can afford. You’ll need one to submit an offer on most homes anyway, so it’s best to get this taken care of before you start seriously looking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Can I buy and sell at the same time?&lt;/strong&gt; The answer is yes, but it’s not a simple process. One strategy we’ve found success with is writing contingent offers. This means that you will only purchase the house once your current home sells. Whether or not this kind of offer is accepted has a lot to do with the kind of market you’re in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. How many homes should I see before making an offer?&lt;/strong&gt; This depends on the individual buyer. Most usually check out at least five to 10 before putting in an offer. However, it might be the first home you see (or the 30th). To streamline the process, focus in on some specific neighborhoods that you’d like to be in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. What will the seller accept as a fair price?&lt;/strong&gt;Typically, knocking 3% to 5% off the list price is a good rule of thumb and won’t ruffle too many feathers. You never know how low a seller is willing to go. If they’re eager to move, you could luck out and score a deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Contingencies are the best way out of a transaction.%20http://jodydonaldson.tv/the-8-most-common-homebuyer-questions.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Contingencies are the best way out of a transaction.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. How do I know if a property is a good deal?&lt;/strong&gt; With research, you can keep the surprises to the minimum. I advise you to look at the recent comparable sales in the area and whether those numbers have been trending up or down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. How quickly can I close?&lt;/strong&gt; The average loan process takes 30 to 45 days, giving you plenty of time to handle all of your contingencies and inspections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Should I get a home inspection?&lt;/strong&gt; The answer is absolutely yes. An inspection takes a big weight off your shoulders by thoroughly looking at the condition of the property. If there are any issues, they can be addressed after the inspection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. When can I back out of the transaction if I change my mind?&lt;/strong&gt; Although buyers can always back out of a deal, doing so without a good reason may cause you to forfeit your earnest money deposit (typically 1% to 2% of the purchase price). Contingencies, like the inspection and appraisal contingencies, are the loopholes that will allow you to get out of the contract and get your earnest money back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other home buying questions or questions about anything else, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 10:10:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://jodydonaldson.tv/the-8-most-common-homebuyer-questions.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jodydonaldson.tv/the-8-most-common-homebuyer-questions.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Winter Is Coming. Is Your Home Prepared?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/lVRLHm7KqJg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though it hasn’t felt like it lately, the end of the year is drawing to a close. Fall is here and winter is on its way. This means there are a few home maintenance and repair projects you should take care of before the weather gets colder and the days get shorter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Care for your trees and shrubs.&lt;/strong&gt; Also, remember to rake your leaves and clear out the underbrush. Now is a great time to do this, since there aren’t as many spiders or snakes out and about at this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Clean gutters and downspouts.&lt;/strong&gt;Making sure these are both clear will help you prepare for any oncoming rain or snow in the months ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Make exterior repairs.&lt;/strong&gt; If there are any projects you meant to take care of earlier in the year but didn’t, don’t put them off any longer. Take care of anything leftover on your to-do list for the exterior of your home. Exterior repairs like fixing your mailbox or removing wood rot shouldn’t wait any longer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Seal the gaps.&lt;/strong&gt; You don’t want any unwanted pests entering your home, so make sure you seal up gaps. Also, add weather stripping to any windows or doors where it’s needed. This will help keep your home energy efficient&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Check the walkways, railings, stairs, and driveway.&lt;/strong&gt; Making sure all of these features are secure and free of holes, since this kind of damage won’t be visible once it’s covered in snow or leaves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=There are a few home maintenance and repair projects you should take care of before the weather gets colder and the days get shorter.%20http://jodydonaldson.tv/winter-is-coming-is-your-home-prepared.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“There are a few home maintenance and repair projects you should take care of before the weather gets colder and the days get shorter.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Stock up on winter supplies.&lt;/strong&gt; Make sure that you have plenty of gas for the snowblower, salt and sand for the walkways, windshield washer fluid for your car, and any other items that will help you prepare for the coming season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Shut off exterior water.&lt;/strong&gt; You probably won’t be needing your hoses or outside spigots for some time, so make sure that you shut them off and store these items in a dry and safe place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. Check safety devices.&lt;/strong&gt; Make sure that your flashlights, smoke detectors, carbon monoxide detectors, and fire extinguishers are in working order. Also, replace the batteries in your smoke and carbon monoxide detectors regularly. This is something that is frequently overlooked, but is very important&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. Clean your dryer vents.&lt;/strong&gt; Making sure this is taken care of on a regular basis will help you prevent fires.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10. Schedule a chimney cleaning service and HVAC system maintenance.&lt;/strong&gt;These items should be taken care of before winter strikes. Preventative maintenance is key, but if you think your HVAC system might need more extensive repairs, hire a professional to help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11. Check and purge your closets.&lt;/strong&gt;Look over these areas, as well as your cabinets and garage, for any infrequently used items that you can donate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 05:22:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://jodydonaldson.tv/winter-is-coming-is-your-home-prepared.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jodydonaldson.tv/winter-is-coming-is-your-home-prepared.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Latest Northern Virginia Real Estate Numbers</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/XXUAriQsk5g?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latest numbers are in for our real estate market here in Northern Virginia so we wanted to highlight a few of the changes we’ve seen for you. &lt;strong&gt;Home purchase activity is a little different than it was at this time last year.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pending contracts have dropped off by about 4.4% from last year, but the number of closed sales increased 2.6% to 2,802.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New listings are down 2.5% from last year. In July, we had just 7,779 active listings. This is well below the five-year average.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The median sale price of $449,000 is up 2.7% from last year. At the same time, the average days on market is way down from last year. Homes are selling in an average of just 35 days now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We’re entering the fall in a strong seller’s market.%20http://jodydonaldson.tv/the-latest-northern-virginia-real-estate-numbers.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We’re entering the fall in a strong seller’s market.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We’re entering the fall market with very low inventory and a steady stream of buyers.&lt;/strong&gt; Northern Virginia is in a strong seller’s market for now, but if you’ve been on the fence about making a move it might be time to consider doing so. Right now, you have an opportunity to sell high and buy low before interest rates go up. When they go up, you might not be able to afford that perfect home that you could afford right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for us, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://jodydonaldson.tv/the-latest-northern-virginia-real-estate-numbers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jodydonaldson.tv/the-latest-northern-virginia-real-estate-numbers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Which Home Upgrades Aren't Worth Making?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/GULA9geEM4M?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I frequently get asked questions about home upgrades and the returns they may or may not bring. Many people wonder whether they’ll get the money they invest into improving their home back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The simple answer is that upgrades don’t always equate to a profit. Upgrades that seem valuable to you may not be valuable to potential buyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing what kind of upgrades are and aren’t worth the effort is essential. So today, I’ve got five common upgrades you should avoid. For as common as these upgrades are, they actually have some of the worst return on investment, according to an article by Trulia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Adding a swimming pool.&lt;/strong&gt; This upgrade can be hit or miss. One of the biggest factors that goes into determining whether or not adding a pool will be a good investment is location. If you are selling a home in Florida, or anywhere else a pool might be used year-round, a pool will be more likely to have a better return. However, even in circumstances like these it’s unlikely you will exceed or even earn back the money you invested in installing the pool to begin with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Highly personalized or customized designs.&lt;/strong&gt; When something about your home is too personalized, you are vastly decreasing the number of people who will find it appealing. Unless you are going to be staying in your home for years upon years to come, you should avoid making design choices that are too risky. Buyers’ tastes won’t always align with your own.  This causes issues not only in attracting buyers, but in other ways as well. Buyers looking at a home that is too customized will take into consideration the cost of changing features that simply aren’t their style. If that price isn’t worth it to them, you’ll be losing a lot of offers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Upgrades that seem valuable to you may not be valuable to potential buyers.%20http://jodydonaldson.tv/which-home-upgrades-arent-worth-making.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Upgrades that seem valuable to you may not be valuable to potential buyers.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Room conversions.&lt;/strong&gt;When buyers search for homes, they do so with a checklist in mind. They’ll often be seeking out a certain number of bedrooms and bathrooms. If you’ve converted one of these spaces into something unusual, you’re actually harming your home’s resale value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Incremental square footage gains.&lt;/strong&gt; While making significant gains in square footage is a good upgrade to make in your home, smaller gains aren’t really worth it. Insignificant square footage gains aren’t like you much return on your investment. Placement, also, is important. Even though a half bath on the first floor might be nice, buyers will be put off if they have to walk through or directly past it to get to the kitchen, for example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Over-improving.&lt;/strong&gt;While this may seem counter-intuitive, you don’t want to be the highest-priced home in the neighborhood. If you have the most expensive property around, your investment isn’t as likely to be returned. When making upgrades, keep your neighborhood’s baseline in mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, there’s nothing wrong with making improvements to your home because you enjoy doing them. The important thing to remember is not to give yourself the false hope that all of these upgrades will bring valuable returns when it comes time to sell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 10:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://jodydonaldson.tv/which-home-upgrades-arent-worth-making.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jodydonaldson.tv/which-home-upgrades-arent-worth-making.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Does the Northern Virginia Market Favor Buyers?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/VZHz5hEk9ek?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because the weather has been miserable with near-record days of rain, we’ve seen fewer showings than we did earlier in the spring. Hang in there though, because **we’ve still got plenty of buyers and low inventory. **&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compared to last April, both sales and units sold were up 8.99% and 6.6%, respectively. The average for days on market dropped from 53 to 51.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This April compared to last April, the number of new listings was down. Additionally, closed sales this April shot up 24.7% from the month before. In Loudoun county, the number of units sold fell 1.42%, but the &lt;strong&gt;average for days on market improved to 49 days this year from 68 last year.&lt;/strong&gt; Nationally, home prices are up 6%, and up 2.6% compared to last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=HOMEOWNERSHIP IS A GREAT INVESTMENT, BOTH FINANCIALLY AND EMOTIONALLY.%20http://jodydonaldson.tv/does-the-northern-virginia-market-favor-buyers.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“HOMEOWNERSHIP IS A GREAT INVESTMENT, BOTH FINANCIALLY AND EMOTIONALLY.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking ahead to future projections, &lt;strong&gt;waiting until next year could cost you almost $200 more in your mortgage payment.&lt;/strong&gt; This proves why homeownership is a great investment both financially and emotionally. Harvard University’s Joint Center of Housing Studies recently released a study showing the top reasons why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Financial Reasons:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Financially, housing is typically the one leveraged investment available, because you’re paying for housing, whether you own or rent.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Housing is usually a form of forced saving.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There are tax benefits to owning.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Owning is a hedge against inflation.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**Emotional Reasons: **&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Owning a home is a good way to build wealth that can be passed along to your family.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You have an actual structure providing space and safety for your family.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You have control over your space, like renovations or updates.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Owning a home provides a place to raise children and give them a good education.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although rates are still low, waiting to buy could be costly for your monthly mortgage payment. Call your lender today and get pre-qualified. If you have any questions about real estate in Northern Virginia, please don’t hesitate to reach out to me!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 11:53:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://jodydonaldson.tv/does-the-northern-virginia-market-favor-buyers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jodydonaldson.tv/does-the-northern-virginia-market-favor-buyers.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Whats the Secret to Making Your Northern Virginia Home Stand out from the Crowd?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/iGsF_TiualE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We’ve all hear the term “curb appeal,” but does it really help sell your home?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Homes that look good from the street - that is, homes with good curb appeal - &lt;strong&gt;should help you get a higher price and take less time to sell.&lt;/strong&gt; To improve your curb appeal, you don’t need to make a bunch of renovations to the exterior of your home. We’re talking about **regular maintenance and some extra beautifying tasks that will go a long way. **&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question becomes which projects will give you the best payoff? &lt;strong&gt;Here’s a list of what we think is worth your time:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wash the front of your house.&lt;/strong&gt; Before you scrape any paint or plant more azaleas, wash the dirt, mildew, and general grunge off the front of your house. This will help show your house in the best light. A power washer is an ideal way to do this, but a bucket of soapy water and a long-handle, soft bristle brush can get the job done as well. Don’t forget to take care of the sidewalks and driveway while you’re at it!  You should also wash your windows inside and out, wipe the cobwebs from the eaves, and wash out your downspouts. Don’t forget to wash off your garage as well.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Freshen the paint job.&lt;/strong&gt; After power washing or scrubbing the front, the most commonly offered advice I share with clients is to give the exterior of the home a good paint job. Buyers will instantly notice it and appraisers will value it. Painting can be an expensive and time-consuming facelift, but it is usually well-worth the effort.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Address the roof.&lt;/strong&gt; The condition of your roof is one of the first things buyers notice when they drive up and that appraisers assess. Missing, faded, or curled shingles add nothing to the look or value to the house. If your neighbors have maintained or replaced their roofs recently, yours will look especially shabby. If the roof is in obvious disrepair, it’s in your best interest to bite the bullet and invest in new shingles.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Doing these eight things will make your home stand out from the competition%20http://jodydonaldson.tv/whats-the-secret-to-making-your-northern-virginia-home-stand-out-from-the-crowd.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Doing these eight things will make your home stand out from the competition”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clean up the yard.&lt;/strong&gt; A well-manicured lawn with fresh mulch and pruned shrubs boosts the curb appeal of any home. Replace your overgrown bushes with leafy plants and colorful annuals, surround bushes and trees with dark mulch to give a rich feel to the yard, put a crisp edge on garden beds, pull the weeds and invasive vines, and plant a few geraniums in the pots. You also need to green up your grass with lawn food and water, cover any bare spots with seeds and sod, and get rid of the crab grass and mow it regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add a splash of color.&lt;/strong&gt; Even a little color attracts and pleases the eyes of would-be buyers. Plant a tulip border in the fall that will bloom in the spring, and dig a flower bed by the mailbox and plant some pansies. Consider placing a colored bench or Adirondack chair on the front porch as well. These colorful touches won’t add to the value of your house, but beautiful colors enhance the curb appeal and can help you sell your house faster.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spruce up your mailbox.&lt;/strong&gt; An upscale mailbox, architectural house numbers, or address plaques can make your house stand out. You can get a really nice mailbox for anywhere from $50-150, or you can just repaint your current one and add new fresh home numbers to it as well. Just make sure any changes you make comply with the HOA guidelines for your neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fence yourself in.&lt;/strong&gt; A picket fence with a garden gate to frame the yard is an asset. Not only will it add visual punch to your property, but appraisers will give extra value to a fence in great condition. Expect to pay around $2,000-3,500 for a professionally installed gated picket fence. If you already have a fence, make sure it is clean and in great condition. Again, be sure to check with your local HOA before you make any purchases.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maintenance is a must.&lt;/strong&gt; Nothing looks worse from the curb and sets off subconscious alarms like hanging gutters, missing bricks, or peeling paint. Not only can these deferred maintenance items damage your home, but they could decrease the value of your home by as much as 10%.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doing these things will make your house stand out from the competition,&lt;/strong&gt; and will help you put your best foot forward when you list your home on the market.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2016 09:41:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://jodydonaldson.tv/whats-the-secret-to-making-your-northern-virginia-home-stand-out-from-the-crowd.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jodydonaldson.tv/whats-the-secret-to-making-your-northern-virginia-home-stand-out-from-the-crowd.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Do Guaranteed Home Sale Programs Really Work in Northern Virginia?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/E4PpwgF-4Vg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ve seen the signs: I’ll sell your home in 60 days, or I’ll buy it. I want to take a minute and share with you &lt;strong&gt;how those programs work,&lt;/strong&gt; and what you should be aware of when considering this type of program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I don’t have a guaranteed sale program. I can’t offer something in good conscience that, in my opinion, is &lt;strong&gt;a bait and switch marketing tactic.&lt;/strong&gt; I have nothing against the Realtors that use these programs, and a lot of the most successful agents in this country have some form of this program in their business plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if you were to talk with several of these agents, &lt;strong&gt;very few end up having to buy the home from their client.&lt;/strong&gt; Even fewer of the clients choose to list their home under these programs. That’s partly due to what’s in the fine print. There are several criteria that the seller must agree and comply with in order to make these programs work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of these programs include &lt;strong&gt;an agreed upon list price,&lt;/strong&gt; which is solely based on recently sold properties and not current market conditions. Other programs include a &lt;strong&gt;pre-agreed upon price reduction every 7 days,&lt;/strong&gt; and that can be a significant amount. Still more programs include an upfront marketing fee of $1,500 to $2,500 and pay for staging and any other things the Realtor recommends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If this program seems too good to be true, it probably is.%20http://jodydonaldson.tv/do-guaranteed-home-sale-programs-really-work-in-northern-virginia.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If this program seems too good to be true, it probably is.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, the pre-agreed upon price that the agent would pay for the home is usually &lt;strong&gt;well below market value&lt;/strong&gt; and includes the same seller commissions and fees as a regular transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reality is that these types of programs might work for a small percentage of people, but ultimately, &lt;strong&gt;guaranteed sale programs are a marketing tool to get the agent’s phone to ring,&lt;/strong&gt; and it often works. I’ve talked to several who use these programs, and they all say that it’s a huge lead generation system for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bottom line, &lt;strong&gt;if it seems too good to be true, it probably is&lt;/strong&gt;. If you’re a motivated seller and you’re willing to do what your agent recommends, price your home aggressively based on the current market conditions, and combine that with a fantastic marketing plan, then your home should sell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, please don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2016 10:17:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://jodydonaldson.tv/do-guaranteed-home-sale-programs-really-work-in-northern-virginia.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jodydonaldson.tv/do-guaranteed-home-sale-programs-really-work-in-northern-virginia.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
