<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Portland Lifestyle Team - your professional Portland Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://realestateportlandblog.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://realestateportlandblog.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 11:30:23 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 11:30:23 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Selling Your First House? Follow These 4 Mega Tips</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/onCOSSBAquA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’ve got four mega tips for you as a first-time home seller. These four tips will help you prepare your home for success on the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Price your home accurately:&lt;/strong&gt; Hire an agent to perform a comprehensive market analysis, which compares your home to nearby homes and what they sold for. They will come up with a value based on a number of factors like size and location. We might check our logic against Zillow, but it shouldn’t be trusted as your only source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Prepare your home for sale:&lt;/strong&gt;Consider taking half of your furniture out of the house because you want buyers to come through and wonder if anybody lives there. You want to give them an idea of what the house looks like without being overwhelmed with clutter and furniture, which can make rooms look small. A fresh coat of paint can add a lot of value as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=iPhones may take good pictures, but you shouldn't market a home with them.%20http://realestateportlandblog.com/selling-your-first-house-follow-these-4-mega-tips.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“iPhones may take good pictures, but you shouldn’t market a home with them.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Be flexible with showings:&lt;/strong&gt; It can be overwhelming, so I always recommend to consider leaving home for the first weekend your house goes on the market to let it be completely available for showings or an open house. When you’re in town and there’s a showing scheduled, you want to be out of the house during that showing so buyers can have open conversations amongst themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Use professional photography:&lt;/strong&gt; iPhones take good pictures but I wouldn’t use it to market a home. Professional photographers have a keen eye for angles that display your home well and showcase color to make photos pop. On our team, we incorporate video and drone photography as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you’re thinking about selling your house, this is a great market to list in and find your next home and we’d love to help. Just give us a call or send us an email soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 05:42:16 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://realestateportlandblog.com/selling-your-first-house-follow-these-4-mega-tips.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://realestateportlandblog.com/selling-your-first-house-follow-these-4-mega-tips.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Make Sure Youre Protected This Tax Season</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1h1J9jkMwE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s tax season! To make sure your refund dream doesn’t turn into a tax fraud nightmare, Peter Wease, our preferred lender from Fairway Independent Mortgage, has three tips for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, file your taxes early. File your taxes before anyone has a chance to steal your information to file for you and collect your refund.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, get a free copy of your credit report. Go online to TransUnion, Experian, or Equifax and they will send you a free copy of your credit report. If you see anything odd going on, make sure you report it immediately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=IF YOU SEE ANYTHING WEIRD ON YOUR CREDIT REPORT, MAKE SURE YOU REPORT IT IMMEDIATELY.%20http://realestateportlandblog.com/make-sure-youre-protected-this-tax.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“IF YOU SEE ANYTHING WEIRD ON YOUR CREDIT REPORT, MAKE SURE YOU REPORT IT IMMEDIATELY.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, get a security freeze put on your credit account. This way, whenever something unusual happens with your credit, the account will freeze until you can review the information and unfreeze it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any further questions for Peter about protecting yourself this tax season, you can reach him at petew@fairwaymc.com or 503-765-1173.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any questions for me, please feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 14:21:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://realestateportlandblog.com/make-sure-youre-protected-this-tax.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://realestateportlandblog.com/make-sure-youre-protected-this-tax.html</guid>
        
        <category>Tax Season</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>4 Tips to Crafting the Best Possible Offer on a Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/IvfyMS8dMX0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve found the perfect home and you’re ready to make an offer, here are four tips to make your offer stand out and ensure that you get that perfect home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, understand what you can afford. Work with a well-known lender who’s highly qualified so they can make you look as solid as possible on paper. You also want to know from them what your big-picture financial situation looks like so you can know what loan programs are available and you can prepare for any future updates or repairs on the home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, act fast. A balanced market is considered to have six months’ worth of inventory. In Portland, we have 1.3 months’ worth of inventory. Our market is very competitive, so once you find a home, you must move forward under the guidance of your agent as quickly as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Our market is very competitive, so you must move quickly.%20http://realestateportlandblog.com/4-tips-to-crafting-best-possible-offer.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Our market is very competitive, so you must move quickly.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third, make sure your offer is solid. Don’t make a lowball offer. Instead, have your agent look through a list of comparable properties in the area and what they have sold for so you can make a good offer. Another thing you could do is write a letter to the seller telling them all about you, your family, what you plan to do with the home, and any other information of that type that might ingratiate yourself to them. You could also have your agent dig further into the motivations of the seller to find out if there is some need of theirs that you can satisfy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, be prepared to negotiate. After you submit an offer, you will probably receive a counter offer, and you need to be prepared to respond. This is another instance where being pre-approved up front is crucial—you know that if you have to raise your price a little bit, you can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this topic or there’s anything else we can help you with, please don’t hesitate to give us a call or send me an email. In the meantime, make it a great day!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions, please feel free to call me or send me a quick email. I’m here to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 16:37:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://realestateportlandblog.com/4-tips-to-crafting-best-possible-offer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://realestateportlandblog.com/4-tips-to-crafting-best-possible-offer.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Does Your Credit Score Impact Buying Power?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/pJH0woJPI_c?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people aren’t aware of how important their credit score is when it comes to purchasing a home. A credit score needs to be high enough to qualify for the loan program they are trying to get approved for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So can you buy a home in Portland with a low credit score? The answer is yes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From about 2000 to 2007, basically all you would need to do to get a stated income loan was tell your lender what you made without having to prove it and they wouldn’t do a credit check. Luckily, those are no longer available. People now have to be qualified for a home, and credit scores are key in getting that done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Your credit score plays a hugh role in if and how you qualify for loan programs.%20http://realestateportlandblog.com/how-does-your-credit-score-impact.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Your credit score plays a hugh role in if and how you qualify for loan programs.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want to get you started by connecting you to the right people. We work very closely with Fairway Independent Mortgage, specifically Pete Wease, and we would love to refer him to you. Pete will sit down with you and discuss the many programs available and take a look at your score. If your score is low, he will help you figure out a strategy to bring it up and in turn get you a better interest rate. To reach Pete, you can call (503-267-6391) or email him at petew@fairwaymc.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are so many different loan programs that you can take advantage of as well. There are low money down programs, some grant programs with no money down, and conventional loans with still historically low interest rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your credit score plays a huge role in if and how you qualify for those loan programs, and Pete and I want to make sure we can get you prepared to take action in the spring market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions please feel free to call me or send me a quick email. I’m here to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 11:43:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://realestateportlandblog.com/how-does-your-credit-score-impact.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://realestateportlandblog.com/how-does-your-credit-score-impact.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Do You Need a Real Estate Professional?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/CuS85cj5tDg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you are looking to buy or sell a home, you don’t want to try to tackle the market alone. I’ve put together a list of five reasons why hiring a real estate professional is always better than trying to go it alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Paperwork. There is much more paperwork that goes into buying or selling a home than there used to be. A transaction of this size requires more than a single sheet of paper. There is a lot of information contained in the paperwork that you should be aware of, and a real estate professional will help you navigate that.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Experience. Having someone who is educated and highly experienced is key.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Negotiations. Having someone help you negotiate who isn’t swayed by emotion will make sure you get the best deal whether you are buying or selling.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Having someone who is educated and highly experienced is key.%20http://realestateportlandblog.com/portland-real-estate-agent-5-reasons-to.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Having someone who is educated and highly experienced is key.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Pricing. Pricing is an art. There are a lot of tools that can help you determine pricing. However, to make sure your home is priced correctly and in order to sell in a brief amount of time, you need to make sure a professional is pricing your home.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Understanding of current market conditions. We shift in and out of buyer’s and seller’s markets, and hiring someone who understands those shifts will provide you with a solid foundation to either look for a home on the market or sell a home on the market.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions please feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 14:49:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://realestateportlandblog.com/portland-real-estate-agent-5-reasons-to.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://realestateportlandblog.com/portland-real-estate-agent-5-reasons-to.html</guid>
        
        <category>Portland Real Estate Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Things for Millennial Home Buyers to Consider</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There is one specific segment of buyers that is making our market extra exciting. These buyers are part of the millennial generation (ages 18-34) and they are an integral part of our market. They will continue to be an integral part for the foreseeable future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see in the video above, the age groups with the highest percentage of people who associate homeownership with the American Dream are those in the 65+ generation and millennials. Business Insider, who did this study, also did a study that examined when these buyers plan to purchase. Over the next five years, over 60% of millennials plan to enter the market. They are going to continue fueling our market going forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don’t see a slowdown coming at all. If you are looking for a larger home or to get out of your rental situation, now is a smart time to do that. We expect significant appreciation to continue for the next few years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for first-time home buyers, many are misinformed about how much it actually costs to buy a home. In fact, 73% of millennials are unaware of the fact that there are many down payment assistance programs available that will allow them to get into a house for just 3% to 5% down. That number can be even lower by taking advantage of certain grant programs that are available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=More and more millennials are choosing to buy.%20http://realestateportlandblog.com/portland-real-estate-agent-new-segment.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“More and more millennials are choosing to buy.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buying a home can be very cost-effective in the long term, and millennials are realizing this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking to buy and want to begin the process, a study by the National Association of Realtors showed that 89% of millennial real estate participants used a Realtor. As a buyer, it costs you nothing for competent, professional representation in a real estate transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are thinking about buying or selling, give us a call or send us an email. We would love to speak to you about your specific situation and answer any questions you may have. We look forward to hearing from you soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2017 18:40:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://realestateportlandblog.com/portland-real-estate-agent-new-segment.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://realestateportlandblog.com/portland-real-estate-agent-new-segment.html</guid>
        
        <category>Portland Real Estate Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We Owe All Our Success to You</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/NEZzFXdjVaM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wanted to take a moment to reflect back on 2016 and how you helped us make it great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We really appreciate all of our new and repeat clients that helped our business this year. I also want to thank everyone who sent us referrals—I can’t even begin to tell you how important they are to us!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Thanks for helping us make this year a great one.%20http://realestateportlandblog.com/portland-real-estate-agent-thanks-for.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Thanks for helping us make this year a great one.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year was an amazing one for the Portland real estate market. We saw some of the most extensive price appreciation that our country has seen in some time. In fact, we led the nation for most of the year in percentage-based appreciation. We expect 2017 to be a very similar year, even though I think the appreciation rate will slow a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you or anyone you know is interested in buying or selling a home in the Portland area as we head into 2017, send them our way and we’ll treat them well. We appreciate you thinking of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Holidays!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 10:21:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://realestateportlandblog.com/portland-real-estate-agent-thanks-for.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://realestateportlandblog.com/portland-real-estate-agent-thanks-for.html</guid>
        
        <category>Portland Real Estate Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Can a Lender Help You?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/fyZidP3K6zY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m here with Pete Wease, our preferred lender, to discuss job satisfaction on the lending side of things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the best parts of Pete’s job is when a client gets to the closing table and signs the dotted line. “They’re smiling ear to ear,” Pete says. “That is the biggest sign of job satisfaction for me.” He knows that his clients are feeling a sense of pride and ownership when they close on their home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, there are situations where a transaction shows signs of trouble. When it looks like a deal might fall apart, Pete just takes a step back, reflects, and communicates with the client to find a solution. “Any time we close a transaction, that’s a home run,” Pete says. “The bottom line is, I am here to help you close on your loan.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Communication and proper preparation will get you to the closing table.%20http://realestateportlandblog.com/portland-real-estate-agent-how-lenders.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Communication and proper preparation will get you to the closing table.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are times when a transaction may not be able to close. Pete says, “If I can’t help you now, I will help you in the future.” Pete believes that preparation and communication are crucial to making it to the closing table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for Pete, you can give him a call at 503-267-6391 or email him at PeteW@FairwayMC.com. We have been working with Pete for four years now and it’s been a fantastic experience. We have nothing but good reviews for Pete here, so we highly recommend that you reach out to him if you are thinking of buying a home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other real estate questions, just give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 10:21:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://realestateportlandblog.com/portland-real-estate-agent-how-lenders.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://realestateportlandblog.com/portland-real-estate-agent-how-lenders.html</guid>
        
        <category>Portland Real Estate Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Don't Kill Your Home Deal With This Mistake</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/yn-f8igsb-o?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some surprises that can seemingly come out of nowhere in a real estate transaction that can take the wind out of your sails or even completely kill a deal. To help me break these surprises down in order to help you avoid them, I’ve brought in mortgage expert Peter Wease with Fairway Independent Mortgage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Peter, the number one killer is opening up new credit. Some home buyers want to buy a new car or new things for their new home like furniture, curtains, paint, etc. Even worse–many buyers open credit without telling their lender. You should avoid opening any new credit at all when buying a house. The house should be the only thing you’re focusing your finances on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Opening new credit is the best way to ruin your mortgage qualification.%20http://realestateportlandblog.com/dont-kill-your-home-deal-with-this.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Opening new credit is the best way to ruin your mortgage qualification.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you close, then you can think about those new purchases. In the early steps of the process, your lender will run a credit check, and your mortgage qualification is based on your credit at that time. If that changes midstream, your credit score or debt-to-income ratio could change, and your lender might not be able to get you approved in the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need help with a home loan or a refinance or you have any questions for him, give him a call at 503-267-6391.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me or you’re thinking about buying or selling a home in Portland, give me a call or send me an email. I’d love to help you in any way I can!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2016 11:27:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://realestateportlandblog.com/dont-kill-your-home-deal-with-this.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://realestateportlandblog.com/dont-kill-your-home-deal-with-this.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Current Health of the Portland Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/c5GHg4UNHjA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To examine the market on a monthly basis, one tool we like is the Case-Shiller S&amp;amp;P Index that you can get online. It continues to show us appreciation across the country at a healthy 5%. The report is broken down into 10 and 20-city composites, with Portland in the 20-city composite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Portland is leading the way in this report. The 20-city composite was actually down slightly in this last report from 5.1% to 5%, but Portland is at 12.4% appreciation. Before you overreact to that, understand that we were even higher than that at one point. We’re starting to see it trend downward, but that’s a good thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The report also notes that most analysts are expecting the Fed to raise interest rates this December. Even if they do, though, the impact on mortgage rates and the mortgage industry are going to be so minimal that we’ll still see these historically low rates, so there’s nothing to get too worried about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Portland is leading the way.%20http://realestateportlandblog.com/the-current-health-of-portland-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Portland is leading the way.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also get questions all the time about whether we’re in a bubble that’s going to pop soon. We’re so programmed with bubbles these days that I believe we just overreact. We know we’re not in a bubble by looking at outstanding mortgage debt and seeing that we’re about 12.6% lower than what it was at its peak in the 1st quarter of 2008, and we’re not seeing much growth there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the video above, you can see a table that demonstrates how healthy the indexes are compared to the peak of the market in 2006 and the trough of 2012. We’re starting to see the market shift, and we need to see the market shift. We’re not seeing up to 10 offers on almost everything, and that’s a good thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions at all about where our market is going and what it means to you as a buyer, seller, or homeowner, give me a call or send me an email. I’d love to hear from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 13:03:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://realestateportlandblog.com/the-current-health-of-portland-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://realestateportlandblog.com/the-current-health-of-portland-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Portland Real Estate Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
