<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Burbank Real Estate Video Blog with Brad Korb</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Brad Korb Real Estate Group - your professional Burbank Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>lasells.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="lasells.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 16:49:14 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 16:49:14 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Compete as a Buyer in Today's Hot Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/llyDMGImUNo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, we’ve had a shortage of inventory. This has led to a lot of bidding wars due to the hot competition over our currently limited supply.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One option buyers are turning to in these competitive times is asking the help of parents and other family members.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the help of a family member, many young buyers are able to beat out the competition by putting forward cash offers. Of course, the mortgage can always be refinanced after closing, but this is a great way to secure a deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A great way to beat out the competition is by putting forward cash offers.%20lasells.com/how-to-compete-as-a-buyer-in-todays-hot-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A great way to beat out the competition is by putting forward cash offers.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re unable to pay cash, &lt;strong&gt;you can also write an offer with fewer contingencies and a strong down payment.&lt;/strong&gt; This is another thing that can make your offer stand out in today’s hot market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope keeping these tips in mind will help you as you enter our low inventory, high demand market. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 11:13:05 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>lasells.com/how-to-compete-as-a-buyer-in-todays-hot-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">lasells.com/how-to-compete-as-a-buyer-in-todays-hot-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Can You Expect From Your Home Inspection?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ui_gtLXpneg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste present-before-paste&quot;&gt;If you’re a homebuyer in our area, it’s important that you get an inspection for the home you’re buying because most of the homes in our marketplace are older.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Typically, you’ll have 17 days to check out the house and complete the inspection.&lt;/strong&gt; We have several great inspectors we’d be glad to refer you to if you’re in search of one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Which inspection contingencies you’ll deal with depends on the property being inspected.%20lasells.com/what-can-you-expect-from-your-home-inspection.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Which inspection contingencies you’ll deal with depends on the property being inspected.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;Which inspection contingencies you’ll deal with depends on the property being inspected. A further roof inspection might be recommended, for example, or you might need to check out the property’s sewer line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;If the property has been remodeled recently, you can also have your Realtor pull the inspection permits to see what’s been done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;If you have any more questions about inspection contingencies and the inspection process, don’t hesitate to give me a call or shoot me an email. I’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 07:17:42 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>lasells.com/what-can-you-expect-from-your-home-inspection.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">lasells.com/what-can-you-expect-from-your-home-inspection.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are You Interesting in Joining Our Team?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-vnf3kf1Ojs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I have some exciting news to share. We’re looking to hire two new buyer partners to our team. This is a great opportunity to get into the real estate business on the ground level. If you’re excited about being in real estate, you’re a self-starter, and you’re motivated, we’d love to speak with you. To learn more about this opportunity, watch our latest video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 05:03:21 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>lasells.com/are-you-interesting-in-joining-our-team.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">lasells.com/are-you-interesting-in-joining-our-team.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Does the Fed’s Recent Interest Rate Hike Mean for You?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/mRvxMsxg3Mc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m joined today by my preferred lender, Brian McKim over at SkyLine Home Plans, to talk about the Fed’s recent interest rate increase and how it’s going to affect you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In case you haven’t heard already, the FED raised rates by .25% this week.&lt;/strong&gt; However, this has been long expected and has been priced into the market for the last few months. The FED also announced that they would probably raise rates again two or three times in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Even though the FED has increased their rates, mortgage interest rates have not been affected.&lt;/strong&gt;They remain excellent and still near historic lows. We don’t expect any major changes in the mortgage rate market for the time being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions in the meantime, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/versions/mckim---x----700-883x---.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;post-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 04:03:03 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>lasells.com/what-does-the-feds-recent-interest-rate-hike-mean-for-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">lasells.com/what-does-the-feds-recent-interest-rate-hike-mean-for-you.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>From Our Family to Yours, Happy Holidays</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/LOl4DhlNDUw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The holiday season is here and we couldn’t be more excited. From our family to yours, we wanted to wish you all the best this year. We hope you have a merry Christmas, a happy New Year, and a joyous holiday season. Thank you for a wonderful year. To see our full holiday message, watch this short video.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 04:57:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>lasells.com/from-our-family-to-yours-happy-holidays.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">lasells.com/from-our-family-to-yours-happy-holidays.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Help Others in Burbank Celebrate Thanksgiving!</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/kuG2-c9xdHI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are very fortunate to have great families, good jobs, and warm homes to go to during the Holidays. Unfortunately, this isn’t a reality for everyone in our area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why we always help the Burbank Temporary Aid Center. Every year, they provide over 1,000 turkeys to families in need. This is our seventh year in a row, and we don’t plan on stopping anytime soon!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need your help! If you’d like to donate your time or some turkeys, please get in touch with us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, refer to us as your No. 1 resource for real estate in the LA area!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 03:33:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>lasells.com/help-others-in-burbank-celebrate-thanksgiving.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">lasells.com/help-others-in-burbank-celebrate-thanksgiving.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What’s Our Fall Market Outlook?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/mHSExP3Cgn0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy fall!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that the season has changed, it’s time to look back on our market and update you on what’s happening now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, we had a phenomenal summer. &lt;strong&gt;Interest rates dropped back down to historic lows, and buyers are out there still buying away.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Homes are still very much in demand.%20lasells.com/whats-our-fall-market-outlook.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Homes are still very much in demand.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment, properties are moving off the shelves in the lower and medium-priced markets. There’s a bit of a softening in the higher-end markets, but homes are still very much in demand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about our LA market or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home soon, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 04:53:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>lasells.com/whats-our-fall-market-outlook.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">lasells.com/whats-our-fall-market-outlook.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are You Ready to Join an HOA?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Bzayk42ZXEk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is Courtney Korb with the Brad Korb Real Estate Group today I’d like to answer 5 important questions about HOAs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, what are the costs involved? &lt;strong&gt;Membership in an HOA requires a monthly fee that you’ll pay on top of your mortgage payment.&lt;/strong&gt; Make sure that you’re financially comfortable adding this fee to your monthly budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, know what is being covered. Are they covering water? Are they covering landscaping? Depending on the complex, different items will be included.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=HOAs are always looking for new residents with new ideas to take part in the committees to try to make their community look even better.%20lasells.com/are-you-ready-to-join-an-hoa.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“HOAs are always looking for new residents with new ideas to take part in the committees to try to make their community look even better.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third, what are the rules of the HOA? Many will have guidelines concerning pets, how many units are allowed to be rented out, etc. Be sure to ask about any restrictions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fourth, are you happy with how the complex looks? The HOA is responsible for appearances. Are the trees trimmed? Is the paint there? Are everyone’s patios looking nice? Consider these factors as a potential new resident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, can you get involved? &lt;strong&gt;Every HOA has a board of directors made up entirely of members living in the community.&lt;/strong&gt; Are you willing to step up? HOAs are always looking for new residents with new ideas to take part in the committees to try to make their community look even better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about HOAs, or are looking at townhomes or condos, we would love to help you. Please give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to speaking with you soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 12:08:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>lasells.com/are-you-ready-to-join-an-hoa.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">lasells.com/are-you-ready-to-join-an-hoa.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Essential Components of a Successful Home Purchase</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7ZcW6b0mwWg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a homebuyer in today’s market, you need to focus on doing five specific things in order to have the smoothest and most profitable transaction possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Move quickly.&lt;/strong&gt; When you see something you like, you’ve got to be able to write an offer right away. If you wait a few days to make an offer, the property might be long gone by then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Understand the seller’s needs.&lt;/strong&gt; You can have your agent reach out to the seller’s agent and ask them what they’re looking for. Do they want a longer escrow period or a larger earnest money deposit? Whatever the case, you can craft your offer to the seller’s liking once you have this information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The more you know about the seller, the better offer you can craft.%20lasells.com/5-essential-components-of-a-successful-home-purchase.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The more you know about the seller, the better offer you can craft.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Have your loan officer call the listing agent.&lt;/strong&gt; If your loan officer lets the listing agent know personally that you are fully approved and ready to go, it can make a world of difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Be aggressive with your terms and pricing.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Work with an experienced real estate agent.&lt;/strong&gt; I’ve been in the business since 1979 and last year, my team sold 169 properties. You want an experienced agent that knows this market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like to apply for the job of helping you buy your next home. If you need my help or if you just have any questions, you can give me a call or send me an email anytime. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 09:23:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>lasells.com/5-essential-components-of-a-successful-home-purchase.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">lasells.com/5-essential-components-of-a-successful-home-purchase.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Does Our Summertime LA Market Look?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/lsiwBz1xEeM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s been going on in our summertime market lately?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have very limited inventory, and the good news for sellers is homes are selling with multiple bids and for more than their listed price—sometimes even above their appraised value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The news is good for sellers in our market.%20lasells.com/how-does-our-summertime-la-market-look.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The news is good for sellers in our market.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our average days on market is fewer than 30 days, home prices are 5% to 7% higher compared to this time last year, and &lt;strong&gt;this momentum doesn’t seem like it will slow down for the rest of the summer or the foreseeable future.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about the state of our current market or you’re thinking about buying or selling a home, feel free to give me a call or shoot me an email. I’d be happy to assist you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 07:17:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>lasells.com/how-does-our-summertime-la-market-look.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">lasells.com/how-does-our-summertime-la-market-look.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
