<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from All Things Real Estate - your professional Colorado Springs Real Estate Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://coloradospringsrealestatevideos.com//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://coloradospringsrealestatevideos.com//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 13:27:20 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 13:27:20 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The 3 Upfront Costs in Any Real Estate Transaction</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/IgeD-G1BItA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any real estate transaction will come with three upfront costs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Earnest money&lt;/strong&gt;: This is like a security deposit you pay as if you were renting. Usually, it’s 1% of the purchase price and acts as a safety net for the home sale so you can move forward with the transaction. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home inspection&lt;/strong&gt;: This is a huge part of the process and the cost usually depends on the size and age of the home. It’s usually around $300 to $500, but it’s the best money you’ll spend throughout the process. Your due diligence is an important part of buying a home, and during inspection periods you can also do sewer and radon tests. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Appraisals&lt;/strong&gt;: You’ll have to pay for this requirement if you’re getting a home loan. The appraiser will go to the home and opine what it’s actually worth, and the cool part is that it will keep you from overpaying for the house. This typically costs between $550 and $800.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Home inspection costs are the best money you'll spend during the whole process.%20http://coloradospringsrealestatevideos.com//the-3-upfront-costs-in-any-real-estate-transaction.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Home inspection costs are the best money you’ll spend during the whole process.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about the costs of buying or home or you’re looking to sell your house, give us a call or send us an email. We’re happy to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 11:02:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://coloradospringsrealestatevideos.com//the-3-upfront-costs-in-any-real-estate-transaction.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coloradospringsrealestatevideos.com//the-3-upfront-costs-in-any-real-estate-transaction.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
