<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The McIntosh Team</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The McIntosh Team - your professional Savannah Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://mcintoshrealtyblog.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://mcintoshrealtyblog.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 15:07:16 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 15:07:16 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>What You Need to Know About the Closing Process</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/FHtJTBrDkEI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The closing process is the culmination of the contract—the transaction that has taken place between the buyer and the seller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Closings typically take place at a closing attorney’s office. The closing attorney is generally chosen by the buyer’s side of the transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, it’s important to keep in mind that the closing attorney does not represent the buyer or the seller when there is financing involved. In that case, the closing attorney actually represents the lender.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the attorney is chosen by the seller’s side of the transaction. For example, if the seller is dealing with probate, they may choose to use the attorney they’ve already been working with to handle the closing for a smoother transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are buying a new construction property, the builder will choose the closing attorney. Builders are very fond of their closing attorneys and will do what they can to keep their closings all in one place. It’s more convenient and it helps the builder with record keeping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The closing attorney represents the lender.%20http://mcintoshrealtyblog.com/what-you-need-to-know-about-the-closing-process.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The closing attorney represents the lender.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The closing attorney’s job is vital to the closing process. The attorney will make sure that the title will transfer with no liens or encumbrances. They will do a very thorough title search and offer you a title insurance policy at the end of closing. I recommend that you take advantage of that policy; it protects you from anything that might not have been found in that search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If at all possible, we do like to have all parties involved present at the signing of the contract. It’s important that we are able to answer any questions that the buyer or seller might have. It’s also important to make sure that both parties have completed all of their obligations to the contract. For example, we need to make sure that the buyer has brought their funds and are capable of closing. We also need to make sure that the seller provides the title and has completed any repairs or replacements as negotiated in the contract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, though, not everyone can make it to the closing table. That’s okay. We just need to know that information as soon as possible so that we can take the proper steps to close the transaction. We may need to get power of attorney or put together a mail-away package in order for that closing to transpire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about the closing process, just give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://mcintoshrealtyblog.com/what-you-need-to-know-about-the-closing-process.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mcintoshrealtyblog.com/what-you-need-to-know-about-the-closing-process.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Advantages of a Home Inspection</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ndEorE1AwNE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every buyer should have a home inspection done on the home they plan to purchase. However, not all inspectors are created the same. You need to know that you are dealing with a reputable inspector, so we have some tips to share today to help you do just that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, let’s talk about how you should go about finding a home inspector. Your best resource is going to be the real estate agent or team you are working with. They should have a short list of inspectors who they have worked with, like, and trust that they can provide you. &lt;strong&gt;We always give our clients at least three different names of inspectors so they can have options and figure out which is best for them.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=An inspection is necessary for every home purchase.%20http://mcintoshrealtyblog.com/the-advantages-of-a-home-inspection.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“An inspection is necessary for every home purchase.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inspector you choose should be licensed, first and foremost. To be able to ask for repairs from the seller at a later date, the inspection must be done by a licensed inspector. We also recommend that you choose an inspector that has errors and omissions insurance. This is a type of insurance that covers inspectors in case there was a defect in the home that they missed during their inspection. &lt;strong&gt;This doesn’t happen often, but it does happen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inspection will be completed during the window of time after the home goes under contract called the due diligence period. If there are any specific repairs that need to be addressed, this gives you the opportunity to do that and renegotiate the deal. Oftentimes, the price can be adjusted as well. &lt;strong&gt;In some rare cases, you may want to eliminate the contract&lt;/strong&gt;. You can do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We always recommend a home inspection for any buyer. It doesn’t make sense to skip it. If you have any questions for us or need a recommendation for a good home inspector in Savannah, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://mcintoshrealtyblog.com/the-advantages-of-a-home-inspection.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mcintoshrealtyblog.com/the-advantages-of-a-home-inspection.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Avoid These 5 Mistakes When Doing an Online Home Search</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/IEP3-OQhKYk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are five mistakes homebuyers make when searching for homes online that you need to avoid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first is &lt;strong&gt;using an agent simply based on a phone call from an inquiry you may have made online or on a search site.&lt;/strong&gt; When using a home search engine such as Zillow, Trulia, or Realtor.com, if you ask a question about a particular home or click that you’re interested in that home, you’ll receive a call from a real estate agent. Don’t make a decision based exclusively on that phone call. Interview several agents and use someone who has your best interests in mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second mistake is &lt;strong&gt;trusting values from home valuation sites.&lt;/strong&gt; For example, Zillow has a tool on their site called a Zestimate. If someone’s looking at values in a particular neighborhood or they want to refinance their house, they’ll type in the address of a property and get back a Zestimate. The problem is Zillow is only using other homes within a particular radius and averaging those values together to formulate that Zestimate. It doesn’t have the ability to see what has sold in that neighborhood or know certain characteristics of a home that affect its value, like if it has an updated garage. To obtain an accurate value of a home, reach out to a real estate professional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third mistake is &lt;strong&gt;shopping for a home on inaccurate sites.&lt;/strong&gt; By “inaccurate,” I mean that sometimes the bigger real estate search engines won’t update their sites as often as real estate professionals update theirs. This leads to buyers finding a home they like on one of these sites only to find out that it’s already under contract or it sold several weeks earlier. Make sure you search for a home on a website that offers real-time information so you don’t get your heart set on something that may no longer be available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=To obtain an accurate home value, reach out to a real estate professional.%20http://mcintoshrealtyblog.com/avoid-these-5-mistakes-when-doing-an-online-home-search.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“To obtain an accurate home value, reach out to a real estate professional.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fourth mistake is &lt;strong&gt;using online mortgage calculators to obtain a potential payment on a house.&lt;/strong&gt; While these are great tools to get an idea on a payment for a house, you should know that these calculators are only giving you payments based on principal and interest. There are other factors to consider, such as escrow payments, that get figured into what a real payment looks like. If your home is located in a flood zone, for example, that too would be figured into the monthly payment. Always talk to your local lender to get an accurate idea of what your mortgage will look like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fifth and final mistake is &lt;strong&gt;acquiring a mortgage through an Internet lender.&lt;/strong&gt; We encourage you to work with a local lender whenever possible because they usually use local appraisers that know our market. Out-of-town lenders or Internet lenders tend to use appraisers who are unfamiliar with our neighborhoods and values, and that can complicate the loan process significantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about shopping for homes online or you have a topic in mind you’d like us to share in the future, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We look forward to talking with you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://mcintoshrealtyblog.com/avoid-these-5-mistakes-when-doing-an-online-home-search.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mcintoshrealtyblog.com/avoid-these-5-mistakes-when-doing-an-online-home-search.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Much Do I Need for a Down Payment?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/sAYBV_zP_30?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many potential homeowners and renters think that they need a large amount of money in order to make a down payment on a home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In fact, 87% of non-homeowners think that you need a minimum of 10% down,&lt;/strong&gt; which is not always the case. There are lots of different loan programs out there. Depending on where you are looking to buy, you can get a home for 5% or 0% down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Speak with a local lender to figure out what your options are.%20http://mcintoshrealtyblog.com/how-much-do-i-need-for-a-down-payment.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Speak with a local lender to figure out what your options are.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in buying a home, I recommend that you speak with a local lender. Local lenders know the options available in the area and generally are better at communicating than national or online lenders. Your lender will help you know which programs are available to you, and you may be surprised at how little of a down payment is required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we’re talking about the lending process, I’d like to mention that now is a great time to buy a home. Overall, interest rates are still low, and our market has certainly stabilized, so there’s not as much risk from a value standpoint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Again, talk to a local lender so that you know what your mortgage options are going forward.&lt;/strong&gt; If you have any other questions about buying a home, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://mcintoshrealtyblog.com/how-much-do-i-need-for-a-down-payment.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mcintoshrealtyblog.com/how-much-do-i-need-for-a-down-payment.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Should You Have Your Own Representation When Buying?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ST0zF9-Nw1o?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re gearing up to purchase a home, it’s important that you are represented by an agent. This agent could represent you as either a customer or a client. &lt;strong&gt;The agent you want is the one who will represent you as a client.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re a client, the agent has your best interests at heart. They aren’t just looking at you as a number or someone they can provide a service for; they want to share their opinion, their expertise, and guide you through the process step by step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Always make sure your agent is included in the transaction. Sometimes buyers will go look at homes without their agent and jump the gun, so to speak. They will make an offer or write a contract with the seller’s agent and totally forget about the agent working on their behalf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Always make sure your agent is included in the transaction.%20http://mcintoshrealtyblog.com/why-should-you-have-your-own-representation-when-buying.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Always make sure your agent is included in the transaction.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to know that &lt;strong&gt;any agent on a yard sign who is showing a home to you is actually representing the seller.&lt;/strong&gt; They have their best interests in mind, not your own. You don’t want to hire that same person who is representing the seller. You want someone who can look out for your best interests instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you are working with an agent now or not, &lt;strong&gt;I encourage you to reach out to a few different agents to interview them for the job. &lt;/strong&gt;That’s how you’ll get the best results for your home sale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://mcintoshrealtyblog.com/why-should-you-have-your-own-representation-when-buying.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mcintoshrealtyblog.com/why-should-you-have-your-own-representation-when-buying.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Navigating Multiple Offers as a Buyer or Seller</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/1AgVrJSSMlU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A multiple offer situation occurs when more than one offer has been submitted on a piece of real estate that’s for sale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a seller, when you have a property that has multiple offers, there are certain things you should look for. One is the &lt;strong&gt;type of financing.&lt;/strong&gt; If one offer is a cash offer, that eliminates the possibility of complications that could occur with a buyer going through the mortgage loan process. You should also &lt;strong&gt;consider the closing date and the amount of due diligence time.&lt;/strong&gt; All of those things play a part in the actual makeup of an offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Oftentimes there are components of an offer that are actually more important to sellers than the sales price.%20http://mcintoshrealtyblog.com/navigating-multiple-offers-as-a-buyer-or-seller.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Oftentimes there are components of an offer that are actually more important to sellers than the sales price.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a buyer, if you find yourself competing against other offers, there are a few things you can do to make your offer stand out. Oftentimes there are components of an offer that are actually more important to sellers than the sales price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if a seller needs a quicker closing date, they might accept a lower price if an offer accommodates that. Cash offers are always very attractive as well. You ultimately want to &lt;strong&gt;make sure your agent communicates with the seller in order to find out what is most important to them&lt;/strong&gt; and what key factors should be present in your offer to make it the most attractive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about multiple offers or any other real estate questions, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://mcintoshrealtyblog.com/navigating-multiple-offers-as-a-buyer-or-seller.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mcintoshrealtyblog.com/navigating-multiple-offers-as-a-buyer-or-seller.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What You Need to Know About the Home Closing Process</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/hFw_Z4Q_oqg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What happens during the home closing process and what does that mean to you as a buyer or seller?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First of all, how long does the closing process actually take? &lt;/strong&gt;Unless a home is being purchased with cash, it takes an average of 30 to 40 days to close. If a home is being bought with cash, then the closing process may happen much faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, the lender will dictate how quickly the transaction will close. It’s essential that a buyer is pre-approved before they make an offer to a seller. A pre-approval does a couple of things. First, as a buyer, it strengthens your offer. The pre-approval shows that a lender has checked your credit report, verified your employment, and looked at your bank accounts. From the seller’s perspective, accepting a pre-qualified offer gives you more security and peace of mind because the buyer is more likely to close.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The lender dictates how long the closing process will take.%20http://mcintoshrealtyblog.com/what-you-need-to-know-about-the-home-closing-process.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The lender dictates how long the closing process will take.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should also know that real estate closings are usually handled by a real estate attorney. Before a house can close, all of the terms of the agreement have to be met. What does that mean? In a purchase contract, you may have a due diligence period, a home inspection, a termite inspection, or other obligations that need to be met before you can close on the house. If there are any lender-required repairs or negotiated repairs after the inspection, those must be completed before you close on the home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The due diligence period&lt;/strong&gt; is basically a window of time that allows the buyer to confirm that they want to move forward with the purchase of the house. During this time, all of the terms will be negotiated before you move forward with closing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, there can be delays during the closing process. For example, if the buyer incurs new debt or the appraisal comes in low, then closing will be delayed. If a lien or judgment on the title is discovered, that can also delay closing. A delay in closing must be agreed upon by the buyer and the seller before you can move forward with the closing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this topic or have another topic in mind you’d like to see us discuss in a future video, feel free to reach out to us. We’d be glad to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://mcintoshrealtyblog.com/what-you-need-to-know-about-the-home-closing-process.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mcintoshrealtyblog.com/what-you-need-to-know-about-the-home-closing-process.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Explaining the Ins and Outs of Counteroffers</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/PHog1d5hGfc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is a counteroffer and what role does it play in a potential real estate transaction?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Typically, a counteroffer is generated by a seller when a buyer presents an offer that has some items or terms that the seller does not agree with.&lt;/strong&gt; Items addressed by a counteroffer can include closing costs, the purchase price, the closing date, or particulars in the loan agreement, among other things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the seller is not the only party that can submit a counteroffer. A buyer can submit a counteroffer back to the seller and there are &lt;strong&gt;no limits on how many counteroffers can be presented until both parties agree.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Make sure all required signatures are present and the counteroffer is submitted before the expiration date.%20http://mcintoshrealtyblog.com/explaining-the-ins-and-outs-of-counteroffers.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Make sure all required signatures are present and the counteroffer is submitted before the expiration date.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a couple ways in which a counteroffer can be rejected. If you’re a buyer, your agent will let the seller’s agent know that there are still some items you are not in agreement with. You can then submit a counteroffer back to the seller. It works the same way if you’re the seller. The other way to reject a counteroffer is to &lt;strong&gt;let the time on it expire.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just like a purchase agreement or sales contract, there will be lines for everyone to sign on a counteroffer. A counteroffer has been officially accepted when all the required signatures are present. You want to make sure those signatures are present and the counteroffer is submitted before the expiration date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions, please feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://mcintoshrealtyblog.com/explaining-the-ins-and-outs-of-counteroffers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mcintoshrealtyblog.com/explaining-the-ins-and-outs-of-counteroffers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Tips to Help You Get the Home You Want in a Competitive Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/efbUSXeFW7A?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I want to share three tips to help you get the home you want in a competitive market like ours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first tip is to &lt;strong&gt;be informed and know the marketplace.&lt;/strong&gt; If there’s an area in town that you are interested in, there are probably a few social media sites you can join that will keep you updated on community events and neighborhood functions. This will give you a chance to meet some neighbors from that area and familiarize yourself with it. It’s also important to spend some time in the neighborhood you’re interested in. You could take a walk or drive through the area several times so you know it as well as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Getting pre-approved puts you in a much stronger position as a buyer.%20http://mcintoshrealtyblog.com/3-tips-to-help-you-get-the-home-you-want-in-a-competitive-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Getting pre-approved puts you in a much stronger position as a buyer.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second tip is to &lt;strong&gt;make sure you are pre-approved for a loan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; Being able to make an offer with a pre-approval letter puts you in a much stronger position than you would be if you made an offer without one. You don’t want to make an offer to a seller and leave them hanging on whether you’re pre-approved or not. When you speak to your lender, depending on the location of the home, remember that there are several different financing options or types of loans available to you. By knowing your loan options, you can greatly reduce the amount of money you put down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third and final tip is to &lt;strong&gt;communicate to your agent all of your must-haves in your prospective home.&lt;/strong&gt; Whether it’s a garage, a pool, or a single level, you need to let them know what you need. As Realtors, we’re constantly familiarizing ourselves with what’s on the market so we can present you with many options. Communicate what your needs are so we can be on the lookout on your behalf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking of buying or selling a home or have any questions you’d like to see us discuss in a future video, please feel free to reach out to us. We’d be happy to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://mcintoshrealtyblog.com/3-tips-to-help-you-get-the-home-you-want-in-a-competitive-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mcintoshrealtyblog.com/3-tips-to-help-you-get-the-home-you-want-in-a-competitive-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Navigate a Contingent Offer</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/SSsgBHbn8Io?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When selling a home, you might find yourself getting an offer with a contingency. Today I’ll go over what a contingency is and how to sell your home with one attached to an offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A contingency is when a buyer wants to buy your house, but they need to sell their home first in order to do so.&lt;/strong&gt; As a seller, there are a couple of things you need to look out for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If your home has been on the market for a while, an offer with a contingency could be a good option for you.&lt;/strong&gt;However, you need to make sure you have a timeline on the contingency so it doesn’t turn out to be a long, drawn-out process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A contingent offer can benefit both the buyer and the seller.%20http://mcintoshrealtyblog.com/how-to-navigate-a-contingent-offer.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A contingent offer can benefit both the buyer and the seller.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can also add something called a “kick out” clause.&lt;/strong&gt; That clause would allow you to keep your home active, and the original purchaser with the contingency would have a certain amount of time to decide if they want to go through with the sale before you could accept another offer. If the buyer backs out, you would give them back their earnest money and proceed with the new buyer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A contingency can benefit both the buyer and seller as long as you have a knowledgeable agent in place who is keeping everyone informed as to what is going on throughout the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions please don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 04:40:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://mcintoshrealtyblog.com/how-to-navigate-a-contingent-offer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mcintoshrealtyblog.com/how-to-navigate-a-contingent-offer.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
