<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from RE/MAX Professionals - your professional Glendale Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 15:26:28 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 15:26:28 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Is It Time for You to Downsize?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/JYxn59E0RuA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I want to go over the subject of downsizing. Ask yourself this: What is the right size for the next 10 years of your life?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looking to buy a home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.natemartinezteam.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search All Homes&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Looking to sell a home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.natemartinezteam.com/home-valuation/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a FREE Home Value Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many people in our country reaching retirement each day. A significant number of these people have homes that are much larger than they need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help people determine whether it’s time to downsize or not, I like to ask the question, &lt;strong&gt;“What is the right size for the next 10 years of your life?”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a lot to think about and discuss on the subject of rightsizing, which is why I’d like for you to join us for our next seminar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This upcoming event will take place on November 15th at the Arrowhead Country Club,&lt;/strong&gt; and I hope to see you there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=IS ALL THAT EXTRA SPACE TRULY NECESSARY?%20localhost:4000/is-it-time-for-you-to-downsize.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“IS ALL THAT EXTRA SPACE TRULY NECESSARY?”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing to think about when you’re considering downsizing is the size of your current home and how that size affects its maintenance. Once the kids are out of the house, is all that extra space truly necessary?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My team and I can help you determine what your options are moving into the future. Whether you choose to live in an active adult community or simply wish to move into a smaller home, you can learn more about your options at our seminar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An attorney, title person, stager, professional photographer, and myself will all be present and ready to help.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 13:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/is-it-time-for-you-to-downsize.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/is-it-time-for-you-to-downsize.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Hasnt Your Home Sold Yet?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/V9Zr93EJQ6U?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Selling your home isn’t easy, but we can make it easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looking to buy a home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.natemartinezteam.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search All Homes&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Looking to sell a home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.natemartinezteam.com/home-valuation/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a FREE Home Value Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you know that 14,904 homes sold yesterday in this country? If your house is on the market and wasn’t one of those sales you need to be asking, “Why not?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This data comes straight from the National Association of Realtors. &lt;strong&gt;With 14,904 home sales on average each day, there are plenty of opportunities out there.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over my 31 years of experience, I’ve realized that whether your home sells or not isn’t because of a bad location or in poor condition. It’s the price. It always comes down to the price. Marketing will help a home sell faster, but the best marketing in the world won’t sell an overpriced listing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=IF YOUR HOME ISN’T SELLING, CHECK THE PRICE FIRST.%20localhost:4000/why-hasnt-your-home-sold-yet.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“IF YOUR HOME ISN’T SELLING, CHECK THE PRICE FIRST.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Last year in Maricopa County, there were 88,000 home sales.&lt;/strong&gt; With over 35,000 Realtors in the Valley, that means each of them only sold two on average. Our team doesn’t settle for average. Our agents average 24 home sales per year, ranking us #1 in Arizona and in the top 50 nationwide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have many great ideas about how to sell your home but if your home isn’t selling, the first thing you should look at and the first thing we will look at is its price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for us or need help properly pricing your home, don’t hesitate to reach out and give us a call or send us an email. We would love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 16:13:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/why-hasnt-your-home-sold-yet.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/why-hasnt-your-home-sold-yet.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title> Does It Really Matter Which Realtor You Hire?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ybQOm4xr4vY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hiring the right Realtor makes a big difference in the success of your home sale or home purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looking to buy a home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.natemartinezteam.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search All Homes&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Looking to sell a home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.natemartinezteam.com/home-valuation/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a FREE Home Value Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does it make a difference which Realtor you hire when you decide to buy or sell a house? &lt;strong&gt;Absolutely.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, there are more than 37,000 Realtors right here in the Valley ready  to serve you.There are more than 4,200 real estate offices, as well. Last year, 88,000 homes sold in the Valley, and that was done by our own real estate population. If you do the math, that’s only an average of 2.4 transactions per agent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=WHEN YOU’RE SEARCHING FOR A REALTOR, MAKE SURE YOU’RE LOOKING FOR THE BEST IN YOUR AREA.%20localhost:4000/does-it-really-matter-which-realtor-you.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“WHEN YOU’RE SEARCHING FOR A REALTOR, MAKE SURE YOU’RE LOOKING FOR THE BEST IN YOUR AREA.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about it—if you were to hire a surgeon to perform an operation on someone you love, would you select one who does a couple operations a year or one who does hundreds?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my 31 years as a Realtor, I’ve experienced many different types of transactions. Some of them are easy; some are very challenging. &lt;strong&gt;Between each Realtor, there are also differences in their education level and commitment to the job.&lt;/strong&gt; I’ve been a full-time agent for all of my 31 years in the business, and I’ve helped more than 5,000 families buy or sell a house in the Valley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re searching for a Realtor, make sure you’re looking for the best in your area. If you have any questions about hiring the right Realtor or you’re considering buying or selling a home, please don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to helping you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 10:13:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/does-it-really-matter-which-realtor-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/does-it-really-matter-which-realtor-you.html</guid>
        
        <category>Nate Martinez Real Estate Agent</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Difference Between Pre-Approval and Pre-Qualification</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qkZOplsG4-w?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How well do you understand the difference between pre-approval and pre-qualification?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looking to buy a home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.natemartinezteam.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search All Homes&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Looking to sell a home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.natemartinezteam.com/home-valuation/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a FREE Home Value Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you know the difference between being pre-approved and pre-qualified?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s actually more simple than you might think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to pre-qualification, nothing has been truly verified. All it means is that you, the buyer, have spoken with a lender about your finances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=WITH A PRE-APPROVAL, EVERYTHING IS TAKEN CARE OF.%20localhost:4000/the-difference-between-pre-approval-and.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“WITH A PRE-APPROVAL, EVERYTHING IS TAKEN CARE OF.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things like income and debt will have been discussed at this point, and the lender will issue a pre-qualification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A pre-approval, however, is quite a bit more involved. &lt;strong&gt;When you are pre-qualified, credit and financial documentation has actually been pulled and looked into.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, the buyer’s done a full-blown credit report and have had their income verified. With a pre-approval, everything is taken care of and there’s no guesswork. If you have any questions about the difference between these two processes or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home in our market, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be glad to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 16:21:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/the-difference-between-pre-approval-and.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/the-difference-between-pre-approval-and.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Are the Benefits of a Home Warranty? </title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/FxqDnl2iCt8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When buying a house, I recommend very highly that you also get a home warranty. There are a couple of important reasons why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looking to buy a home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.natemartinezteam.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search All Homes&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Looking to sell a home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.natemartinezteam.com/home-valuation/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a FREE Home Value Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a home warranty in place is one of the most important aspects of buying a house, next to the home inspection. What are all the benefits of having a home warranty?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It guarantees you’ll be free and clear of any additional out-of-pocket costs for the next 12 months after you buy the house.&lt;/strong&gt; Many things can go wrong inside a house with all the plumbing, heating, cooling, air conditioning, and electrical systems. If something does go wrong, your warranty is there to protect you. For a $60 deductible, they’ll cover anything you want for that 12-month period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=YOU CAN KEEP YOUR HOME WARRANTY INDEFINITELY IF YOU LIKE.%20localhost:4000/what-are-benefits-of-home-warranty.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“YOU CAN KEEP YOUR HOME WARRANTY INDEFINITELY IF YOU LIKE.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Home warranties are renewable, so you can keep yours indefinitely if you like. They’ve helped many clients of mine over the years—both buyers and sellers. I also have home warranties on all the properties I own, and whenever something goes wrong, one quick call to the home warranty company saves the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you buy a house with us and we can’t get a home warranty negotiated in the purchase contract, we’ll buy one for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about the benefits of a home warranty or you’re thinking about buying or selling a home, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 09:59:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/what-are-benefits-of-home-warranty.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/what-are-benefits-of-home-warranty.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Reasons a Home Warranty Is Important</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/QkS4kfYnOm4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you list with us, we offer a home warranty free for six months. There are a few reasons why having a home warranty is important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looking to buy a home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.natemartinezteam.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search All Homes&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Looking to sell a home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.natemartinezteam.com/home-valuation/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a FREE Home Value Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When listing your house, there are a few reasons I recommend you get a home warranty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the primary reasons I recommend this is because when you list your house with us, you get free coverage for the first six months of warranty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do this so that if anything happens, you won’t have to worry. Having a home warranty isn’t just a good preventative measure, though— &lt;strong&gt;it also helps with the inspection process.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you have a home inspection company come in to examine the items on your property prior to a buyer seeing the home, you’ll be able to fix any issues on your own terms. If you catch problems before a buyer is able to find them themselves, the process becomes much easier and can often be less costly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=IF YOU HAVE A WARRANTY AND ANYTHING BREAKS IN YOUR HOME, YOU’LL ONLY PAY A SMALL DEDUCTIBLE.%20localhost:4000/reasons-home-warranty-is-important.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“IF YOU HAVE A WARRANTY AND ANYTHING BREAKS IN YOUR HOME, YOU’LL ONLY PAY A SMALL DEDUCTIBLE.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another good reason to have a warranty is because we advertise to the buyer that there will be a year of warranty in place at close of escrow. This offer gives buyers a sense of assuredness. It lets them feel confident that they will be able to enter your property without fear of problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, if you have a warranty and anything does break in your home, you’re only going to pay a small $59 deductible to have it repaired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, let’s say the compressor on your air conditioning suddenly stopped working. With as hot as our summers are, that sort of issue would be a pain both physically and financially. Without a home warranty, &lt;strong&gt;that kind of repair could cost thousands.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 13:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/reasons-home-warranty-is-important.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/reasons-home-warranty-is-important.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Seller's Guide to Multiple-Offer Situations</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/HXIg0AdIz9w?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the seller in a multiple-offer situation, you are ultimately in control. Here’s what you need to know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looking to buy a home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.natemartinezteam.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search All Homes&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Looking to sell a home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.natemartinezteam.com/home-valuation/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a FREE Home Value Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few things that sellers need to know about handling multiple-offer situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When your property receives multiple offers there’s no doubt that you are ultimately in control.&lt;/strong&gt; However, there are still some important steps to follow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First off, your agent should be contacting the buyers’ lenders to make sure that their finances are in order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Make sure that you are looking only at the strongest buyers%20localhost:4000/a-sellers-guide-to-multiple-offer.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Make sure that you are looking only at the strongest buyers”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will make sure that you are looking only at the strongest buyers, who will be able to close on time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using a multiple counter offer sets each buyer on a different stage. Ideally a buyer’s offer should meet your goals as well as theirs. You should also remember the following tips in your multiple counter offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Go with the buyer who puts the most amount of earnest money down,&lt;/strong&gt; shorten the period for the response time, and also remove any contingencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want any more information or have any other questions, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 12:56:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/a-sellers-guide-to-multiple-offer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/a-sellers-guide-to-multiple-offer.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Ways to Get Your Offer Accepted</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/D-BWoPq2DXQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting an offer accepted in this market isn’t easy. Here are three ways you can help your offer stand out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looking to buy a home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.natemartinezteam.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search All Homes&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Looking to sell a home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.natemartinezteam.com/home-valuation/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a FREE Home Value Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In today’s market we are finding that sellers are consistently receiving multiple offers. When this happens, the sellers are going to have the luxury of choosing the offer that meets their needs. That’s an important thing to remember when making an offer yourself. &lt;strong&gt;Here are three ways to make sure your next offer meets the seller’s needs:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Get pre-approved.&lt;/strong&gt; This shows the sellers that you are serious about buying. It also allows you to quickly make an offer once you find a home because you are already approved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A PRE-APPROVAL SHOWS YOU ARE SERIOUS.%20localhost:4000/3-ways-to-get-your-offer-accepted.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A PRE-APPROVAL SHOWS YOU ARE SERIOUS.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Write a good offer.&lt;/strong&gt; Expect to pay full price or better to win in this market. Limit that inspection time, increase your earnest money deposit, and be confident that it’s the strongest offer possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Write a letter to the seller.&lt;/strong&gt; If you write a compelling letter to the seller that tells them why you love the house so much, it can create an emotional connection. If you’re neck and neck against another buyer, this could be enough to put you over the edge. Recently, one of our buyers won out in a multiple offer situation with the help of a custom video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions for us, don’t hesitate to reach out and give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 14:42:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/3-ways-to-get-your-offer-accepted.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/3-ways-to-get-your-offer-accepted.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Are the Pitfalls of Pricing Your Home Too High?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/A2fM5994iXk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overpricing your home can cause you a lot of headaches as a home seller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looking to buy a home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.natemartinezteam.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search All Homes&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Looking to sell a home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.natemartinezteam.com/home-valuation/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a FREE Home Value Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a home seller, pricing your home too high can cause major pitfalls for your sale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest challenges you’ll come across if you do this is &lt;strong&gt;your home will spend a longer time on the market.&lt;/strong&gt; In a hot market, homes usually sell in a matter of weeks, so if a house has been listed for a period of 30 to 60 days or longer, buyers will start to wonder what’s wrong with it. At that point, they’ll come in with an extremely low offer to offset your days on market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=PRICING YOUR PROPERTY PROPERLY IS CRITICAL AS A HOME SELLER.%20localhost:4000/what-are-pitfalls-of-pricing-your-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“PRICING YOUR PROPERTY PROPERLY IS CRITICAL AS A HOME SELLER.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Realtors will also use your overpriced home to justify the value of other listings in the community. The last thing you want for your home is for it to be the one that causes other homes in your neighborhood to sell quickly and for top dollar. This is why properly pricing your property is critical as a home seller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about how to price your home or any other real estate topic, don’t hesitate to give me a call or shoot me an email. I’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 14:03:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/what-are-pitfalls-of-pricing-your-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/what-are-pitfalls-of-pricing-your-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dont Skip the Home Inspection</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/modf5Kojonw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why should you have a home inspection before closing a property?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looking to buy a home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.natemartinezteam.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search All Homes&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Looking to sell a home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.natemartinezteam.com/home-valuation/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a FREE Home Value Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Home inspections are one of the most important parts of buying a house. There are many reasons why, but the most important is to look for any deal killers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your inspector will focus on things like mold, a leaky roof, or plumbing problems. You don’t want to waste your time negotiating for cosmetic issues like dings on the wall. The home inspection is done to &lt;strong&gt;unveil any issues that would cost you tens of thousands of dollars&lt;/strong&gt; in repairs after closing on the home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you hire a home inspector, make sure that they have a lot of experience. Ideally, your inspector will carry some type of liability insurance, as well as omission insurance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=THE HOME INSPECTION REVEALS ANY MAJOR ISSUES WITH THE HOME BEFORE YOU BECOME THE OWNER.%20localhost:4000/dont-skip-home-inspection.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“THE HOME INSPECTION REVEALS ANY MAJOR ISSUES WITH THE HOME BEFORE YOU BECOME THE OWNER.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Home inspections are a big part of the real estate transaction. In Arizona, you have 10 days from the time your contract is accepted to complete the inspection. Once the inspection is complete, the seller has five days to respond to any of your repair requests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your home inspection reveals too many deal killers or the seller is not willing to negotiate, you also have the option to &lt;strong&gt;walk away from the deal.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you are buying a resale property or a new construction property, I absolutely recommend that you hire a home inspector. I’ll explain more about home inspections on new homes later. In the meantime, if you have any questions, please don’t hesitate to give me a call. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 13:51:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/dont-skip-home-inspection.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/dont-skip-home-inspection.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
