<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>Our mission at SC Homes and Land Realty is to be your best resource for Midlands of South Carolina real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The SC Homes and Land Realty, your professional Midlands of South Carolina Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 11:12:49 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 11:12:49 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How a Beautiful Yard Can Impact Your Listing</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0q_dG1Y8-go?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are thinking of selling your home sometime in the future, there are certain things you can do ahead of time to make your property shine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buying a Columbia Home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all Homes for Sale&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Selling a Columbia Home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Check out our FREE Home Value Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are preparing to list your home, there are several things you can do to improve the value of your home. We all know that &lt;strong&gt;a beautiful house sells faster and for money.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Certain things like painting can have a big impact on your home in very little time. But one thing people tend to forget about is the yard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A beautiful yard is just as important as a beautiful home. Unlike the quick fixes of fresh paint or new countertops, a great yard can’t happen overnight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making your yard shine is going to take time and effort. Still, &lt;strong&gt;if you take the time to mow, water, and weed your yard regularly, you are going to be left with some serious curb appeal.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s an old saying in real estate: The outside gets them in, and the inside sells them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0q_dG1Y8-go?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you put consistent effort into your home and yard long before you’re ready to sell, you will be much more prepared when it comes time to list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 09:38:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-beautiful-yard-can-impact-your.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/how-beautiful-yard-can-impact-your.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Being Local Makes a Difference in Real Estate</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/r2de1OIGs4s?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to real estate, the same thing doesn’t work in every area. Real estate is local, and it needs to be treated that way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buying a Columbia Home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all Homes for Sale&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Selling a Columbia Home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Check out our FREE Home Value Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I want to discuss the fact that real estate is local.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Real estate is widely different from other products and the way they’re sold. For example, if you’re selling a box of cereal, you can put it on shelves in Los Angeles and Columbia and it’s going to meet the exact same market demand in both places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t the case for real estate. Real estate is going up and seeing a lot of action right now, but this wasn’t always the case. A lot of agents in the recession were struggling to find work and were taking on part-time jobs as a way to supplement their income.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it’s worth mentioning that here on the Lance Woodley team, &lt;strong&gt;we actually doubled our business during that time.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we’re doing well, a lot of agents from outside of our area are coming in thinking that real estate here will be easy. However, real estate is never easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine you’ve got an agent from Greenville, Charleston, or even somewhere out of state. Now, they want to try moving into the Midlands to find work here. They may have done a good job in their previous markets, but real estate isn’t the same as other products. &lt;strong&gt;The same thing doesn’t work for every market.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=REAL ESTATE IS LOCAL.%20localhost:4000/how-being-local-makes-difference-in.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“REAL ESTATE IS LOCAL.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Real estate is local. If you are looking to complete a real estate transaction, it is absolutely essential that you work with a local expert who knows the nuances of the area. Someone can’t simply move somewhere and immediately expect to have the same knowledge as an agent who is truly local.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Lance Woodley team has been successfully selling real estate for over 25 years in this area.&lt;/strong&gt; If you want to sell fast and for top dollar, don’t be fooled by the new guy on the block. I highly recommend that you work with us and let us provide you with the best service possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 14:23:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-being-local-makes-difference-in.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/how-being-local-makes-difference-in.html</guid>
        
        <category>Columbia Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Downsize in 3 Easy Steps</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/SlU1si-F4Ok?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been getting a lot of questions about downsizing as of late. Here’s what you should know about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buying a Columbia Home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all Homes for Sale&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Selling a Columbia Home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Check out our FREE Home Value Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been getting a lot of questions lately about downsizing, so I wanted to offer some tips for any of you who are thinking of selling your big house and moving into something a bit more manageable. &lt;strong&gt;Here are the first three things you should do:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Make a plan.&lt;/strong&gt; We can help you with that. The difficult task here is going through all of your things and sorting them into what you’ll keep, what you’ll donate, and what you’ll throw away or get rid of. This is an important step because it plays a role in the size of the home you’re downsizing too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A GOOD AGENT MAKES THE PROCESS SO MUCH EASIER.%20localhost:4000/how-to-downsize-in-3-easy-steps.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A GOOD AGENT MAKES THE PROCESS SO MUCH EASIER.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Start searching.&lt;/strong&gt; Get a feel for what you want in a home, where you want to live, and more. There are homes, townhouses, and condos to choose from. The more you look, the better you’ll be able to tell what you like and don’t like. This will help you create an even better lifestyle moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Getting your home ready.&lt;/strong&gt; This is where a good agent can really help. You want to get the most out of your existing home sale, right? The best way to do that is by looking at your home and determining if there is any work that needs to be done before listing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;These are just the first three steps to downsizing.&lt;/strong&gt; There are plenty more that come after. If you have any questions for me about downsizing or anything else relating to real estate, give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 15:07:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-to-downsize-in-3-easy-steps.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/how-to-downsize-in-3-easy-steps.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rules and Regulations that Affect Construction and Renovation</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/agbubvz8x68?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should investors be able to renovate homes they purchase in historic areas? I think so, but what’s your opinion?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buying a Columbia Home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all Homes for Sale&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Selling a Columbia Home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Check out our FREE Home Value Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An interesting thing has been happening in our real estate market lately. The city of Columbia has started putting historic overlays on certain neighborhoods that we haven’t been able to fully understand. The historic overlays prevent homeowners from improving or renovating their homes, even in the most basic ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In fact, I know of an investor who wasn’t even allowed to replace broken windows with rotting wood.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, after selling thousands of new and renovated homes, property owners should have rights and one of those rights should be to repair their home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see in the video above, a lot of these properties are in very poor condition. They say this kind of home is “An example of a minimalist style that we don’t want to lose”, &lt;strong&gt;but I see it differently.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=ONE PROPERTY IS BRINGING ALL OTHER VALUES DOWN.%20localhost:4000/rules-and-regulations-that-affect.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“ONE PROPERTY IS BRINGING ALL OTHER VALUES DOWN.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact is that for most of the homes in this neighborhood, this property represents potential. In its current condition, however, not so much. The poor condition of the home is bringing down the values of all the other bigger, nicer homes in the neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wouldn’t it be better if the owner of this home was allowed to tear this shack down and build a new home? Or at least renovate the home to an acceptable condition?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to know what your opinion is in the comment section below. Should the government have a say in what property owners can and can’t do to their homes? &lt;strong&gt;You already know my opinion. What is yours?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions for me, don’t hesitate to reach out. I would love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 12:47:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/rules-and-regulations-that-affect.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/rules-and-regulations-that-affect.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Buy a Bigger Home Without Increasing Your Payment</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wmgCjZw8-C0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now is a great time to move up into a new home. If you have a lot of equity, you can actually secure a lower monthly payment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buying a Columbia Home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all Homes for Sale&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Selling a Columbia Home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Check out our FREE Home Value Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of people want to move up into a bigger, nicer house in a better neighborhood. Maybe they want a great view, like a golf course or a lake. It can be difficult to make the numbers work. However, with the latest market increase, if you’ve been in your home for a few years you may have more equity than you think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In fact, you might have enough equity to be able to get that new home in a nicer area while keeping the same monthly payment.&lt;/strong&gt; If you sell your home with our advice and take the equity you’ve earned to apply as a down payment on your new home, you will see a ton of savings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=THE WINDOW OF OPPORTUNITY IS CLOSING.%20localhost:4000/buy-bigger-home-without-increasing-your.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“THE WINDOW OF OPPORTUNITY IS CLOSING.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll be able to get a lower interest rate, and if you’re able to put more than 20% down with your equity, you won’t have to pay mortgage insurance either. &lt;strong&gt;Your payment will drop and it might even cost you less than what you are paying right now.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The window of opportunity to take advantage is closing. If you have any questions or want to know more about how you can move up easily in this market, give us a call or send us an email. We would love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2017 11:59:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/buy-bigger-home-without-increasing-your.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/buy-bigger-home-without-increasing-your.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2017 Quarter One Market Update</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/f1yULK2Jnz0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I wanted to update you on the state of the real estate market in the Midlands and how our first quarter turned out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve got good news. The market continues to improve, and today I want to give you some statistics from the first quarter of 2017 for you to think about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time last year, in the first quarter from the 1st of January to the end of March, 2,423 houses went on the market and sold. This year, the number of properties sold in the first quarter jumped up to 2,663. This is an almost 10% increase in volume.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Homes have also sold quicker this quarter than the same time last year.&lt;/strong&gt; We’re seeing a 10% decrease in the time it takes for a home to sell this year, which is great for our market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MORE HOUSES ARE SELLING AT HIGHER PRICES, AND THEY ARE SELLING CLOSER TO THE ASKING PRICE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Home prices have also gone up in the Midlands this quarter compared to the first quarter of 2016. This time last year, houses were listed for an average of $179,482. This year, the average home price has gone up to $182,332. This 1.6% increase seems small, but it is a sign that the market is going in the right direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve also noticed that the “negotiable factor,” or the amount that the average seller has to discount in a negotiation, has seen a bit of a shift as well. Last year, sellers were getting 96.75% of their list price on average. This year that average has gone up to 97.07%, which is pretty great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More houses are selling at higher prices, and they are selling closer to the asking price. This all good news — &lt;strong&gt;we are going in the right direction.&lt;/strong&gt; The Midlands is not only a great place to live, but real estate in the Midlands is a good investment as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other real estate questions or you’re looking to buy or sell a home, please don’t hesitate to reach out. I’d be happy to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 15:54:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/2017-quarter-one-market-update.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/2017-quarter-one-market-update.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How We Can Help You Buy or Sell Anywhere in the Country</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/m7mZ-kROp4c?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re part of a network of top agents that spans the entire country so we can help buyers and sellers in any area reach their goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you know, our team covers the whole Midlands in South Carolina, so we can help anyone in that area buy and sell their homes effectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=OUR ABILITY TO HELP YOU SPANS BOTH COASTS.%20localhost:4000/how-we-can-help-you-buy-or-sell.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“OUR ABILITY TO HELP YOU SPANS BOTH COASTS.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there’s something else you should know about us. &lt;strong&gt;We’re also part of a countrywide network of agents who are the No.1 or No. 2 ranked agents in their area.&lt;/strong&gt; This means if you’re moving to another area of the country or you know someone in another part of the country that needs to buy or sell a home, you can give us a call and we’d be able to recommend you to the top agent in that area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will help you get the best results possible in your real estate endeavors. If you have any questions, please don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d be glad to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 14:41:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-we-can-help-you-buy-or-sell.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/how-we-can-help-you-buy-or-sell.html</guid>
        
        <category>Columbia Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Our Service Is Even Better Than Youve Heard</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/1IPsYgN0om4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to our service, we list a wide variety of price ranges and charge competitively with 95% of the other agents in our area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I want to answer a couple frequently asked questions about our service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first has to do with the price ranges of the houses we sell. We’re known for marketing and selling homes in the higher price ranges, but &lt;strong&gt;we list a wide variety of price ranges.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=WE’RE HERE TO SELL REAL ESTATE.%20localhost:4000/why-our-service-is-even-better-than.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“WE’RE HERE TO SELL REAL ESTATE.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll list homes from $80,000 to $90,000 all the way up to $1 million or more. Our home selling system is proven, duplicatable, and backed by market research so it can be applied to all price ranges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second question has to do with how much our service costs. A lot of people assume that because we do so much marketing and sell so many houses, we automatically charge a high percentage rate. That’s not true — &lt;strong&gt;our rate is very competitive.&lt;/strong&gt; In fact, it’s the same rate you would get with 95% of the other agents in the area. Rates are not set by law—they’re negotiable and set by the companies. There is no extra charge to get the Lance Woodley Team on your side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you or someone you know has a home to sell, give us a call today. We’re ready to sell your home.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 15:59:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/why-our-service-is-even-better-than.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/why-our-service-is-even-better-than.html</guid>
        
        <category>Columbia Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dont Miss Our New Ad Airing Soon on NBC!</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/QNrTClt_BfQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m proud to announce that we’ve shot a new commercial that’s now airing on NBC&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you follow my video blog, you know that my team and I are the best in the business at selling homes. We try to help as many people as we can with their real estate needs, so today I’m proud to announce that we’ve shot a new commercial that’s now airing on NBC, and I wanted to give you a sneak peek at it. If you have any real estate questions or are looking to buy or sell a home, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. In the meantime, to get a glimpse of our spot on NBC, watch this short video.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 15:18:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/dont-miss-our-new-ad-airing-soon-on-nbc.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/dont-miss-our-new-ad-airing-soon-on-nbc.html</guid>
        
        <category>Columbia Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Tax Benefits &amp; Deductions You Only Get as a Homeowner</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/JUGpcn7mqck?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tax season is here, so today we’ve got a quick guide on how to reduce your taxable income if you’re a homeowner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s that time of year again—tax time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One of the biggest advantages of being a homeowner is that you can use part of what you pay for your home to reduce your taxable income.&lt;/strong&gt; This holds true for first-time homebuyers or anyone who owns a home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you bought a home in 2016, there’s a one-time deduction you can take for the costs incurred when buying the house. This includes closing costs, banking fees, and interim interest to name a few. There are also ongoing deductions you can deduct year after year as long as you own the house. These include mortgage interest and property taxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=WE RECENTLY HAD A CLIENT WHO SAVED $2,400 A YEAR BY BECOMING A HOMEOWNER.%20localhost:4000/the-tax-benefits-deductions-you-only.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“WE RECENTLY HAD A CLIENT WHO SAVED $2,400 A YEAR BY BECOMING A HOMEOWNER.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These deductions can combine with your other deductions to decrease your overall tax burden. In fact, &lt;strong&gt;a recent client of ours saved $2,400 a year in taxes by being a homeowner that he wouldn’t have been able to take advantage of as a renter.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking about buying a home, we would love to help you reap all the benefits of home ownership. Just give us a call or send us an email and we can discuss your unique situation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 12:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/the-tax-benefits-deductions-you-only.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/the-tax-benefits-deductions-you-only.html</guid>
        
        <category>Columbia Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
