<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from RE/MAX Professionals - your professional Glendale Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 13:22:04 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 13:22:04 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How We Plan on Donating $100,000 to Charity in 2017</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/yUGyQOnxw0g?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I want to talk to you about charitable contributions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past 25 years, I’ve had the great pleasure being able to donate a portion of our team’s earned commissions to the Phoenix Children’s Hospital. Our office is involved in a lot of different charities—each agent has their own pet charity, if you will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the Phoenix Children’s Hospital, we’ve gotten involved in the last year with a group called One Life Fully Lived, which is a group that reaches out to young adults and high school-aged kids in an effort to give them some guidance on their futures. We’re also a contributor to the Singleton Moms Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=THIS YEAR, OUR GOAL IS TO GIVE BACK.%20localhost:4000/how-we-plan-on-donating-100000-to.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“THIS YEAR, OUR GOAL IS TO GIVE BACK.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of our initiatives in 2017 is to give back. My goal is to donate $100,000 to charities. Instead of us picking a charity that we think is good to donate to, we will ask our sellers which charities they’re fond of and make donations to those charities in our clients’ names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or you know some worthwhile charities that could use some help, please don’t hesitate to reach out to me. We’d love to speak with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 13:33:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-we-plan-on-donating-100000-to.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/how-we-plan-on-donating-100000-to.html</guid>
        
        <category>Nate Martinez Real Estate Agent</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dont Wait Any Longer to Sell Your Home in 2017</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/IcFCPuP7rBo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been thinking about selling your house, I have four reasons why you should absolutely do it in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first reason you should sell your home right now is that mortgage rates are still low. Today, rates are at around 4%, but the NAR, Zillow, and other publications have stated that interest rates will probably climb to about 5% by the end of the year. With interest rates currently low, buyers can afford more house, which puts you in a better position to sell your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, inventory is low and buyer demand is high. This combination of supply and demand provokes multiple offers on homes, which is great news for the seller as multiple offers result in top dollar for their home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=WITH INTEREST RATES CURRENTLY LOW, BUYERS CAN AFFORD MORE HOUSE, WHICH PUTS YOU IN A BETTER POSITION TO SELL YOUR HOME.%20localhost:4000/dont-wait-any-longer-to-sell-your-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“WITH INTEREST RATES CURRENTLY LOW, BUYERS CAN AFFORD MORE HOUSE, WHICH PUTS YOU IN A BETTER POSITION TO SELL YOUR HOME.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third, home prices have gone up. Over the last year, the NAR stated that homes prices rose by 6.8%. High home prices combined with low inventory creates a perfect storm for sellers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, the job market is improving nationwide, which means the economy is improving. This in turn is causing people to feel more comfortable making bigger purchases such as cars and homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about the four reasons you should sell your home in 2017 or have any other real estate-related questions, please feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 14:36:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/dont-wait-any-longer-to-sell-your-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/dont-wait-any-longer-to-sell-your-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Great Opportunity for Local Business Owners</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wmXHM6cr--I?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a local business owner, I’d like to help you out by getting you more customers. I’ve been in the real estate business for over 30 years and have helped over 6,000 people buy a house in the Northwest Valley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a large database of great past clients, I’d like to see if I can connect them to your business to help it grow. I’d love to sit down for breakfast, lunch, or coffee with you and learn a little bit more about you and your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it seems like a good fit, I’ll put your business in the referral directory I send out to all my past clients. I can then refer them to use your services and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=IF IT’S A GOOD FIT, I’LL PUT YOUR BUSINESS IN MY REFERRAL DIRECTORY.%20localhost:4000/a-great-opportunity-for-local-business.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“IF IT’S A GOOD FIT, I’LL PUT YOUR BUSINESS IN MY REFERRAL DIRECTORY.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my goals in 2017 is to have a deeper connection with all of you and make you part of my life by helping you grow your business. If you have any questions for me or you’d like to have lunch, don’t hesitate to reach out. Just give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 10:59:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/a-great-opportunity-for-local-business.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/a-great-opportunity-for-local-business.html</guid>
        
        <category>Nate Martinez Real Estate Agent</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Now Might Be a Better Time to Sell Than Spring</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/eSk1x4N5W2w?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: &amp;quot;arial&amp;quot; , &amp;quot;helvetica&amp;quot; , sans-serif;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Listing your home now might be a better idea than waiting until spring. Heres why.*&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: &amp;quot;arial&amp;quot; , &amp;quot;helvetica&amp;quot; , sans-serif;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; 
&lt;/b&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: &amp;quot;arial&amp;quot; , &amp;quot;helvetica&amp;quot; , sans-serif;&quot;&gt;**Looking to buy a home? [Search All Homes](http://www.natemartinezteam.com/)**&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: &amp;quot;arial&amp;quot; , &amp;quot;helvetica&amp;quot; , sans-serif;&quot;&gt;**Looking to sell a home? [Get a FREE Home Value Report](http://www.natemartinezteam.com/home-valuation/)**&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: &amp;quot;arial&amp;quot; , &amp;quot;helvetica&amp;quot; , sans-serif;&quot;&gt; 
&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: &amp;quot;arial&amp;quot; , &amp;quot;helvetica&amp;quot; , sans-serif;&quot;&gt;Is now a better time to sell your house than waiting until spring? 
&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: &amp;quot;arial&amp;quot; , &amp;quot;helvetica&amp;quot; , sans-serif;&quot;&gt; 
&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: &amp;quot;arial&amp;quot; , &amp;quot;helvetica&amp;quot; , sans-serif;&quot;&gt;With the interest rate hike that we just witnessed, **buyers are entering the market now instead of waiting until spring to purchase a house.** Not only that, but our current inventory is extremely low, and the demand from buyers is extremely high. 
&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: &amp;quot;arial&amp;quot; , &amp;quot;helvetica&amp;quot; , sans-serif;&quot;&gt; 

&lt;div class=&quot;quote-box&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;quote-text&quot;&gt;Now is the right time to sell your house.      &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: &amp;quot;arial&amp;quot; , &amp;quot;helvetica&amp;quot; , sans-serif;&quot;&gt; 
&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: &amp;quot;arial&amp;quot; , &amp;quot;helvetica&amp;quot; , sans-serif;&quot;&gt;This makes our current market the perfect place to possibly get top dollar in a very short amount of time. 
&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: &amp;quot;arial&amp;quot; , &amp;quot;helvetica&amp;quot; , sans-serif;&quot;&gt; 
&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: &amp;quot;arial&amp;quot; , &amp;quot;helvetica&amp;quot; , sans-serif;&quot;&gt;If you have any questions about current interest rates or what our market inventory looks like, please feel free to reach out to me. Id be happy to speak with you! to speak with you! 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 15:07:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/why-now-might-be-better-time-to-sell.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/why-now-might-be-better-time-to-sell.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Impact of Rising Interest Rates in Our Phoenix Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/40Qd7l7riyg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s happening with rising interest rates in our current market?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In November, they were holding steady at 3.8%. That means if you borrowed $200,000 at that time, your monthly payment would have been roughly $931.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we move into the first quarter of 2017, prices have gone up. Interest rates have gone up as well. Hypothetically speaking, if the price goes up $10,000 on that $200,000 house and interest rates rise from 3.8% to 4.8%, your monthly payment would increase to $1,105. That’s $175 more you would have to pay each month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Federal Reserve tells us that we will probably see additional increases in rates this year, so the sooner you can jump into the market and buy a house, the better off you will be. This is because your purchasing power as a buyer diminishes as rates rise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=THE SOONER YOU CAN BUY A HOUSE, THE BETTER.%20localhost:4000/the-impact-of-rising-interest-rates-in.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“THE SOONER YOU CAN BUY A HOUSE, THE BETTER.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, at a 3.75% interest rate, your monthly payment for a $300,000 house would be $1,389. If that rate rises a quarter of a point, the amount you could qualify for drops by 2.5% to $292,500, and your monthly payment would increase to $1,396. If the rate rises a full percentage point, the amount you could qualify for drops by 10% to $270,000, and your monthly payment would increase to $1,408.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a certain point, we should see a leveling off of the increase in home prices we’ve been experiencing here in the Phoenix area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re in the market to buy or sell a home, please feel free to reach out to me by phone or email. I’d be happy to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2017 16:14:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/the-impact-of-rising-interest-rates-in.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/the-impact-of-rising-interest-rates-in.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
