<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Edina Realty - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://TheChadandSaraRealEstateBlog.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://TheChadandSaraRealEstateBlog.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 10:33:07 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 10:33:07 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Can Homebuyers Expect From Our Spring Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/IKNRD7ZXuSc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For our a look ahead at our spring market, we’ll focus separately on the Prior Lake Savage and Shakopee areas and talk about how inventory levels are shaking out in three distinct price ranges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first of those price ranges is the first-time buyer market, which typically represents homes priced up to $250,000. In both Prior Lake Savage and Shakopee, there is no new construction in this level of inventory. What’s really interesting, though, is that the number of active listings and the number of pending listings in both communities are identical. This tells us that though first-time  buyers may not be able to build a new home, the inventory that is coming on the market is moving at a nice clip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second price range is the move-up buyer market, which is roughly between $250,000 and $400,000. This market is slightly different in both Prior Lake Savage and Shakopee in that there is some new construction inventory. However, existing inventory tends to pend or sell faster in this range because move-up buyers look for value, and you can often find better value in the existing market where home features like decks, patios, gutters, and window treatments are already done for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;North of $400,000, it’s an entirely different ball game. There is a lot more pending inventory and an extensive amount of active inventory because there are fewer buyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Pay attention to prices as more inventory comes on the market.%20http://TheChadandSaraRealEstateBlog.com/what-can-homebuyers-expect-from-our-spring-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Pay attention to prices as more inventory comes on the market.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does this mean moving forward in 2018? It means &lt;strong&gt;first-time buyers will predominantly stick to existing inventory. &lt;/strong&gt;Above the $400,000 mark, there will be a lot of new construction inventory and existing inventory because we’re already in a low-inventory market in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Considering inventory levels are so low, make sure you make a smart buying decision if you are a homebuyer. &lt;strong&gt;By that we mean pay attention to prices as more inventory comes on the market during spring and summer&lt;/strong&gt; because they may get inflated. Also, remember that interest rates are still low and very competitive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, whatever you do, make sure you have an experienced agent on your side. If you have any questions about our market or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d be glad to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 08:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://TheChadandSaraRealEstateBlog.com/what-can-homebuyers-expect-from-our-spring-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://TheChadandSaraRealEstateBlog.com/what-can-homebuyers-expect-from-our-spring-market.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Do You Know What Your Home Is Worth?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/fGCKP6H9V1o?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is it important to get a look at your home’s current market value, and what are the benefits of knowing that information?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a good time of year for people to assess their current home. We can come out, take a look, and give you an idea of what your home’s value might be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People often like to ask us about what they can work on to improve the value of their home while maintaining the property and keeping it up to date. &lt;strong&gt;We can help determine what you need to do to keep your home in good condition.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if you’re not selling in the next couple of months—or the next couple of years—it’s good to have a baseline of the market value of your home so that you can make a decision based on its value in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=It’s important to know your market value because our market is constantly changing.%20http://TheChadandSaraRealEstateBlog.com/do-you-know-what-your-home-is-worth.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“It’s important to know your market value because our market is constantly changing.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also good to understand your market value because of all the changes that happen in our area. Our market sees a lot of new construction, commercial growth, and farms being bought and sold that may soon be developed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result of all this change, people want to know, “Is it a good time to sell? Are market values going up or down?” Knowing where your home currently sits in terms of market value will give you a sense of comfort, &lt;strong&gt;as well as an idea of what your future home sale could look like.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like a home valuation, or if you have any other questions, just give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 08:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://TheChadandSaraRealEstateBlog.com/do-you-know-what-your-home-is-worth.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://TheChadandSaraRealEstateBlog.com/do-you-know-what-your-home-is-worth.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Look at the Home Buying Process</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/LqsMiCtyfCg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we want to take a quick look at the home buying process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a first-time homebuyer, the first thing you need to do is have a conversation with us. &lt;strong&gt;We’ll talk about your wants and needs, the areas you’re looking at, and how we can get you into contact with a loan officer so that you can get pre-approved right off the bat.&lt;/strong&gt; This will answer a lot of initial questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=There are a lot of moving pieces, but we can help you work them out.%20http://TheChadandSaraRealEstateBlog.com/a-look-at-the-home-buying-process.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“There are a lot of moving pieces, but we can help you work them out.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re a homeowner who is going to be buying and selling a home at the same time, we have a bit of a different puzzle.&lt;/strong&gt; First, we’ve got to evaluate the equity in your current home. You may be able to qualify for a pre-approval before selling your current home. You might have to sell first in order to make an offer, however. That’s the puzzle we have to piece together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of moving pieces, but we can help you work them out. If you have any questions for us or if we can help you buy or sell a home in any way, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 05:20:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://TheChadandSaraRealEstateBlog.com/a-look-at-the-home-buying-process.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://TheChadandSaraRealEstateBlog.com/a-look-at-the-home-buying-process.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Happy Holidays From Our Team</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ol18g4EUVRo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would just like to wish you all a happy holiday season this year. If you’re traveling, we hope your journey is safe. Thank you to all of our clients and everyone who referred clients to us in 2017. If we can do anything for you in 2018, please let us know. To see our full holiday message, watch this short video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 08:40:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://TheChadandSaraRealEstateBlog.com/happy-holidays-from-our-team.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://TheChadandSaraRealEstateBlog.com/happy-holidays-from-our-team.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Should You Buy a Home During the Off-Peak Season?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/gsZccNvmIws?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When people think of buying a home, they often naturally gravitate towards the spring market. As a result, spring is a common time for buyers to enter the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, buyer traffic is very heavy in the springtime. In low inventory markets, some of our listings may get as many as 25 to 30 showings over the course of one weekend in the spring. As a buyer looking to buy a home, particularly a first home, it can be intimidating to buy a home in the spring. It may even feel hopeless at times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The benefit of trying the market in an off-peak season is &lt;strong&gt;that the buyer is able to explore what’s out there without all of the competition.&lt;/strong&gt; Shopping for a home in off-peak seasons like fall and winter also increases the likelihood that you will find a home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You will be able to explore your options without all of the competition.%20http://TheChadandSaraRealEstateBlog.com/why-should-you-buy-a-home-during-the-off-peak-season.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You will be able to explore your options without all of the competition.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are searching for a home this winter, we recommend that you get written verification from sellers regarding certain winterization projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all, the AC unit should be shut off and the sprinkler system should be winterized, which means the inspector won’t be able to test them in the winter. Just ask for the seller to &lt;strong&gt;confirm that those things were working before they were properly shut down in the fall.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about buying a home in the winter market, just give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 04:15:57 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://TheChadandSaraRealEstateBlog.com/why-should-you-buy-a-home-during-the-off-peak-season.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://TheChadandSaraRealEstateBlog.com/why-should-you-buy-a-home-during-the-off-peak-season.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What’s Happening in the Prior Lake/Savage/Shakopee Real Estate Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/C27dcgqYn7g?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s time for your fall real estate market update.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just like this past spring and summer, inventory is low across the board. The market did slow down in August as families wrapped up vacations and went back to school. That slowdown can often transition into early September, so we do see the market pick up again in late September, October, and into Thanksgiving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if you are thinking of buying or selling a home, &lt;strong&gt;the market is still active during this key part of the season.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’d also like to touch on some new construction development that’s been going on lately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you drive down County Road 42 in Prior Lake, you’ll see a lot of activity. Pulte Homes and Lennar Homes are clearing a lot of trees for new developments on the south side of 42. There will be single-family homes and townhomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The market does pick up again from late September.%20http://TheChadandSaraRealEstateBlog.com/whats-happening-in-the-prior-lakesavageshakopee-real-estate-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The market does pick up again from late September.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lennar and Summit Preserve will also be building single-family homes and townhomes. M/I Homes, formerly known as Hans Hagen, will also be building some properties around that 42 corridor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Shakopee on County Road 16, Lennar is also building a lot of homes. We’re talking hundreds of lots. Although there is a lot of building going on, those properties are not included in our current inventory numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next year though, you will see some big changes in inventory. There will be a lot of lots available and the market will be pretty competitive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of that said, this actually could be a very good time to look at buying or building a home. &lt;strong&gt;The fall season is still a good time to be in the market.&lt;/strong&gt; A lot of people are busy with their kids’ sports and activities. If that’s not taking up a lot of your time, then now is a good time to look at the homes that are available because you will have less competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about our current market, please don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 08:59:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://TheChadandSaraRealEstateBlog.com/whats-happening-in-the-prior-lakesavageshakopee-real-estate-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://TheChadandSaraRealEstateBlog.com/whats-happening-in-the-prior-lakesavageshakopee-real-estate-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Representation in a New Construction Transaction</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/sQUHRmPdiT0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two components to representation in a new construction transaction. The first is your representation during the actual purchase of the site of the new home. The second is when you have a home to sell in order to purchase a new construction home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you buy a new build site, it’s important to know that the agent at the model home represents the seller. In this case, the seller is the builder. It’s important that the consumer realizes that the agent represents the builder’s best interests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a buyer, if you want to make an offer on a new build property, working with a buyer’s agent can be very important. We’ve seen a lot of people fall in love with all of the beautiful, shiny things that new construction has to offer. In terms of resale, it’s important to work with an agent who works in the existing resale market to figure out what you can do to make the home of value to others in the future should you ever decide to sell it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, we often see people put stainless steel appliances and granite countertops above a third garage stall in terms of importance. If you’re building a $500,000 house, the third stall is just an expectation at that point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=An independent agent will represent your best interests over the builder’s.%20http://TheChadandSaraRealEstateBlog.com/representation-in-a-new-construction-transaction.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“An independent agent will represent your best interests over the builder’s.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second component of representation is when you are building a new home but have an existing home that you need to sell first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oftentimes, the builder won’t begin digging on your new home until you have your existing home under contract. Something to consider when evaluating which agent to sell your home is whether they are independent or work with the builder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An independent agent may have more of a voice for you in terms of your unique situation. They will work to get the best price possible for your home, as well as the best possible terms. An agent who works with the builder is focused on selling your existing home so that you can get into your new house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, whether you work with an independent agent or an agent attached to the builder depends on your unique situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about buying a new construction property, just give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 05:42:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://TheChadandSaraRealEstateBlog.com/representation-in-a-new-construction-transaction.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://TheChadandSaraRealEstateBlog.com/representation-in-a-new-construction-transaction.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Is Included in a Seller Disclosure Statement?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/USLobrmSNMY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here in the state of Minnesota, there are two types of seller disclosure statements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One is the seller’s property disclosure statement, also known as the full disclosure.&lt;/strong&gt; There is also an alternatives form, which is only used in certain circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually, though, a seller will use the full property disclosure statement. This is a very lengthy, 10-page document that goes through everything a prospective buyer will need to know about the condition of the property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The full disclosure form will ask about the age of the roof and if the mechanical systems and appliances are in working order. &lt;strong&gt;If you have a private well or septic system, those need to be disclosed as well.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you’ve done a radon test in the past, you need to disclose the results.%20http://TheChadandSaraRealEstateBlog.com/what-is-included-in-a-seller-disclosure-statement.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you’ve done a radon test in the past, you need to disclose the results.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of years ago, our state added a radon disclosure piece as well. One of the most common questions we get from prospective sellers is, “Do I need a radon test?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The state of Minnesota does not require a radon test prior to selling your home. However, if you’ve had a test completed in the past, you do need to give the results of the test to any potential buyers of the property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There will be a radon warning statement attached to the disclosure statement.&lt;/strong&gt; The radon warning is a two-page document provided to the buyer at the time of their purchase agreement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about seller disclosure statements or real estate in general, just give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 08:49:57 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://TheChadandSaraRealEstateBlog.com/what-is-included-in-a-seller-disclosure-statement.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://TheChadandSaraRealEstateBlog.com/what-is-included-in-a-seller-disclosure-statement.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>4 Tips to Sell Your Home During the Offseason</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Y7846vt7P4A?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here in Minnesota, most people signal market off-peak seasons once the weather turns cold, school starts, or the holiday season begins. &lt;strong&gt;If you’re putting your home on the market during this time, there are four tips you need to follow.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, stage for the season. Whether it’s Halloween, Thanksgiving, Christmas, or Valentine’s Day, stage your house with the appropriate decorations in mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, take photographs of your home during the summer. Even if you plan on listing during the winter, having a nice, green shot of your yard to use for supplemental purposes is a nice touch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Come out of the gate competitively in terms of price.%20http://TheChadandSaraRealEstateBlog.com/4-tips-to-sell-your-home-during-the-offseason.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Come out of the gate competitively in terms of price.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third, come out of the gate competitively in terms of price, because the window of time before the new year period is limited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, &lt;strong&gt;have patience. &lt;/strong&gt;There are typically fewer buyers out and about during an off-peak market, but those who do come out tend to be more serious about buying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about selling in an off-peak market, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We’d be glad to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 05:16:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://TheChadandSaraRealEstateBlog.com/4-tips-to-sell-your-home-during-the-offseason.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://TheChadandSaraRealEstateBlog.com/4-tips-to-sell-your-home-during-the-offseason.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Changes Have Been Made to the Home Inspection Contingency</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/1o0CKKvrWns?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Big changes are happening in our state regarding the home inspection contingency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past, inspection contingencies allowed a set amount of time for buyers to inspect the home and contact the seller for any repair requests and a set amount of time for sellers to respond. This was complicated and cumbersome because people would get these timelines confused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Minnesota has simplified this process by setting a timeline for the entire inspection contingency.&lt;/strong&gt; This includes any inspections, repair requests, and bids for the work that needs to be done on those repairs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=There is no automatic cancellation specified in the purchase agreement anymore.%20http://TheChadandSaraRealEstateBlog.com/what-changes-have-been-made-to-the-home-inspection-contingency.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“There is no automatic cancellation specified in the purchase agreement anymore.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other big change is that if the buyer lets the inspection contingency ride out all the way through without any agreement on repairs from the seller, they can move forward with the house—&lt;strong&gt;there is no automatic cancellation specified in the purchase agreement.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What kind of tests does the inspection contingency cover? Basically, any tests the buyer needs to conduct to satisfy themselves that the home meets their standards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new inspection contingency also provides access to the buyer to the attic or crawl space of the house. In the past, this was an issue because buyers wanted to get into this area for their inspection but sellers didn’t want to break the seal on their attic. This new inspection contingency verbiage grants that access to the buyer so they can complete their inspection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about inspections, what’s going on in our market, or you’re thinking about buying or selling a home, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 03:19:46 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://TheChadandSaraRealEstateBlog.com/what-changes-have-been-made-to-the-home-inspection-contingency.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://TheChadandSaraRealEstateBlog.com/what-changes-have-been-made-to-the-home-inspection-contingency.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
