<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Central Iowa Real Estate Video Blog with Misty Soldwisch</title>
    <description>Our mission at The Misty SOLDwisch Home Selling Team is to be your best resource for Central Iowa real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The The Misty SOLDwisch Home Selling Team, your professional Central Iowa Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 14:45:18 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 14:45:18 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Come to Our Open Houses This Fall for a Chance to Win Something Delicious</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8jYE3Ft5mUA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve got a great chance for you to win the latest edition of the Better Homes and Gardens Cookbook. You might even find the home of your dreams while you’re at it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to sell your Central Iowa home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.centraliahomevalues.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free home value report&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Want to buy a Central Iowa home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://mistysold.searchcentraliowahomes.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all the homes on the MLS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Better Homes And Gardens Real Estate Innovations, we’ve got a great recipe for success when it comes to house hunting in the coming fall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, we’re adding a little incentive for you to come out and see what we mean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you come to any of our open houses in October or November, you will be entered to win the latest edition of the Better Homes and Gardens Cookbook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What better way to take your family into the holidays than by cooking up a recipe from this classic cookbook’s 16th edition.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=WE’VE GOT A GREAT RECIPE FOR SUCCESS.%20localhost:4000/central-iowa-real-estate-agent-weve-cooked-up-a-fun-prize-for-you.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“WE’VE GOT A GREAT RECIPE FOR SUCCESS.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And who knows, you might even find the home of your dreams while you’re at it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re considering making a change with your home, we would love to help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 12:38:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/central-iowa-real-estate-agent-weve-cooked-up-a-fun-prize-for-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/central-iowa-real-estate-agent-weve-cooked-up-a-fun-prize-for-you.html</guid>
        
        <category>Central Iowa Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Get the Home You Want Through a Backup Offer</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/72hc1l2pRQw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frustrated homebuyers in the Central Iowa market may be able to use the backup offer strategy to their advantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to sell your Central Iowa home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.centraliahomevalues.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free home value report&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Want to buy a Central Iowa home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://mistysold.searchcentraliowahomes.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all the homes on the MLS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of Central Iowa homebuyers are frustrated right now. Certain segments of the market are on fire, and they aren’t able to get into homes fast enough. As a result, they feel they don’t have very many homes to choose from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There may still be hope if you use the backup offer strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past, once a home went under contract, there’s very little chance for a competing buyer to get their foot in the door. Once the seller had chosen another buyer’s offer, typically they made it to the closing table with no problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, in those super hot segments of the market, &lt;strong&gt;we are seeing a higher fallout rate. Why is that?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, many buyers feel like they need to make a quick decision in those market segments or they will lose the home. As a result, it’s very common for people to make offers on a home without fully vetting the property to make sure it’s the right home for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=IF THE FIRST DEAL FALLS APART, THE SELLER HAS YOUR OFFER TO FALL BACK ON.%20localhost:4000/central-iowa-real-estate-agent-new-hope-for-homebuyers-in-the-backup-offer.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“IF THE FIRST DEAL FALLS APART, THE SELLER HAS YOUR OFFER TO FALL BACK ON.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, multiple offer situations really drive up the price of a home. Buyers then have very high expectations of how that home will perform during the inspection. Buyers and sellers have a hard time agreeing what condition the property should be in, which has led to a number of deals falling apart after the home inspection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Having a backup offer in place puts pressure on that first offer.&lt;/strong&gt; If for any reason that deal falls apart, the seller would much rather go to your offer than go through the hassle of putting the home on the market again. Plus, since you have a backup offer in place, the seller may be more willing to let the first deal fall apart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not all agents can navigate the ins and outs of the backup offer, but we work hard at honing our skills in order to give our buyers the edge in this competitive market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this strategy or anything else, just give us a call or send us an email. Remember, if we choose your question for one of our upcoming videos, you’ll get a free subscription to Better Homes and Gardens magazine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 14:40:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/central-iowa-real-estate-agent-new-hope-for-homebuyers-in-the-backup-offer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/central-iowa-real-estate-agent-new-hope-for-homebuyers-in-the-backup-offer.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Were Excited to Join Forces With Better Homes and Gardens Real Estate</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/l94BUnQeU5k?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have an exciting announcement to make today. It’s going to change the future of our company for the better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to sell your Central Iowa home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.centraliahomevalues.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free home value report&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Want to buy a Central Iowa home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://mistysold.searchcentraliowahomes.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all the homes on the MLS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are excited to announce that as of August 2, 2017, &lt;strong&gt;we have joined forces with Better Homes and Gardens Real Estate to form Better Homes and Gardens Real Estate Innovations.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a huge honor to be welcomed into the fold at Better Homes and Gardens Real Estate as a broker/owner. In fact, I’m the only broker/owner of this company in Iowa. This company has a rich history around here. &lt;strong&gt;The publisher of the magazine is actually rooted in Des Moines.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m so pleased that we will have this marketing and media powerhouse behind us 100% to enhance the experiences of our clients and agents. We are now aligned with a brand that is not only relevant to the people we serve but also has relevant information available for them 365 days a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll start seeing green Better Homes and Gardens signs up with our team’s name on the side here shortly. &lt;strong&gt;Keep an eye out for them.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you or anyone you know is thinking about buying, selling, or investing in real estate, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 11:03:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/central-iowa-real-estate-agent-an-announcement-from-our-team.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/central-iowa-real-estate-agent-an-announcement-from-our-team.html</guid>
        
        <category>Central Iowa Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Get an Extra Chance to Win $2,500 Towards Your Next Iowa Home </title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/00rJ2OZqelY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Iowa Finance Authority has a special sweepstakes right now offering $2,500 in cash or down payment assistance! We can help you get an extra chance to win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to sell your Central Iowa home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.centraliahomevalues.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free home value report&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Want to buy a Central Iowa home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://mistysold.searchcentraliowahomes.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all the homes on the MLS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Iowa Finance Authority is holding a great sweepstakes right now. You could win $2,500 in cash or in down payment assistance!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Iowa Finance Authority is a state-sponsored entity that promotes homeownership, which is so important to my team and I. The IFA also has a number of great programs available for down payment assistance and mortgages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=WRITE MY NAME IN AS YOUR REALTOR TO GET AN EXTRA CHANCE AT THAT $2,500!%20localhost:4000/central-iowa-real-estate-agent-dont-miss-this-chances.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“WRITE MY NAME IN AS YOUR REALTOR TO GET AN EXTRA CHANCE AT THAT $2,500!”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want two chances to win, simply write my name in as your Realtor. You can enter the contest HERE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t wait too long—the contest only runs through the month of August!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you are buying a home for the first time or making a change, this is a great chance to win some money towards your dream home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, feel free to reach out to us. In the meantime, go ahead and enter. We hope that someone who knows our team wins this opportunity. Good luck!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 15:21:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/central-iowa-real-estate-agent-dont-miss-this-chances.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/central-iowa-real-estate-agent-dont-miss-this-chances.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Easy and Helpful Moving Hacks</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/i2Ha1YymoHw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a home seller, how do you know which offer to pick in a multiple offer situation?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to sell your Central Iowa home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.centraliahomevalues.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free home value report&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Want to buy a Central Iowa home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://mistysold.searchcentraliowahomes.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all the homes on the MLS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re moving, these three tips should help you out quite a bit:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Don’t pick a peak day to move:&lt;/strong&gt; In the central Iowa market, Fridays and Saturdays are the peak days, as well as the 1st, 30th, and 31st of each month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Pack smart:&lt;/strong&gt; You can read about some great moving hacks here. They’ll help you plan, organize, and execute the process of getting all your belongings together efficiently. On top of these hacks, you should try to take the emotion out of packing. It’s hard to avoid taking a trip down memory lane when you pack your stuff, but try to save it for when you’re in your new place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=AVOID MOVING ON PEAK DAYS IF AT ALL POSSIBLE.%20localhost:4000/3-easy-and-helpful-moving-hacks.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“AVOID MOVING ON PEAK DAYS IF AT ALL POSSIBLE.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Use our moving truck:&lt;/strong&gt; This is a big advantage to working with us. We’ll even give you the manpower to help you move things. Our truck isn’t some rickety old truck either; it’s shiny and new!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking about making a move and need to buy and or sell a home, give us a call or send us an email. We’d love to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2017 14:09:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/3-easy-and-helpful-moving-hacks.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/3-easy-and-helpful-moving-hacks.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Should You Do When There Are Multiple Offers on Your Home?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/MqGVnzApnjg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a home seller, how do you know which offer to pick in a multiple offer situation?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to sell your Central Iowa home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.centraliahomevalues.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free home value report&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Want to buy a Central Iowa home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://mistysold.searchcentraliowahomes.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all the homes on the MLS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The central Iowa real estate market is pretty hot right now, which creates unique challenges for buyers and sellers. For sellers, it’s incredibly important that you choose an agent who has experience with multiple offer situations, as they are common in our market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you receive multiple offers on your home, how do you know which is the best one? There are a few things you should consider:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Price. Obviously, we want to maximize your equity and get you the best price available for your home.&lt;/strong&gt; Our expertise really comes in handy when it comes to looking at the full terms of the offer, because the offer with the highest price is not necessarily the best one for your interests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. What kind of time frame are they looking for?&lt;/strong&gt; How flexible will the buyer be on possession? As a seller, that can make or break your ability to get into your next property, so it’s important to know that up front.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=THE OFFER WITH THE HIGHEST PRICE IS NOT ALWAYS THE BEST ONE FOR YOU.%20localhost:4000/what-should-you-do-when-there-are.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“THE OFFER WITH THE HIGHEST PRICE IS NOT ALWAYS THE BEST ONE FOR YOU.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. What kind of contingencies does this buyer have that might cause stumbling blocks in the process?&lt;/strong&gt; Inspections, HOA documents, or having a survey completed are just a few examples of little things that might seem irrelevant, especially if the buyer is offering a high price. However, each of those contingencies gives the buyer a chance to renegotiate after they’ve won the deal, which could make the transaction unpleasant for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. What are the financing terms?&lt;/strong&gt; We love cash offers, but cash isn’t always better than financing. Someone who has a loan commitment is just as important as someone who has cash. The fortunate thing about working with an experienced agent is we know what to expect from different lenders. We know if a buyer is working with a reputable lender or a lender that we’ve had issues with in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, we will sit down, look at all your different options, and work together to make sure that your needs are being met and that you choose the best offer possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about selling your home in our current market, just give us a call. We would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 10:39:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/what-should-you-do-when-there-are.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/what-should-you-do-when-there-are.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Join Mistys Team:  Were Hiring a Home Selling Specialist!</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/r-L5ocH8JsA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My team is on the lookout for a good Home Selling Specialist. Joining us comes with many advantages and opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to sell your Central Iowa home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.centraliahomevalues.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free home value report&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Want to buy a Central Iowa home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://mistysold.searchcentraliowahomes.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all the homes on the MLS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I have some important news to share—my team is in the process of hiring a Home Selling Specialist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Home Selling Specialists are a highly valued member of my team. In this position, your job is to meet face to face with our sellers and help them strategize pricing, value, what kind of marketing approach is appropriate to take for their goals, and guide them through the process of a successful sale and closing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three tremendous advantages of being a Home Selling Specialist with my team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first is our unparalleled marketing. With exposure on radio, television, and many Internet enhancements, our sellers have the exposure to help them get top dollar for their home in the shortest amount of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second is our amazing operations team. Instead of spending your time as a courier putting up signs or as an administrative assistant filling out forms, we provide that service for you so that you’re able to leverage your time for the highest-producing activity—selling!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=THERE ARE TREMENDOUS ADVANTAGES TO BEING A HOME SELLING SPECIALIST ON MY TEAM.%20localhost:4000/before-you-decide-to-downsize-from-your.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“THERE ARE TREMENDOUS ADVANTAGES TO BEING A HOME SELLING SPECIALIST ON MY TEAM.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third is a guaranteed, steady flow of highly qualified seller leads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’d love for our ideal candidate to have a real estate license and some real estate experience. However, we’re open to candidates who have experience in related industries, such as insurance or mortgage. It’s extremely important that our Home Selling Specialist enjoys working with numbers, analyzing data, and coming to conclusions to give our sellers good advice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also important for them to have the ability to have both happy conversations about retaining equity and tough conversations about changing the seller’s expectations, especially when they have a life-changing need such as a death or a divorce that require them to get their home sold in a timely fashion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this sounds like something that would be of interest to you—to be able to leverage your time, our amazing marketing machine, and 17 years of real estate sales experience, I’d love to talk. &lt;strong&gt;Just click on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.soldincentraliowa.com/Join-Misty-s-Team&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“Join Misty’s Team”&lt;/a&gt; button on my website to get started. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any real estate questions, I’d love to answer them. We’re here to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 11:56:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/before-you-decide-to-downsize-from-your.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/before-you-decide-to-downsize-from-your.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>When Is the Right Time to Downsize?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/W23s2r2wmK0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you decide to downsize from your current home, ask yourself these three questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to sell your Central Iowa home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.centraliahomevalues.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free home value report&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Want to buy a Central Iowa home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://mistysold.searchcentraliowahomes.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all the homes on the MLS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One question we are asked on a pretty regular basis by clients is, “How do I know when the right time to downsize is?” There are some very important questions you need to ask yourself in order to determine this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Can you really live with less space?&lt;/strong&gt; A lot of empty nesters realize that they don’t need as much space or as many rooms but when it comes down to it, a lot of them aren’t ready to give things up to fit in a smaller space. If you’re not ready to give up some of the luxuries of having a large home, downsizing doesn’t make sense right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=CAN YOU REALLY LIVE WITH LESS SPACE?%20localhost:4000/central-iowa-real-estate-agent-right.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“CAN YOU REALLY LIVE WITH LESS SPACE?”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Are you ready for a truly lower-maintenance lifestyle?&lt;/strong&gt; Going from a large home to a condo or townhome leaves you with less yard work, less maintenance, and less square footage to take care of. If that sounds like an exciting change in your life, it’s something for you to consider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. What kind of equity position do you have on your home?&lt;/strong&gt; If you are in a great market, the timing might be perfect for you to maximize the equity you will pull out of the home. It might be time for you to talk to us if that is the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for us or are looking to buy or sell in Des Moines, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 08:32:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/central-iowa-real-estate-agent-right.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/central-iowa-real-estate-agent-right.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Do Home Warranties Benefit Both Buyers and Sellers?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/4Bp3Iv2nXlM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why do we recommend that every home buyer or seller gets a home warranty? Here are the benefits that warranties provide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to sell your Central Iowa home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.centraliahomevalues.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free home value report&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Want to buy a Central Iowa home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://mistysold.searchcentraliowahomes.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all the homes on the MLS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you are a home buyer or a seller, one thing that we always think is a good idea to include in your real estate transaction is a home warranty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is a home warranty? &lt;strong&gt;It’s an agreement with a warranty provider to cover the mechanical systems and moving parts of your home for a period of time.&lt;/strong&gt; Warranties usually last up to one year after the closing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do home warranties benefit buyers? The biggest benefit is that it &lt;strong&gt;significantly reduces the potential for large, out-of-pocket expenses after the home purchase.&lt;/strong&gt; When we consider everything that is included in the home—appliances, the HVAC, electrical systems, and plumbing to name a few—the peace of mind that comes from knowing that a provider will cover any issues is critically important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=WARRANTIES USUALLY LAST UP TO ONE YEAR AFTER THE CLOSING.%20localhost:4000/central-iowa-real-estate-agent-should.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“WARRANTIES USUALLY LAST UP TO ONE YEAR AFTER THE CLOSING.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How does a home warranty work? Whenever you experience an issue during that warranty coverage period, you’ll contact the warranty provider rather than your local plumber or handyman. They will connect you with one of their preferred providers and come out to look at the home. There will be a service charge up front, which you will know when you have the warranty coverage in place. They will then repair the item, and if they’re not able to do so, then they will replace it for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How does a home warranty benefit sellers? &lt;strong&gt;Most warranty providers provide free listing coverage during the time that your home is on the market.&lt;/strong&gt; It is also a wonderful way to eliminate your liability after the closing in the event that anything goes wrong for that buyer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our personal warranty provider is HWA Warranty. They have an awesome platinum warranty that covers the home for 13 months, rather than the 12 months covered by most providers. We have had a lot of success with it and think that it is well worth the cost to provide our buyers with peace of mind after they have purchased their largest investment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about how a home warranty can benefit you or anything else related to real estate in Central Iowa, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I’d be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 11:51:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/central-iowa-real-estate-agent-should.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/central-iowa-real-estate-agent-should.html</guid>
        
        <category>Central Iowa Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Avoid Surprise Costs When Buying an Iowa Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/DYOdGw3NjJ8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There tend to be a few common costs that buyers overlook when they purchase their home. Today, I have a full list of these items that will help buyers avoid getting surprised by extra costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to sell your Central Iowa home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.centraliahomevalues.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free home value report&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Want to buy a Central Iowa home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://mistysold.searchcentraliowahomes.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all the homes on the MLS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you buy a home, there are some hidden costs that you should be aware of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the home shopping process can be exciting, certain costs tend to sneak up on buyers. Here are some key tips to help you be fully informed when buying:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Property taxes.&lt;/strong&gt; Of your monthly house payments, property taxes are the item that can fluctuate the most during the lifetime of your mortgage. That’s why it’s important to pay attention to the assessed value of your home and the tax rates in the area you chose. If the seller you’re buying from did a great job with home renovations but they’re not reflected in the assessed value, be prepared for the potential of your property taxes jumping up in the next year or so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Insurance costs.&lt;/strong&gt; Many people have a general idea of homeowners insurance based on the value of the home they buy, but some special considerations can greatly affect the costs. For example, acreages that are long distances from a fire station can cause the cost to go up exponentially. Another would be having an in-ground swimming pool. If you have any special circumstances, be sure to check what your insurance agent’s rate is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=MANY BUYERS FORGET TO CONSIDER EXTRA COSTS FOR A NEW HOME, LIKE WINDOW TREATMENTS AND INSTALLING LANDSCAPING.%20localhost:4000/central-iowa-real-estate-agent-extra.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“MANY BUYERS FORGET TO CONSIDER EXTRA COSTS FOR A NEW HOME, LIKE WINDOW TREATMENTS AND INSTALLING LANDSCAPING.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Utility bills.&lt;/strong&gt; Here in Iowa when we go from five below to 105 degrees over the course of the year, we really use our heating and cooling systems. It’s important to get a sense of the cost of running and maintaining them, and it’s very easy for us to get a 12- to 24-month average from a provider. Having that knowledge up front really helps you prepare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Maintenance costs.&lt;/strong&gt; We all know there will be maintenance involved—it’s part of the fun of owning a new place. There are, however, some things people don’t think about as much. Older homes, for example, will have a great, mature landscape with lots of trees and plants, but it can be costly to maintain with watering and other maintenance costs. With newer homes, people often overlook things like the cost of window treatments, landscaping installation, and all the things you need to buy because no one has lived there before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All these items are very easy to overcome; it’s all about having the knowledge up front instead of getting surprised down the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about the costs of homeownership or you’re thinking about buying or selling a central Iowa home, just give me a call. I’d be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 17:07:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/central-iowa-real-estate-agent-extra.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/central-iowa-real-estate-agent-extra.html</guid>
        
        <category>Central Iowa Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
