<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>South Florida Real Estate Video Blog with Traci Cope Tam and Julie Frederick</title>
    <description>Our mission at The RealtyGirls is to be your best resource for South Florida real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The The RealtyGirls, your professional South Florida Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://realtygirlsreveal.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://realtygirlsreveal.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 15:15:01 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 15:15:01 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Important Information About Today's South Florida Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/sRq6zK81emw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As real estate professionals, one of the most common questions people ask us is, “How’s the market?” Today, we’ll be bringing you the answer. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In our local real estate market, we’ve currently got more buyers than available homes.&lt;/strong&gt; This has created a high level of demand, especially among first-time homebuyers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The housing supply continues to be increasingly tight, with 10% fewer homes than what we saw this time last year. This means we’re currently in a seller’s market, where multiple offer situations are common.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Our South Florida real estate market is still very healthy overall.%20http://realtygirlsreveal.com/important-information-about-todays-south-florida-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Our South Florida real estate market is still very healthy overall.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if you are looking to sell, now is the perfect time. The median sales price of single-family homes remains on the rise in Florida, with a year-over-year improvement of 6.5% as of January 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With regards to interest rates, the 30-year average mortgage rate is now over 4.25%, and we may see interest rates rise in 2018. However, they are still currently very low. &lt;strong&gt;This increase is unlikely to diminish the number of buyers in the market, but it could cause inventory to drop even lower. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, don’t worry. As a whole, our South Florida real estate market is still very healthy overall. Our team is currently working with some amazing sellers who are about to list their homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; If you have plans to list this year, you might be surprised to learn what your property is worth. &lt;strong&gt;You can find an estimate of your home’s value &lt;a href=&quot;http://realtygirlsreveal.com/homevalue/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions, would like more information, or would like help achieving your real estate goals for 2018, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://realtygirlsreveal.com/important-information-about-todays-south-florida-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://realtygirlsreveal.com/important-information-about-todays-south-florida-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Hire Us?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/LaqKp7kTyLw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking to buy or sell in South Florida? As owners of a well-known boutique brokerage with an amazing team, we’re ready to make your move a reality! Call us at 305.248.1488 or message us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/realtygirls/&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;. If you’re in the market to buy, you can search every home for sale on the MLS just like we do. Or, if you need to sell, we can let you know what your home could sell for with an instant home valuation report. Let us share our real estate and South Florida lifestyle experience with you. We pride ourselves on negotiating real results. Like us on Facebook for a sneak-peak into our newest listings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Traci and Julie, The RealtyGirls&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 13:29:42 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://realtygirlsreveal.com/why-hire-us.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://realtygirlsreveal.com/why-hire-us.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
