<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Savvy Agent - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://blog.savvyagent.biz/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.savvyagent.biz/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 14:15:33 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 14:15:33 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Key to Successful Communication in Life and Business</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/NUQoJCE4rQI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two most critical skills to succeed at a high level in both business and in life are  communication and problem-solving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite quotes is: &lt;strong&gt;“The single greatest problem in communication is the illusion that it has taken place.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about the number of times you’ve been in a conversation where you felt that you really understood each other &lt;strong&gt;only to walk away realizing that you each left the table with a very different idea of what was said.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best way to understand this is to realize that there’s more to communication than talking, alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help walk you through the process of communication I’d like to begin by telling a story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One Christmas Eve during my teen years, I remember lying awake at night too excited to sleep. Being a little mischievous, I decided to sneak down to my parents’ storage room where I found an old, tattered pair of cowboy boots. I took the boots back upstairs, wrapped them up, and wrote “To: Mason, From: Santa” on them. After that, I put them in my little brother’s pile of presents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Mason opened the present the next day he had an absolute look of bewilderment on his face. I thought it was hilarious, but I’m not sure my parents shared that opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My point is that just like with wrapping a present, there is a process to communication starting with encoding, then wrapping, and then delivering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We need to deliver messages in a way that the person receiving them would find appealing.%20http://blog.savvyagent.biz/the-key-to-successful-communication-in-life-and-business.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We need to deliver messages in a way that the person receiving them would find appealing.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we decide that something needs to be communicated, we encode that message in our minds. In other words, we develop a plan. The next step is deciding a form of delivery—or how to “wrap it up.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, we deliver the message. This delivery can be in-person, over the phone, through email, written, or in many other ways as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem that comes from this process is that &lt;strong&gt;after we deliver the message, we feel as if we’re finished with the communication. But, that’s not the case.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The message still needs to be unwrapped and decoded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might remember the game “Telephone”—where you stand in a circle and pass along a whispered message. As you may recall, the message was almost never the same once it reached the end of the chain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A successful communication occurs when the message that we encoded is the same one that ends up being decoded.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To achieve this, we have to realize that not everyone is wired the same way. We need to deliver the message and wrap it up in a way that the person receiving it would find appealing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try implementing this process over the next few days in your life and business. See how it can work to help you improve the way you communicate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.savvyagent.biz/the-key-to-successful-communication-in-life-and-business.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.savvyagent.biz/the-key-to-successful-communication-in-life-and-business.html</guid>
        
        <category>Agent Advice</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
