<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The AskSarita Team - your professional Portland Real Estate Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 15:30:33 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 15:30:33 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Understanding How Property Taxes Are Calculated</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/SrOd12ejEIU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How are property taxes calculated? Why does one house in one neighborhood have such a high property tax and another house in an adjacent neighborhood have such a low one?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few guidelines to help you understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, the good news—one of the amazing things about living in Oregon is &lt;strong&gt;our property taxes don’t go up over time after we buy a home.&lt;/strong&gt; For example, if you buy a home for $200,000 and over time it adds up in value and you sell it later on for $600,000, a tax assessor can’t just assess that property at $600,000. According to our tax code, a property’s assessed value can only go up approximately 3% every year, even if the property is sold over and over again. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Here in Oregon, a property’s assessed value can only go up approximately 3% every year.%20localhost:4000/understanding-how-property-taxes-are-calculated.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Here in Oregon, a property’s assessed value can only go up approximately 3% every year.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are other reasons your property tax can go up, though. If you do a permitted remodel, your home’s assessed value can go up. Every once in awhile (maybe 10 or 15 years), a particular area will also get reassessed out of necessity. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general, though, if you sell your home for quite a bit more than what it was assessed for, that won’t necessarily flag the assessor. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind, I’m not a tax assessor, so &lt;strong&gt;if want the most accurate answer possible to this question, you should visit your county’s tax assessment office.&lt;/strong&gt; They can not only answer your questions, but they can also show you how you can protest your property’s assessed value. We’d be happy to pull comparables to help you with this process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, remember that every neighborhood has different property tax rates, so they can be all over the map. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like more resources on this topic or you have any other real estate questions or needs I can take care of, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be glad to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 13:45:31 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/understanding-how-property-taxes-are-calculated.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/understanding-how-property-taxes-are-calculated.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Understand Escrow Better</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/zQJuKzatWV0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’re going to talk about escrow. It’s a big part of our lingo as real estate agents and escrow is an important part of any real estate transaction, but we rarely define it for our clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The best way to describe escrow is by using this example from the past.&lt;/strong&gt; Back when eBay first came out around the turn of the century, I would bid on something and win, but the following back and forth with the seller was tough. I wanted to buy the item and the seller wanted to sell to me, but there needed to be some sort of trust involved. I didn’t want to send my money until I got the item, and the seller didn’t want to send the item until they got their money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Escrow is an essential part of a successful transaction.%20localhost:4000/how-to-understand-escrow-better.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Escrow is an essential part of a successful transaction.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, Elon Musk came up with Paypal to act as a middleman in these transactions. That’s pretty much the same function of escrow in real estate. &lt;strong&gt;It’s a neutral third party that holds the deed and the funds in an account until the appropriate time.&lt;/strong&gt; Once escrow is completed, the seller signs over the deed, the buyer signs over the money, and the transaction is recorded by this third party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, there are plenty of other details about escrow to get into. If you have any questions or want to learn more, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 14:51:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-to-understand-escrow-better.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/how-to-understand-escrow-better.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>6 Tips that Will Make Your Home Shine During a Showing</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/WTduLJ_N-LY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do you need to do to make your home show beautifully?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know the truth of the matter—we all live differently than when our home is on the market and we’re trying to sell it. When I was selling my home, I even vacated it so I could stage it properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few tips that will make your home shine when it’s time to sell it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Light your home up.&lt;/strong&gt; Turn up all the lights and open all the blinds and curtains. We live in Portland where it can get a little gray sometimes, so no matter what, make your home as bright as possible. A good agent should turn on lights while they’re showing a home, but you never know for sure, so take care of that task for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Clear the counters.&lt;/strong&gt; In the bathroom, you may have hairspray bottles that need to be cleared. In the kitchen, you might have a coffee maker and a toaster oven that need to be removed. In any case, clear your counters so they look big and expansive and remove all personal items sitting on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Clean the house.&lt;/strong&gt; You can never have your house be too clean. You want it to look like a model home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=No matter what, make your home as bright as possible.%20localhost:4000/6-tips-that-will-make-your-home-shine-during-a-showing.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“No matter what, make your home as bright as possible.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Create an inviting scent.&lt;/strong&gt; It doesn’t hurt to bake some cookies or do whatever you need to do to make the home smell good. You want people to stay longer than they normally would, and creating an inviting scent can do the trick. Avoid odors that are overly pungent or overwhelming, though. This means no fish dinners the night before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Set the thermostat to a pleasing temperature.&lt;/strong&gt; I once had a client who was out of town for a showing and set their home’s thermostat at an arctic freeze. As soon as we walked into that home with the potential buyer, we walked right back out. It was that uncomfortable. You don’t want your home to have that kind of effect. You want people to want to stay inside it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Depersonalize the home.&lt;/strong&gt; If you have a lot of trinkets, pictures, or other personal items cluttering the interior, people won’t remember the home itself. Remove these kinds of things and hide them. That includes anything for your pets as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any more questions about making your home shine during a showing or you’re thinking about buying or selling a home, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be glad to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 04:16:42 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/6-tips-that-will-make-your-home-shine-during-a-showing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/6-tips-that-will-make-your-home-shine-during-a-showing.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>For Any Question Big or Small: Ask Sarita</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/4N7W71im4Xc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I’d like to tell you a story from my past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I was a Realtor, I had an experience as a client that I want to share with you. At that time, I remember my agent paying a lot of attention to my husband. Admittedly, I was jealous. I felt that no one was paying attention to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were moving to a new area for my husband’s job, but I had a lot of important life changes going on myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only was I adjusting to having a new baby, I was also adjusting to life in a new area. &lt;strong&gt;I had no idea where to find the best pediatrician, hair stylist, or even Chinese restaurant.&lt;/strong&gt; It was really hard not knowing my area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Even after I help you close a transaction, I am always here for you.%20localhost:4000/for-any-question-big-or-small-ask-sarita.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Even after I help you close a transaction, I am always here for you.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to now, 17 years later, and I feel very at home and connected here in Portland. We’ve lived in four homes over that time, which is one of the reasons I became an agent in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve got a lot of great connections. &lt;strong&gt;In fact, my clients think of me as their own personal “Angie’s List.” I like to call it “Sarita’s List.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My clients know that they can ask me any time they need a referral for anything here in Portland. I’m happy to help you buy and sell homes, but I also want to be the first person you think of when you need a recommendation for a service, big or small.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If I don’t already have a connection to a resource, I will seek one out for you.&lt;/strong&gt; Even after I help you close a transaction, I am always here for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 04:25:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/for-any-question-big-or-small-ask-sarita.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/for-any-question-big-or-small-ask-sarita.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tangible Proof That Portland Is the Place to Live</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/UKevj8VzDFc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Portland has been in the news recently in a big way. Specifically, there were a few recent articles in Forbes that I wanted to address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first is a list of the companies with the happiest employees. Nike, where my husband works, came in at No. 2. Keller Williams actually took the top spot! &lt;strong&gt;We’re so grateful to work for such great companies and we can definitely say that we are extremely happy to be where we are at.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=This is a great place to be in business.%20localhost:4000/tangible-proof-that-portland-is-the-place-to-live.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“This is a great place to be in business.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another article from Forbes rated Portland as the No. 1 city for business growth. This study was based on 14 different metrics, including income growth, costs, education level of the labor force, and other factors. Personally, as someone who is working here day in and day out, I see people flocking here in droves from the East Coast and other West Coast markets like San Francisco and Seattle. &lt;strong&gt;This is a great place to live, great place to invest, and a great place to be in business.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me or any real estate related needs I can assist with, give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 08:20:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/tangible-proof-that-portland-is-the-place-to-live.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/tangible-proof-that-portland-is-the-place-to-live.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Holiday Message From Our Team to You</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/mbgPRJDxK1Q?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m getting into the holiday spirit today, as you can see from my choice of headwear. I just wanted to stop by and say thank you for all your support this past year. To all my friends, clients, family, and colleagues, I’m so grateful for your business and more importantly, your friendship. We are looking forward to an even better 2018. To see my full holiday message, watch this short video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We are so grateful for your business!%20localhost:4000/a-holiday-message-from-our-team-to-you.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We are so grateful for your business!”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 04:37:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/a-holiday-message-from-our-team-to-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/a-holiday-message-from-our-team-to-you.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Should You Inspect Your Home Before You List It?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/kaS-kbQRieU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste present-before-paste&quot;&gt;Are pre-inspections a good idea if you’re a home seller? Not necessarily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;You see, if you have the home inspected, make all the noted repairs, and then list the house, guess what’s going to happen? The buyer will also have the home inspected and pay anywhere from $500 to $1,000 for a battery of their own inspections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;When they hire an inspector, they’ll want to get their money’s worth, so you can be sure that &lt;strong&gt;they’ll find many other problems with the home&lt;/strong&gt;, because no two humans are going to find the same list of issues. While you’d think you’d be prepared by getting a pre-listing inspection, you could still be faced with many issues that come up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;Ultimately, the decision to get a pre-inspection is up to you. If you’re the type of person who prefers to have a little peace of mind that’s afforded by a pre-inspection, then by all means get one. You may find some issues you didn’t know your home had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Pre-inspections aren’t necessarily a good idea.%20localhost:4000/should-you-inspect-your-home-before-you-list-it.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Pre-inspections aren’t necessarily a good idea.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;If you’re the kind of person who wants perfection, though, there is no such thing. A buyer is still going to inspect the home on their own and find their own set of issues, and if you do choose to inspect your home and you find some issues that you choose not to take care of, you’ll be obligated to disclose those in a disclosure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In most cases, you’re better off leaving the inspection to the buyer.&lt;/strong&gt; That’s what their due diligence period is for. In the meantime, you can work with a professional such as myself to prepare your home to sell. That’s what we’re here for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;If you have any questions about this or any other real estate topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 08:35:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/should-you-inspect-your-home-before-you-list-it.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/should-you-inspect-your-home-before-you-list-it.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Importance of Working With a Buyer’s Agent</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ImGx6iquvTI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I talk to friends and buyer clients all the time who say that they don’t want to waste my time because they’re still trying to figure out what they want in a home. My reaction to that gracious sentiment is always the same. You’re not wasting my time. &lt;strong&gt;In fact, if we visit a home and you don’t like it, that’s the opposite of a waste of our time.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see, it’s my job to help you. To do that to the best of my ability, I need to understand exactly what you’re looking for. The more homes we look at, whether you like them or not, the better idea I’ll have of what you’re looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Not working with a buyer’s agent leaves you vulnerable.%20localhost:4000/the-importance-of-working-with-a-buyers-agent.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Not working with a buyer’s agent leaves you vulnerable.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The alternative to working with a buyer’s agent isn’t that great. By going to a home and only working with the listing agent, you’re not helping anybody (except for maybe the seller).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A buyer’s agent does much more than just show a home.&lt;/strong&gt; That’s why it’s important to work with one every step of the way. Not only can we help you find the perfect home, we can help you write a contract and negotiate the best terms on the sale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for us about buyer’s agents, seller’s agents, or anything else about real estate, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 06:58:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/the-importance-of-working-with-a-buyers-agent.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/the-importance-of-working-with-a-buyers-agent.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are You Asking Agents the Right Questions?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/4j2-sEdZLsY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’d like to go over the five things you need to ask when interviewing a potential listing agent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How long have they been in business?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What experience do they have in your neighborhood?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How are they going to price your home?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is their marketing strategy?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do they have a team? If they’re an individual agent, how will they cover all the tasks?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Selling homes is a complex job. &lt;strong&gt;This is one instance where numbers really do matter.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following example is one way I like to explain what I mean by this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine that you needed to get your appendix out. Who would you trust? Would you trust a surgeon who successfully performed 150 appendectomies a year? Or, would you trust a surgeon who only did one or two per year?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The only real way to determine which agent will provide you with the best service is by asking key questions.%20localhost:4000/are-you-asking-agents-the-right-questions.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The only real way to determine which agent will provide you with the best service is by asking key questions.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer is obvious, and this is the same way you should approach your real estate needs. &lt;strong&gt;Someone like myself who sells 150 homes per year and other agents who sell far less may have close to the same commission rate.&lt;/strong&gt; So, the only real way to determine which agent will provide you with the best service is by asking key questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An agent should be able to show you their experience and results. You need proof of their success and references to confirm their claims.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 06:17:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/are-you-asking-agents-the-right-questions.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/are-you-asking-agents-the-right-questions.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Inspection Process Is All About Give and Take</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/r9HUH3M3DYw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today’s topic is one that is near and dear to my heart: inspections. This subject is loaded with expectations. For right now, I’d like to cover it from the buyer’s perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When buyers move forward with purchasing a home, it’s very exciting. Then the inspection comes and the buyer is given a 53-page report detailing everything wrong with the property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing to keep in mind is that inspections have a two-fold purpose. The first objective is to find anything that needs to be repaired in the property. The second objective is &lt;strong&gt;to understand the condition of the house and how to operate systems and appliances within it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inspector not only finds things that are wrong, they also educate the buyer on the home. After the inspection, the honeymoon period of home buying is pretty much over. When buyers get the inspection report, &lt;strong&gt;their rose-colored glasses usually come off and they start to feel nervous about their decision.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=With the right person by your side, inspections don’t need to be scary.%20localhost:4000/the-inspection-process-is-all-about-give-and-take.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“With the right person by your side, inspections don’t need to be scary.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once buyers know what’s wrong, they may start thinking about what they can realistically expect the seller to take care of. The level to which a seller might comply with these expectations can really vary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a home has been sitting on the market for a while, a seller might be more willing to take care of more items. Ultimately, it’s all about negotiation. &lt;strong&gt;Buyers and their agents can ask for repairs, but should know that the seller doesn’t have to agree.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the seller doesn’t agree to fix something, the buyer may terminate the contract and receive a refund. The important thing is to know that you can’t force the seller’s hand. They may have a backup offer in their pocket. It’s important to weigh your options before pulling out of a deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inspection could scare you, but the right agent is going to be able to tell you what is normal and what isn’t. Agents like myself will also be able to provide you with access to a large network of quality vendors who can help. With the right person by your side, inspections don’t need to be scary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 05:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/the-inspection-process-is-all-about-give-and-take.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/the-inspection-process-is-all-about-give-and-take.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
