<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PalmerHouse Properties</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from PalmerHouse Properties STL - your professional St. Louis Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://realestatetalk.org/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://realestatetalk.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 12:21:35 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 12:21:35 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>2 Key Tips for Choosing a Realtor</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Wz6TnjOJIho?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choosing a Realtor is not an easy task. Recently, I learned that there are 40,000 Realtors in the state of Missouri. That is a crazy number!
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;I have two suggestions to help you pick the right Realtor:
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;1. Just because they were recommended by a friend or family member &lt;strong&gt;does not mean they are the right Realtor for you.&lt;/strong&gt; Meet up with the Realtor first and make sure that you like them. Buying or selling a home should be a fun experience, and it won’t be if you can’t stand your Realtor. Make sure you like the person you are working with.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;2. Make sure your Realtor &lt;strong&gt;knows what they’re doing.&lt;/strong&gt; Hire an experienced Realtor who knows what they’re doing, not just a paper pusher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Hire a Realtor that you like, not just someone who was recommended to you.%20http://realestatetalk.org/2-key-tips-for-choosing-a-realtor.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Hire a Realtor that you like, not just someone who was recommended to you.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, this is the biggest investment of your life. Hiring the right Realtor is an incredibly important part of achieving your real estate goals.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;If you have any other questions about hiring a Realtor or about real estate in general, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://realestatetalk.org/2-key-tips-for-choosing-a-realtor.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://realestatetalk.org/2-key-tips-for-choosing-a-realtor.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
