<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Cornerstone Capital Advisors - your professional Corporate 401K Planning Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 09:24:52 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 09:24:52 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are Your Employees on Track to Retire?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/39YPZsUX3zs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine you’re getting ready to go on a great vacation and you’re standing at the gate at the Cleveland Hopkins International Airport. All of the sudden, the gate agents says. “Ladies and gentleman, the captain would like to inform you that there is an 85% chance that this flight will not make it to your destination.” Are you going to get on that flight? Of course not!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my many years as a 401(k) advisor, I’ve learned that 85% of employees won’t meet their retirement savings goals. I would like to share proven strategies that will help your employees meet their retirement goals, which are detailed in my new book, “The Retirement Bullseye.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=85% of employees won’t meet their retirement savings goals.%20localhost:4000/are-your-employees-on-track-to-retire.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“85% of employees won’t meet their retirement savings goals.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This video series is going to be all about my book and my strategies to getting your employees to reach their retirement goals. If you’d like to get started right away, you can get a free copy of my book by &lt;a href=&quot;javascript:void(location.href='mailto:'+String.fromCharCode(105,110,102,111,64,99,99,97,100,118,105,115,111,114,115,46,99,111,109))&quot;&gt;clicking here&lt;/a&gt;. Otherwise, over the next year, I’ll be sending you a couple videos a month that will detail how to ensure your employees get that paycheck for life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The videos will be short and informative and will cover topics relating to your employee’s retirement. For example, in 2006 the Pension Protection Act was passed. This encourages you as an employer to follow specific ways to add automatic features to your retirement plan design.  By taking advantage of automatic features, you can help your employees save more money now, invest wisely, and retire on time with enough money to create a paycheck for life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to hear more, stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, if you have any questions or comments, please send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/are-your-employees-on-track-to-retire.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/are-your-employees-on-track-to-retire.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
