<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>St. Cloud Real Estate Video Blog with Chris Hauck</title>
    <description>Our mission at Coldwell Banker Burnet is to be your best resource for St. Cloud real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Coldwell Banker Burnet, your professional St. Cloud Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 17:04:12 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 17:04:12 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How We Get Full Price for Our St. Cloud Listings</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ehbz7N3Hy-k?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do we help sellers get top dollar for their home in St. Cloud? Here’s a brief overview of our process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;in-post-cta&quot;&gt;Looking to buy in St. Cloud? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coldwellbankerhomes.com/minnesota/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a full home search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Looking to sell in St Cloud? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coldwellbankerhomes.com/mn/saint-cloud/agent/christopher-chris-hauck/aid_36032/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free Home Price Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A question I’ve been hearing a lot recently is, “How can I get full price on my home sale?” Well, the first thing you should do is give us a call, but here’s where we’ll go from there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The key to getting a full price offer is in the preparation and presentation of your home.&lt;/strong&gt; Most buyers today are looking for something that’s move-in ready, so cleaning and decluttering are two of the most important things you can do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also have the luxury of going through 30 to 100 homes every week, which gives me a great opportunity to see what buyers like, what they don’t like, and ultimately, what’s going to get you that full price offer you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The initial showing for a home today is online, so it must be represented well there. &lt;strong&gt;Professional photography and great curb appeal are the most important things here.&lt;/strong&gt; When you’re home’s presented well online, it will create interest among buyers and start to generate showings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A HOME’S FIRST SHOWING THESE DAYS IS ONLINE.%20localhost:4000/a-guide-to-getting-full-price-offers.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A HOME’S FIRST SHOWING THESE DAYS IS ONLINE.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By getting your home prepared properly and setting things up the right way, we can help you have the most successful sale possible in St. Cloud. If you have any questions for us or you’re looking to sell your home this fall, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 13:59:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/a-guide-to-getting-full-price-offers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/a-guide-to-getting-full-price-offers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How the St. Cloud Real Estate Market Looks This Fall</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/KXkyYXV-9ws?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have an extremely attractive market in St. Cloud right now for buyers and sellers. Here’s why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looking to buy in St. Cloud?&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coldwellbankerhomes.com/minnesota/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a full home search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Looking to sell in St Cloud?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coldwellbankerhomes.com/mn/saint-cloud/agent/christopher-chris-hauck/aid_36032/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free Home Price Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been an outstanding year for our team so far. We’ve been able to help 83 families buy or sell a home this year, and we’re looking forward to helping many more as the year goes on. &lt;strong&gt;We just wanted to bring you a few of the most recent numbers that show where our market is at and where it’s going.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have been 1,750 home sales in the St. Cloud area over the last six months. This is a good, solid number for our market. Our pending sales are strong as well. We currently have 290 of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We currently have 954 homes on the market in St. Cloud. This gives us about a four-month-supply of inventory, which is much more than there is in the Twin Cities. &lt;strong&gt;Our inventory is stronger, which helps buyers, while the average home can still sell within two to eight weeks if it’s prepared properly for the market.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=OUR INVENTORY IS MUCH STRONGER THAN IN THE TWIN CITIES.%20localhost:4000/whats-happening-in-st-clouds-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“OUR INVENTORY IS MUCH STRONGER THAN IN THE TWIN CITIES.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an extremely attractive market for buyers and sellers. Sellers can sell their homes quickly and for a good price, while buyers have a decent amount of inventory to choose from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for us or need any help buying or selling a home in St. Cloud, don’t hesitate to reach out and give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 09:51:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/whats-happening-in-st-clouds-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/whats-happening-in-st-clouds-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How I Discovered My Calling in the Real Estate Business</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/gbARJTLE0MQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently received an email from a good friend of mine that had some great questions in it. They were so good, in fact, that I wanted to answer them for you today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looking to buy in St. Cloud?&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coldwellbankerhomes.com/minnesota/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a full home search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Looking to sell in St Cloud?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coldwellbankerhomes.com/mn/saint-cloud/agent/christopher-chris-hauck/aid_36032/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free Home Price Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine, Jim Mcallister, recently sent in an email that asked a bunch of questions about my career. I thought I’d answer them today so you all can get to know a little bit more about me too. &lt;strong&gt;Here are Jim’s questions and my answers.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did you get into the business?&lt;/strong&gt; I started in real estate at a young age. My grandfather had transitioned from a career as a successful salesman to a successful real estate agent and found it was a good fit. He eventually talked me into moving back to Minnesota from Seattle to learn the business directly from him. 40 years later, here we are. My grandfather was a great teacher, and I’ve done my best to carry on his legacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why do I stay in the business?&lt;/strong&gt; The main reason is because it interests and excites me. It keeps me on my toes while giving me an opportunity to help people accomplish their goals and make one of the biggest investments of their lives. I love helping growing families, empty nesters, and everyone in between. The best part is having conversations with these people years later about how we made such a big difference for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=THIS BUSINESS EXCITES ME DAILY.%20localhost:4000/a-little-background-info-for-you.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“THIS BUSINESS EXCITES ME DAILY.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me or you’re looking to buy or sell a home in St. Cloud, give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 10:34:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/a-little-background-info-for-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/a-little-background-info-for-you.html</guid>
        
        <category>Questions</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Mid-Year Market Update for St. Cloud</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/EX2_mLVBx40?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our summer market has been great so far, and that trend is expected to continue into fall. Let’s take a look at the numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looking to buy in St. Cloud?&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coldwellbankerhomes.com/minnesota/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a full home search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Looking to sell in St Cloud?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coldwellbankerhomes.com/mn/saint-cloud/agent/christopher-chris-hauck/aid_36032/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free Home Price Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that summer is ending and we’re about halfway through the year, it’s the perfect time for a look at what’s going on in our St. Cloud market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, I’ve received a lot of calls from people asking if it’s too late for them to jump into a real estate transaction. The truth is: no.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Though summer markets are notoriously hot, this fall market is set to be excellent, as well.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the last six months, 1,621 homes have sold in our local market. With 3,200 families making a move, this has been a very good year so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current 363 pending sales we’re seeing today is down only just slightly from March, when that number was 452.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Within a 20-mile radius of St. Cloud, there are 962 homes on the market.&lt;/strong&gt; Compared to the 640 homes on the market we saw in January, this is a significant growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a good selection of homes, a market time between two to eight weeks, and interest rates at record lows, our current market holds a lot of great opportunities for buyers and sellers alike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=OUR CURRENT MARKET HOLDS A LOT OF GREAT OPPORTUNITIES FOR BUYERS AND SELLERS ALIKE.%20localhost:4000/is-it-too-late.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“OUR CURRENT MARKET HOLDS A LOT OF GREAT OPPORTUNITIES FOR BUYERS AND SELLERS ALIKE.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 14:09:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/is-it-too-late.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/is-it-too-late.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Should You Trust Zestimates?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/o-R-P0mMweI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zillow and its Zestimates have become a common topic of conversation. Here’s what you should know about them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looking to buy in St. Cloud?&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coldwellbankerhomes.com/minnesota/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a full home search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Looking to sell in St Cloud?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coldwellbankerhomes.com/mn/saint-cloud/agent/christopher-chris-hauck/aid_36032/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free Home Price Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most common questions I’ve been receiving lately is: “How accurate is the Zillow Zestimate?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every time we do a market evaluation on a home, we pull up its Zestimate and we are also pulling up recent comparable sales numbers. &lt;strong&gt;After reviewing dozens of these Zestimates and comparing them with the home’s actual market value, I have a few thoughts about them.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first is that they are extremely good at analyzing large amounts of data. If you had 10,000 homes as a sample size, the numbers would be right on the money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, when it comes to individual homes the numbers aren’t as accurate. In fact, they are off by 15% to 22% nearly 70% of the time. It’s a good tool to use when you’re just starting the process, but &lt;strong&gt;when you’re trying to come up with an actual list price for your home, there is a much better way to determine what that price should be.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=WE CAN GET YOU AN ACCURATE HOME VALUATION.%20localhost:4000/st-cloud-real-estate-thoughts-on.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“WE CAN GET YOU AN ACCURATE HOME VALUATION.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about the value of your home or if you or someone you know is looking to make a move, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I would love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 14:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/st-cloud-real-estate-thoughts-on.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/st-cloud-real-estate-thoughts-on.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What's Going on in the St. Cloud Real Estate Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/oLMjUpiqFKs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s going on in the St. Cloud real estate market? I’ve got a quick update for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looking to buy in St. Cloud?&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coldwellbankerhomes.com/minnesota/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a full home search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Looking to sell in St Cloud?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coldwellbankerhomes.com/mn/saint-cloud/agent/christopher-chris-hauck/aid_36032/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free Home Price Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to the state of the St. Cloud real estate market, I’m happy to report that it’s continuing to be very strong like it has been in recent months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inventory of homes for sale is a bit low, but has gone up since the first of the year. We have about 864 homes on the market, and interestingly enough, we also have 498 pending sales in our market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compared to last year at this time, we had about 380 pending sales, so sales are strong currently. Inventory last year was about 1,200 homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inventory is good, but it’s a little bit tight. &lt;strong&gt;As a result, homes are moving quickly.&lt;/strong&gt; We see quite a few homes sell as fast as a week to eight weeks. The great news in real estate is that interest rates are right around 4% or even better on some days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=THE GREAT NEWS IS THAT INTEREST RATES ARE ONLY ABOUT 4% CURRENTLY.%20localhost:4000/st-cloud-real-estate-st-cloud-real.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“THE GREAT NEWS IS THAT INTEREST RATES ARE ONLY ABOUT 4% CURRENTLY.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking about making a move, it’s a great time due to low interest rates and good home prices with a decent selection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, you can always give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to helping you with your move!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 15:12:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/st-cloud-real-estate-st-cloud-real.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/st-cloud-real-estate-st-cloud-real.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Do Rising Interest Rates Affect Our Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/kiuF4NK1gRc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do rising interest rates affect you? I’ll go over a couple of things you should know if you plan on buying or selling a home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looking to buy in St. Cloud?&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coldwellbankerhomes.com/minnesota/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a full home search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Looking to sell in St Cloud?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coldwellbankerhomes.com/mn/saint-cloud/agent/christopher-chris-hauck/aid_36032/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free Home Price Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have been a lot of questions about rising interest rates lately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The good news is that mortgage rates are still extremely attractive&lt;/strong&gt; and hovering around 4%. Financing is readily available, and you can get a home loan with 10%, 5%, or 3% down. If you qualify for a VA loan or want to buy in certain rural areas, you can get a home with no down payment at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What happens if interest rates go up in a year or two years from now?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we don’t know what rates will be, let’s say they go up to 6%. If you’re looking at a $200,000 house, your monthly payment would go up $273 a month thanks to your 6% interest rate; you would have to pay $1,192 a month. So, if you want to wait to buy a home, it could cost you more down the line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=IF YOU WAIT TO BUY A HOME, YOUR MONTHLY PAYMENTS WILL GO UP WITH INTEREST RATES.%20localhost:4000/st-cloud-real-estate-how-rising.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“IF YOU WAIT TO BUY A HOME, YOUR MONTHLY PAYMENTS WILL GO UP WITH INTEREST RATES.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, let’s say that you qualify for a $200,000 house at a 3.75% interest rate. If rates go up to 6%, you would only qualify for a $155,000 house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rising rates dramatically impact your purchasing power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are two advantages to buying today.&lt;/strong&gt; First, you will have a lower monthly payment for as long as you own the home. Second, if you do want to buy a home, then you will qualify for a lot more home now than you will in a couple of years (assuming that the rates go up).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, you have a great selection of homes on the market. If you are looking to sell and then buy, doing so now is fairly predictable, as most houses are selling in two to eight weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you are interested in buying or selling a home, or if you have any other real estate questions, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 15:23:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/st-cloud-real-estate-how-rising.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/st-cloud-real-estate-how-rising.html</guid>
        
        <category>Interest Rates</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>If Youre Moving Soon, Youll Need to Know This</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/WBVgiOibsY8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve got an important notice for anyone moving this spring or summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looking to buy in St. Cloud?&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coldwellbankerhomes.com/minnesota/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a full home search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Looking to sell in St Cloud?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coldwellbankerhomes.com/mn/saint-cloud/agent/christopher-chris-hauck/aid_36032/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free Home Price Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve got some important information if you’re moving this spring or summer. We’ve been talking to a few of the local moving companies this year and it seems that they are getting booked up pretty far in advance, especially for moves at the end of the month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure you get your movers booked as soon as you’ve got your closing date. In fact, &lt;strong&gt;it would be a really good idea to plan your closing date more toward the middle of the month when movers aren’t quite as busy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=MAKE SURE YOU GET YOUR MOVERS BOOKED AS SOON AS YOU’VE GOT YOUR CLOSING DATE.%20localhost:4000/if-youre-moving-soon-youll-need-to-know.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“MAKE SURE YOU GET YOUR MOVERS BOOKED AS SOON AS YOU’VE GOT YOUR CLOSING DATE.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or need anything from me and my team, please feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We’re more than happy to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2017 15:29:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/if-youre-moving-soon-youll-need-to-know.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/if-youre-moving-soon-youll-need-to-know.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Are Things Looking Up in Our St. Cloud Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Fwbtg_yHjPc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the latest market statistics, it’s a great year to be a buyer or a seller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looking to buy in St. Cloud?&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coldwellbankerhomes.com/minnesota/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a full home search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Looking to sell in St Cloud?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coldwellbankerhomes.com/mn/saint-cloud/agent/christopher-chris-hauck/aid_36032/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free Home Price Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you’re buying or selling in our market, I have some good news to share with you today. Let’s start with a few statistics to give you an idea of where the market currently stands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have been 1,095 home sales in the last six months, which is a really good number. We currently have 439 homes waiting to close, or what we call ‘pending sales.’ That number is up quite a bit from last year. Our inventory has also grown quite a bit. At the beginning of the year, we had about 654 homes on the market, and today we’re up to 807, which is a little less than the 1,100 to 1,200 we would’ve had last year. If you’re a seller, &lt;strong&gt;this means there’s a good chance your house will sell in a reasonable amount of time.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a buyer, the really good news is that &lt;strong&gt;mortgage rates are close to record lows.&lt;/strong&gt; In fact, on a 30-year fixed rate for a conventional loan, you’re looking at rates in the 3.75% to 4% range. For FHA or first-time buyer financing, rates will probably be in the 3.5% to 3.75% range. If you’re considering financing 15 years or less, your rate will be quite a bit better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=IT’S A GREAT TIME TO BE A BUYER OR A SELLER.%20localhost:4000/st-cloud-real-estate-your-latest-st.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“IT’S A GREAT TIME TO BE A BUYER OR A SELLER.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking about selling, it’s a great year to do it. If you’re thinking about buying, you’ll save a lot of money over the life of your mortgage with rates where they are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about our market or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We would be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 12:47:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/st-cloud-real-estate-your-latest-st.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/st-cloud-real-estate-your-latest-st.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>St. Cloud Spring Real Estate Market Update</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/olWVKxSMfnQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;News is good across the board in the St. Cloud market as we head into spring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looking to buy in St. Cloud?&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coldwellbankerhomes.com/minnesota/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a full home search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Looking to sell in St Cloud?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coldwellbankerhomes.com/mn/saint-cloud/agent/christopher-chris-hauck/aid_36032/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free Home Price Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s good news all over the St. Cloud real estate market as we head into spring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of right now, there are 717 homes on the market, which is great for anyone looking to buy a home because it’s up substantially from the 650 we had just a couple weeks ago. If you’re selling your home, it’s a less competitive market and it’s a good year to be a seller again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of the first week of March, we had 286 home sales waiting to close that went under contract in the last 60 to 90 days. At this time of the year, that’s a really good start. I think it’s due to the great mortgage interest rates and the warm weather we’ve had lately. &lt;strong&gt;The spring market started early.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=IT'S A REALLY GOOD TIME TO BE IN THE MARKET EITHER AS A BUYER OR A SELLER.%20localhost:4000/st-cloud-real-estate-market-update-good.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“IT’S A REALLY GOOD TIME TO BE IN THE MARKET EITHER AS A BUYER OR A SELLER.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a really good time to be in the market either as a buyer or a seller. If you’d like any additional information, give us a call or send us an email. &lt;strong&gt;We look forward to helping you in this great market.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 10:57:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/st-cloud-real-estate-market-update-good.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/st-cloud-real-estate-market-update-good.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
