<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Base Template</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Elliott Team Realtors - your professional Northern Virginia Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2016 13:27:46 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2016 13:27:46 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thanks for Your Support This Year!</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-cpbqWBga5E&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just wanted to take a minute to stop and express our sincerest gratitude for the relationship we’ve developed with you. We greatly appreciated your business and support in 2016 and in years past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we spend time with our families this season, it’s a great time to reflect on the importance of relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Thank you for your continued support.%20localhost:4000/thanks-for-your-support-this-year.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Thank you for your continued support.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wish you and your family a very Merry Christmas and a Happy New Year!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to any real estate needs you have, remember, you have a friend in the business!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 09:49:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/thanks-for-your-support-this-year.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/thanks-for-your-support-this-year.html</guid>
        
        <category>General</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Do You Need to Do to Prepare for the Spring Market? </title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/IDyWq-O07sg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to sell in the springtime, what are the first steps that you need to take? When do you need to take them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The very first thing you need to do is determine when the spring market begins. A lot of people operate under the misconception that the spring market starts in April and continues from there. The reality is that the spring market starts right after the Super Bowl weekend. So after the Redskins win the Super Bowl on February 5th, you want your house to be on the market on February 12th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why do you want to be on the market so early? Most people put their house on the market later in the spring, which means you will have a lot of competition. In February, buyers have already started searching. They are looking to buy a house and inventory is low, which puts you in a great position to sell more quickly and for more money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Call your Realtor at least a couple months ahead of time.%20localhost:4000/what-do-you-need-to-do-to-prepare-for.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Call your Realtor at least a couple months ahead of time.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you know when the market begins, what do you do? The first thing you should do is call your Realtor. We’ll go through your exact timeline, give you an overview of the process, and figure out what your goals are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideally, we’ll meet two months before you put your home on the market. There are 83 steps in our sales process from the initial phone call to putting your house on the market. We want to start taking you through this process as soon as possible so that it’s not stressful and overwhelming. We want to have a plan in place so that you know exactly what to do and when to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that initial call, we’ll meet with you, put together a market analysis, and get a stager out to your house. We’ll put together a detailed report of items that need to be addressed before you go on the market. There are things that you can do to maximize your return on the sale of your home. You may need to paint, update the flooring, clean, and declutter in order to get the most money from your home sale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once those things have been taken care of, a professional photographer will come in and take photos. We even do a 3-D scan for some of our listings. From there, we will execute our pre-listing marketing program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re in a crunch, we can get a house on the market in three days. However, we’d rather not do that. We want enough time to do all the steps properly to maximize the amount of money you’ll get for the home, and we want you to have a stress-free experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if you are thinking of putting your home on the market, give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you get started!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2016 11:39:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/what-do-you-need-to-do-to-prepare-for.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/what-do-you-need-to-do-to-prepare-for.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Difference Between Home Inspections &amp; Appraisals</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/yiEFmlzdrvU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the difference between a home inspection and an appraisal? Both are crucial elements of the home buying process, but they are not the same thing at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, let’s look at home inspections. When you buy a home, once the contract is ratified, you will order a home inspection. You will pay a professional inspector to go through the home and look for defective items, marginal items, and acceptable items. The inspector will give you a full report of any issues they find in the home, and you then have the opportunity to ask the seller to fix or replace certain items. The home inspection is there to protect the buyer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the time, buyers get a loan or mortgage through a bank or lender. The lender will order an appraisal in order to make sure that the loan amount lines up with the value of the property. The appraiser will find what the bank considers to be the true market value of the home so that you, the buyer, won’t overpay.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A home inspection lets the buyer know if there are any issues with the property.%20localhost:4000/the-difference-between-home-inspections.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A home inspection lets the buyer know if there are any issues with the property.”&lt;/a&gt;
Sometimes, homes don’t appraise. For example, one of our buyers made an offer of $610,000 and the seller accepted. When the appraisal came back, however, the property was only valued at $600,000. There are a few different things that can happen:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The buyer can pay the $10,000 difference out of their own pocket.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The seller can reduce the sales price to match the appraisal price.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The buyer and seller can meet somewhere in the middle. This is the most common course of action.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If neither side can reach an agreement, you can walk away from the transaction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You won’t lose your deposit by walking away from the transaction. The appraisal is there to protect everyone. You simply won’t close on that property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is the difference between a home inspection and a home appraisal. If you have any questions about the buying or selling process, just give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 16:10:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/the-difference-between-home-inspections.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/the-difference-between-home-inspections.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title> How The Elliott Team Helped Claudia Sell her Home</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: normal;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif;&quot;&gt;“For the team they constantly check in and give advice on selling and so they got  tips for us on how to attract more people to come to the house we were selling.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2016 15:01:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-elliott-team-helped-claudia-sell.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/how-elliott-team-helped-claudia-sell.html</guid>
        
        <category>Testimonial</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How The Elliott Team Negotiated on Behalf of Dane</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe frameborder=&quot;no&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/294471027&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: normal;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: &amp;quot;arial&amp;quot; , &amp;quot;helvetica&amp;quot; , sans-serif;&quot;&gt;“I got a house, pretty quick, within a week. And it was the house we really wanted. The process was really smooth, he worked very well with the seller in pretty much making sure he represented our best interests and getting us the best results. I would say just A+ across the board. We actually had an appraisal issue with the house so the house actually came in $7000 below what we offered. And originally we were thinking it was going to come down to some type of split but Doug really negotiated and kind of used some of the good faith and honorable type of lingo I guess to get the sellers to actually cover the entire appraisal because we really didn’t want our closing costs to go up. So that really saved us some money both on closing and also the full purchase of the house. “&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2016 14:57:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-elliott-team-negotiated-on-behalf.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/how-elliott-team-negotiated-on-behalf.html</guid>
        
        <category>Testimonial</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Will Your Home Be Safe When You’re Away During the Holidays? </title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/MYsininTILo&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of people travel during the holiday season, so today, we’re here with the top five tips to keep your home safe while you’re away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1. Implement new technology. WiFi doorbells are becoming more and more popular these days. That’s because they send notifications to your smartphone whenever someone is at your front door. Even if you are lounging at the beach, you will be able to see who is trying to get into your home. Many of these doorbells take video recordings as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2. Let your neighbors know that you’ll be gone. Tell some of your trusted neighbors that you’re going out of town so they can keep an eye on your house while you travel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3. Use exterior lighting. Motion-activated light systems are inexpensive and will make it seem like someone is home. Exterior lighting keeps thieves away from your house because they don’t want to be seen breaking in.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Make sure you triple check that your doors and windows are locked!%20localhost:4000/will-your-home-be-safe-when-youre-away.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Make sure you triple check that your doors and windows are locked!”&lt;/a&gt;
4. Put your mail and your newspaper on hold. If your mail starts to pile up and there is a stack of newspapers on your porch, that makes your home an easy target for thieves. Hop online and put your mail on hold or ask a neighbor to collect your papers to protect your property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5. Lock your doors and windows. This may sound silly, but 30% of break-ins are not forced entry. That means someone left a back door or first-level window open, allowing easy access for thieves. Triple check that you have everything locked up before you leave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you follow these five tips, your home will be safe this holiday season. If you have any other questions about home security or about the holiday real estate market, just give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 12:55:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/will-your-home-be-safe-when-youre-away.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/will-your-home-be-safe-when-youre-away.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title> How The Elliott Team Got Nina a Contract in 3 Days</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe frameborder=&quot;no&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/291974405&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: normal;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: &amp;quot;arial&amp;quot; , &amp;quot;helvetica&amp;quot; , sans-serif;&quot;&gt;“The results were very quick, instantaneous! And we got above our asking price. We sold our house, we had a contract within 3 days of putting it on the market. The entire process they went above and beyond. They were always there, we got updates on email, we were able to contact Doug when we had questions. Very responsive, very considerate and I find everything that his whole team did was very professional, timely, excellent.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2016 15:35:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-elliott-team-got-nina-contract-in-3.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/how-elliott-team-got-nina-contract-in-3.html</guid>
        
        <category>Testimonial</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Benefits of Selling During the Holidays</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jyWKZ4yNWjk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contrary to popular belief, the holidays are a great time to sell your home. Why? A couple of reasons, actually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first is that if you wait until spring to sell your home, you’ll be competing against a lot of other properties. This reduces the buyer pool. The second reason is that you’ll know that the buyers who are out there looking for homes now are dead serious about buying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To illustrate this point, I want to tell you a personal story about a house I once sold for a very good friend of mine. We were considering putting this house on the market before Christmas, so that’s what we did—we listed it the very week before. Everybody called us crazy, but I told my friend the same two things I just shared with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=In three days, we escalated $27,000 above our asking price.%20localhost:4000/the-benefits-of-selling-during-holidays.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“In three days, we escalated $27,000 above our asking price.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we did our open house that weekend, we got more than 50 groups of people that came through. They were literally tripping over each other’s shoes because it was snowing outside. We ended up getting nine offers on the property. We put the house on the market at $440,000 that Friday. The following Monday, we were ratified at $467,000. We escalated $27,000 above our asking price and ratified the contract on Christmas Eve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if you have people telling you you’d be crazy to try and sell during the holidays, remember to speak to a professional first. We’d love to be the ones to speak to you, so if you have any questions, don’t hesitate to reach out to us by phone, text, or email. We look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 12:32:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/the-benefits-of-selling-during-holidays.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/the-benefits-of-selling-during-holidays.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Mark is Very, Very Happy with The Elliott Team</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: normal;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: &amp;quot;arial&amp;quot; , &amp;quot;helvetica&amp;quot; , sans-serif;&quot;&gt;“I got great results, we sold a house for almost full price, it was done very quickly, and he was very helpful. Well I think throughout the process he was very communicative with me, he always let me know what was going on and he handled the negotiation very well, so I was very, very happy with that.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 17:04:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/why-mark-is-very-very-happy-with.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/why-mark-is-very-very-happy-with.html</guid>
        
        <category>Testimonial</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How The Elliott Team Put Kerry’s Interests First</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe frameborder=&quot;no&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/286167234&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: normal;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: &amp;quot;arial&amp;quot; , &amp;quot;helvetica&amp;quot; , sans-serif;&quot;&gt;“They were fantastic, he sold our house before it even went on the market so you can’t ask for better than that. He’s also helping us buy our new house and he’s been fantastic there too. Just the whole process he went above and beyond. I know he worked really hard. The builders that we’re using to build our new house, in the beginning, were a little hard to work with and he definitely went above and beyond to make sure our interests came first and make sure that, I know he really had to fight hard for us on a few things that we needed to get from the builders. And I know Doug was working really hard and went way above and beyond working with the builders that we had to deal with.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 10:39:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-elliott-team-put-kerrys-interests.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/how-elliott-team-put-kerrys-interests.html</guid>
        
        <category>Testimonial</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
