<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Career Advancement Video Blog</title>
    <description>Govig &amp; Associates is one of the largest privately held firms in the Executive Search industry. With more than three decades in staffing and recruiting, we have the knowledge, the network and the speed to provide unparalleled service to our clients.</description>
    <link>http://govigblog.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://govigblog.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 15:48:45 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 15:48:45 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Do Telecommuters Affect a Workforce?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/pAwov8ggeDE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do telecommuters affect a workforce?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Telecommuters who work from home are healthier, happier, more loyal, and have a much better work-life balance. &lt;/strong&gt;The regular, work-at-home, non-self-employed population has grown 103% in the last 10 years. While there is no real census bureau or government data, global workplace analytics research shows that 50% of the U.S. workforce is already compatible to work remotely. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, 80% to 90% of the workforce would love to do it. Their preference would be to work this way part-time (meaning generally two to three days a week), which they feel would give them a great balance of concentrative work at home and collaborative work at the office. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortune 1,000 companies have already started revamping their offices globally to support the people that already work mobile. Within every company, studies have shown that employees are only at their desk 50% to 60% of the time. I know companies are worried about whether people actually work when they work from home, but we’ve found that 76% of telecommuters say they actually put in more work and work harder when companies support their position. They are also more loyal to that organization. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On average, work-from-home programs for businesses save $2,000 per person, per year. &lt;/strong&gt;They’ve also reduced the turnover rate by 50%. We all know that when turnover is reduced, it saves a company exponential amounts of money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The companies that are growing the fastest are the ones embracing telecommuters.%20http://govigblog.com/how-do-telecommuters-affect-a-workforce.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The companies that are growing the fastest are the ones embracing telecommuters.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This move toward telecommuting can be either a blessing or a curse to the office furniture industry. I think companies that have perfected or are moving toward being able to sell 1,000 home workstations in the same amount of time that they’re selling 1,000 workstations for an office space are going to have tremendous opportunities in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bottom line is &lt;strong&gt;companies who are growing the most aggressively are the ones able to make the shift and have the ability to support telecommuters. &lt;/strong&gt;Keep in mind, though, that you still have to hire the right person with the right mindset and the right capability to work remotely and still be effective. It’s still an adjustment for many people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about the emergence of telecommuters in the workforce, please don’t hesitate to give us a call. We’d be happy to speak with you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/how-do-telecommuters-affect-a-workforce.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://govigblog.com/how-do-telecommuters-affect-a-workforce.html</guid>
        
        <category>Building Products</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Can You Compete in the Top 1% in Your Industry?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/slaHA0cIzlo&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s the number one thing you can do to compete in the top 1% in terms of career progression? It’s really simple, but it takes commitment. There’s a simple saying I’d like to share in that regard: There is no such thing as luck—it’s only preparation meeting opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do you think that means? How does that apply to you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, ask yourself three questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are you disciplined?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are you willing to commit one hour a week?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are you willing to do it for the rest of your career?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the answer is yes and if you think you can compete in the top 1%, then follow these suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, &lt;strong&gt;read for an hour a week&lt;/strong&gt;. Pick 10 to 12 publications and sift through them rapidly within that hour. These publications should cover all aspects of the world and relate to whatever industry you’re focused in, whether that’s politics, economics, and/or technology. You can pick many ways to get this information—digital, hard copy, newspaper, magazines, etc. It really doesn’t matter. What matters is that you’re getting a wide range of information and getting it fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=There is no such thing as luck—it’s only preparation meeting opportunity.%20http://govigblog.com/how-can-you-compete-in-the-top-1-in-your-industry.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“There is no such thing as luck—it’s only preparation meeting opportunity.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, &lt;strong&gt;‘pulse-read’ through that information.&lt;/strong&gt; What do I mean by that? Pulse reading means going through any magazine, looking at each topic, and deciding whether it’s relevant to the topic you’re interested in. If not, read only the first paragraph and move on. If the next topic you pick is of deeper interest, you might read the first paragraph, then the second paragraph, and only the last paragraph before moving on. You’ll do this with any publication you subscribe to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, after months of months (or years and years) of doing this, &lt;strong&gt;you’ll have a repertoire of information you can draw on that will allow you to make decisions in an expert manner&lt;/strong&gt; because you’ll have a wealth of subject matter relevant to those decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most successful people I’ve known over the years—over a wide range of industries—have always been avid readers. If you have any questions about this topic, please feel free to reach out to us. We’d be happy to speak with you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/how-can-you-compete-in-the-top-1-in-your-industry.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://govigblog.com/how-can-you-compete-in-the-top-1-in-your-industry.html</guid>
        
        <category>Bio Pharma</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Formatting an Effective Resume</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/yIZ76DLuOU4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can you format a resume to make it the most effective?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first piece is the most basic but often overlooked, which is making sure all of your contact information is up to date. Make sure you don’t have an outdated email address or cell phone number on your resume.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, &lt;strong&gt;you need to keep it consistent.&lt;/strong&gt;You might update your resume with your most recent positions, which is fine, but make sure the font size, type, and color, are the same as the rest of the resume. Also, make sure bullet points are the same size and things that need to be italicized are italicized. It needs to look uniform throughout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Make sure all of your contact information is up to date.%20http://govigblog.com/formatting-an-effective-resume.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Make sure all of your contact information is up to date.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;sure you don’t come across as a job hopper&lt;/strong&gt;. If you have moved up in a company or have held multiple positions, put all those under the one company header.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, &lt;strong&gt;you need to showcase your achievements, especially in terms of numbers.&lt;/strong&gt; Anytime you can show accomplishments using numbers on a resume is fantastic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions, feel free to email us or give us a call. We look forward to hearing from you.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/formatting-an-effective-resume.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://govigblog.com/formatting-an-effective-resume.html</guid>
        
        <category>Health Care</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Find Great DON Candidates</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_O7QrCQ2Vnw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I started here eight years ago, we were able to find qualified director of nursing candidates within 72 hours, generally, but times have changed. &lt;strong&gt;In January of 2017 alone, there were 7,500 postings for director of nursing candidates and only 1,200 active candidates, which shows the scarcity of these candidates out there.&lt;/strong&gt; New York, Los Angeles, and Chicago were hit the hardest. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how can you combat this? There are a couple things you can do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first is to &lt;strong&gt;develop your bench strength&lt;/strong&gt;. Look at your RNs, your MDS coordinators, your ADONs, and really put in the time and energy to mold them into someone who can step into that director of nursing role if needed. Generally speaking, the best hires you can make are people who know the organization, the culture, the leadership, and the vision of the company. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, when you conduct interviews, &lt;strong&gt;interview for potential rather than just experience&lt;/strong&gt;. I think the days of interviewing a director of nursing with 25 years of experience are coming to a close. Look at a candidate’s potential—can they step into that role two or three positions into their career? Do they have the potential to be molded and trained to be a director of nursing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Interview for potential rather than just experience.%20http://govigblog.com/how-to-find-great-don-candidates.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Interview for potential rather than just experience.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, &lt;strong&gt;make sure that your director of nursing is engaged.&lt;/strong&gt; As a search firm, the number one reason we hear candidates want to leave is that they’re not being supported by the subordinates that report to them, the leadership, or both. Make sure you touch base with that director of nursing periodically and that they’re engaged and happy in the role. We all know that the relationship between an administrator and director of nursing is vital, so they need to make sure they feel supported and have everything they need to feel supported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a vacancy, there a couple things you can do. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For one, you can engage the staff you already have. Ask anybody in a clinical role who they’ve worked with in the past and respect who would be a great director of nursing. Some of the best referrals you can get come from employees you already have in the building. If you have exhausted all your resources, I really recommend engaging a search firm for the position. If you have 7,500 postings out there and only 1,200 active candidates, finding that needle in a haystack can be difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about this topic, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I’d be glad to help!
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/how-to-find-great-don-candidates.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://govigblog.com/how-to-find-great-don-candidates.html</guid>
        
        <category>Health Care</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Best Way to Figure Out Who You Want to Hire</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2KOL4GdW3Vg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you define the profile of a person you are looking to hire?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Defining the type of person you want to hire may seem difficult to do. However, whenever we ask someone who they don’t want to hire, the answer comes very easily to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if you are really struggling to figure out how you want to hire, we recommend that you sit down and figure out who you don’t want to hire first. Think about the skills that you don’t need the candidate to have or personality traits that won’t align with your core values.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Your top three qualities are non-negotiable.%20http://govigblog.com/the-best-way-to-figure-out-who-you-want-to-hire.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Your top three qualities are non-negotiable.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After you figure that out, you should be able to have some clarity on who you want to hire.&lt;/strong&gt; Once that clarity hits, you need to write down your do’s and don’ts for the ideal candidate. Then, you need to highlight the top three qualities that your ideal candidate would have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those three qualities are non-negotiable. No candidate is perfect. Just make sure that your candidate matches with your top three, non-negotiable qualities. Those qualities should fit into where you see your company going in the future. You need to make sure that the candidate can grow with your organization, both through their role and through the culture of the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this helps you define the right type of person that you want to hire. If you need any help in the future, please don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/the-best-way-to-figure-out-who-you-want-to-hire.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://govigblog.com/the-best-way-to-figure-out-who-you-want-to-hire.html</guid>
        
        <category>Building Products</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Best Ways to Prepare for an Interview</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/roD0RBVsDwo&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you effectively interview? How can you prepare for an interview?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you are a two-year or 15-year veteran, most people are not good at interviewing for two reasons. First of all, socially, we are not really allowed to talk highly about ourselves or brag about ourselves, so we’re very bad at it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, most people don’t prepare properly for an interview, which is really kind of silly. If you were going to present to a group of executives, you would prepare. You would practice and know exactly what you’re going to say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here are two ways to effectively prepare for an interview:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, open up a Word document and then, stream of consciousness style, put together words or phrases that describe your best attributes and characteristics. You may write something like sales leadership or communication skills. Leave a space between each skill that you write down so you can go back and effectively, concisely write an example of that specific skill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=It’s absolutely crucial to prepare for an interview.%20http://govigblog.com/the-best-ways-to-prepare-for-an-interview.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“It’s absolutely crucial to prepare for an interview.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using two to three sentences at the most, leave them with the idea that you absolutely can perform that skill effectively. For example, you may say that over the last five years, you’ve built two teams from scratch. You hired, fired, and trained all of the top people that worked for your team and made them some of the top 10 contenders in your business. Your team brought in $2 million of new business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That is very concise and direct, and shows how you can impact that particular company.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, when you begin to interview, you don’t know what they’re going to ask you about. On your list, have 10 to 15 different skill sets prepared. As early in the interview as you can, you should say, “Tell me what you want me to accomplish for you.” They will outline that for you so you get a chance to speak directly to what they want you to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a 30-minute interview, you need to speak concisely about five to 15 years of business experience and how that experience applies to the job you are being considered for. These two tips will help you do just that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about the interview process, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/the-best-ways-to-prepare-for-an-interview.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://govigblog.com/the-best-ways-to-prepare-for-an-interview.html</guid>
        
        <category>Bio Pharma</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Benefits Are Wooing Candidates?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/S-6rLm9Yucs&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we are here to answer a question from Jennie, an HR manager in the Twin Cities who asked, &lt;strong&gt;“What are candidates honing in on right now when choosing an employer?”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first big thing we are hearing from candidates is that they want to join a company that is in growth mode. Career growth for the company means career growth for the employee as well. Candidates are honing in on these growing companies so that they can create an upward trajectory for their career as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benefits are a hot button topic right now as well.&lt;/strong&gt; The cost of benefits is going up a lot, especially for families. The cost is going to be higher at your position than it was in the past as well. Can you find another way to compensate an employee, maybe in the form of a little higher salary? Being flexible like this is the key to getting the best hires.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Focus on the person, not the title.%20http://govigblog.com/what-benefits-are-wooing-candidates.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Focus on the person, not the title.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another big thing to remember about hiring is that you want to focus the search on a specific person instead of a title. If you find an exceptional candidate, but you can’t offer them as much vacation as they are already getting, &lt;strong&gt;I encourage you to try and find ways around the black and white HR handbook you adhere to. &lt;/strong&gt;It’s a small sacrifice to make in order to find the perfect fit for a role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, candidates are really concerned about who they are working for. There has got to be a good rapport there. Consider bringing the hiring authority in on the process from the beginning to get candidates excited about taking a position with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions for us about hiring, career growth, retention, or anything else, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/what-benefits-are-wooing-candidates.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://govigblog.com/what-benefits-are-wooing-candidates.html</guid>
        
        <category>Health Care</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Never Put These 5 Things on Your Resume</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/PzdJIXRoFs8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://govig.com/request-information/&quot;&gt;Request a Consultation&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://govig.com/contact/&quot;&gt;Hire Us to Fill Your Job Openings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you already know, there are a ton of resources available out there that show how to write a great resume. In turn, we’re often asked what not to put on a resume. So today, we wanted to provide you with a list of the top five things you shouldn’t put on your resume.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You want to make sure your resume is a reflection of yourself. A lot of people put canned things on their resume to make themselves look good, but they’re ultimately not comfortable with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Do not put your picture on your resume.&lt;/strong&gt; There are a ton of social media sites where someone can look you up. A picture is still not appropriate to have on your resume and we don’t like to see them on there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Keep the format simple.&lt;/strong&gt; Some people like to spruce up their resume by having different fonts, colors, or margins, but remember, people will often look at your resume on their phone or a number of different programs. Extra fonts and colors can not only be distracting, they can get jumbled up when being looked at on different devices or programs. Keep it simple with clean lines, right indentation, and one font that can be bolded or italicized in certain areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. No paragraphs.&lt;/strong&gt; People in HR or recruiting look at a ton of resumes every day, so you want to make sure it’s easy to read. Use bullet points, but make sure they have quantifiable achievements. Don’t use the same bullet points for every role that you’ve had; they want to make sure that you have put some thought into it and listed exactly what you’ve done in that role even if the responsibilities were similar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Recruiters and HR people look at a ton of resumes every day, so make yours easy to read.%20http://govigblog.com/never-put-these-5-things-on-your-resume.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Recruiters and HR people look at a ton of resumes every day, so make yours easy to read.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Don’t use an objective&lt;/strong&gt;. You’ll get many opinions on this since it may seem normal to put an objective on your resume, but the problem is that it becomes very canned. We all know that your objective is to get a position with a stable, well-branded company and such. It’s better to leave it off and use that space to highlight your successes or talents, or dive right into things regarding your most recent position. Don’t fill it just for the sake of filling it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Keep it to two pages.&lt;/strong&gt; Obviously, the more experience you have, the harder it is to do this. However, it’s OK to use bullets for your last two to three positions and then just summarize the positions you’ve held before that, especially if it was more than 10 years ago. Once you get up to three, four, or even five pages, nobody will read it anyway. Remember that this is a marketing brochure; it’s not going to tell the whole story. You want people to want to read it and be attracted to your resume.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I hope you found this information helpful if you’re updating your resume or getting ready to send it out. If you have any questions at all, just give us a call or send us an email. We’d be happy to answer them for you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/never-put-these-5-things-on-your-resume.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://govigblog.com/never-put-these-5-things-on-your-resume.html</guid>
        
        <category>Building Products</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Effectively Negotiate Your Salary</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Z1zjesEwzYw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question of how to be effective at salary negotiation is a common one for us, so we wanted to cover it for all of you who have been asking the same question. As we discuss salary negotiations, there are three main topics I want to cover. Although they might sound simple at first glance, most people don’t do them. &lt;strong&gt;Following their lead could cost you, so here are three things you should know heading into salary negotiations:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Know how much compensation you are currently taking home on an annual basis. &lt;/strong&gt;Consider your base salary in addition to any bonuses, incentives, stock benefits, or other monetary value you take home. When you understand that critically, you can make a decision on what your bottom line number is and what your ideal number is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Figure out what your yearly compensation is first.%20http://govigblog.com/how-to-effectively-negotiate-your-salary.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Figure out what your yearly compensation is first.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Look at the new opportunity you are interviewing for. &lt;/strong&gt;You have to make the decision of if this is the right career choice for you. In the end, you want to be able to ask yourself if the job has enough challenge, opportunity, and experience. If you can see yourself making the same amount of money while also enjoying the new job more, you’re on the right track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Actually negotiate the salary. &lt;/strong&gt;There are two methods that are common in the marketplace and I like them both. The first is to present a hiring manager with what you are making now and what you would like to make in the future. Give them a mid-range and a high-range number. The other option you have is to not present any numbers at all. Just tell the person that you are very interested in the role and are confident in receiving a fair offer. This gives the hiring manager the opportunity to give you their best offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this information has helped you out. If you have any other questions for us, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We would love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/how-to-effectively-negotiate-your-salary.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://govigblog.com/how-to-effectively-negotiate-your-salary.html</guid>
        
        <category>Bio Pharma</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What’s the Top Trait We Look for in a Recruiter?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/zgu5zaCwLYY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s the number one trait we look for in a recruiter?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We look for risk takers. How do we identify risk takers? We find that the risk-taking trait manifests itself in recruiters in three different ways.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first way is how &lt;strong&gt;they tend to want to be paid for performance instead of having a set salary&lt;/strong&gt; that’s oftentimes based more on tenure than anything else. Risk takers are people who want to work hard, log extra hours, spend extra energy, and are compensated accordingly. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second way is in &lt;strong&gt;their relationships with people.&lt;/strong&gt; The best recruiters tend to be themselves in the recruiting process—they don’t try to replicate somebody else’s style. They put their own personality into the process, and as a result, they’re very sincere and authentic and come across as trustworthy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Be yourself, but be louder.%20http://govigblog.com/whats-the-top-trait-we-look-for-in-a-recruiter.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Be yourself, but be louder.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third way is by being comfortable in a sales process where you don’t control everything. Our business is unlike a process that simply allows you to sell a specific product that has certain traits, features, and benefits that you can market. With our process, we’re selling a service that matches a candidate with a hiring authority. Both sides are represented by people who don’t always know exactly what they want until they see it. This means there’s a lot of human psychology involved, and our job can mimic that of a marriage broker—we help manage two people come to a conclusion to solve mutual needs and requirements. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this topic, please feel free to reach out to us. We look forward to talking with you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/whats-the-top-trait-we-look-for-in-a-recruiter.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://govigblog.com/whats-the-top-trait-we-look-for-in-a-recruiter.html</guid>
        
        <category>Careers</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
