<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Florida's Emerald Coast Real Estate Video Blog with Nathan Abbott</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Nathan Abbott Team - your professional Florida's Emerald Coast Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://ownemeraldcoast.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 15:41:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 15:41:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Recap of Our Amazing Retreat in Port St. Joe</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/nqt6Ux8Iv_A?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re currently in Port St. Joe, Florida, which is also known as “Florida’s forgotten coast.” A lot of our clams and oysters are harvested out of this bay. There’s so much untouched beauty here, and I love visiting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My recent trip out here was a special one because it was with my team.&lt;/strong&gt;As a team, it’s great to get out of the office setting, spend some quality time with each other, and then come back and serve our customers on a much higher level because we work together better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=This was great for our team to spend some quality time together.%20http://ownemeraldcoast.com/a-recap-of-our-amazing-retreat-in-port-st-joe.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“This was great for our team to spend some quality time together.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We are natives to Northwest Florida and live a coastal lifestyle, and we can deliver expert local advice for our customers in order to deliver the ultimate results that they desire.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for us about the real estate market, buying or selling a home, or anything else, give us a call or send us an email today. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/a-recap-of-our-amazing-retreat-in-port-st-joe.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ownemeraldcoast.com/a-recap-of-our-amazing-retreat-in-port-st-joe.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Making Memories Through Real Estate</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/uY1zYGu4yG0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the greatest things about being in real estate is the people that you meet along the way and the memories you share with the people that you serve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I recently got back from one of the most amazing vacations.&lt;/strong&gt; I’ve been snowboarding since I was a kid, and I’ve always been really into the outdoors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just got back from Bella Coola in British Columbia. Bella Coola is one of the most remote mountain regions in the world. There are 2.5 million acres of terrain. You have to take a prop plane, a two-day boat ride, or drive through the mountains for 12 hours to get to civilization, a.k.a. Vancouver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=I was able to share this amazing experience with three different people I’ve served in real estate transactions.%20http://ownemeraldcoast.com/making-memories-through-real-estate.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“I was able to share this amazing experience with three different people I’ve served in real estate transactions.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I was able to share this amazing experience with three different people that I’ve served in real estate transactions.&lt;/strong&gt; They all had a passion for skiing or snowboarding like I did. I put the trip together on a whim, and we just got back with some great memories that we will share for the rest of our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the video above for a short film of our skiing adventure. I hope to create some great memories with you as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any real estate questions, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/making-memories-through-real-estate.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ownemeraldcoast.com/making-memories-through-real-estate.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Prepare for Unexpected Costs After Closing</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/aJ8rEMCcytw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buying a new real estate property is exciting, but they often come along with some unexpected expenses right after closing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People commonly forget about these expenses and they can certainly add up. &lt;strong&gt;Here are just a few examples:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Moving expenses.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New furniture.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Window treatments.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dishes and cutlery.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shower curtains.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=I was amazed when I bought my first home to see just how lengthy and expensive a process it was.%20http://ownemeraldcoast.com/how-to-prepare-for-unexpected-costs-after-closing.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“I was amazed when I bought my first home to see just how lengthy and expensive a process it was.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many more beyond what I’ve listed. I was amazed when I bought my first home to see just how lengthy and expensive a process it was to fully furnish and decorate the home. &lt;strong&gt;Between shelving, appliances, paper goods, and more, fine details can really add up.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For that reason, it’s important to do some budgeting beforehand. Compile a list of the things you’ll need when you move in so that you aren’t surprised at the additional costs associated with your new home. However, &lt;strong&gt;don’t buy these items prior to closing.&lt;/strong&gt; This can have a negative impact on your loan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/how-to-prepare-for-unexpected-costs-after-closing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ownemeraldcoast.com/how-to-prepare-for-unexpected-costs-after-closing.html</guid>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Paradise in Northwest Florida</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qzFPCB5fu_8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re doing a little bit of exploring today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Defuniak Springs is a beautiful area with tons of countryside, and it’s only an hour north of the beach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of great places to explore in Northwest Florida and Defuniak is definitely one of those areas. Downtown Defuniak Springs has a charming, small-town feel, and was recently rated one of the best small towns in the Southeast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=See the beauty that Defuniak Springs has to offer.%20http://ownemeraldcoast.com/paradise-in-northwest-florida.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“See the beauty that Defuniak Springs has to offer.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I highly recommend that you get out, explore a bit, and see the beauty that Northwest Florida has to offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the video above to see more of Defuniak Springs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any real estate questions, I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/paradise-in-northwest-florida.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ownemeraldcoast.com/paradise-in-northwest-florida.html</guid>
        
        <category>Outdoor Entertainment</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Experience Florida at Deer Lake State Park</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/iOoXaeDnP1E?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Located in Seagrove Beach, Deer Lake State Park provides a great opportunity for people to explore Florida in it’s natural state. The park is nestled between the Watersound community to the immediate east and Deer Lake Dunes and Seclusion Dunes to the west. Between the beautiful scenery and the beach, which is accessible by way of the boardwalk, a visit to Deer Lake State Park is a great experience. To see the full tour, watch this short video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A visit to Deer Lake State Park is a great experience.%20http://ownemeraldcoast.com/experience-florida-at-deer-lake-state-park.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A visit to Deer Lake State Park is a great experience.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/experience-florida-at-deer-lake-state-park.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ownemeraldcoast.com/experience-florida-at-deer-lake-state-park.html</guid>
        
        <category>Outdoor Entertainment</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sitting Down With Mike Ragsdale of 30A.com</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ma9zKKsaTPg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mike Ragsdale, owner and founder of 30A.com, has an amazing story behind the foundation of the 30A brand, and I’m proud to be able to interview him and share that story with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mike business background started at the University of Alabama, where he graduated with a master’s degree in advertising and public relations. “Despite how clever and educated I thought I was, I couldn’t get a job,” Mike recalls. He then bought a computer and forced himself to start a graphic design business. He ran that company successfully for seven years, and it grew in size to about 60 or 70 employees. After that, though, he had a long string of business failures. Those failures, however, led him to move to the Emerald Coast and start 30A.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mike had been vacationing in this area for years, and he always felt that it was a special place. “The natural beauty is just unparalleled, and it felt like the perfect place to raise a family,” he says. When he arrived at the Emerald Coast, the area didn’t have a cohesive brand. 30A was not used to the degree that it is today—a company in Texas actually owned the URL. &lt;strong&gt;Every individual community in the Emerald Coast had its own brand, but the one thing that tied all of them together was Highway 30A.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Today, we really don’t view it as a location—we view it as a lifestyle.” What he means when he says that is scenic 30A here in South Walton is just one of four 30A roads. State Road 30 runs from the Alabama state line to Perry, Florida, and there are four alternate routes (hence the “A”) that branch off that old state highway. 30A isn’t just here—there’s also a 30A in Bay County and two 30As in Franklin County. To him, the 30A idea evokes small-town America and “old” Florida.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=It’s a lifestyle brand, not a tourism brand.%20http://ownemeraldcoast.com/sitting-down-with-mike-ragsdale-of-30a-com.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“It’s a lifestyle brand, not a tourism brand.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mike originally moved here to become a writer, so he initially bought the 30A.com domain name to be a blog. He had no intention of turning it into a business, but after several years of developing the URL, people started asking him if they could advertise on the site, and he agreed. He describes this evolution as “very organic and unintentional.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Today, 30A.com has three different divisions: the digital division, the retail division, and licensing division.&lt;/strong&gt;The digital division includes their radio station, mobile app, Facebook page, and their websites. Their retail division includes their four 30A stores, but their apparel can be found in over 100 locations nationwide. “Think of it as Patagonia,” he explains. “Patagonia is a place, but you don’t have to go to Argentina to wear Patagonia apparel.” Their licensing division takes first-class products and licenses their brand to the companies that produce them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mike was surprised by how fast his company grew, but as an entrepreneur, he always has an eye for growth and business. Having 900,000 Facebook fans is something he never really anticipated, but he thinks they’re just getting started, and they’re now focused on taking the brand national. Not the tourism brand—the lifestyle brand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I tell people it’s small-town America at the beach, and that’s what we’re trying to capture in everything that we do.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As to where 30A.com ranks online, it’s difficult to say and depends on a few different metrics. To them, though, the goal isn’t about online rankings. They view their website as a way to share stories. &lt;strong&gt;Everything they do in their company comes down to four words: “We love the beach.”&lt;/strong&gt; That could mean loving it in ways that include music, cocktails, food, and lifestyle, and also loving it in ways that mean preserving and protecting the beach itself. That’s where they feel the company is going as much as the digital side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s next for 30A.com? They’re about to launch their 30A Sessions concert, and they have Lady Antebellum as their first opening act. They also have several shows coming up next year featuring big names and world-class talent which will be captured for broadcasts on major networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;30A is a blessing for our area, and we’re glad they’re here. We all look forward to seeing what’s next for them. If you have any questions about this interview, feel free to reach out to me. I’d be happy to chat with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/sitting-down-with-mike-ragsdale-of-30a-com.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ownemeraldcoast.com/sitting-down-with-mike-ragsdale-of-30a-com.html</guid>
        
        <category>Outdoor Entertainment</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fall 2017 Northwest Florida Housing Update</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Fall is upon us, and with it the end of the high season for real estate.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;However, if you’re thinking you’ve missed your chance to sell your home, let me reassure you.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This autumn actually presents a fantastic moment to sell.&lt;/strong&gt; Here’s why.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;First off, housing inventory is still pretty low along the Emerald Coast.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In fact, according to data from the Census Bureau and the National Association of Realtors, inventory remains well below historic averages, and is 50% less than the peak in 2006.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Second, while mortgage rates also remain very low, recent announcements by the Federal Reserve might cause them to finally start rising.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This would make mortgages less affordable and might turn away a significant number of potential buyers.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This is even more of a concern when you consider the continuing growth of home prices—6.9% in the last year alone.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Third, contrary to conventional wisdom, fall is generally a great time to list your home.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buyers in the fall are likely to be more serious&lt;/strong&gt; because they have probably been searching for months without success.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Also, because fewer homes are listed in the fall, this means &lt;strong&gt;there’s even less competition&lt;/strong&gt; than we’ve seen due to the general low inventory.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So what do you get when you put all those things together?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Well, if you were to list your home right now, chances are good that you would be able to sell it and for a solid price.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;On the other hand, if you decide to wait, the situation might not be as favorable because mortgage rates might rise or because new construction might pick up.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That means the time to list your home is now.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You can get started with this home value calculator on my website, which takes into account recent Northwest Florida sales:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Enter your home address to find out what your home is currently worth.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://search.nathanabbottteam.com/idx/homevaluation&quot;&gt;This calculator will give you a good idea of what your home is worth.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And if you would like a more precise estimate of what your home could sell for this fall, or if you have any other questions about the current Destin real estate situation, give me a call at 850.632.0136. I’m here to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/fall-2017-northwest-florida-housing-update.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ownemeraldcoast.com/fall-2017-northwest-florida-housing-update.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Can the Tortoise Clinic Do for You?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-uLhCKx-HdE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m super excited to bring you a look at a place my family and I have been visiting for years: the Tortoise Clinic. &lt;strong&gt;The acupuncture and herbal medicine they provide here are both absolutely amazing.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help me explain what the clinic does, I spoke with medical director Drew Smith. Drew first got involved in acupuncture fairly early in life. In middle school, he developed an interest in martial arts and in Eastern culture in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was specifically his junior year in high school when Drew says he first stumbled across the subject of Eastern medicine. He was browsing the shelves at a bookstore when he came across some material on the subject and was immediately fascinated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After graduating, Drew went on to graduate school at Florida State University. There, he met his future wife. When she had to return home to Japan, he knew he had to do whatever it took to follow her there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He received a scholarship from the Japanese government, allowing him to pick any university and course of study. On his second day of classes, he met a neighbor who happened to be a scholar of Chinese medicine The two began to practice tai chi together in the parks on campus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drew briefly returned to FSU, but then returned to Japan. &lt;strong&gt;He had sustained some injuries from judo, and found that Eastern medical treatments worked very well for them.&lt;/strong&gt; From then on, he knew he wanted to study this kind of medicine. So, he found a school in Maryland and has been working in related fields since&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The possibilities for what Eastern medicine can achieve are as broad as the field itself.%20http://ownemeraldcoast.com/what-can-the-tortoise-clinic-do-for-you.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The possibilities for what Eastern medicine can achieve are as broad as the field itself.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all of that traveling, I wondered why Drew returned specifically to the Emerald Coast. He told me that since he grew up in Florida, he had always known and thought of our area as the state’s “sweet spot.” He didn’t originally have plans of returning to Florida, but ultimately wanted to fully pursue acupuncture and Eastern healing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having previously worked in a chiropractic clinic, he knew it was time to pursue his passion. It was actually when he saw an ad for an acupuncture business online that he decided to reply and see what would happen. That’s when he found the Tortoise Clinic. Next thing Drew knew, he and his wife moved to the area and have been here for nearly 10 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as the benefits of acupuncture and eastern medicine, Drew believes the possibilities are as broad as the field itself.  He says you could spend a lifetime studying the use of plants as medicine, and there would still be more to learn. &lt;strong&gt;In order to do this for a living, he believes you have to be able to help every pain there is.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, he enjoys helping people boost their fertility. He also says that acupuncture can benefit people emotionally and digestively. Eastern medicine has been around for so long and is largely about your body healing itself through stimulation from acupuncture and herbal medicine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to learn more about the Tortoise Clinic, you can visit their website at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thetortoiseclinic.com/&quot;&gt;www.TheTortoiseClinic.com&lt;/a&gt;. To drop by in person, simply go to 2441 US Highway 98 W Unit 111, Santa Rosa Beach. Their phone number is (850) 267-5611. I highly recommend checking them out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, for all of your real estate needs, call The Nathan Abbott Team at (850) 632-0136. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/what-can-the-tortoise-clinic-do-for-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ownemeraldcoast.com/what-can-the-tortoise-clinic-do-for-you.html</guid>
        
        <category>Venue Reviews</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Have You Been to the Sunset Bay Cafe?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7AY6Oxqxfb4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re here today at the Sunset Bay Cafe with owner Bryce Jarvis. He’s here to talk a little bit about his restaurant and why you will love it the next time you stop in for a bite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in high school, Bryce worked in banquet setup with Abbott Resorts. He turned that experience into over 20 years of working in restaurants. &lt;strong&gt;Now, he has one of his own.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Bryce was looking for a location for his restaurant, he wanted something unique. He found that at Sandestin Resort, where Sunset Bay Cafe is located. There’s plenty of parking and space inside the restaurant and out on the patio. The vision was to put together a nice, family-friendly restaurant that you could come to for any occasion. That vision has clearly been realized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The menu is as diverse as it is delicious.%20http://ownemeraldcoast.com/have-you-been-to-the-sunset-bay-cafe.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The menu is as diverse as it is delicious.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The menu is as diverse as it is delicious. For breakfast, Bryce recommends the Hillbilly Benedict. It consists of a fried gouda grit cake, topped with a fried chicken breast, a poached egg, and hollandaise. For lunch, their shrimp and grits is the way to go. &lt;strong&gt;Gouda grits, blackened shrimp, and a delicious red-eye gravy to top it off.&lt;/strong&gt;It’s fantastic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sunset Bay Cafe is located right on the Sandestin Golf and Beach Resort inside of the Linkside Conference Center at 158 Sandestin Boulevard N. You can learn plenty more about them at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sunsetbaycafesandestin.com/&quot;&gt;www.sunsetbaycafesandestin.com.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, if you have any real estate needs we can help fulfill or any questions at all, don’t hesitate to reach out and give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/have-you-been-to-the-sunset-bay-cafe.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ownemeraldcoast.com/have-you-been-to-the-sunset-bay-cafe.html</guid>
        
        <category>Venue Reviews</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Here Are a Few Examples of the Beautiful Homes in Paradise Cove</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/c1VG7W6M0mk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boswell Builders have been building amazing custom homes along the Emerald Coast for over 40 years and bring an incredible level of expertise to our marketplace. You’ll see it in the level of interior detail they have in the model homes shown above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Boswell filled an immediate need for high-quality new construction homes at an affordable price.&lt;/strong&gt; This is how Paradise Cove was created. The homes here are priced starting at $350,000 and you’ll certainly be proud of whichever home you choose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Pineview floorplan is a 4-bedroom, 3.5-bathroom with 2,441 sq ft. There are a lot of great custom features in here and it’s in a great price point for this community. It also has a great open floor plan that transitions from living room, to dining room, to kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Most builders charge extra for these features.%20http://ownemeraldcoast.com/here-are-a-few-examples-of-the-beautiful-homes-in-paradise-cove.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Most builders charge extra for these features.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In addition to the great kitchen, here are a few other amenities you’ll find in these Boswell homes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Self-closing drawers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stainless steel appliances&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Granite countertops in the kitchen and bathrooms&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Full chef’s kitchen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of builders charge extra for features like these, but they’re automatically included in all of these homes. The master bedroom in this floorplan is great as well. It lets in a lot of natural light and has a spacious closet and bathroom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, these homes in Paradise Cove have all the elements that you’d be proud of at your primary residence. &lt;strong&gt;To learn more about the community and the homes within it, visit the Paradise Cove website &lt;a href=&quot;http://myparadisecove.com/{:target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for us or you’d like to tour one of these beautiful homes, give us a call or send us an email. We are open seven days a week and would love to hear from you today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/here-are-a-few-examples-of-the-beautiful-homes-in-paradise-cove.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ownemeraldcoast.com/here-are-a-few-examples-of-the-beautiful-homes-in-paradise-cove.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
