<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>A Video Blog about Honolulu Real Estate; It's industry, and the people working in it. Whether you're just starting out, aspiring to begin, or been working in the field for a few years, tune in to get updates, tips, tricks and more!</description>
    <link>http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 16:06:25 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 16:06:25 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The 5 Second Rule</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/pFNcDmczzbg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 08:24:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/the-5-second-rule.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/the-5-second-rule.html</guid>
        
        <category>Habits of Successful People</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meet Yana Novikov</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wVg_l5M697E?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did I hear about Team Lally?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first heard from my cousin, Veronica Edwards, who is a buyer’s agent here on the team. Then, I did my own research and found out that it’s the No. 1 real estate team in Hawaii.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What motivated me to join the team?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As I mentioned, Team Lally is the No. 1 team in Hawaii whose team leaders are using advanced home search tools to stay ahead of the competition. They also use a home-selling device and professional expertise to provide services to our clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=I love the culture here.%20http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/meet-yana-novikov.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“I love the culture here.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is my role on the team?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I’m a buyer’s agent who works exclusively with buyers, representing them and their best interests, as well as educating them on the current market conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do I enjoy most about working on the team?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love the culture here. I love the constant growth and learning from the top producers to improve my negotiation skills, as well as having fun and connecting with the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me personally or are looking to buy a home, feel free to reach out to me at 808-633-2368. I’d be glad to help you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yana Novikov, License #RS-80340, 808-633-2368&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 05:58:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/meet-yana-novikov.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/meet-yana-novikov.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Listing Partner Benjy Gilholm Has to Say About Team Lally</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZznfyTxJht4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meet Benjy Gilholm, one of our great agents here at Team Lally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Benjy first heard about our team, he was working at another top real estate team here in Honolulu. During that time, &lt;strong&gt;he noticed his team was referring all of their short sales over to agents on our team.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benjy took note of our good reputation and decided to make the switch. What ultimately motivated his move to our team was that he didn’t want to be a solo agent anymore. Being part of a team where you have a specific duty is something he was definitely attracted to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=At Team Lally, we create great experiences.%20http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/what-listing-partner-benjy-gilholm-has-to-say-about-team-lally.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“At Team Lally, we create great experiences.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team Lally has a “great team environment that is based around continuing education,”&lt;/strong&gt; says Benjy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a listing partner for our team, Benjy specializes in getting listing agreements signed and properties sold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing he most enjoys about working with Team Lally is our atmosphere. According to him, “We create great experiences.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 07:17:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/what-listing-partner-benjy-gilholm-has-to-say-about-team-lally.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/what-listing-partner-benjy-gilholm-has-to-say-about-team-lally.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Make Your Marketing Videos More Effective</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/EvvJMJ7d0qo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I want to talk to you guys about video marketing and how you can use videos to leverage your overall business in the real estate industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially, I wanted to talk about this subject using PowerPoint slides, but to really bring the point home, I decided to make it into a video. &lt;strong&gt;The great thing about doing this on video is that I won’t get that awkward silence when I ask for questions or feedback.&lt;/strong&gt; What’s more, if someone misses something, they can go back and rewatch the part they missed or didn’t understand fully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I’ve got four tips for you, which I turned into the acronym &lt;strong&gt;SEER (Story, Educate, Entertain, and Retention)&lt;/strong&gt;. Hopefully these tips will make your video marketing more effective in your business life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since there’s a lot to cover, I’ll timestamp each section so that you can learn about each one at your leisure—&lt;strong&gt;yet another awesome aspect of video!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Story (1:40)—make your videos revolve around a story.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Educate (2:34)—come from a place of education.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Entertain (3:35)—make your videos as entertaining as possible.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Retention (4:03)—edit your videos so that the audience will watch the whole thing.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7:28—hear examples of ideas I have that utilize SEER.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;8:30—a note about potential compliance and legal issues that you might come across if you don’t perform your due diligence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, being in front of a camera is very awkward for me. Even though I’m uncomfortable doing it, it’s going to improve my speech, communication skills, my knowledge of the industry, and so much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this, feel free to contact me via phone or email, or keep an eye out for my future video blog posts. Thank you all so much, and have a great day!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 08:52:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/how-to-make-your-marketing-videos-more-effective.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/how-to-make-your-marketing-videos-more-effective.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Powur Certified Agent Training for Realtors</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/R-jXH1bnMbE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/the-powur-certified-agent-training-for-realtors-tickets-39297245118?utm_source=KWCV-+Jim%27s+list+to+agents&amp;amp;utm_campaign=fe1b0a4604-EMAIL_CAMPAIGN_2017_11_16&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_term=0_2026cf1a3f-fe1b0a4604-197879241&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;REGISTER HERE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keller Williams is proud to present The Powur Certified Agent Training for Realtors for &lt;strong&gt;FREE on November 16th.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This training will provide information and resources to help agents be prepared for the many issues that can and will come up when handling a transaction involving solar.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;It’s more important than ever for agents to understand the impact of solar on the buying and selling of homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Powur Certified Agent Training covers:Solar Training&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why do agents lose home sales b/c of solar?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How we power the energy grid today&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How Net metering works&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Solar Financing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lease/Loan Assignments &amp;amp; Transfers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How identify and validate the value and economic benefit of a home with solar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The 5 Reasons homeowners don’t do solar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to avoid losing sales in escrow because of solar issues&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The difference Between Owned and Leased Systems&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Solar Eligibility&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How solar really affects the sales price of a home&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Legal Training&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What every agent should know about RESPA&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The new laws being passed that require solar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marketing Training&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to become a “trusted advisor” for your homeowners regarding solar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to provide additional value to your homeowner database&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How smart agents are creating a competitive advantage to win more listings with the solar conversation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to earn commission on solar referrals from multiple providers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DATE:&lt;/strong&gt; Thursday, November 16th&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TIME:&lt;/strong&gt; 12pm-1:30pm&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LOCATION:&lt;/strong&gt; KW Honolulu training room&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;COST:&lt;/strong&gt; FREE (Lunch will be provided)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BYOB:&lt;/strong&gt; (Bring Your Own Bill) to learn how to read your bill and enter a drawing for a gift card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/the-powur-certified-agent-training-for-realtors-tickets-39297245118?utm_source=KWCV-+Jim%27s+list+to+agents&amp;amp;utm_campaign=fe1b0a4604-EMAIL_CAMPAIGN_2017_11_16&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_term=0_2026cf1a3f-fe1b0a4604-197879241&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;REGISTER HERE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 10:45:46 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/the-powur-certified-agent-training-for-realtors.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/the-powur-certified-agent-training-for-realtors.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Today: Agent Profitability Workshop</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/v7JlxmVvmJc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste present-before-paste&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kwhonoluluevents.com/business-planning&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;RSVP HERE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;Are you a real estate agent who wants to build wealth, bring balance to your life, stabilize your income, and increase your profits?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Well, we’d like to invite you to attend our Agent Profitability Workshop. In this workshop, we’ll be giving away all our systems that you can use to build a profitable real estate business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;These will be hands-on, nuts-and-bolts strategies that we use every day&lt;/strong&gt;, day in and day out. These strategies will help you run an efficient business and bring some balance into your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;We will show you how to embrace the mindset and the habits of a successful business owner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;Isn’t that what you deserve? What your family deserves?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We will show you how to embrace the mindset and the habits of a successful business owner.%20http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/today-agent-profitability-workshop.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We will show you how to embrace the mindset and the habits of a successful business owner.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;There will be an opportunity to ask us any questions that can help you grow your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At the end of the workshop, should you feel the need for a one-on-one consultation for help in putting together a business plan, we would be happy to schedule that.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;There is absolutely no obligation to meet with us, just our way of coming from contribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kwhonoluluevents.com/business-planning&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Please RSVP here.&lt;/a&gt; Seating will be limited, and our workshops do fill up quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;There is only one catch—you have to show up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;And here is our promise: If you execute on everything we teach, your success will be certain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;We look forward to meeting you in person at our next Agent Profitability Workshop.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 07:17:59 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/today-agent-profitability-workshop.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/today-agent-profitability-workshop.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meet Buyer Specialist Miranda Haws</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/iqe7T7iL-VE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’d like to introduce our buyer specialist Miranda Haws.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Miranda first heard about our great success on the radio from hosts Rick Hamada and Sean Hannity. Once she’d heard about us, she began to think about joining our team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Miranda was curious as to what set Team Lally apart from other real estate teams here in Hawaii. Most agents compete against each other, but &lt;strong&gt;here at Team Lally we compete for each other.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just part of the reason why we’re so successful. The opportunity for collaboration that this mindset brings is what Miranda says she enjoys most about working on our team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each agent brings something different to the table, so &lt;strong&gt;everyone on the team combines their experiences and outlooks to find the best solutions for any transaction.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=On Team Lally, everyone brings something different to the table.%20http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/meet-buyer-specialist-miranda-haws.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“On Team Lally, everyone brings something different to the table.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In her role as a buyer specialist, Miranda works with families who are looking to purchase homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help find the home that will best fit their criteria and lifestyle, Miranda sifts through a number of properties before finding the right ones to show them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 06:23:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/meet-buyer-specialist-miranda-haws.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/meet-buyer-specialist-miranda-haws.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Introducing Veronika, Team Lally’s Newest Member</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/VBc4bmDcUtY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our newest team member, Veronika Edwards, was born and raised in Russia and came to the U.S. at age 19. Her life took her all over the country until she settled in Clarksville, Tennessee, where she got her real estate license in 2007. &lt;strong&gt;Even though she entered the business at the worst possible time, her passion, determination, and persistence helped her assist over 150 families in making their American Dream come true.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The housing crisis helped Veronika master her skills quickly to be able to help her best assist her clients’ needs. In 2016, her husband’s military job relocated her family to Hawaii. Veronika has two beautiful kids, ages four and nine months. She’s worked with many families with different life situations and understands how to provide her clients with “Raving Fan” level customer service. &lt;strong&gt;Her number one priority is exceeding her clients’ expectations.&lt;/strong&gt; Today, we want you to get to know her a little better. We sat down and asked her a few questions recently—here’s what she had to say:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did you hear about us?&lt;/strong&gt; I heard about Team Lally from my previous team leader, who thought I would be a great fit. I did my own research as well to find the best in Hawaii.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We’re excited to have her on the team.%20http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/introducing-veronika-team-lallys-newest-member.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We’re excited to have her on the team.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What motivated you to join our team?&lt;/strong&gt; Team Lally’s track record and reputation. Team Lally has the proper systems and tools in place to keep me organized and professional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is your role on the team?&lt;/strong&gt; I’m going to be a buyer specialist who helps families find their dream home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you enjoy most about working on the team? &lt;/strong&gt;Team Lally is a place that is jam-packed with motivation, ambition, success, and inspiration. Not only do they want you to grow as a businessperson, they want you to grow as a person in general. The environment is so warm and welcome. I feel like I’m part of a big family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to learn more about Veronika or if she can help you with any of your real estate needs, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 06:19:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/introducing-veronika-team-lallys-newest-member.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/introducing-veronika-team-lallys-newest-member.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meet Benjy Gilholm, Our Listing Partner Specialist</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/E1jh3BrmGeA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Meet Benjy—a listing partner specialist at Team Lally. Through a combination of teamwork and working closely with clients, Team Lally remains a step above the rest.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Team Lally, we have a unique and collaborative approach to real estate—which is one of the main reasons why Benjy Gilholm is so excited to be working as a part of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This hands-on, team-oriented way of thinking benefits not only us but also our clients. &lt;strong&gt;Through a combination of teamwork and maintaining continuous contact with our clients, we are able to get the most out of what we do for you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=AS A TEAM, WE REMAIN A STEP ABOVE THE REST.%20http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/meet-benjy-gilholm-our-listing-partner-specialist.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“AS A TEAM, WE REMAIN A STEP ABOVE THE REST.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to ensure that we are working together efficiently and putting out the best work for you, we hold weekly meetings between our buyer agents, seller agents, listing partner specialists, like Benjy, our in-house escrow officer, and our in-house listing manager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This helps to ensure that, as a team, we remain a step above the rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We consider the way we work together to be one of our greatest tools—it allows us to close on the highest volume of homes possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or would like to learn more about Team Lally and what we can do for you, feel free to call or email us. We look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2017 09:41:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/meet-benjy-gilholm-our-listing-partner-specialist.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/meet-benjy-gilholm-our-listing-partner-specialist.html</guid>
        
        <category>Word Of Mouse Team Lally</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kapolei Mastermind Key to Success - Last Friday Of Every Month</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/X-5K6o3YSUI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We have another mastermind coming up and we’d love for you to join us.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we wanted to talk to you about the power of the mastermind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Napoleon Hill calls the mastermind the key that will open the door to your desires—whatever they may be. He defines it as two or more people that work in perfect harmony for the attainment of a definite purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are holding a mastermind session in our Kapolei Business Center like we do every month on the last Friday from 12:30 p.m. to 1:30 p.m. The agenda is always filled with topics that will bring you success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=THIS INVITATION IS FOR ANYONE INTERESTED IN LEARNING THESE SUCCESS SECRETS.%20http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/kapolei-mastermind-key-to-success-last-friday-of-every-month.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“THIS INVITATION IS FOR ANYONE INTERESTED IN LEARNING THESE SUCCESS SECRETS.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This mastermind will feature Mr. William, a professional voice coach. &lt;strong&gt;He will teach you how to improve your ability to communicate with clients and loved ones.&lt;/strong&gt; This will bring you more clients and improve your relationships. Become a trained speaker whether one-on-one or to a group. His most important points are power, confidence, and clarity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to learn how to do all this? All you have to do is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.teamlally.com/kw-mastermind.php&quot;&gt;click here to RSVP.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks and Aloha!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 11:46:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/kapolei-mastermind-key-to-success-last-friday-of-every-month.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/kapolei-mastermind-key-to-success-last-friday-of-every-month.html</guid>
        
        <category>Team Lally Mastermind</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
