<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Career Advancement Video Blog</title>
    <description>Govig &amp; Associates is one of the largest privately held firms in the Executive Search industry. With more than three decades in staffing and recruiting, we have the knowledge, the network and the speed to provide unparalleled service to our clients.</description>
    <link>http://govigblog.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://govigblog.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 14:11:40 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 14:11:40 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Learning How to Delegate to Your Team</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/1RAH5vE1p78&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I want to talk about leadership in the workplace. How can you create an autonomous group that is productive, highly creative, and engaged?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fundamental thing that you need to learn to do effectively is &lt;strong&gt;how to delegate and not micromanage.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s really difficult from a management perspective to learn this, but if you do you will see unprecedented levels of production, engagement, and retention on the teams you oversee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the baseline things to do when you are creating an autonomous group. As you delegate, give them parameters within which they can make decisions that are away from the standard. Give them authority to make those decisions and take risks. In doing so, you need to be able to create a space where they can make mistakes and you are able to back them up and help them learn from them should they happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you can delegate without micromanaging your employees, you will see great levels of growth and success.%20http://govigblog.com/learning-how-to-delegate-to-your-team.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you can delegate without micromanaging your employees, you will see great levels of growth and success.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a person feels like there will be significant personal ramifications for failures, then it’s difficult for them to take those risks that could be beneficial to the projects they are working on. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I would recommend to help you delegate to your employees without feeling completely out of control as a manager is to have them send you an outline of what they accomplished during their work day. &lt;strong&gt;This way you’re able to keep a record of their progress on an ongoing basis. &lt;/strong&gt;This will help you, as well help them see what progress they’re making.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, if you can delegate without micromanaging and allow your employees to feel autonomous, what will happen is your people will feel fulfilled, creative, like they are trusted and respected, and they will be able to grow quickly in terms of their skillsets and abilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about this or any other leadership topic, please give me a call. I would love to help you.
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/learning-how-to-delegate-to-your-team.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://govigblog.com/learning-how-to-delegate-to-your-team.html</guid>
        
        <category>Bio Pharma</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Leaders Need Feedback</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/z_7rUQSoBYU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing about great leaders is that they are also great followers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest struggles faced by leaders is how hard it is to get constructive, positive feedback. Unsolicited, constructive feedback is something leaders desperately seek and need. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure you can approach people to ask them directly for an evaluation of things like a decision you’ve made, &lt;strong&gt;but in those cases you run the risk that they may simply tell you what they think you want to hear. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this kind of feedback simply isn’t helpful in determining whether you’re on the right track as a leader. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To illustrate this, I’d like to share a personal example of a time within my own organization where I was unable to get any feedback. Years ago someone mentioned to me the idea of using two monitors on a desk instead of one. While this is common today it certainly wasn’t at the time because monitors often cost between $600 and $700 a piece.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Opening the lines of communication between leaders and followers is essential.%20http://govigblog.com/why-leaders-need-feedback.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Opening the lines of communication between leaders and followers is essential.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, we went and bought about eight monitors, put them up, and waited to see what everyone thought. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The waiting went on for what seemed like an indefinite amount of time and it wasn’t until a couple of months later that I was able to get enough feedback to validate the decision. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, we were sitting with a budget of about $30,000 lined up to fund getting multiple monitors for the rest of the organization but were set back by three months before we were able to proceed simply because people were so unwilling to respond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Opening the lines of communication between leaders and followers is as essential as realizing that great leaders are great followers. &lt;strong&gt;No matter where you are, you ought to look for ways of providing feedback to the people making decisions. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want more information or have any questions, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you.
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/why-leaders-need-feedback.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://govigblog.com/why-leaders-need-feedback.html</guid>
        
        <category>Careers</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Advantages of Calling an Audible</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Z0gCYy7CIHg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you have the guts to call an audible? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We recently worked with a company that underwent a significant change from an enabling company culture to an empowering one. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The leadership had built some enabling habits over the years. Basically, leadership would run in and save the day, which really handcuffed those who had the authority—and responsibility—to solve the problem.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One of the leaders decided that he had the guts to call an audible.&lt;/strong&gt; He had just lost one of his five direct reports to retirement. Instead of rushing out and hiring for that role, he called his team together, explained the situation, and asked them to come up with a solution. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Calling an audible is a great way to find a solution you may have missed.%20http://govigblog.com/the-advantages-of-calling-an-audible.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Calling an audible is a great way to find a solution you may have missed.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He realized that maybe their solution would be to hire for the role, but he didn’t want to assume that would be the only option. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A week went by and when the team came back to him, he was thrilled with the solution they came up with. They had rewritten their job descriptions to absorb the responsibilities of that position. As a result, this leader had more engaged and fulfilled employees, a more efficient team, and fewer payroll costs. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Calling an audible means that you’re going to allow those closest to the problem to solve it.&lt;/strong&gt; Their line of sight can be very different from yours, and they may be able to see a solution that you would miss. That is what calling an audible is all about. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about calling an audible or if you need help with anything else, just give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/the-advantages-of-calling-an-audible.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://govigblog.com/the-advantages-of-calling-an-audible.html</guid>
        
        <category>Futurity</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We've Expanded Our Building Products Practice Team</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qEZ5hG6KBmM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last six months, I’ve been sending out videos answering questions that you send in. Today, I wanted to take a little bit of a different approach and update you on where our Building Products practice stands today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last six to eight months, we have been experiencing a higher hiring demand because of the growth that our clients are experiencing. We found that in order to continue to service you with the quality that we’ve had in the past, we’ve had to add to the team. &lt;strong&gt;As an organization, we have invested a tremendous amount back into the Building Products side. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently we added seven new employees, five of which are executive recruiters and two are full-time internet researchers. These internet researchers are helping fulfil the pipeline needed in order for our clients to continue to receive high quality service from our executive recruiters, and to free up the recruiters to talk to the candidates in the marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We specialize with manufacturers and distributors.%20http://govigblog.com/weve-expanded-our-building-products-practice-team.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We specialize with manufacturers and distributors.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Each of the executive recruiters on this team reach out to nearly 100 people &lt;/strong&gt;each day. Our team is 13 people strong, reaching out to 100 people each every day in this industry. That’s an average of 1300 people each and every day. That enables us to continue to remain dialed in to what’s going on in this industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a reminder, we do specialize with manufacturers and distributors, both in the residential and commercial sides. We also work with interior products as well as exterior products in all types of roles within the organization. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My recommendation is to reach out with one of our consultants. Whether you’re somebody that has a need on a proactive basis or reactive basis, either from a company perspective or on a personal level, call, email, InMail, or just connect with a consultant on LinkedIn so that they can keep you up to speed on what’s happening in the market. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a hiring need that you’d like to discuss, or you’re looking to schedule a career consultation, please give us a call. We’d be happy to help!
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/weve-expanded-our-building-products-practice-team.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://govigblog.com/weve-expanded-our-building-products-practice-team.html</guid>
        
        <category>Building Products</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Effectively Close an Interview</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/K_uCNLGyi64&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many candidates have difficulty closing an interview. Here are three of the most effective ways to end the interview and impress the hiring manager:
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Ask if there is anything else you can provide.&lt;/strong&gt;How do you phrase that question? Simply say, “Is there any additional information I can provide to help you make this decision?” They may ask you to clarify an earlier answer, provide work samples, or give them your references.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Ask questions about the opportunity and the company.&lt;/strong&gt;I cannot stress how important this is. Asking questions shows that you are interested in the opportunity and have done some research prior to the interview. Write down at least five questions before the interview. Inevitably, the hiring manager will answer the majority of your questions, so having them written ahead of time will give you something to fall back on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Write down at least five questions before your interview.%20http://govigblog.com/how-to-effectively-close-an-interview.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Write down at least five questions before your interview.”&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Ask about the next steps in the interview process.&lt;/strong&gt; Ask what the next steps are and what the timeline looks like. That way, you can manage your expectations by knowing the hiring manager’s exact process. This question also gives you a reason to follow up with the hiring manager if you have not heard back from them in the time period they promised.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;These three questions will definitely help you close the interview and make a positive impression on the hiring manager. If you have any other questions about preparing for the interview process, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/how-to-effectively-close-an-interview.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://govigblog.com/how-to-effectively-close-an-interview.html</guid>
        
        <category>Careers</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>These 3 Traits Make a Great Team Player</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/KpGLfMjYqxA&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does the ideal team player look like?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently read a book by Patrick Lencioni called “The Ideal Team Player,” and the premise of this book is that when the author hires for his team or assesses his team, he hones in on three main traits: &lt;strong&gt;humble, hungry, and smart&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Humble” is pretty self-explanatory because you don’t want a team member who is arrogant or egocentric. Someone who is humble and plays well with others will put the team before themselves. Herb Brooks said it best in “Miracle,” the name on the front of the jersey should always be more important than the name on the back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone who is hungry will want more responsibility, will want to learn more, and be self-motivated. They won’t need to be micromanaged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Someone who is hungry will want more responsibility, to learn more, and be self-motivated.%20http://govigblog.com/these-3-traits-make-a-great-team-player.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Someone who is hungry will want more responsibility, to learn more, and be self-motivated.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, when he says someone is “smart,” it’s not the first thing you think of when it comes to intelligence. In this context, it refers more to being socially smart. A smart team member knows how to read people, knows how they’re perceived, and is aware of their social presence in a conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With these traits, there are also three extremes to be aware of as well.&lt;/strong&gt; Someone who is too humble could be afraid to contribute or speak up when it could benefit their team. Someone who is too hungry can be a steamroller, rolling over anyone at any cost to succeed. Someone who is too socially smart might be considered a schmoozer who tells you everything you want to hear, even when it might not be the truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to talk further about how these traits affect a team dynamic or you’d like to talk more about your career, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I’d love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/these-3-traits-make-a-great-team-player.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://govigblog.com/these-3-traits-make-a-great-team-player.html</guid>
        
        <category>Health Care</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Conflict Resolution in the Workplace</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7yglxiGlEo8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are the top leadership skills? There are really quite a few skills we’d like to cover, so this video is the first of a bimonthly series on this topic. The first skill I wanted to focus on is how to navigate relationships in the workplace, or conflict resolution.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Conflict resolution is not a topic that most people are eager to discuss. However, fundamentally, &lt;strong&gt;it is one of the most important things you can learn how to do and learn how to be effective at&lt;/strong&gt;. This is because everything is team-oriented today. We rarely see business environments that don’t have people somehow involved in a team. Plus, it’s a management skill; how do you create teams that are effective, efficient, and that have good communication?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Everything is team-oriented today.%20http://govigblog.com/conflict-resolution-in-the-workplace.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Everything is team-oriented today.”&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Patrick Lencioni’s book “The Five Dysfunctions of a Team” helped me significantly in learning and mastering this particular leadership skill and I recommend it highly for anyone who is interested. The process of conflict resolution is:
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;1. Identify the problem and decide what the end goal will be and why that outcome will be beneficial.
&lt;br /&gt;2. Craft your language with an objective third party.
&lt;br /&gt;3. Have a meeting with the person you have a concern with. Be straightforward with the issue right away.
&lt;br /&gt;4. Compliment the person on their good aspects to diffuse any kind of defensiveness they may have as you discuss the issue.
&lt;br /&gt;5. Move on to what your concern is, what your end goal is, and why that would be beneficial to both that person and the team as a whole.
&lt;br /&gt;6. Ask for feedback.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;It sounds simple, but you need to practice this tactic. It is fundamental to not only leadership within a group, but also how effectively you can manage and navigate relationships as you progress to management.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;In our next video, we’ll talk more about leadership skills. If you have any questions about this or any other topic we’ve covered, please don’t hesitate to reach out. We’d be happy to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/conflict-resolution-in-the-workplace.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://govigblog.com/conflict-resolution-in-the-workplace.html</guid>
        
        <category>Bio Pharma</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Must Companies Constantly Reinvent Themselves?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/fT_36L3-8OY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To keep pace with constant changes in the market and in the world at large, businesses must learn how to adapt and continually reinvent themselves in order to secure a future. Why do companies need to do this, though? It reminds me of the Winchester Mansion project. Let me tell you why.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Sarah Winchester was an heir to the Winchester Rifle fortune. Unfortunately, after her husband died she became convinced that she was cursed by all the victims that had lost their lives to Winchester rifles.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;She decided to build a sprawling mansion and she never stopped. She built stairways to ceilings, doorways in floors, and all sorts of hidden passageways and secret rooms. What appeared to be beautiful from the outside was actually very chaotic and confusing on the inside&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Many factors can lead to chaos.%20http://govigblog.com/why-must-companies-constantly-reinvent-themselves.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Many factors can lead to chaos.”&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;An evolving business can be like that. &lt;strong&gt;When you think about the technology advancement, market shorts, organic growth, and new leadership all playing a part in a company’s future, what can appear to be calm on the outside is often chaotic from the inside.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;When you’re living in a business day in and day out, you don’t necessarily see what’s going on. So take a step back and be objective when looking at your organization and how it needs to adapt in order to continue its success in the future. &lt;strong&gt;What was relevant yesterday just might not be relevant today.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;If you’d like to talk more about your business or how you can ensure it’s as efficient and effective as possible, give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/why-must-companies-constantly-reinvent-themselves.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://govigblog.com/why-must-companies-constantly-reinvent-themselves.html</guid>
        
        <category>Futurity</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Telephone and Virtual Interview Tips</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/NEcRwQgQX5c&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We recently had a question about how to better handle telephone interviews or virtual (Skype) interviews. I am going to elaborate a little bit on this topic today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In both of these instances, you want to make sure you’re prepared and know your skills, your accomplishments, and how those things benefit the person you’re interviewing with. Secondly, you want to make sure you’ve done your research on the hiring authority, their background, and their accomplishments. Finally, you’ve got to do your research on the company. &lt;strong&gt;The more prepared you are, the more confident you will be.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=In either instance, you want to be prepared.%20http://govigblog.com/telephone-and-virtual-interview-tips.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“In either instance, you want to be prepared.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For telephone interviews, the best tip I have for you is to stand up. By standing up, you will have more energy in your voice and in terms of how you bring across the information that is relevant in the interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re doing a Skype interview, it’s not as simple. You typically have to sit down in that situation, so standing up can be difficult. &lt;strong&gt;The big thing to remember is to keep distractions at a minimum.&lt;/strong&gt; That means making sure everything shown on camera is neat and anyone else in the house with you knows to keep loud noises at a minimum for the duration of your interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this topic or want to learn more interview tips, give me a call or send me an email. I would be glad to discuss this topic further with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/telephone-and-virtual-interview-tips.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://govigblog.com/telephone-and-virtual-interview-tips.html</guid>
        
        <category>Bio Pharma</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Few Outside the Box Hiring Tips</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/r4oz30UsuGg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do companies in this industry grow faster than the industry average? &lt;strong&gt;The common denominator is that they think outside the box when bringing new people on board.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you think about it, every company is basically looking to fill their roles by looking at the same criteria. You want someone with product experience, selling experience, and a proven track record. The only thing that separates the top companies from the average ones is the culture of the organization. In fact, a recent USA Today study concluded that &lt;strong&gt;85% of the people that were hired only had 65% of the actual criteria they were looking for.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Companies are hiring people who fit their culture as opposed to people who have the exact skill sets they are looking for. They are thinking outside the box about what skills could be transferrable from a similar industry just by teaching the product. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We’ve had success recruiting pharmaceutical reps%20http://govigblog.com/a-few-outside-the-box-hiring-tips.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We’ve had success recruiting pharmaceutical reps”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we look for A&amp;amp;D reps, we certainly would love to find someone with that experience, but we also have had a tremendous amount of success actually recruiting pharmaceutical reps. A&amp;amp;D reps update libraries, work with a designer to influence them to specify their product on a particular project, and they do lunch and learns. Pharmaceutical reps have a very similar transactions with their doctors. They influence the doctor to write the scripts, work with the office in updating samples, and do lunch and learns. &lt;strong&gt;As you can see, those skills are very transferrable and this strategy has been very successful for the companies we have worked with.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re thinking about hiring, thinking outside the box is important. Don’t go down that normal track because you have the same people always cycling through the industry, just with a different business card. Be different and be bold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/a-few-outside-the-box-hiring-tips.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://govigblog.com/a-few-outside-the-box-hiring-tips.html</guid>
        
        <category>Building Products</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
