<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>Our mission at Lake Realty is to be your best resource for Lake Norman Area real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Lake Realty, your professional Lake Norman Area Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://blog.makemorekeepmoregetmore.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.makemorekeepmoregetmore.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 15:16:17 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 15:16:17 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Let's Talk About Your Real Estate Career</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Most likely, you chose to get into real estate or are thinking about a career change into real estate because you are an independent person wanting to enjoy the benefits of running your own business. Real estate allows you to be your own boss, set your own schedule, and generate levels of income reflected by your efforts and not a corporate hierarchy. These benefits—coupled with a relatively low barrier of entry and financial investment without the headache of employees—make real estate a very attractive career path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The challenge for many is not “if” I should do real estate, but “how” I should do real estate…&lt;a href=&quot;/join-our-team/&quot;&gt;Click Here to Read More&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.makemorekeepmoregetmore.com/lets-talk-about-your-real-estate-career.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.makemorekeepmoregetmore.com/lets-talk-about-your-real-estate-career.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
