<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Home Smiths Team - your professional Denver Real Estate Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 16:22:33 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 16:22:33 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Can You Save Money by Itemizing Your Taxes This Year?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/rkaeXG0aZ5c?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you purchased a house in 2016, you’re probably considering whether you should itemize your taxes or take the standard deduction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing you want to do is add up all the costs of buying the house. Find your closing settlement statement to figure out your loan costs and fees, which can be deducted. These fees include your application fee and underwriter fee, among others. Your biggest item on this list will be your mortgage interest, and the best place to find this is probably your last statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also deduct property taxes, but only for the period of time that you’ve owned the home. If you put down less than 20% to buy your home and you have mortgage insurance, it can be itemized as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If your costs exceed the standard deduction amount, you'll save money by itemizing your taxes.%20localhost:4000/can-you-save-money-by-itemizing-your.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If your costs exceed the standard deduction amount, you’ll save money by itemizing your taxes.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add up that list and compare it to the standard deduction; $6,300 for a single person or $12,600 if you’re married. If your list of costs exceeds the standard deduction, it makes more sense to itemize your taxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for us or you need a referral for a great accountant to help you out, we’re always here to help. Just give us a call or send us an email soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 14:01:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/can-you-save-money-by-itemizing-your.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/can-you-save-money-by-itemizing-your.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Use Real Estate for Retirement</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ai3Qy1ozJs0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are an investor, feel comfortable in real estate, and want to diversify your retirement portfolio, I recommend setting up a self-directed IRA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t like that your 401K or other IRA dollars are subject to the stock market, the self-directed IRA gives you more control by allowing you to use those funds to purchase real estate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What kinds of real estate can you purchase? You can purchase raw land, an apartment building, condos, a rental single-family home, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The self-directed IRA gives you more control.%20localhost:4000/how-to-use-real-estate-for-retirement.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The self-directed IRA gives you more control.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, there are a few rules. I won’t go into all of them today, but here are a few you should be aware of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You cannot live in the property yourself. 
There may be some issues if you manage the property yourself.
You cannot collect the rents and use them for your personal funds; they have to stay in the account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since real estate is something that I understand, I would much rather invest in that than the stock market. The self-directed IRA gives you more control and is a great way to diversify your retirement portfolio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about a self-directed IRA or you’re interested in investing in real estate, give me a call or send me an email. I’d be happy to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 12:04:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-to-use-real-estate-for-retirement.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/how-to-use-real-estate-for-retirement.html</guid>
        
        <category>Denver Real Estate Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Are We Already Making Pies for Thanksgiving?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/uaudhbxrkaI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the midst of an incredible season in Denver, I wanted to reach out to all of you. As Thanksgiving approaches, we wanted to let you know how much we appreciate you, from our friends and family to all of our past, present, and future clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of our team is hard at work right now in the kitchen making Thanksgiving pies for you all. We will be giving out pies once again this year to show our thanks. We’ll have pumpkin and apple this year, so make sure that you get one!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Keep an eye out for the postcard in the mail.%20localhost:4000/why-are-we-already-making-pies-for.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Keep an eye out for the postcard in the mail.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep an eye out in the mail for our postcard, which has all the details about your pie on it. If you haven’t received one yet, or would like to, give us a call or send us an email and we will send one out. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 12:18:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/why-are-we-already-making-pies-for.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/why-are-we-already-making-pies-for.html</guid>
        
        <category>The HomeSmiths Team</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Avoiding the Capital Gains Tax on Your Home Sale</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/AbQ2nLZ4XKE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you avoid paying the capital gains tax on the sale of your home?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a rental property or an investment property, you can avoid paying capital gains and use all that equity to trade into another property and defer those gains until further down the road by doing a 1031 exchange. There are six rules to know if you’re interested in doing a 1031 exchange:
  1. Both the old property and the new property must be held for investment. You can do any kind of trade, real estate for real estate, as long as it’s held for investment.
  2. There is a 45-day identification requirement. From the sale of the old property, you have 45 days to identify the new investment property that you’re going to eventually purchase.
  3. There is a 180-day purchase requirement. From the sale of the relinquished property, you have six months to close on the new one.
  4. You must have a qualified intermediary. This person will hold the proceeds of the sale in an escrow account. We have some great recommendations of qualified intermediaries if you need them.
  5. There are title requirements. You have to hold title in both properties. If one property was bought with a company name, for instance, the other has to be in that company’s name too.
  6. You have to reinvest all cash proceeds and purchase at equal or greater value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Knowing these rules will help you generate more cash flow.%20localhost:4000/avoiding-capital-gains-tax-on-your-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Knowing these rules will help you generate more cash flow.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This information will allow you to use all the equity and be able to have more leverage to buy a bigger home or a different property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking to buy a home, sell a home, or invest in real estate, we’re here with expert advice and guaranteed results. Just give us a call or send us an email and we’d be happy to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 14:03:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/avoiding-capital-gains-tax-on-your-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/avoiding-capital-gains-tax-on-your-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Advice for Denver Sellers</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Handle a Low Appraisal in the Middle of a Transaction</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/14r4Y931pCs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do you do if your appraisal comes in low in the middle of a transaction?
This is a real challenge in our marketplace today. Low appraisals can happen because our market is appreciating very quickly and has been for the last several years, there are fewer comparable properties, and each sale seems to be higher than the last one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the definition of  an appraisal? It’s what a willing buyer and a willing seller come to terms on. The reality, though, is that we have to sell the home and its value to three different groups: the brokers in the marketplace, the buyers themselves, and the bank. The brokers help us find the buyer for your home. The buyers need to believe your value is justified. The bank has to believe in the home’s value because they’re the ones putting up the majority of the money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We have to sell the home and its value to three different groups of people.%20localhost:4000/denver-real-estate-agent-what-if-my.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We have to sell the home and its value to three different groups of people.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What happens if you get a low appraisal? There are three ways to proceed: the buyer can terminate the offer, the buyer can pay the difference in cash between the appraised price and the purchase price, or the buyer and seller can negotiate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any event, it’s important to have a real estate expert in your corner to manage this process and go to bat for you with the appraisal company or the appraiser. We want to be confident in how we’re positioning your home in the marketplace and know what the best strategy is going forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or concerns regarding a particular topic, drop us a line or send us an email and we’d be happy to cover it for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2016 17:46:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/denver-real-estate-agent-what-if-my.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/denver-real-estate-agent-what-if-my.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>12 Questions You Need to Ask Before Hiring an Agent</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/6CGDgImqm4g?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What questions do you ask when you are hiring a real estate professional? There are about a dozen you should ask to find the right person to help you buy or sell a home. Remember, not all agents are created equal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How long have you been practicing real estate? Experience matters.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What qualifications do you have to sell real estate? Is this your full-time or part-time job? Make sure they have enough time for you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How many homes have you sold this week? This year? In your career? The best way to predict an agent’s future results is to look at their past record.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tell me about your personal real estate operation. Are you an individual or team agent?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can you give me a list of client references to call? You don’t just want to look at written testimonials; speak with actual past clients as well.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do you have a formal and written marketing plan for selling homes? Don’t work with someone who just shoots from the hip. We have a 151-point strategy for selling your home.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Are they proactive about real estate?%20localhost:4000/denver-real-estate-agent-top-12.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Are they proactive about real estate?”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How often will I hear from you, and in what fashion? Make sure you have open communication with your agent throughout the process.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do you guarantee your performance? When you work with us, you are obligated to us for one day at a time. This holds us accountable for our end of the bargain.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can you refer me to a reputable mortgage lender, inspector, and more?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What percentage of your business comes from referrals?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How many people do you speak with each day about real estate? Are they proactive?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is their monthly advertising budget? A lot of agents don’t spend much on advertising, so it’s important to know that number.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in one of our reports for more details on these questions, give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 11:13:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/denver-real-estate-agent-top-12.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/denver-real-estate-agent-top-12.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Avoid These 7 Costly Mistakes When Selling Your Denver Property</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qVqpU6fwv_Y?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for stopping by! There are several mistakes you want to avoid when moving up to a larger home or selling your property. I’ve narrowed the list down to the most important seven, which I want to discuss today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Failing to “dress” your property for sale. How you initially position the property in the market is very important. We’ve talked in the past about how if you want to put your best foot forward, you need to stage it so that it looks good, smells good, and feels good.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Pricing your home incorrectly. You need a pricing strategy that’s going to attract the most amount of buyers. At HomeSmiths, our price range positioning strategy is designed to expand the pool of buyers potentially searching for your home.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Limiting the marketing of your home. You want to expose your home to the most amount of people in the marketplace. Our job is to get as many footsteps to your front door as possible. For this we have a 151-step system that we use to sell and get top-dollar for all of our properties.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=How you position the property in the market is very important.%20localhost:4000/denver-real-estate-agent-7-mistakes-for.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“How you position the property in the market is very important.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Thinking that an online source is the real value of your home. Zillow and Realtor.com offer instant home valuations and are good places to start, but you need a full equity analysis to get your home’s true value.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Not understanding your rights and obligations. Make sure that you’re walking through each page of that contract and understanding your rights and obligations.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Signing a listing agreement with no way out. Many agents in the marketplace will try to sign you up for six months or longer. To guarantee that we live up to your expectations on a day-to-day basis, we offer a one-day listing that allows you to fire us at any time if you’re dissatisfied.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Selecting the wrong broker. How long have they been in the business? What’s their track record? How many houses have they sold? These are questions you absolutely need to know before hiring your broker.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, this list of costly issues will be helpful to you and give you a better idea of the right way to get your home sold. As always, we want to thank you for watching our video. We’re here to serve with expert advice and guaranteed results. Give us a call or shoot us an email if you have any questions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2016 08:38:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/denver-real-estate-agent-7-mistakes-for.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/denver-real-estate-agent-7-mistakes-for.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title> How Much Home Can You Afford?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/yiLz7Z6GPoU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every case is different, but your affordability mostly depends on your income and other financial obligations. The general rule of thumb is that you can afford approximately 30% of your gross monthly income on a house payment. They are going to also allow 10% of your monthly income towards other debts, without it negatively affecting your mortgage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a good idea to check your credit score and make sure it’s where it needs to be. The minimum score to get an FHA mortgage is 580, and for a conventional mortgage it’s 620. The higher your score, the better loan you’ll get.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your lender is going to want to see a history of your income, as well as the ability to predict where your income will be in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a myth out there that you have to have a 20% down payment in order to get a loan. We’ve got programs available for as low as 3% down, and even lower in some cases. Consider this myth busted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You can get a loan for 3% or less down!%20localhost:4000/how-much-home-can-you-afford.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You can get a loan for 3% or less down!”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, loan terms will affect how much your payment is each month and how much you can qualify for. If you want to really knock it out quick, you can get a 10-year or 15-year loan, but most people choose 30-year terms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are curious as to what kind of home you can afford, click here to use our home affordability calculator. We also have a monthly payment calendar to give you an idea of what your payment will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Figuring out what you can afford is the first step you should take in the buying process. Getting pre-approved is crucial in this market. We really appreciate you and are here to serve you with expert advice and guaranteed results. If you have any questions for us, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 09:01:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-much-home-can-you-afford.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/how-much-home-can-you-afford.html</guid>
        
        <category>Denver Home Loans</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title> Tips for Denver Sellers During Home Showings </title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/omsOFL2LvH8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lately, a lot of sellers have been asking, “Should I be present during my home showings?” My answer is absolutely not! There’s never an instance where that’s a good idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I understand how you feel. It’s a huge inconvenience to leave your home for every showing. You might also feel that you are the best person to point out the features in your home. After all, you know your house best. You probably also want to know what potential buyers think of your home, so you want to be there and see the reaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the homeowner is there, the buyer tends to clam up. They don’t talk. They don’t want to offend you. We need the buyer to be open and vocal. We need to hear what they think about the paint colors, the flooring, and the price of the home. That way, we can overcome any objections and get an offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Never turn down a showing%20localhost:4000/denver-real-estate-agent-how-to-handle.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Never turn down a showing”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of our showings are going to be set up within a two-hour window. You don’t have to leave for the full two hours. Be ready to go. Have the dog and the kids in the car, and when the buyer shows up, go for a drive around the block. Most showings only take ten minutes. If you’re sitting at the corner waiting for them to leave and they’re taking half an hour, get excited! That means the buyer is likely interested in the property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Showings can be inconvenient, but it’s important to never turn down a showing. I know emergencies come up, but every time we turn down a showing, there’s a chance the buyer is going to go down the street and buy your neighbor’s house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are also going to request feedback. We ask every buyer who looks at your house what they like, what they dislike, and what we can change. We will share that feedback with you so you’re never out of the loop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also have a quick sheet with tips to help you prepare for your showings. If you are interested, just give me a call or send me an email. I’d be happy to share it with you and answer any other questions you might have!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2016 12:26:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/denver-real-estate-agent-how-to-handle.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/denver-real-estate-agent-how-to-handle.html</guid>
        
        <category>Advice for Denver Sellers</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
