<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Calgary Real Estate Video Blog with Eric Mortimer</title>
    <description>Our mission at Eric Mortimer &amp; Associates is to be your best resource for Calgary real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Eric Mortimer &amp; Associates, your professional Calgary Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 14:26:07 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 14:26:07 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Major Mistakes to Avoid When Selling Your House</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/tAxr4rFkxW8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are trying to sell your property, it’s important to avoid these three cardinal real estate sins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Winging it without a proper pricing strategy&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s very important to have the correct pricing strategy right from the start. The price is not just about location, location, location and the strengths and weaknesses of your property. We have to look at the technical analysis and economic data, which includes things like the absorption rate, days on market, and trends in your neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To determine the right price for your home, we’ll look at a few different factors. First of all, we’ll look at expired, withdrawn, or terminated listings. Those homes were rejected by the market. Then, we’ll look at recently sold properties, which will give us an idea of what your home could sell for. Finally, we’ll look at active listings that are currently on the market. These listings are your competition, so we need to see how your home compares to those properties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Determining the price of your home means walking the very fine line between selling your home close to market value without leaving any money on the table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Promoting too little&lt;/strong&gt;. There are a lot of distractions out there these days. Corporations spend billions of dollars on weapons of mass distraction to get your attention. To get and keep a homebuyer’s attention, you need superior online and offline marketing strategies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That means we will promote your home on social media and online classifieds with professional photos and virtual tours. Offline, we’ll use door hangers, open houses, and signage. People still look at traditional, offline strategies. Since we never know where a buyer will come from, it’s important to cover all of our bases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not making your property presentable&lt;/strong&gt;. You don’t get a second chance to make a great first impression. Make sure your property looks its best from the very start. It should look fantastic in the pictures and for every showing. Make sure that the house looks clean and consider adding a fresh layer of paint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Work with an agent who has a professional stager.%20http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/3-major-mistakes-to-avoid-when-selling-your-house.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Work with an agent who has a professional stager.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s very important to pick everything up in your home. Even a little bit of clutter can stop a buyer from making an offer. Work with an agent who has a professional stager. Having the property professionally staged will put your home over the top and ensure that your sale will happen as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you avoid these three major mistakes when selling your home, you will succeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about selling your home or pour current real estate market, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 05:31:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/3-major-mistakes-to-avoid-when-selling-your-house.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/3-major-mistakes-to-avoid-when-selling-your-house.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Ways to Avoid Buyer's Remorse</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/AHE3dKk3zHk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Far too often, buyers find what they think is the perfect home only to be disappointed after they move in. Once the rose-colored glasses come off and problems start to become apparent, they are left with serious buyer’s remorse. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to real estate, regretting your purchase isn’t as simple as going back to a store and telling the cashier that you’ve changed your mind about what you bought. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, this situation can be avoided if you’re equipped with the right knowledge. There are a few key things you should never overlook when buying a home. Today, I’d like to share five tips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make sure to go see the property at night.&lt;/strong&gt; You want to make sure that you see your property at various times of the day. A home can look and be very different at different times. It isn’t just danger you need to worry about. Perhaps you’ve only seen the property during the day when many of your neighbors were out or at work. If you move in believing you have plenty of street parking only to find out that the entire block looks different after sundown, you could end up with some problems.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t forget to figure out your new commute. &lt;/strong&gt;Nowadays, distance tends to be measured in time instead of in kilometers or miles. Make sure you check out your route to work and other critical places when considering a new home. Traffic is another thing to consider, so be sure to drive the route you would take during different times of the day. This will give you the best feel for what things will truly be like. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pay attention to features that can’t be changed.&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t let yourself be blinded by flashy details. Things like a jacuzzi or an Elvis mural shouldn’t outweigh features like the floorplan and the lot location. Personal details and flashy touches can be added down the line. For example, even the most spectacular house may not be worth it if it’s in a terrible location. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t overlook the property’s resale value.&lt;/strong&gt; Properties will always come with their own unique set of features and challenges. While a home sitting on a busy street may not be a problem for you, it will be an issue for other buyers. Even if you don’t plan to move for quite some time, you still need to think about resale value from the very start.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pay attention to the bedroom-to-bathroom ratio. &lt;/strong&gt;Ideally, you want to have an ensuite and at least one guest bathroom. The more bathrooms, the better. No one should ever be upset about too many bathrooms. And no, two toilets in one room do not count as multiple bathrooms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=When it comes to real estate, regretting your purchase isn’t as simple as going back to a store and telling the cashier that you’ve changed your mind.%20http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/5-ways-to-avoid-buyers-remorse.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“When it comes to real estate, regretting your purchase isn’t as simple as going back to a store and telling the cashier that you’ve changed your mind.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 09:48:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/5-ways-to-avoid-buyers-remorse.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/5-ways-to-avoid-buyers-remorse.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Do the Latest Figures Say About Our Calgary Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7G7HiFmE_6Q?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s the latest real estate news from Calgary?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is still some uncertainty in our market with fluctuating interest rates, and there are some new rules in place that have knocked some buyers out of the market. &lt;strong&gt;Due to decreased demand, inventory has increased.&lt;/strong&gt; However, there are new rules coming down the pipeline which will most likely give us a little boost because buyers have a fear of missing out before the rules change again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s look at the latest numbers. &lt;strong&gt;In September, we had 6,861 listings and 1,462 home sales, and Calgary’s overall benchmark price for that month was $441,500.&lt;/strong&gt; The average price for detached houses was $508,900, the price for attached homes was up to $336,000, and the price for condos was $263,700.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I often say, though, averages are dangerous. You can have your head in the oven and your feet in the freezer and your average temperature would be OK, but you wouldn’t be feeling too good. This rationale also applies to our market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=As I often say, averages are dangerous.%20http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/what-do-the-latest-figures-say-about-our-calgary-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“As I often say, averages are dangerous.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a look at our months of inventory, for example. In Northwest Calgary, things are relatively hot, and we’re just above our three-month moving average. Just above that in North Calgary, the moving average is also just above three months, but in reality, things are much cooler because there is about 5.5 months of inventory available on the market right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are challenges and opportunities in both these kinds of markets&lt;/strong&gt;—it really just depends on where you are, having the right skill set, and having the right plan in place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next time, we’ll talk about three seller mistakes you want to avoid in today’s changing market and what you shouldn’t overlook when buying your next property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, if you have any questions about our current market, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 06:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/what-do-the-latest-figures-say-about-our-calgary-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/what-do-the-latest-figures-say-about-our-calgary-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
