<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Andrey Bustamante Team</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from  - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://bustamanteblog.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://bustamanteblog.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 16:24:43 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 16:24:43 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are You a Real Estate Agent Open to New and Exciting Opportunities?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wweeYA24ZwM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re looking for agents to join our real estate team.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Specifically, we’re looking for people that have just as much passion for real estate as we do. We work with clients all day, and we’re committed to providing the best possible service we can.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The Andrey Bustamante Real Estate Team is a great fit for anybody who wants to build a strong real estate foundation. The ideal candidate is self motivated, self managed but learning based and coachable. A team player that can integrate and work well within a team environment. Enthusiastic, positive, hardworking, confident but humble, resourceful, techie, and most of all honest and ethical. Must be committed to personal and professional development through reading and constant learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The Andrey Bustamante Real Estate Team is a great fit for anybody who wants to build a strong real estate foundation.%20http://bustamanteblog.com/are-you-a-real-estate-agent-open-to-new-and-exciting-opportunities.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The Andrey Bustamante Real Estate Team is a great fit for anybody who wants to build a strong real estate foundation.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you’re motivated to meet financial goals and love learning with a team, we encourage you to visit our career day on December 8th from 2-4pm at 400 North Mills Avenue, Orlando Florida. Please RSVP to Careers@BustamanteRE.com.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you have any questions, visit our website, give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://bustamanteblog.com/are-you-a-real-estate-agent-open-to-new-and-exciting-opportunities.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://bustamanteblog.com/are-you-a-real-estate-agent-open-to-new-and-exciting-opportunities.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are Zestimates Trustworthy?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/X1Va84E5LCI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you go about determining the value of your home?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, in today’s modern world, much of our research for any real estate transaction starts online. This is true for determining home values as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there have been a lot of questions raised recently about researching home value online. Zillow’s Zestimate in particular has been the topic of many conversations lately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, &lt;strong&gt;an Illinois homeowner is actually suing Zillow because of how she believes the Zestimate has damaged her listing.&lt;/strong&gt; She believes that the Zestimate massively undervalued her home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our endorser Barbara Corcoran, real estate mogul and star of the show “Shark Tank,” recently went on “Good Morning America” to talk about Zillow and this lawsuit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This lawsuit, Barbara says, actually makes sense. The homeowner believed her home was &lt;strong&gt;worth $626,000 compared to the Zestimate’s value of $562,000—that’s a $64,000 difference.&lt;/strong&gt; This homeowner claimed this made a difference because buyers saw and responded to that lower price while doing their research on Zillow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the lawsuit was filed, Zillow actually responded by saying that “The Zestimate is a starting point to determine a home’s value and isn’t an official appraisal. The plaintiff can update her own Zestimate by adding the square footage of her home.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Zillow doesn’t claim that their Zestimate is an appraisal, but consumers are using it like one.%20http://bustamanteblog.com/are-zestimates-trustworthy.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Zillow doesn’t claim that their Zestimate is an appraisal, but consumers are using it like one.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Barbara Corcoran admits that Zillow has been very upfront about their Zestimate not being an official appraisal. However, the issue is that &lt;strong&gt;this doesn’t change the fact that many buyers assume this information is accurate.&lt;/strong&gt; This is especially problematic given the fact that the margin of error for the Zestimate is about 5%. Additionally, one in 10 homes are valued at more than 20% less than they’re actually worth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Zestimate, Barbara says, is not accurate. Instead, it should be a starting point. The Zestimate will give you a range of values, but can’t take into consideration things like upgrades. If you’ve extended the patio, added a pool, renovated the kitchen, or made other improvements, the Zestimate simply can’t account for these changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As much as technology companies would like to replace agents in real estate transactions, it simply won’t happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though Zillow doesn’t claim that their Zestimate is an appraisal, consumers are using it as if it is one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If homeowners truly want to get the best price, they need to deeply understand its value. &lt;strong&gt;Barbara recommends relying on the help of a real estate professional instead of on an algorithm.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to learn how we can help you sell your home, want more information, or have any other questions, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://bustamanteblog.com/are-zestimates-trustworthy.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://bustamanteblog.com/are-zestimates-trustworthy.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
