<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Greater Vancouver Group Real Estate Video Blog</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from the Greater Vancouver Group - your professional Vancouver Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://yvrrealestateblog.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://yvrrealestateblog.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 16:57:11 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 16:57:11 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>10 Secrets Every Homebuyer Deserves to Know</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wHZoK0BVTuo&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most homes up for sale on the market are resale homes, but one out of every four homebuyers opts for a brand new home. New and resale homes each come with their own advantages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, how do you know which is the right choice for you?
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;On average, resale homes are less expensive and generally have the warmth and feeling of an established neighborhood. New homes, on the other hand, offer modern energy efficiency, innovative use of space, and everything is new—including the neighbors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=This report is full of secrets that most homebuyers don't know and builders won't divulge.%20http://yvrrealestateblog.com/10-secrets-every-homebuyer-deserves-to-know.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“This report is full of secrets that most homebuyers don’t know and builders won’t divulge.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Determining which option is best for you depends on many things, from your tastes to your family makeup and your finances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, there’s a new special report recently released that shares 10 secrets that every buyer should know if they are looking to buy a new home. &lt;strong&gt;These are secrets that most homebuyers don’t know and builders won’t divulge.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.greatervancouvergroup.com/info/new-homes-vs-resale&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Click here to see the full report&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This report will undoubtedly impact your decision to buy a new home or a resale property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about the market here in the Vancouver, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email soon. We’re here to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://yvrrealestateblog.com/10-secrets-every-homebuyer-deserves-to-know.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yvrrealestateblog.com/10-secrets-every-homebuyer-deserves-to-know.html</guid>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>End the Waiting Game and Enter the Housing Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/OM38EIECA7A&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming up with an adequate down payment is perceived as an insurmountable barrier to many potential homebuyers. However, there is a new homeownership program that lowers this barrier for qualified buyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of whether you are renting and looking to buy your first home or if you have owned a home before, this program can help you purchase a home with little to no money down. You don’t need $20,000 or more for a down payment, so don’t hesitate to enter the market. &lt;strong&gt;After all, why not build your own equity instead of paying your landlord’s mortgage?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=End the waiting game and enter the real estate market!%20http://yvrrealestateblog.com/end-the-waiting-game-and-enter-the-housing-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“End the waiting game and enter the real estate market!”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Industry insiders have prepared a new special report called, “How to Buy a Home With Little or No Money Down” which explains how this new, innovative program can get you into the market immediately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;End the waiting by requesting your copy of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.greatervancouvergroup.com/info/buy-with-zero-down&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;this report here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. If you have any other questions, please don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://yvrrealestateblog.com/end-the-waiting-game-and-enter-the-housing-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yvrrealestateblog.com/end-the-waiting-game-and-enter-the-housing-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Our Hot List Can Help First-Time Vancouver Homebuyers</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/KGIM97JG_e0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you a first-time homebuyer in the Vancouver area?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ve probably noticed that affordable homes in desirable neighborhoods sell very quickly. Timing is incredibly important. If you want to buy your first home, then you need to be ready to act right away, especially in this market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our hot list of first-time buyer homes will give you the advanced information that you need to be prepared.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The hot list gives you a huge advantage over other buyers in the market.%20http://yvrrealestateblog.com/our-hot-list-can-help-first-time-vancouver-homebuyers.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The hot list gives you a huge advantage over other buyers in the market.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will receive a free report with photos which identifies the best buys on the market for first-time buyers. The list will feature homes in your desired price range and location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hot list uses a simple, efficient format to provide you key information at no extra cost or obligation. This list will give you a huge advantage over other buyers in the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get your list, go to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.greatervancouvergroup.com/info/first-time-buyers-hotlist&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mybuyershotlist.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and enter your criteria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, please don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://yvrrealestateblog.com/our-hot-list-can-help-first-time-vancouver-homebuyers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yvrrealestateblog.com/our-hot-list-can-help-first-time-vancouver-homebuyers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Get Your Agent to Work 2x Harder</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Lp1Er39M-64&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The fact is, there isn’t much more to the average agent than the agent themselves.&lt;/strong&gt; Most agents operate a one-person show and they are probably breaking their backs trying to do a good job for their clients. Most agents couldn’t work harder than they are already working.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sometimes, clients can actually suffer from their agent’s good intentions.&lt;/strong&gt; The fact is, you may be sympathetic to the fact that your agent is working as hard as humanly possible, but if the quality and profitability of your home sale suffers as a result of them trying to do everything themselves, you have the right to feel cheated.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;The simple explanation is that we have built a team of professionals to help us be in 10 places at once, therefore greatly enhancing the quality of service we can deliver to our clients. This is how other professionals like your banks and lawyers run their businesses. On top of that, we have used cutting-edge technology to dramatically improve the speed, efficiency, and innovative capabilities of every part of the service we deliver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We sell our clients’ homes for more money.%20http://yvrrealestateblog.com/how-to-get-your-agent-to-work-2x-harder.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We sell our clients’ homes for more money.”&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;We don’t expect you to care about the fine details of the inner-workings of our office. What you should care about is that because of the highly unique way we have structured our real estate office, &lt;strong&gt;our clients’ homes sell for more money in less time.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Our team sells a lot of homes. We have extensive home selling experience that puts more money in our clients’ pockets. To find out more about how our team approach can make you more successful in the real estate market, simply visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.greatervancouvergroup.com/info/our-team&quot;&gt;www.getmorewithus.net&lt;/a&gt; and fill out the form. We’ll be in touch!
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;If you have any questions for us, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We would love to hear from you. Stay tuned for next week’s episode.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://yvrrealestateblog.com/how-to-get-your-agent-to-work-2x-harder.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yvrrealestateblog.com/how-to-get-your-agent-to-work-2x-harder.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What 6 Mistakes Do Home Buyers Make Most Often?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/SoAusKXWzyU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s good, Vancouver family? Welcome to 2017! If you’ve been considering moving up to a bigger home, we’ve got great news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our new report has been released titled “6 Things You Must Know Before You Buy.” When you are planning to buy a new home while you already own one, there are certain factors that can make a situation more complicated than it was the first time. Before you list your home for sale, it’s very important to understand these issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides financing, you also have to time the sale of your present home so you can avoid the “Real estate catch-22”. This means either bearing the financial burden of owning two homes at once or facing the dilemma of having no place to live in the gap between possession dates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=This report will help you make an informed choice.%20http://yvrrealestateblog.com/what-6-mistakes-do-home-buyers-make-most-often.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“This report will help you make an informed choice.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To address these issues, we have prepared a free special report for you, the aforementioned “6 Things You Must Know Before You Buy”. &lt;strong&gt;To receive a copy, simply&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.greatervancouvergroup.com/info/6-buyer-mistakes&quot;&gt;visit our site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt; and request your copy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This report will help you make an informed choice before putting your home on the market in preparation for moving to a larger home. Order this report now to find out what you need to know to make your move to a larger home free of worry and complication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for us, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://yvrrealestateblog.com/what-6-mistakes-do-home-buyers-make-most-often.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yvrrealestateblog.com/what-6-mistakes-do-home-buyers-make-most-often.html</guid>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Keys to Negotiating Your Home's Best Price</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/OpV2f8xjSI4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For most people, “getting top dollar” is number one on their list of goals when selling their home. These same people, however, feel ill-equipped to achieve this goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since various market factors can cause large swings, pricing a home is an imperfect science to begin with, and the skills of the person responsible for negotiating for the home can also impact the outcome of the transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, negotiating effectively doesn’t have to be as difficult or scary as you would expect. Like anything else, &lt;strong&gt;if you have a proven system to follow and know the signals and language, you can successfully turn the tables in your favor.&lt;/strong&gt; Who better to borrow these skills from than professional negotiators who sit across the table to try to out-bargain their opponents every day?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The art of negotiation doesn’t have to be difficult or scary.%20http://yvrrealestateblog.com/the-keys-to-negotiating-your-homes-best-price.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The art of negotiation doesn’t have to be difficult or scary.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The system we follow as professionals is outlined in a new, free special report for home sellers that explains the four most common mistakes sellers make when negotiating the sale price of their home. One local area resident credits the knowledge gained from the information revealed in this free special report with netting thousands more than their original asking price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get this report, visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.greatervancouvergroup.com/info/getting-the-best-price&quot;&gt;www.mostmoney.net&lt;/a&gt; and find out how you can get the highest possible price when you sell your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking of buying, selling, or investing, please visit our website, give us a call, or email us today. Keep it real, Vancouver—we look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://yvrrealestateblog.com/the-keys-to-negotiating-your-homes-best-price.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yvrrealestateblog.com/the-keys-to-negotiating-your-homes-best-price.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
