<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Robbins Real Estate - your professional Dallas-Fort Worth Texas Real Estate Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>Mindyandjayrobbins.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="Mindyandjayrobbins.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 14:03:41 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 14:03:41 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>We’re Making Our Service Even Better in 2018</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/voGMcaSLbM8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We have some very exciting news to share with you today. We want you all to be the first to know that Robbins Real Estate Group is now officially a part of Coldwell Banker Residential Real Estate Brokerage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We’re proud to announce that we’ve joined Coldwell Banker.%20Mindyandjayrobbins.com/were-making-our-service-even-better-in-2018.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We’re proud to announce that we’ve joined Coldwell Banker.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those of you who have worked with us in the past, you know to expect the highest possible level of service. Now that we’re a part of Coldwell Banker, &lt;strong&gt;we can introduce you to an even higher level of service with our advanced marketing, luxury branding, and global reach of professional Realtors.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re really excited to help you, so if you’re thinking of buying or selling a home anytime in the near future, please reach out to us via phone or email. We would love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 11:00:29 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>Mindyandjayrobbins.com/were-making-our-service-even-better-in-2018.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">Mindyandjayrobbins.com/were-making-our-service-even-better-in-2018.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Handling Multiple Offers as a Buyer or Seller</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/h0cPjJfjR1o?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we deal with both buyers and sellers, we see a lot of multiple offers at our brokerage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multiple offers come with their own unique set of issues on both sides of the transaction,&lt;/strong&gt; which is something we’ve seen firsthand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sellers, for example, might have a hard time knowing which to choose when they receive multiple offers. Price isn’t the only factor to consider when looking at all the different offers on the table, but it should be the first thing you look at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That said, the highest price isn’t always the best offer.&lt;/strong&gt; Sometimes you’ll need to weigh your options. For instance, a buyer who offers cash but offers to pay slightly less than the highest offer may still be a strong choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a cash offer, you wouldn’t need to worry about the mortgage approval or appraisal.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you’re a buyer, multiple offer situations are more likely to be a sure thing.%20Mindyandjayrobbins.com/handling-multiple-offers-as-a-buyer-or-seller.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you’re a buyer, multiple offer situations are more likely to be a sure thing.”&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;There are other factors to be considered, as well. For example, a flexible buyer who is willing to let you lease the property while you finish your own moving process may be the strongest offer for your situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a buyer, multiple offer situations are likely more of a sure thing. In today’s competitive market, there’s a strong chance you’ll need to find ways to make yourself stand out against other offers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few ways you can do this. Putting down a lot of earnest money, making a high down payment, making the highest offer possible, and making the terms easy for the seller are all things that will make your offer more attractive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, when you work with an agent who has a good reputation, &lt;strong&gt;you’ll find that the seller’s listing agent will be more likely to recommend your offer to their client.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 06:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>Mindyandjayrobbins.com/handling-multiple-offers-as-a-buyer-or-seller.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">Mindyandjayrobbins.com/handling-multiple-offers-as-a-buyer-or-seller.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Is the Dallas Market Doing?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/OEN4ImAuPvs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;Mindy and I often get asked about the state of today’s market. In fact, this is probably the No. 1 question we get from buyers and sellers alike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;Thankfully, our market here in Dallas is very healthy. We’ve had a strong seller’s market for years, but from looking at recent news &lt;strong&gt;we may be seeing the market begin to cool off.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;Recently we had lunch with a big, local lender who told us that applications for mortgage purchase loans are down by 10%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;This information points to a potential balancing off coming into the market.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Our market here in Dallas is very healthy.%20Mindyandjayrobbins.com/how-is-the-dallas-market-doing.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Our market here in Dallas is very healthy.”&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;But this doesn’t mean that you should panic if you’re a seller. &lt;strong&gt;If you have a good Realtor who will be able to do the right kind of marketing, you can still command top dollar for your listing.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;And if you’re a buyer, this shift in the market could mean you’ll have more leverage so long as you know where to look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;Homes under $300,000 still have a lot of high demand and are likely to continue seeing multiple-offer situations. However, these conditions still aren’t quite as harsh as what we’ve seen in the last couple of years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call at (214) 444-9014 or send us an email at Jay@TeamRobbins.com.  We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 10:34:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>Mindyandjayrobbins.com/how-is-the-dallas-market-doing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">Mindyandjayrobbins.com/how-is-the-dallas-market-doing.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Accurate Is Zillow's Zestimate?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/GtQEAbmnyM4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zillow is one of the most common websites used today by people trying to figure out the value of their home.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;However, while Zillow might be a good way to get a ballpark figure, you might think twice about trusting its accuracy. In fact, The New York Times and multiple Seattle newspapers have reported that &lt;strong&gt;the CEO of Zillow sold his home for 40% less than the Zestimate.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;In other words, the Zestimate can be and often is, inaccurate. Right here in Dallas, it tends to be off by an average of 5%.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;This might sound like a fairly close evaluation but for those seriously considering buying or selling a home 5% could total about $15,000 in today’s local market
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The best way to make sure that your estimate is accurate is to hire a real estate professional.%20Mindyandjayrobbins.com/how-accurate-is-zillows-zestimate.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The best way to make sure that your estimate is accurate is to hire a real estate professional.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;The best way to make sure that your estimate is accurate and that you are making the most out of a real estate transaction is to hire a real estate professional.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Working alongside someone able to determine a realistic price is going to make a big difference in your pocket.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;So how does Zillow determine values, anyway? Well, they use a computer. As you and I both know, a computer is not what determines the value of a home.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A home’s value is determined by what a buyer is willing to pay as well as what the seller is willing to list it for.&lt;/strong&gt; These two figures can be vastly different from what a computer might estimate.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;If you’re looking to buy or sell a home, want professional advice, or have any other questions, feel free to give us a call at (214) 444-9014 or send us an email at Jay@TeamRobbins.com. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 10:21:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>Mindyandjayrobbins.com/how-accurate-is-zillows-zestimate.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">Mindyandjayrobbins.com/how-accurate-is-zillows-zestimate.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
