<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>St. Louis Metro Area Real Estate Video Blog with Sandie Hea, CRS</title>
    <description>Our mission at RE/MAX Results is to be your best resource for St. Louis Metro Area real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The RE/MAX Results, your professional St. Louis Metro Area Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://aboutstlouishomes.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://aboutstlouishomes.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 17:03:12 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 17:03:12 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Tips for Airbnb Investment Properties</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/sVKMNRQk0NQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’re talking about Airbnb. I’ve had a lot of real estate investors calling me up recently and telling me that they want to buy a property to use as a short-term rental. In most cases, investors actually make a lot more money on these properties than they do on long-term rentals, but &lt;strong&gt;there are three factors you definitely need to consider when looking at making an investment in this type of property.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. The zoning and restrictions in the area.&lt;/strong&gt; For example, you can have an Airbnb in Maplewood, but there are certain restrictions involved. In the city of St. Louis, there are currently no such restrictions in place. Crestwood is another area where Airbnb properties aren’t allowed, but that isn’t really an area where you should be looking for an investment property like this anyway. In St. Louis, Airbnb is mostly used by tourists. They would rather stay in the heart of the city near tourist attractions than out in the suburbs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Management.&lt;/strong&gt; You’ll have to furnish your short-term rental property with linens, kitchen supplies, furniture, and more. You’ll also need to have the place cleaned between visitors. You can do this yourself, but you can also hire a property manager to do it for you. Collecting the booking fee is the easy part. Keeping up with the day-to-day management of the property is the real challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Do you have an exit strategy?%20http://aboutstlouishomes.com/3-tips-for-airbnb-investment-properties.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Do you have an exit strategy?”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Your exit strategy.&lt;/strong&gt; What happens if the ordinances change in your area or you just get tired of managing the property? Turning it into a long-term rental property is certainly an option, especially if you’re in an area with consistent home appreciation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been running my own Airbnb and have first-hand knowledge so I hope these tips are helpful. If you have any questions for me about this or any other topic related to real estate or real estate investing, don’t hesitate to reach out and give me a call or send me an email. I would love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 14:23:56 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://aboutstlouishomes.com/3-tips-for-airbnb-investment-properties.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://aboutstlouishomes.com/3-tips-for-airbnb-investment-properties.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Facts That Peel Back the Curtain on Zillow</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/5vzFaFKiTEQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You probably know this already, but the website Zillow has something that they call a Zestimate. It’s essentially an automated home valuation tool. &lt;strong&gt;I want to point out three things about this tool that show just how reliable (or unreliable) it is:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Zillow is a marketing company, not a real estate company. &lt;/strong&gt;As a marketing company, the data that they have is provided by real estate agents. However, not all agents want to give up their data to Zillow. This means the data is often inaccurate and ultimately limited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Zillow uses an algorithm.&lt;/strong&gt; However, this algorithm uses that same limited data to come up with a Zestimate. For instance, a house that backs up to a highway or a railroad track could be valued the same as a house in a quiet cul-de-sac. A house that hasn’t been updated in decades and a house that’s had a major overhaul could be right next door to each other and their Zestimates could be almost identical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Let me help you navigate the market.%20http://aboutstlouishomes.com/3-facts-that-peel-back-the-curtain-on-zillow.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Let me help you navigate the market.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Did you know that Zillow’s CEO sold his Seattle home for 40% under its Zestimate? &lt;/strong&gt;Zillow’s website even has a disclaimer that says their figures could be up to 15% inaccurate. 15% on a $300,000 house is $45,000. That’s a huge swing in either direction. That’s like fudging on your weight by 15 lbs and getting caught by your doctor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In short, never rely on Zillow as a means to price a home you want to sell &lt;/strong&gt;or to figure out a good asking price on the house you want to buy. Let me help you navigate the real estate market with the truth of the numbers in the MLS and my own personal experience in the business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or need any real estate advice, give me a call or send me an email anytime. I look forward to hearing from you soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 09:18:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://aboutstlouishomes.com/3-facts-that-peel-back-the-curtain-on-zillow.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://aboutstlouishomes.com/3-facts-that-peel-back-the-curtain-on-zillow.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>See How Realtors Are Getting Rich Off of You!</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZTl4Ab4h6Rw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our current market, many people think that agents get rich off of seller commissions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’ll illustrate where those commission funds go during a real estate transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For the sake of easy math, let’s imagine the commission fee is $1.&lt;/strong&gt;Out of that $1, the traditional listing agent will give back half to the buyer’s agent. Of the 50 cents left, the agent will then give half to their broker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This leaves the agent with just 25 cents left from the original commission. Out of that 25 cents, the agent is paying for their own health insurance, retirement fund, gas/insurance for their car, and self-employment tax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For RE/MAX agents, that 25 cents is split up a little differently. This goes towards a monthly management fee, the costs of travel, marketing expenses, office rent, health insurance, signs/lockboxes, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With all of the out-of-pocket expenses agents pay, there isn’t much of a profit left over after everything is said and done.&lt;/strong&gt;It’s easy to see that agents like myself are in this business because we want to help you succeed with your real estate goals. It isn’t about the money—it’s about serving our clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 09:02:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://aboutstlouishomes.com/see-how-realtors-are-getting-rich-off-of-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://aboutstlouishomes.com/see-how-realtors-are-getting-rich-off-of-you.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>When You Leave Your Home, What Should Stay Behind?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/dno-8if0n00?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a seller, what items should you leave behind for the buyer when you move out of your home? Here’s a list of key items and things to consider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Leave a key for every door.&lt;/strong&gt; This includes any outdoor buildings, sheds, or padlocks that are on the property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Leave your garage door remotes.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Leave the keyless code for garage entry.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Leave any warranty paperwork.&lt;/strong&gt; Remember to leave behind receipts for repairs and instruction manuals for any of the items in your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Leave building materials.&lt;/strong&gt;Some buyers will not want these items. Which brings us to the next point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Ask buyers if they want certain items.&lt;/strong&gt; This includes paint, building materials, shelving units, and big pieces of furniture that are difficult to remove.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Wipe down appliances and countertops.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. Sweep and vacuum.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. Leave a note about the neighborhood and neighbors.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10. Leave a bottle of wine, a wine opener, and a nice note.&lt;/strong&gt; If you have had a very positive experience with the buyer so far, this can be a good way to foster further positivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 03:43:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://aboutstlouishomes.com/when-you-leave-your-home-what-should-stay-behind.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://aboutstlouishomes.com/when-you-leave-your-home-what-should-stay-behind.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Does Earnest Money Function Within a Home Sale?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Y2fX1gi-nlU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is earnest money? As a buyer, how much do you need and what happens to that sum if the deal terminates?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Earnest money is the amount of money a buyer puts down to ask the seller to take their house off the market&lt;/strong&gt; in order for them to do their due diligence during a certain time frame. That money is held in a non-interest bearing escrow account, typically by either the title company or the real estate company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How much earnest money you need depends on what area you live in&lt;/strong&gt;, but a typical scenario would be 1% of the purchase price of the house. It can always be more or less than that because it’s a negotiable item on the contract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Typically, earnest money accounts for 1% of the total purchase price.%20http://aboutstlouishomes.com/how-does-earnest-money-function-within-a-home-sale.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Typically, earnest money accounts for 1% of the total purchase price.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the deal terminates, the earnest money is supposed to be returned to the buyer if the buyer did everything they were supposed to do according to the contract, the contingencies were not fulfilled, and they’re legally allowed to back out of the contract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if the buyer simply changes their mind and has no legal ground for terminating the offer, the earnest money could be up for grabs. The earnest money isn’t simply handed back over to the buyer. There is paperwork called a “mutual release,” which must be signed by all parties stating how much of that money is to be returned to the buyer, whether that means all of it or some of it. There can be a lot of other issues that go along with returning earnest money, but that’s it in a nutshell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any more questions about earnest money or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home in the St. Louis metro area, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 10:41:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://aboutstlouishomes.com/how-does-earnest-money-function-within-a-home-sale.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://aboutstlouishomes.com/how-does-earnest-money-function-within-a-home-sale.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Secret to Winning a Bidding War</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/LGU_2Gn_-0M?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is an escalation clause? How does it pertain to you as a homebuyer?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The escalation clause is something that’s written into your contract by your buyer’s agent. It states that &lt;strong&gt;you will pay X amount of money (let’s say $500 to $1,000) over the asking price of any other bona fide contract that the seller receives prior to the acceptance of any offers.&lt;/strong&gt; The escalation goes up to a certain dollar amount.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say the house you want is $300,000 and you’d be willing to pay $320,000 for it. Rather than just write an offer for $320,000, you would write an offer that’s a little bit over what everyone else wrote. If there are five other offers and the highest one is $305,00, and you said you’d pay as much as $1,000 over any other offer, you’d pay $306,000 for the house. This way, you get the house without having to pay the full $320,000!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=An escalation clause can mean the difference between winning and losing your dream home.%20http://aboutstlouishomes.com/the-secret-to-winning-a-bidding-war.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“An escalation clause can mean the difference between winning and losing your dream home.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The escalation clause is a lot more complicated than what I just made it out to be, but it’s one of those things that, if used correctly, &lt;strong&gt;can mean the difference between winning the house and losing the house.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m an expert when it comes to escalation clauses, and I’d love to help you win your next bid on your next dream home. If you have any questions about this topic or our St. Louis market, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I’d be happy to speak with you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 06:57:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://aboutstlouishomes.com/the-secret-to-winning-a-bidding-war.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://aboutstlouishomes.com/the-secret-to-winning-a-bidding-war.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A 3rd Quarter Update for the St. Louis Metro Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZCUK1zy9hZ4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s time for another market update. Today, I want to bring you some information from the third quarter of 2017 in St. Louis’ metro market. This update will include data from St. Louis City, St. Louis County, and Charles County.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;St. Louis City saw an uptick of $10,000 in the median sales price this year compared to last.&lt;/strong&gt;In 2016, there were 1,024 sales in the third quarter. This year, there were 1,034 sales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In St. Louis County, there were 4,428 sales this year. This is up from 4,340 sales last year. However, median sales price barely changed. Last year it was $190,554. This year, the median sales price for the third quarter was $191,333.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of the large amount of new construction in Charles County, their prices have increased quite a bit. In St. Charles County, there were 2,108 sales in 2016, but sales dropped in the third quarter of 2017 to just 2,083.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=My overall feeling about the market is that now is a good time to buy.%20http://aboutstlouishomes.com/a-3rd-quarter-update-for-the-st-louis-metro-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“My overall feeling about the market is that now is a good time to buy.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the median sales price was up considerably, going up to $217,667 from last year’s $201,250. &lt;strong&gt;New construction is largely to thank for this increase in price.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My overall feeling about the market is that now is a good time to buy. Rates are still significantly low, hovering around 4%. External factors are also in our favor since we don’t tend to experience severe weather that could impact our market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 05:43:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://aboutstlouishomes.com/a-3rd-quarter-update-for-the-st-louis-metro-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://aboutstlouishomes.com/a-3rd-quarter-update-for-the-st-louis-metro-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>These 3 Inspections Could Save You a Lot of Trouble Later On</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/za84fMM39qs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I’m back talking about more home inspections I recommend you get before purchasing a property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buying a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stlouispropertysearch.net/&quot;&gt;Click here to perform a full home search&lt;/a&gt;Selling a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stlouishomevalues.net/&quot;&gt;Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’re back with part two of our coverage on home inspections. Like last time, I’ll be going over a few inspections I think are the most important if you’re buying a new home. Whenever you are about to make a home purchase, you need to know exactly what you’re getting into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, don’t underestimate the importance of a termite inspection. Termites can do a great deal of damage. You certainly wouldn’t want to purchase a home only to find out that you’ll be dealing with these pests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Termites are also something homeowners should check for on an annual basis.&lt;/strong&gt; For about $65, a termite inspection is well worth the cost. Mud tunnels or damage to the wood are two strong indicators that a home may have termites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, I recommend a radon inspection. Radon is an odorless, colorless gas that seeps out from the Earth’s surface. This gas can come up through cracks in the basement or foundation, as well as through any holes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=YOU NEED TO KNOW EXACTLY WHAT YOU’RE GETTING INTO WHEN YOU PURCHASE A HOME.%20http://aboutstlouishomes.com/these-3-inspections-could-save-you-a-lot-of-trouble-later-on.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“YOU NEED TO KNOW EXACTLY WHAT YOU’RE GETTING INTO WHEN YOU PURCHASE A HOME.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the EPA, a radon level higher than 4.0 picocuries per liter is a hazard. At this point the levels will need to be mitigated, since &lt;strong&gt;radon is the second leading cause of lung cancer in the United States.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, there are ways to test for it. Certified radon inspectors can come out and set up a test that will monitor your home for two-and-a-half days. This test costs about $150 and will determine whether the radon level needs to be lowered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third inspection I recommend is to have an environmental inspection done. This is especially important if your family has allergies. Having a test for mold is one of the more common environmental inspections out there. &lt;strong&gt;Mold can be present anywhere in a home, and is especially likely if the property has taken on any water.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 10:37:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://aboutstlouishomes.com/these-3-inspections-could-save-you-a-lot-of-trouble-later-on.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://aboutstlouishomes.com/these-3-inspections-could-save-you-a-lot-of-trouble-later-on.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Common Real Estate Contract Contingencies</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0JBkrLDEyLA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which contingencies should you know about? Here are five of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buying a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stlouispropertysearch.net/&quot;&gt;Click here to perform a full home search&lt;/a&gt;Selling a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stlouishomevalues.net/&quot;&gt;Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is a real estate contingency? By definition, it’s a future event or circumstance that is possible but can not be predicted with certainty. There can be quite a few of them included within a real estate contract, as far as buyers are concerned. Here are five of the most common contingencies buyers include in a contract and what they mean:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Financing.&lt;/strong&gt; This kind of contingency means they will buy the house if the lender gives them the mortgage at the interest rate and terms they first agreed on and which are written into the sales contract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Appraisal.&lt;/strong&gt; This contingency means they will buy the house if the appraiser says the house is worth at least what the contract price is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Inspection.&lt;/strong&gt; In this case, the contingency states that will buy the house if they are happy with the inspections or negotiated repairs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=THESE CONTINGENCIES ARE STANDARD.%20http://aboutstlouishomes.com/5-common-real-estate-contract-contingencies.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“THESE CONTINGENCIES ARE STANDARD.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Survey.&lt;/strong&gt; A contingency based on a survey means buyers will buy the house if they are happy with the way the improvements fall within the boundaries of that property, as determined by a boundary survey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Title exam.&lt;/strong&gt; This contingency means they will buy the house if the title company determines that there are no liens or encumbrances against the seller on the title of that house and it comes out clear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Real estate transactions are complicated. Leave them in the hands of a professional. If you have any questions for me or any real estate needs I can assist with, I’d love to help you navigate the real estate jungle. Just give me a call or send me an email today. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 10:08:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://aboutstlouishomes.com/5-common-real-estate-contract-contingencies.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://aboutstlouishomes.com/5-common-real-estate-contract-contingencies.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Which Home Inspections Should You Order?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ekWMkvKCU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What inspections should you have done on the home you’re buying? Here’s a few to get you started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buying a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stlouispropertysearch.net/&quot;&gt;Click here to perform a full home search&lt;/a&gt;Selling a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stlouishomevalues.net/&quot;&gt;Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why should you have a home inspection when buying a home? Which inspections should you order? The first answer is obvious, but the second is not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home inspections protect your investment as a buyer.&lt;/strong&gt; If your home has a plumbing issue that may cost you thousands of dollars to repair down the line, wouldn’t you want to know about it before committing to purchase it? That’s the idea of home inspections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there are many different kinds of home inspections, so which is right for you? I’m going to go through a few of them today and explain how the process works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For starters, every homebuyer should have a building inspection that is completed by a certified home inspector. They will give you an overview of any problems in the house you are buying. They aren’t plumbers or electricians, but they are very knowledgable and will be able to spot a problem when they find it.The inspector will take note of any and all problems. &lt;strong&gt;They can then refer you to a professional who can better estimate the repairs.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inspector will spend at least a few hours in the home (around four hours for a 2,500 sq ft. house) and it’s important that you are with them every step of the way. It will help you better understand their findings and what you can do resolve any issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=EVERY BUYER SHOULD HAVE A BUILDING INSPECTION.%20http://aboutstlouishomes.com/which-home-inspections-should-you-order.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“EVERY BUYER SHOULD HAVE A BUILDING INSPECTION.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside from the building inspection, a gas inspection is another important one to consider. In the past, they were done by the local utility company. Now you can hire your own HVAC contractor to perform tests and make sure that any gas powered appliances are following the proper code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last inspection I wanted to mention today is the sewer lateral inspection. &lt;strong&gt;If you’re not buying a brand new home, there is a possibility that the plumbing underneath your home is made of old, clay pipes.&lt;/strong&gt; A sewer lateral inspection will alert you to any creaks, leaks, or invasive roots blocking your sewage lines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are just a few of the many inspections you can choose to have done on a home. Stay tuned for part two, where we’ll cover even more ground. In the meantime, if you have any questions for me at all don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email at your convenience. I look forward to hearing from you&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 14:22:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://aboutstlouishomes.com/which-home-inspections-should-you-order.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://aboutstlouishomes.com/which-home-inspections-should-you-order.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
