<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Your Key To Memphis - your professional Memphis Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 13:12:32 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 13:12:32 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>101 Things To Do In Memphis #76: The Bar-B-Q Shop</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/img/006.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bar-B-Q&quot; /&gt;
The Bar-B-Q Shop, &lt;strong&gt;voted #1 ribs in America&lt;/strong&gt; by the &lt;strong&gt;Food Network’s “Top Five Restaurants”&lt;/strong&gt;, located in the heart of Midtown, less than a mile from the Overton Square Entertainment District, is a local Memphis barbecue eatery that opened in November of 1987. It is a place known for real-pit barbecue with old fashioned barbecue sauces and cole slaw that are made from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The unique taste of The Bar-B-Q Shop’s gourmet award winning sauces has always been something that has set The Bar-B-Q Shop off from other barbeque restaurants. The recipes for our gourmet sauces have been around for over fifty years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Original (mild) Sauce provides a thickness that can be used to baste, marinade, or provide flavoring for your meat of choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our Hot Sauce also provides the same level of thickness but with a little warmth behind it. Our Hot Sauce does an excellent job of providing your meat with a hot flavor without taking away from the barbeque, smokey flavor itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bar-B-Q Shop’s Dry Seasoning was created later by Frank Vernon in the mid eighties. Our Dry Seasoning is an extraordinary seasoning because it can be used to season anything from chicken breasts, hamburger steaks, salmon or fillet catfish, to even a beef roast. The seasoning can be used with a marinade while prepping your food item, or it can be applied when your food comes out of the oven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1782 Madison Ave, Memphis, TN 38104
Restaurant: 901.272.1277
Sauce Order: 888.372.8237&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By and photo credit: &lt;a href=&quot;http://thebar-b-qshop.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Bar-B-Q Shop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/101-things-to-do-in-memphis-76-bar-b-q.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/101-things-to-do-in-memphis-76-bar-b-q.html</guid>
        
        <category>101 Things to do in Memphis</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>101 Things To Do In Memphis #76: The Bar-B-Q Shop</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/img/003.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Singles Dream Home&quot; /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Some Highlights:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-According to NAR’s Profile of Home Buyers &amp;amp; Sellers, the share of recent homebuyers who were single at the time of purchase held steady at 24% last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-The percentage of first-time buyers who were single females rose to 17% (up from 16%), as the share of single men dropped from 11% to 8%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-The primary reason for buying a home amongst singles was the desire to own a home of their own (38% for women and 37% for men).
​
​Contact your local expert’s at The Melissa Thompson Team 901-729-9526 to find out if you qualify to buy your dream home!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: KCM Crew&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/singles-are-falling-for-their-dream.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/singles-are-falling-for-their-dream.html</guid>
        
        <category>101 Things to do in Memphis</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Luxurious Laundry Rooms</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The laundry room is probably not the first space you think of when you hear the word luxurious.  But it is a room you spend a lot of time in.  Doing laundry is a necessary part of life, so why not make it more appealing by creating a comfortable, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hgtv.com/design/rooms/other-rooms/beautiful-and-efficient-laundry-room-designs-pictures&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;practical and pretty environment&lt;/a&gt; that will make it feel less like a chore and more like a pleasant task. You don’t have to spend a lot of money to make your laundry room a calm and soothing work space.  There are opulent touches you can add that will improve your disposition while performing the essential duties of washing, drying, folding and ironing.
*Paint the room in a soft, neutral color - choose from greens, blues or yellow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Hang some art on the walls.  Pick pieces that you love or are meaningful to you. You don’t have to spend a lot of money…just choose paintings or pictures that bring you joy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/img/004.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Detergent&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-If you lack storage in your laundry room, add some simple shelves with clean lines.  Get some clear containers for your detergent, fabric softener sheets, clothes pins etc. so you can dispose of the unsightly bags and boxes they come in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pinterest.com/explore/laundry-room-baskets/?lp=true&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Use baskets or bins&lt;/a&gt; to pre-sort clothes into whites, colors, sheets, towels etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-If your laundry room is spacious, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.diynetwork.com/videos/building-a-laundry-table-0136467&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;create a folding area.&lt;/a&gt;  You can have a table or if you are using front loading machines, design a counter to go on top of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/img/005.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Washer and Dryer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Add a small, wall-mounted television and a comfy chair, and folding clothes won’t seem so boring anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Add a small vase with fresh flowers.  Being amidst the beauty of nature will make you feel better about being stuck indoors doing laundry!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, guests are not likely to see your laundry room, so make it all about YOU.  Be funky and unique with your décor and have fun with it!  Before you know it, you will look forward to doing all that washing, drying and folding.  Ok…maybe you won’t look forward to it, but at least you won’t dread it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;More Resources:&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yourkeytomemphis.com/Blog/Quick-Fix-Tricks-to-Make-Your-House-Sparkling-Clean&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Quick Fix Tricks to Make Your House Sparkling Clean&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yourkeytomemphis.com/Blog/Top-Home-Renovations-for-Maximum-ROI&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Top Home Renovations for Maximum ROI&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yourkeytomemphis.com/Blog/Clearing-the-Clutter&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Clearing the Clutter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 11:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/luxurious-laundry-rooms.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/luxurious-laundry-rooms.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Improvement</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>101 Things To Do In Memphis #75: 29th Annual WEVL Blues on the Bluff</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/img/002.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Blues on the Bluff&quot; /&gt;
Bring your chairs and blankets and celebrate 29 years of fun on the bluffs of the Mississippi River in a beautiful park-like setting on the grounds of The Metal Museum.
Giant shady oaks, cool river breezes, the smell of BBQ, fantastic music, and absolutely the best view of the Mississippi in the entire mid-South!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Details:&lt;/strong&gt;
Schlafly Beer is the beer sponsor.
Beer, wine and non-alcoholic drinks being sold
Award-winning BBQ and more from Central BBQ Food Truck being sold
No pets or outside food or beverage permitted
Kids welcome when accompanied by watchful parents
Silent auction
WEVL Merchandise and Blues on the Bluff posters for sale
Free guarded parking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The line-up:&lt;/strong&gt;
The MD’s
6:30 p.m.
The Ghost Town Blues Band
8 p.m.
Marcella &amp;amp; Her Lovers
9:35 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Admission is $20 in advance, $25 at the gate
Kids 11 and under are $12 at the gate&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saturday, July 22nd
Gates open at 6 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By and photo credit: &lt;a href=&quot;http://wevl.org/bob&quot;&gt;http://wevl.org/bob&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 13:52:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/101-things-to-do-in-memphis-75-29th.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/101-things-to-do-in-memphis-75-29th.html</guid>
        
        <category>101 Things to do in Memphis</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Important Things to Fix Before Putting Your House on the Market</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/img/001.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Home Improvement&quot; /&gt;
If you want the best price for your house, you may have to do some repairs before selling it. Potential buyers will be willing to spend more for a home that doesn’t need a lot of work.  Here are 5 important things to fix before selling:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exterior&lt;/strong&gt; - When was the last time the exterior of your house was painted?  Is the paint faded and chipping?  Is wood rotting around the windows?  Is your front door dingy?  First impressions matter when it comes to selling your home and buyers will get their first impression when they see the outside of your house whether in pictures or in person.  Don’t forget the landscaping.  A well-kept lawn and simple, but clean flower beds will go a long way toward creating an enticing aesthetic for your property.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interior Paint&lt;/strong&gt; - If the walls are looking a bit shabby and the trim a bit grimy, painting is a quick and easy fix.  The same applies if you went through a crazy color phase a few years back and decorated with hues that might not appeal to everyone.  Choose neutral colors that will allow buyers to focus on the spaces without being distracted.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kitchen&lt;/strong&gt; - The kitchen is one of the most important rooms that buyers focus on when looking at a house.  So, if yours is looking run-down you will want to update it.  It will be worth the investment to replace appliances that are on their last legs or putting in a new granite counter.  Or it might be as simple as repainting cabinets and adding shiny, new handles.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bathroom&lt;/strong&gt; - Nothing turns buyers off faster than an unsightly bathroom.  Sparkling, clean fixtures and a fresh coat of paint will go a long way toward impressing someone searching for their dream home.  Inexpensive touches like a decorative mirror or a lovely picture on the wall will add to the ambiance without breaking the bank.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flooring&lt;/strong&gt; - If your carpets are stained or thread bare, it is worth your while to replace them.  Otherwise, buyers may ask for a carpet allowance when they make an offer on your house.  The same applies if your vinyl floors are in bad shape.  Hardwoods are always popular, but you may want to consider getting them refinished if they are looking old and scruffy.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may seem counter intuitive to spend money on repairing or fixing up a house you are getting ready to sell, but at the end of the day, it will not only help you sell your house faster, but you will get a better price for it too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;More Resources:&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yourkeytomemphis.com/Blog/Quick-Fix-Tricks-to-Make-Your-House-Sparkling-Clean&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Quick Fix Tricks to Make Your House Sparkling&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yourkeytomemphis.com/Blog/Tips-for-Showing-Your-Home-to-Potential-Buyers&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tips for Showing Your Home to Potential Buyers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 14:13:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/5-important-things-to-fix-before.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/5-important-things-to-fix-before.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Improvement</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Tips to Protect First-Time Homebuyers</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-YCZBqFfekc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you or someone you know is considering buying a home for the first time, there are a few things you need to be aware of. Here are our top three tips to protect first-time homebuyers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Know what you can afford.&lt;/strong&gt; This doesn’t just include your mortgage payment. You need to make sure you can afford that in addition to property taxes, utilities, and various other maintenance fees.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=HOME VALUES HAVE BEEN INCREASING YEAR BY YEAR IN MEMPHIS.%20localhost:4000/3-tips-to-protect-first-time-homebuyers.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“HOME VALUES HAVE BEEN INCREASING YEAR BY YEAR IN MEMPHIS.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Choose your lender wisely.&lt;/strong&gt; Online lenders aren’t always the best option, even if they advertise the lowest rate. You should really get a recommendation from a Realtor or some other person you trust. Local lenders tend to work best in terms of being able to close on time.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t overlook the details.&lt;/strong&gt; Purchase contracts have a lot of them. Take your time to read through it carefully and don’t hesitate to ask your Realtor any questions you have.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are just three tips for successfully buying a home for the first time. If you would like some more tips or just have a question, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 12:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/3-tips-to-protect-first-time-homebuyers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/3-tips-to-protect-first-time-homebuyers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Buying a House</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Promising Numbers From Our Memphis Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/49EKjBgJOo0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do the numbers from our current market compare to where we were at this time last year?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The number of units sold has risen 9% from 1,625 to 1,771, which is good.&lt;/strong&gt; Home values have been increasing year by year in the Memphis area as a whole, and the median sale price is up to $165,000. The number of home sales above $500,000 has increased 32%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=HOME VALUES HAVE BEEN INCREASING YEAR BY YEAR IN MEMPHIS.%20localhost:4000/promising-numbers-from-our-memphis.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“HOME VALUES HAVE BEEN INCREASING YEAR BY YEAR IN MEMPHIS.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a related note, I’d like to remind you that we’re donating the commission of our 100th home sale to a local charity, and you have the opportunity to vote on this website for who wins. The candidates are HopeWorks, Youth Villages, and the Bartlett Animal Shelter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about our market, you’d like to know what your home is worth, or you’re thinking about buying or selling a home, feel free to reach out to me. I’d be happy to assist you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 08:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/promising-numbers-from-our-memphis.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/promising-numbers-from-our-memphis.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Make Your Offer on a Memphis Home Stand Out</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jB1WeeHYk7M?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking to buy a home here in Memphis, you might have to compete against other offers for a home you like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For starters, remember that no other buyers know what the offers are, so you don’t have to worry about your offer being revealed. However, you can do a few things to make your offer better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, put down as much &lt;strong&gt;earnest money&lt;/strong&gt; as possible. This speaks volumes to the seller about your interest level in the home and that you can follow through with the loan process. Putting down a small amount means you don’t have any skin in the game, and the seller might not see your offer as worth it at that point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, &lt;strong&gt;show the seller that you are qualified for a home loan.&lt;/strong&gt; Get fully pre-approved for a loan instead of just getting pre-qualified, which carries less weight. An offer with a pre-approval is akin to a cash offer for a seller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=SHOW THE SELLER THAT YOU ARE QUALIFIED FOR A HOME LOAN.%20localhost:4000/how-to-make-your-offer-on-memphis-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“SHOW THE SELLER THAT YOU ARE QUALIFIED FOR A HOME LOAN.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also &lt;strong&gt;give the seller extra time to move.&lt;/strong&gt; Call the listing agent and ask them what’s important to their seller, because it’s not always all about money. For example, I recently worked with a seller who needed to rent the house back for a couple months after closing because they have a handicapped child. There are many situations going on in people’s lives, and accommodating them can help you win the home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, &lt;strong&gt;add a personal touch&lt;/strong&gt; by writing a letter telling the seller why you love the home. Also be aware of what you’re willing to pay for the home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about multiple offer situations when buying a home, give us a call or send us an email soon. We’d be more than happy to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 13:36:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-to-make-your-offer-on-memphis-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/how-to-make-your-offer-on-memphis-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Get the Best Possible Credit When Applying for a Home Loan</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ETYdFY854P8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking about buying a home, you need to start preparing to have the best possible credit when applying for a mortgage loan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, &lt;strong&gt;pay attention to your accounts&lt;/strong&gt;. Don’t close any accounts or open any new ones when preparing to buy a home. Also, make sure your credit to debt ratio looks good on all your open accounts. If you have a $500 limit, don’t let the balance sit at $495.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, &lt;strong&gt;don’t switch jobs&lt;/strong&gt;. If you do need to switch, try to stay in the same field so lenders have information about the switch. They want to see some job security, so if you’ve hopped around a lot that can be a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=DON’T CLOSE ANY ACCOUNTS OR OPEN ANY NEW ONES WHEN PREPARING TO BUY A HOME.%20localhost:4000/how-to-get-best-possible-credit-when.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“DON’T CLOSE ANY ACCOUNTS OR OPEN ANY NEW ONES WHEN PREPARING TO BUY A HOME.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pay attention to your balances&lt;/strong&gt;. If you have a high limit and you’ve maxed that out, it won’t look good to lenders. On the other hand, if you had a credit card that you use and pay off regularly, lenders will love that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, &lt;strong&gt;don’t make any big purchases until after closing on a home&lt;/strong&gt;. After you’ve got the keys to your new home, feel free to get that new furniture, just hold off until then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or are looking to buy or sell a home, please feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I’m always happy to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 13:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-to-get-best-possible-credit-when.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/how-to-get-best-possible-credit-when.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Homeowners &amp; Homebuyers Need to Know About Taxes</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/x2aIONXEvXs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m here with Wendy Thompson of the Wendy Thompson Lending Team to talk about your tax appraisal. Unless you live in the downtown area, you should have received your appraisal by now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you disagree with your appraisal, you can go to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.assessor.shelby.tn.us/content.aspx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Shelby County tax assessor site&lt;/a&gt; and fill out &lt;strong&gt;an informal request for a reassessment.&lt;/strong&gt; You don’t have to provide a lot of documentation for an informal request, so it is a fairly easy process. That said, there is a short time frame for informal requests. Beginning on May 1st, you can make a formal request. That is a much more involved process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=MAKE SURE YOUR LENDER IS USING THE CORRECT TAX ASSESSMENT.%20localhost:4000/what-homeowners-homebuyers-need-to-know.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“MAKE SURE YOUR LENDER IS USING THE CORRECT TAX ASSESSMENT.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are selling your house and your taxes have gone up, this could impact you. Since taxes are divided between you and your potential buyer at closing, the buyer could come to you and ask for additional taxes since your appraisal went up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a buyer and you are currently under contract to purchase a home, &lt;strong&gt;make sure that your lender is using the correct tax assessment.&lt;/strong&gt; Unfortunately, in some instances even a slight increase in monthly taxes can make a huge difference between getting approved for a loan or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any questions about this topic, just give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 12:39:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/what-homeowners-homebuyers-need-to-know.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/what-homeowners-homebuyers-need-to-know.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
