<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wes Peters Group Real Estate Video Blog</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Wes Peters Group - your professional Baltimore Metropolitan Area Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://wpghomeblog.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://wpghomeblog.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 14:26:30 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 14:26:30 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Looking for a Career Change in 2018?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/yXhwGYblPGk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just wanted to let everyone know that we are hiring for 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are looking to grow our team, and there are a lot of great opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you had thought about a career in real estate and not had time to transition or are looking for a part-time opportunity, I’d love to talk to you. If you have a license and are looking for full-time opportunities, I’d love to talk to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if you are an established agent who needs more support for administrative work and marketing, I’d love to talk with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We have a good track record of getting new agents into the business&lt;/strong&gt; through different career paths, and we’re really proud of that. We are looking to grow our team, and we have a great value proposition that I’d love to talk to everyone about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 26,000 real estate agents in Maryland and the D.C. area, and about 100,000 homes sell each year in Maryland. Some might say that the industry is over-serviced, but I disagree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can tell you that only about 10% of agents renew their licenses after two years in the business. That means that 90% of agents get out of the business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a huge amount to learn, from technology to contract changes and beyond. As great as some brokerages are, it can be hard to provide everything an agent needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why teams are so prevalent now. &lt;strong&gt;Teams are able to provide training, accountability, and leadership.&lt;/strong&gt;Keller Williams has world-class training that we are really proud of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if you or anyone you know would be interested in a career in real estate, I would love to talk to them. In the meantime, I hope you have fun this holiday season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://wpghomeblog.com/looking-for-a-career-change-in-2018.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://wpghomeblog.com/looking-for-a-career-change-in-2018.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What’s Happening in the Baltimore Real Estate Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/BNcm8xKTRQA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we get to the latest news and information on the Baltimore Metro real estate market, I want to say thanks. Our recent Thanksgiving pie party was a huge success. We were so happy that so many of you made it out to say hi, help us collect nearly 100 toys for Toys for Tots, and take home some delicious pies. &lt;strong&gt;Thanks to all of you and all of your referrals, we have also been able to raise over $10,000 for Cool Kids this year.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next year, we’re stepping up our referral game and giving away a $5,000 Apple vacation gift card. Anybody who gives us a referral in the next year will be eligible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re on the fence about getting into the market next year, let’s take a look at the most recent numbers to see how things are shaping up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nationally, the market is up 6.3% in 2017, with Fannie Mae predicting about 5% appreciation growth next year. &lt;strong&gt;Here’s what we’re seeing in a few different areas of the Baltimore metro:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Baltimore County: The market is up about 4% year to date, and the average sale price is up to $260,000.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Howard County: The market is up 2.8% year to date, and the average price is at $410,000.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Carroll County: This market has seen the best growth in the metro. The average sale price is up to $310,000.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Anne Arundel County: The market is up 2.1% year to date, and the average sale price is $325,000.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hartford County: The market is up 2.1% year to date, and the average sale price is up to $245,000.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Baltimore City: The market is up 3.9% year to date, and the average sale price is $135,000.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, &lt;strong&gt;most homeowners in the Baltimore metro are continuing to build steady equity on a year-by-year basis.&lt;/strong&gt; Look for this trend to continue, and also look for homeowners to start cashing in on this equity.**&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Homeowners may start cashing in on their equity.%20http://wpghomeblog.com/whats-happening-in-the-baltimore-real-estate-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Homeowners may start cashing in on their equity.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of factors that will drive supply and demand over the next year. One is the fact that we’re expecting 2.3 new million residents in the U.S. this next year. However, the biggest factor in the market next year will be the new households being formed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me in the meantime, give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://wpghomeblog.com/whats-happening-in-the-baltimore-real-estate-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://wpghomeblog.com/whats-happening-in-the-baltimore-real-estate-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Does the Cool Kids Campaign Help Children With Cancer?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Sw6DbRXuDA8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m joined by Kristen Rutherford and Mackenzie Wieder from the Cool Kids Campaign. Kristin is the Community Relations Coordinator, and Mackenzie is the Operations Coordinator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a local charity that we partner with. We contribute a portion of our commission from every settlement at Keller Williams to the campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cool Kids Campaign helps improve the quality of life for pediatric oncology patients and their families.&lt;/strong&gt; The Cool Kids Campaign focuses on academic, social, and emotional support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They have many great programs in place. During the summer, there is a “Mommy and Me” drop-off for the kids to come and hang out. They also have a camp for all of the kids and their siblings, as well as a condo in Myrtle Beach, where they send the families for vacation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The Cool Kids Campaign helps children with cancer and their families.%20http://wpghomeblog.com/how-does-the-cool-kids-campaign-help-children-with-cancer.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The Cool Kids Campaign helps children with cancer and their families.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Cool Kids Campaign also sends care packages out across the country with all of the kids’ favorite things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a look at the video to see their great facility in Towson, Maryland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We are on track to donate $10,000 to the Cool Kids Campaign this year&lt;/strong&gt;, and we are proud to help such an amazing organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Kristen and Mackenzie for joining me today. You can learn more about the Cool Kids Campaign at their &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.coolkidscampaign.org/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, please don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://wpghomeblog.com/how-does-the-cool-kids-campaign-help-children-with-cancer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://wpghomeblog.com/how-does-the-cool-kids-campaign-help-children-with-cancer.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Team Is Putting Our Money Where Our Mouth Is for Our Sellers</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/AeUpsaOO0OI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I wanted to take a minute to tell you all about our Guaranteed Sale Program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we’re currently in a seller’s market, this isn’t something that has been coming into play all that often. Nevertheless, I wanted to give you an idea of what it is and how it works. &lt;strong&gt;I personally like to give sellers what I think are the pros and cons of their situation&lt;/strong&gt;, and what the best and worst-case scenarios are in any given circumstance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though I like to provide this information and feedback, I still want to give sellers the freedom to choose their own initial list price—within reason. Still, a lot of sellers ask me what I would do if I were in their shoes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where the Guaranteed Sale Program comes into play. This program lets me put my money where my mouth is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If we can't sell your home for you within 60 days for a price you're happy with, we will sell it for free!%20http://wpghomeblog.com/my-team-is-putting-our-money-where-our-mouth-is-for-our-sellers.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If we can’t sell your home for you within 60 days for a price you’re happy with, we will sell it for free!”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the seller lists their home at a price my team and I recommend and agree with and doesn’t sell within 30 days, the listing will undergo an agreed-upon price reduction. This reduction is usually about 3%. &lt;strong&gt;If the listing still doesn’t sell within 60 days, we will continue to market your property at no cost.&lt;/strong&gt; Though we’ll still need to pay the buyer’s agent, my team and I will basically be working for free at that point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This guarantee does not include short sales or tenant-occupied properties, and there needs to be equity in the property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pre-appraisals and pre-inspections are both required for the Guaranteed Sale Program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This allows us to be totally transparent with any potential buyers. This also allows us to take care of any issues that arise in the report ahead of time. &lt;strong&gt;With a pre-inspection, a lot of surprises are taken out of the transaction.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The program also requires that you meet with our in-house stager Rose, and agree to any of her recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://wpghomeblog.com/my-team-is-putting-our-money-where-our-mouth-is-for-our-sellers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://wpghomeblog.com/my-team-is-putting-our-money-where-our-mouth-is-for-our-sellers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Has Technology Changed the World of Lending?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/cVcN-B949Wc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m joined by a special guest, Andy Duda from Caliber Home Loans, to talk about the current state of mortgages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been in the business for 13 years, but Andy has been helping me with loans even before then. &lt;strong&gt;In the time we’ve known each other, Andy has assisted me with hundreds of loans.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a big deal for my team and I to have lenders that we trust, so professionals like Andy are a huge resource to us. We try to introduce Andy to as many of our clients as possible when they are in need of his services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lending has changed a little bit over the year. I always tell people that lending in 2017 is somewhat vanilla. Most lenders have the same products, so the real difference comes down to interest rates and customer service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Andy, the world of lending ultimately changed after the economic crisis in 2007. Ultimately, traditional financing is king. There are niche programs out there, but most people tend to go more standard routes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=As technology moves forward, so does the world of real estate.%20http://wpghomeblog.com/how-has-technology-changed-the-world-of-lending.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“As technology moves forward, so does the world of real estate.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One of the most important things is to talk to your lender early on in the process.&lt;/strong&gt; Doing so will help you determine what price range you should be shopping in and what programs will be the best fit for you. Having this information will also help your Realtor service you to the highest level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though most loan products are fairly standardized, there are some neat features available these days. For example, Caliber Home Loans has introduced the possibility of a digital mortgage for buyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This allows the company to digitally verify income and assets without the hassle of a lot of paperwork. &lt;strong&gt;People can become fully approved and can close without ever having to dig up paystubs.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While not all employers will facilitate this as a possibility, it is a great option for those who can make use of it. As technology moves forward, so does the world of real estate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://wpghomeblog.com/how-has-technology-changed-the-world-of-lending.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://wpghomeblog.com/how-has-technology-changed-the-world-of-lending.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Great News About Our Zillow Reviews and a Quick Market Update</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/aNkp5Uqul5A?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s the latest word on our Baltimore market as we head into fall?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I have some great news to share with you. Our team has reached 200 reviews on Zillow. It’s taken us years to accumulate this number, and it’s a milestone we’re extremely proud of. If you’re a past client of ours and you contributed one of those reviews, I want to personally thank you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I want to remind you &lt;strong&gt;that we’re hosting an outdoor cookout for all of our past clients on September 23rd at the Columbia Sports Park at 5 p.m.&lt;/strong&gt; My wife’s been putting a lot of effort into planning this event, so if you’re a past client and you haven’t gotten your invitation in the mail, we’d love for you to come join us. We’ll have a live DJ, an open bar, and plenty of fun activities for the whole family to enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We’ll see an uptick in the market in the next 60 to 75 days.%20http://wpghomeblog.com/great-news-about-our-zillow-reviews-and-a-quick-market-update.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We’ll see an uptick in the market in the next 60 to 75 days.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, onto the latest real estate news. The Baltimore market experienced a little bit of a slowdown this past August because of people vacationing later in the year due to a later school year start date. This has caused some frustration among the active buyers out there because of the available inventory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good news if you’re a buyer, however, is that &lt;strong&gt;you’ll see a new wave of homes coming on the market next week&lt;/strong&gt;—our team alone has about 10 homes being listed next Wednesday or Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good news if you’re a seller is that &lt;strong&gt;we’ll see an uptick in the market in the next 60 to 75 days&lt;/strong&gt;, which will provide you a great window to sell your home. It’s arguably a better time to sell during this timespan than the spring months because—from an appraisal standpoint—you have great comparables of homes that sold in May, June, and July.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about our market or you’re thinking about buying or selling a home soon, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d be glad to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://wpghomeblog.com/great-news-about-our-zillow-reviews-and-a-quick-market-update.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://wpghomeblog.com/great-news-about-our-zillow-reviews-and-a-quick-market-update.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Where Does Our Baltimore Market Stand for Buyers and Sellers?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/p9gGoP72JSY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s the latest news from our Baltimore metro area market?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let’s start by sharing some statistics from the month of June:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The median sale price was just shy of $279,000, which is the highest it’s been since July 2007.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There were 4,509 closed sales and 4,313 pending sales—the highest number for either category in a decade.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Active inventory continued to decline by double digits for the twelfth consecutive month, and ended at 11,097 homes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get a more in-depth look at how our market fared in June, check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rbintel.com/blog/baltimore-area-hits-highest-monthly-tally-decade-over-4500-homes-sold-june&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Real Estate Business Intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you’ve missed out on a home, August might be a great time to find a good value.%20http://wpghomeblog.com/where-does-our-baltimore-market-stand-for-buyers-and-sellers.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you’ve missed out on a home, August might be a great time to find a good value.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One trend I’ve noticed lately is that many buyers who’ve been trying to secure a home before summer ends and school starts have found what they were looking for. The market tends to slow down in August and then pick back up after Labor Day. I always say &lt;strong&gt;this window is the second-best time period to sell your home, after the spring market.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the buyer side, if you’ve missed out on a home in the last few months, August might present some valuable opportunities since fewer buyers will be in the marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a different note, we have a client appreciation event coming up on September 23rd at the Columbia Sports Park from 5 p.m. to 9 p.m., so keep your eyes peeled for an upcoming invitation. It should be a great time for everyone involved, so we hope to see you then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, if you have any questions about our market or are thinking of buying or selling a home, feel free to give me a call or shoot me an email. I’d be happy to speak with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://wpghomeblog.com/where-does-our-baltimore-market-stand-for-buyers-and-sellers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://wpghomeblog.com/where-does-our-baltimore-market-stand-for-buyers-and-sellers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How You Can Take Advantage of a Great Jumbo Mortgage Program</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/6sTt8WLrqqY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.realtrends.com/&quot;&gt;Realtrends.com&lt;/a&gt; came out with their list of the top agents in the country recently, and while we weren’t quite able to make the top 1,000 real estate agents in the country, we are excited to announce that we were ranked No. 20 in the state of Maryland for 2016 in terms of all units sold. Considering that there are around 26,000 agents in Maryland and D.C., we are pretty proud of that accomplishment and wanted to thank all of our clients for supporting us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also wanted to take a little bit to talk about jumbo mortgages and what’s going on in the jumbo mortgage industry. Traditionally, if you wanted to borrow anywhere from $500,000 to $1 million, it would’ve been more expensive in the Maryland area to borrow $1 million than a couple hundred thousand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It actually hasn’t been that way for the last couple of years. In Maryland, if you were to borrow under $424,000 with a conventional mortgage with 5% down, your interest rate would be right around 4.5%. If you were to move into the jumbo category and borrow more than $424,000 with 10% down, your interest rate would be about 4.25% and you wouldn’t need mortgage insurance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Interest rates do get better as you have a larger down payment.%20http://wpghomeblog.com/how-you-can-take-advantage-of-a-great-jumbo-mortgage-program.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Interest rates do get better as you have a larger down payment.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t have to put down 20% for a jumbo mortgage in order to get mortgage insurance out of your life, but &lt;strong&gt;it’s cheaper to borrow $1 million at 10% down than it is to borrow $200,000 at 5% down.&lt;/strong&gt; Interest rates do get better as you have a larger down payment, and there are a lot of banks that have programs that are geared toward the more affluent buyer and offer incentives to take your banking to these particular banks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There is a popular program geared toward people who are looking to buy new construction but have a home to sell.​&lt;/strong&gt; If a buyer is willing to put 10% down on a mortgage for a new build and are able to sell their home within six months, they can then recast their mortgage, put an additional 10% with the money they gained from selling the house, and then have their interest rate lowered by 3/8ths of a point. It’s actually a free refinance and you can keep the original interest rate that you locked in when you first acquired the mortgage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this topic or need recommendations for some lenders to talk to, please give me a call. I’d be happy to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://wpghomeblog.com/how-you-can-take-advantage-of-a-great-jumbo-mortgage-program.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://wpghomeblog.com/how-you-can-take-advantage-of-a-great-jumbo-mortgage-program.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Navigate Our Market as a Move-Up Buyer</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/DzIlXi2W2nc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the clients I’ve been working with lately are what you call “move-up buyers.” Who are move-up buyers? What are they trying to achieve?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Move-up buyers are often living in their first home and are hitting a point where they need a little bit more space&lt;/strong&gt; or have different family goals. Hence, they’re seeking a fresh start and a new home. When I meet with these buyers, I’ll ask them a few important questions, such as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are there homes out there that excite you?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do you already know the home you want to purchase or do you need to get out there and see what the current inventory looks like?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do you need to sell to buy?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is your timeline?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those questions help us put a plan together, and after that initial discussion I typically see three common scenarios. The first is putting a contingent offer on a new home, then settling on the old home and new home on the same day. The second is selling first and then buying. The third is buying first and then selling. &lt;strong&gt;Each option has its advantages and disadvantages.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Having good people in place will help you make good decisions.%20http://wpghomeblog.com/how-to-navigate-our-market-as-a-move-up-buyer.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Having good people in place will help you make good decisions.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first option means the purchase of your next home is contingent on the sale of your current home. A couple dominos have to fall in this scenario. It represents the least amount of risk for move-up buyers, but it’s also the least attractive option to sellers—especially when we’re in a seller’s market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second option occurs when people want to buy in a specific area and there’s a unique type of home they’re looking for so they sell their current home and move in with friends or relocate to a short-term rental. When that home does come on the market, they can be very nimble, and they can also put a non-contingent offer on it, which makes their offer more attractive to the seller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last option happens more than you think. This tends to occur with families with kids or pets and there are a lot of barriers to get their home ready and approved for showings once it’s on the market. By moving into their new home, they can get their old home ready for the market. Once it’s listed, they can approve every showing because they aren’t living there anymore. The downside of this is that family may have to carry two mortgages for a month or two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a move-up buyer (or any type of homebuyer), the best advice we can give you is this: &lt;strong&gt;set a big goal and make a date when you want to move into your new home.&lt;/strong&gt; Once you establish that big goal, break it down into smaller micro-goals and collaborate with your agent to put a strategic plan into place to make sure you’re taking the right steps and maximize your potential once you hit the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, have trusted partners you can rely on. Whether it’s a lender, an inspector, or a staging consultant, having good people in place will help you make good decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or are looking to make a move in our market, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://wpghomeblog.com/how-to-navigate-our-market-as-a-move-up-buyer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://wpghomeblog.com/how-to-navigate-our-market-as-a-move-up-buyer.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What You Can Learn From Zillow's Lawsuit</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/sBW3-ySnun0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, Zillow and their Zestimate have been in the news because of a homeowner taking issue with how the Zestimate has negatively affected her home sale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This homeowner paid $626,000 for the home six years ago and tried to sell it for a similar price. The Zillow Zestimate valued the property at $564,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The argument by the homeowner (which hasn’t quite gone to court yet) is that Zillow is acting as if they are an appraiser in this situation. Zillow is adamant that the Zestimate is just an estimate, but they had an average error rate of about 6% in 2016. That can get pretty significant in higher price points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Zestimate is meant to be just a starting point for buyers, but many look at it as more of an appraisal, which is not how it intended to be.&lt;/strong&gt; This homeowner isn’t seeking damages, but rather just to get Zillow out of the appraisal side of things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The Zestimate is meant to be just a starting point for buyers.%20http://wpghomeblog.com/what-you-can-learn-from-zillows-lawsuit.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The Zestimate is meant to be just a starting point for buyers.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to know what your home is worth, you can use a website like Zillow or you can hire a licensed appraiser, and there is an argument to be made for both. &lt;strong&gt;A licensed appraiser will take a more analytical approach by accounting for price per square foot and make adjustments for amenities.&lt;/strong&gt;However, many times, the appraiser hasn’t actually seen the homes they compare yours to when coming up with a value. They don’t know if the home had a strong odor, backed up to power lines, or sat on the market for a long time, for instance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An appraiser doesn’t have their finger on the pulse of the active market like a real estate agent who has been in the majority of homes that you’re comparing it to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about finding your home’s value or you want to know what it’s worth, we’d love to help you out. Just give me a call or send me an email soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://wpghomeblog.com/what-you-can-learn-from-zillows-lawsuit.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://wpghomeblog.com/what-you-can-learn-from-zillows-lawsuit.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
