<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Baystate Financial Video Blog with Stephen Cunha</title>
    <description>Stephen Cunha can help you take charge of your financial future by developing a customized strategy to reach your financial goals and further your success.</description>
    <link>localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 10:11:51 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 10:11:51 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Vyral Marketing Show Episode 31</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0vDQUM65gMk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll learn the top five warm advertising audiences for lead generation on Facebook. You’ll generate higher quality leads from the people who know you than strangers. It’s also cheaper to reach them. These warm “audiences” include the emails in your database, the people who visit your website, the people who watch your videos, your Facebook fans, and people who interact with your Facebook page. All this is tracked and you can run ads to these people. In this video, you’ll learn how to set up your Facebook ad account correctly - first by making strong offers to your warm audiences, and then boosting educational videos to your entire cold target market to build awareness. Interested in Facebook advertising?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Essential Facebook advertising to your email database and website traffic is included in our core service.%20localhost:4000/episode31.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Essential Facebook advertising to your email database and website traffic is included in our core service.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Essential Facebook advertising to your email database and website traffic is included in our core service. These warm audiences are so responsive (and inexpensive) it’s recommended every client does it if you have an extra $5 a day ad budget. We also offer premium Facebook, YouTube and Display advertising if you want to add-on full scope advertising management. We’ll setup your first Facebook ad campaign for free. Contact john@getvyral.com or visit the “How it Works” page on our website to learn more. If you’re considering adding Facebook advertising to your marketing plan, this video is where to start.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 04:38:35 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/episode31.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/episode31.html</guid>
        
        <category>Financial Advice</category>
        
        <category>Wealth Management</category>
        
        <category>Business Owners</category>
        
        <category>Investor Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Vyral Marketing Show Episode 29</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/C_rHUhKv_wE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll learn how to read a simple script into a microphone so you don’t have to be on camera. A voiceover is the best way to record a video when you must be 100% on message. Voiceovers work best for sales and promotional videos. Simply send us photos or footage. We’ll add in music and the voiceover. We can record the voiceover for you (once we agree on the script) or you can record it using your computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Remember, we can record the voiceover for you so there’s no work required of you.%20localhost:4000/episode29.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Remember, we can record the voiceover for you so there’s no work required of you.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this episode, you’ll see how real estate clients taking my upcoming recruiting class to launch Jan 8th are creating videos to sell tickets to upcoming training events. I use the Yeti microphone, with the levels set correctly, to read a client’s script into recording software (Audacity). This way you can see how it works to record your own voiceover. Remember, we can record the voiceover for you so there’s no work required of you. This is available to all clients. If you want to make a promotional video, and you don’t want to be on camera, this episode is for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 04:35:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/episode29.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/episode29.html</guid>
        
        <category>Financial Advice</category>
        
        <category>Wealth Management</category>
        
        <category>Business Owners</category>
        
        <category>Investor Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Vyral Marketing Show Episode 30</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/c_ZhfGYMajw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll learn how to hire an assistant in the Philippines, if you can’t afford American labor rates, to help with your marketing efforts or phone calls. I was invited to speak last month at an employee appreciation event outside of Manila for www.1000CallsADay.com – an outbound prospecting company – lead by Jessica Sanders who worked here at Vyral Marketing as our own lead follow up specialist. Jessica oversees 70+ callers, all based in the Philippines, earning $3-5 an hour. Each caller speaks with, on average, 35 people a day to pass 30-60 leads to you a month. WARNING: There are several marketing pillars to implement first (like referral, database marketing and inbound lead generation systems) BEFORE scaling up your outbound calling, however, the results do speak for themselves that outbound calling does work at scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you’ve ever wondered what it’s like to employ talent overseas, especially in the Philippines, this video is for you.%20localhost:4000/episode30.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you’ve ever wondered what it’s like to employ talent overseas, especially in the Philippines, this video is for you.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I want you to know hiring a call center - or even implementing an outbound calling plan - isn’t for everyone. Most importantly you must know the laws and expect long lead conversion cycles. But, when I was over there, I learned so much about the country, the working conditions, the pay rates, and more I wanted to share with you how it all works if you’re interested in this as a complement to your Vyral Marketing plan. I know many of you need help with extra marketing beyond the scope of our core service, help with calling people to invite to them to events or to subscribe to your video newsletters, or just plain ‘old recruiting. If you’ve ever wondered what it’s like to employ talent overseas, especially in the Philippines, this video is for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 04:31:32 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/episode30.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/episode30.html</guid>
        
        <category>Financial Advice</category>
        
        <category>Wealth Management</category>
        
        <category>Business Owners</category>
        
        <category>Investor Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>this is a test post</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/SFFy_drFrZs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Master cleanse pork belly pour-over VHS kogi locavore. Butcher chartreuse pour-over, farm-to-table slow-carb asymmetrical hexagon man braid. Echo park fingerstache man bun, humblebrag direct trade lyft hot chicken tofu green juice tacos shabby chic deep v. Gentrify meh narwhal woke post-ironic, yr intelligentsia keytar franzen af. Poke vape skateboard, la croix beard pok pok mlkshk scenester ramps &lt;strong&gt;gastropub marfa r&lt;/strong&gt;etro roof party kinfolk unicorn. Lomo keffiyeh gochujang slow-carb kitsch celiac. Succulents asymmetrical franzen intelligentsia tofu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bushwick&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;'http://google.com'&quot;&gt;marfa&lt;/a&gt; wayfarers heirloom pork belly. Tumblr ramps roof party, church-key portland tbh viral letterpress. &lt;a href=&quot;http://google.com&quot;&gt;Fanny&lt;/a&gt; pack flannel neutra, polaroid fam thundercats kale chips kogi gluten-free chicharrones cray tumblr meh keffiyeh messenger bag. Church-key vegan mixtape, ramps DIY fixie PBR&amp;amp;B keffiyeh pinterest pop-up offal. Waistcoat jianbing pok pok, mustache glossier tattooed deep v selfies DIY. Beard fingerstache cray XOXO, iPhone readymade forage offal. Twee snackwave activated charcoal YOLO, tattooed synth narwhal man bun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Celiac copper mug iceland, snackwave bushwick tbh hell of occupy tilde tousled. Tilde microdosing glossier vinyl, you probably haven’t heard of them single-origin coffee banjo mumblecore tumblr sriracha kombucha synth lo-fi scenester yuccie. Dreamcatcher XOXO gochujang, aesthetic offal synth fap. Taxidermy stumptown normcore quinoa deep v. DIY four loko succulents pinterest raclette, la croix butcher fam semiotics kogi quinoa. Salvia four dollar toast gochujang mlkshk, bushwick tousled 90’s fixie try-hard lo-fi mumblecore. Authentic kitsch listicle man bun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=This is an example of a pull quote%20localhost:4000/this-is-a-test-post-copy-2.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“This is an example of a pull quote”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually trust fund ugh banjo, affogato shabby chic single-origin coffee copper mug live-edge banh mi put a bird on it. Tote bag stumptown banjo typewriter. Authentic chillwave literally, artisan disrupt distillery mustache pug gluten-free. Direct trade echo park tbh meditation YOLO kinfolk. 3 wolf moon typewriter vape listicle, ennui pug kale chips tilde marfa. PBR&amp;amp;B photo booth helvetica gluten-free. Fashion axe normcore hammock yuccie blog dreamcatcher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh. You need a little dummy text for your mockup? How quaint.I bet you’re still using Bootstrap too…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/this-is-a-test-post-copy-2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/this-is-a-test-post-copy-2.html</guid>
        
        <category>Financial Advice</category>
        
        <category>Wealth Management</category>
        
        <category>Business Owners</category>
        
        <category>Investor Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Fox in Space</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/SFFy_drFrZs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Master cleanse pork belly pour-over VHS kogi locavore. Butcher chartreuse pour-over, farm-to-table slow-carb asymmetrical hexagon man braid. Echo park fingerstache man bun, humblebrag direct trade lyft hot chicken tofu green juice tacos shabby chic deep v. Gentrify meh narwhal woke post-ironic, yr intelligentsia keytar franzen af. Poke vape skateboard, la croix beard pok pok mlkshk scenester ramps &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://google.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;gastropub&lt;/a&gt; marfa r&lt;/strong&gt;etro roof party kinfolk unicorn. Lomo keffiyeh gochujang slow-carb kitsch celiac. Succulents asymmetrical franzen intelligentsia tofu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bushwick&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;'http://google.com'&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;marfa&lt;/a&gt; wayfarers heirloom pork belly. Tumblr ramps roof party, church-key portland tbh viral letterpress. Fanny pack flannel neutra, polaroid fam thundercats kale chips kogi gluten-free chicharrones cray tumblr meh keffiyeh messenger bag. Church-key vegan mixtape, ramps DIY fixie PBR&amp;amp;B keffiyeh pinterest pop-up offal. Waistcoat jianbing pok pok, mustache glossier tattooed deep v selfies DIY. Beard fingerstache cray XOXO, iPhone readymade forage offal. Twee snackwave activated charcoal YOLO, tattooed synth narwhal man bun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;list item&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;list item&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;list item&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;list item&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;list item&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;list item&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;list item&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;list item&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;list item&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;list item&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Celiac copper mug iceland, snackwave bushwick tbh hell of occupy tilde tousled. Tilde microdosing glossier vinyl, you probably haven’t heard of them single-origin coffee banjo mumblecore tumblr sriracha kombucha synth lo-fi scenester yuccie. Dreamcatcher XOXO gochujang, aesthetic offal synth fap. Taxidermy stumptown normcore quinoa deep v. DIY four loko succulents pinterest raclette, la croix butcher fam semiotics kogi quinoa. Salvia four dollar toast gochujang mlkshk, bushwick tousled 90’s fixie try-hard lo-fi mumblecore. Authentic kitsch listicle man bun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=This is an example of a pull quote%20localhost:4000/a-fox-in-space.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“This is an example of a pull quote”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually trust fund ugh banjo, affogato shabby chic single-origin coffee copper mug live-edge banh mi put a bird on it. Tote bag stumptown banjo typewriter. Authentic chillwave literally, artisan disrupt distillery mustache pug gluten-free. Direct trade echo park tbh meditation YOLO kinfolk. 3 wolf moon typewriter vape listicle, ennui pug kale chips tilde marfa. PBR&amp;amp;B photo booth helvetica gluten-free. Fashion axe normcore hammock yuccie blog dreamcatcher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh. You need a little dummy text for your mockup? How quaint.I bet you’re still using Bootstrap too…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/a-fox-in-space.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/a-fox-in-space.html</guid>
        
        <category>Financial Advice</category>
        
        <category>Wealth Management</category>
        
        <category>Business Owners</category>
        
        <category>Investor Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
