<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>A Video Blog about Honolulu Real Estate; It's industry, and the people working in it. Whether you're just starting out, aspiring to begin, or been working in the field for a few years, tune in to get updates, tips, tricks and more!</description>
    <link>http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 18:15:05 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 18:15:05 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meet Benjy Gilholm, Our Listing Partner Specialist</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/E1jh3BrmGeA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Meet Benjy—a listing partner specialist at Team Lally. Through a combination of teamwork and working closely with clients, Team Lally remains a step above the rest.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Team Lally, we have a unique and collaborative approach to real estate—which is one of the main reasons why Benjy Gilholm is so excited to be working as a part of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This hands-on, team-oriented way of thinking benefits not only us but also our clients. &lt;strong&gt;Through a combination of teamwork and maintaining continuous contact with our clients, we are able to get the most out of what we do for you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=AS A TEAM, WE REMAIN A STEP ABOVE THE REST.%20http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/meet-benjy-gilholm-our-listing-partner-specialist.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“AS A TEAM, WE REMAIN A STEP ABOVE THE REST.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to ensure that we are working together efficiently and putting out the best work for you, we hold weekly meetings between our buyer agents, seller agents, listing partner specialists, like Benjy, our in-house escrow officer, and our in-house listing manager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This helps to ensure that, as a team, we remain a step above the rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We consider the way we work together to be one of our greatest tools—it allows us to close on the highest volume of homes possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or would like to learn more about Team Lally and what we can do for you, feel free to call or email us. We look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2017 09:41:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/meet-benjy-gilholm-our-listing-partner-specialist.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/meet-benjy-gilholm-our-listing-partner-specialist.html</guid>
        
        <category>Word Of Mouse Team Lally</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kapolei Mastermind Key to Success - Last Friday Of Every Month</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/X-5K6o3YSUI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We have another mastermind coming up and we’d love for you to join us.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we wanted to talk to you about the power of the mastermind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Napoleon Hill calls the mastermind the key that will open the door to your desires—whatever they may be. He defines it as two or more people that work in perfect harmony for the attainment of a definite purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are holding a mastermind session in our Kapolei Business Center like we do every month on the last Friday from 12:30 p.m. to 1:30 p.m. The agenda is always filled with topics that will bring you success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=THIS INVITATION IS FOR ANYONE INTERESTED IN LEARNING THESE SUCCESS SECRETS.%20http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/kapolei-mastermind-key-to-success-last-friday-of-every-month.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“THIS INVITATION IS FOR ANYONE INTERESTED IN LEARNING THESE SUCCESS SECRETS.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This mastermind will feature Mr. William, a professional voice coach. &lt;strong&gt;He will teach you how to improve your ability to communicate with clients and loved ones.&lt;/strong&gt; This will bring you more clients and improve your relationships. Become a trained speaker whether one-on-one or to a group. His most important points are power, confidence, and clarity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to learn how to do all this? All you have to do is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.teamlally.com/kw-mastermind.php&quot;&gt;click here to RSVP.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks and Aloha!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 11:46:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/kapolei-mastermind-key-to-success-last-friday-of-every-month.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/kapolei-mastermind-key-to-success-last-friday-of-every-month.html</guid>
        
        <category>Team Lally Mastermind</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Miranda Helps Your Real Estate Transaction Run Smoothly</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8-86eYOstng?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Today we wanted to introduce you to Miranda Haws, one of our beloved inside sales agents here at Team Lally.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Miranda heard about Team Lally from the radio and also by seeing our yard signs throughout the community. She was motivated to join us after hearing about our success as the No. 1 team in Hawaii.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I had to come and see what all the rave was about,” she says. “It turned out that Adrienne and Attilio are just really down-to-earth people. They care about the team and they care about their business.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=HER FAVORITE PART OF THE JOB IS THE COLLABORATION EVERYONE BRINGS TO THE TABLE.%20http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/how-miranda-helps-your-real-estate-transaction-run-smoothly.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“HER FAVORITE PART OF THE JOB IS THE COLLABORATION EVERYONE BRINGS TO THE TABLE.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an inside sales agent, Miranda works hand-in-hand with buyers and listing agents to help guide our clients to the best resources and all the information they desire. Her favorite part of the job is the collaboration everyone brings to the table from their many years of experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Any time there’s a problem or conflict that comes up, we can all work together to figure it out,” Miranda says.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for Miranda or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home here in Hawaii, you can always give us a call or send us an email. We’re here to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 12:39:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/how-miranda-helps-your-real-estate-transaction-run-smoothly.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/how-miranda-helps-your-real-estate-transaction-run-smoothly.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Strategic Driven Business Is How We Did $82 Million Last Year </title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/DH-dz1YGUgY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have you thought about starting a career in real estate? Here’s how to approach it to set yourself up for a prosperous career.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we want to talk for a minute about a career in real estate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People always ask how the market is and whether now is a good time to get into real estate. &lt;strong&gt;A common misconception is that the answer depends on what kind of market we’re in.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what we have learned from being in real estate for more than 10 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s not what the market conditions are, but whether you have the right strategies for success.&lt;/strong&gt; How do we know this? We had a phenomenal year during the worst real estate bubble in history. We did a ton of short sales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=WE ADJUST TO THE MARKET WE’RE IN TO MAINTAIN A HIGH LEVEL OF SUCCESS.%20http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/a-strategic-driven-business-is-how-we.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“WE ADJUST TO THE MARKET WE’RE IN TO MAINTAIN A HIGH LEVEL OF SUCCESS.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is an example of having the right strategy—we adjusted for the market we were in. In fact, we have been able to grow strategically year over year for the last 10 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have what we call a strategically driven business, and not an economically driven business. The difference? Our business does not go up and down with the economy, but rises upward with strategic growth. How do we do that? Come to one of our Career Nights or check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jointeamlally.com/&quot;&gt;JoinTeamLally.com&lt;/a&gt; to learn more. We’d love to see you there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks and Aloha!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 15:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/a-strategic-driven-business-is-how-we.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/a-strategic-driven-business-is-how-we.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate Agent Insiders</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title> Team Lally Shares the Dirt on $82 Million in Sales </title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/5ju79c4sM1Q?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We want to give you a peek behind the curtain into what a true real estate career looks like with a career night. Here’s how you can join us.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we want to talk to you about a career in real estate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone’s perception of real estate is what they see on those reality shows. Well, here’s the reality about reality TV—it’s not real!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why we want to give you a peek behind the curtain into the real real estate career. We’re everyday people providing exceptional levels of service, and we’re looking for superstars to join us. How do we do that? With a career night, which will be held on March 6th, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please RSVP &amp;lt;a href=https://www.teamlally.com/career-night.php”&amp;gt;here&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; to save a seat, because we do fill up.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the things you will learn include:
- The first three steps to becoming a successful Realtor.
- The two critical mistakes brand-new Realtors make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll also answer any questions you may have. If you have any questions in the meantime, please don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’re looking forward to meeting you there in person. Thanks and aloha!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 11:38:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/team-lally-shares-dirt-on-82-million-in.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/team-lally-shares-dirt-on-82-million-in.html</guid>
        
        <category>Team Lally Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kapolei Mastermind Key to Success - Last Friday Of Every Month</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Fb7pt3hLWaM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The power of the mastermind is undeniable. We’d love for you to join us on the last Friday of the month for one.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we want to talk about the power of the mastermind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Napoleon Hill calls the mastermind “the key that will open the door to your desires,” whatever they may be. He defines it as two or more people that work in perfect harmony for the attainment of a definite purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We want to bring this to you, so we’re holding a mastermind session in our Kapolei Business Center.&lt;/strong&gt; We do this every month on the last Friday of the month from 12:30 p.m. to 1:30 p.m. The agenda is filled with topics that, if implemented, will make you more money in 2017. The invitation is to anyone interested in learning our secrets of success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=THESE SECRETS HELPED US GENERATE OVER $82 MILLION IN SALES LAST YEAR.%20http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/kapolei-mastermind-key-to-success-last.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“THESE SECRETS HELPED US GENERATE OVER $82 MILLION IN SALES LAST YEAR.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These secrets helped us generate over $82 million in sales in 2016 and we are going to share them with you. Now, we know that you’re thinking we won’t really share our secrets, but you’re wrong. &lt;strong&gt;We have learned that it is good to be abundant-minded and that sharing is caring.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you still don’t believe us, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.teamlally.com/kw.php&quot;&gt;RSVP here&lt;/a&gt; and bring your questions to us on the last Friday of the month. In the meantime, take a look at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.forbes.com/sites/chicceo/2013/10/21/7-reasons-to-join-a-mastermind-group/#38b986e817ab&quot;&gt;this recent Forbes article&lt;/a&gt; we found that will give you seven better reasons to join a mastermind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. Thanks and aloha!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 13:56:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/kapolei-mastermind-key-to-success-last.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/kapolei-mastermind-key-to-success-last.html</guid>
        
        <category>Agent Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Team Lally Interviews President of the CCIM Board Anthony Provenzano </title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/vh0mk7sotm0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The CCIM Board of Hawaii is hosting an upcoming event to talk about the 2017 market forecast. We caught up with their President to talk about the event.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we want to talk to you about a special event coming up. This is the CCIM Annual Forecast event to be held at the Hawaii Convention Center. CCIM stands for Certified Commercial Investment Member.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This event takes place Friday, February 3rd from 8 a.m. to 11 a.m.&lt;/strong&gt; Paul Brewbaker, a local economist, with be one of the speakers. Topics include a forecast for industrial, investment, office, retail and residential real estate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ccimhawaii.org/documents-2017/Forecast%20Registration%20Feb%203.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to RSVP. Parking and breakfast are included.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With us today we have the of the President of the CCIM Hawaii chapter, Anthony Provenzano, who also has his broker designation and is the Senior Vice President of Sofos Realty. He is here to give us his top three reasons to attend this event, which are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Network with more than 600 industry professionals.
2. Learn where the industry experts see their specialty going in 2017.
3. Gain an overall understanding of the economy and commercial real estate for 2017.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=YOU WILL GAIN INVALUABLE INFORMATION AT THIS EVENT.%20http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/team-lally-interviews-president-of-ccim.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“YOU WILL GAIN INVALUABLE INFORMATION AT THIS EVENT.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In prior years, speakers made 10 to 15 minute presentations, and questions and answers were done at the end of the program. This year, speakers will limit their slide presentation to two to three slides. The moderator, along with the audience, will be able to ask questions to the speaker at the time of the presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mission statement of the CCIM is to provide the best commercial and investment real estate education and services which afford members a unique competitive advantage in the marketplace, and recognition of the designation as the hallmark of competence, integrity, and professionalism in the industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get even more information about this event, you can also check out the interview with Anthony about the event from our radio show, which you can listen to on our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.teamlally.com/blog/anthony-provenzano-vice-president-of-sofos-realty.html&quot;&gt;podcast.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t miss this opportunity to attend one of the largest events of the year for the those who want to be in the know&lt;/strong&gt; regarding our local real estate market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CCIM has also extended the deadline for their CI101 scholarships&lt;/strong&gt; to January 27, 2017! For all those interested, you can you can find a &lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Adrienne+Lally/Albert+S.+P+Wong+101+Scholarship.pdf&quot;&gt;scholarship application here.&lt;/a&gt; Find &lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Adrienne+Lally/CI+101+2017.pdf&quot;&gt;CI101 registration forms here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, don’t hesitate to reach out and give us a call or send us an email. Thanks and Aloha!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 09:29:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/team-lally-interviews-president-of-ccim.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/team-lally-interviews-president-of-ccim.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate Events</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Did Benjy Gilholm Join Our Team?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/IzVq5VcszEk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Benjy Gilholm is a great listing partner on our team.
Hear from the man himself about how he came to join our team.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are excited to introduce another great member of our team. Benjy Gilholm is a listing partner with Team Lally and he is going to talk about what led him to us today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benjy had actually heard about us first in 2008 when he was working for a different team.&lt;/strong&gt; His team referred all their short sales to us. The first thing that attracted him to us was the fact that we did a good job with those referrals and had a stellar reputation for doing so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Benjy’s number one goal is taking care of his clients.%20http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/why-did-benjy-gilholm-join-our-team.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Benjy’s number one goal is taking care of his clients.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing that gave Benjy the fire to actually join our team was listening to our Sunday morning radio show. Benjy joined us as a listing partner because he loves getting on the phone, getting people into properties, and helping sellers list their homes successfully. His number one goal is always to take care of his clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benjy loves the team environment and the fact that the process of joining our team was so competitive.&lt;/strong&gt; He looks forward to closing 180 homes this year and continuing his success in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for Benjy or if you’re looking to get your home on the market, give him a call at (808)-647-0002. If you have any other questions, don’t hesitate to reach out. Talk to you soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 15:22:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/why-did-benjy-gilholm-join-our-team.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/why-did-benjy-gilholm-join-our-team.html</guid>
        
        <category>Meet Team Lally</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meet Tina Funk, a Buyer Specialist on Team Lally</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ipciDa16Foo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tina Funk is one of our great buyer specialists. She is here today to talk about what attracted her to our team and why she enjoys working with us.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are back to introduce yet another great member of Team Lally. Tina Funk heard about us from another agent in Honolulu that thought she would be a great fit with us. She came out and met with us and left very impressed about how much we care about our clients and how we treat our agents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=TINA HAS BEEN A GREAT FIT.%20http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/meet-tina-funk-buyer-specialist-on-team.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“TINA HAS BEEN A GREAT FIT.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there, Tina joined our team as a buyer specialist and &lt;strong&gt;she loves the role because she is responsible for one thing and one thing only, taking care of our buyers.&lt;/strong&gt; She knows that she has the support of our team through training, technology, and marketing, among other things. Tina uses all of this to bring together an incredible experience for our clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you have any questions for Tina about buying a home,&lt;/strong&gt; send her an email to tina@teamlally.com or give her a call at (808) 888-5021. If you have any other questions, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 09:52:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/meet-tina-funk-buyer-specialist-on-team.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/meet-tina-funk-buyer-specialist-on-team.html</guid>
        
        <category>Meet Team Lally</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Have You Met Kelii Lum?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/SSCelgunPDU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keli’i Lum is a buyer specialist here at Team Lally. What he enjoys most about working with us is the atmosphere and support we provide.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, we wanted you to get to know a little bit about Keli’i Lum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did you hear about Team Lally?&lt;/strong&gt;
A while ago, I decided I wanted to be a real estate investor, so I went to a real estate seminar and thought to myself: “I want to get out there and hit the real estate market and start selling homes and buying homes. Everything under the sun dealing with real estate.” So I went to these seminars and they advised reaching out to a real estate company and spending six months or so learning from professionals within the industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What motivated you to join Team Lally?&lt;/strong&gt;
They’re among the top teams and top companies in Hawaii, and that’s what led me to go out there and join them. If you want to be the best, you have to learn from the best. I want to serve my clients and customers the best way I possibly can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=IF YOU WANT TO BE THE BEST, YOU HAVE TO LEARN FROM THE BEST.%20http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/have-you-met-kelii-lum.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“IF YOU WANT TO BE THE BEST, YOU HAVE TO LEARN FROM THE BEST.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s your role on the team?&lt;/strong&gt;
I’m a buyer specialist. I’m here to help buyers get into homes, educate them about the process, and get them into a comfortable state so that by the time we get to the end, they’re a happy customer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you enjoy most about working on a team?&lt;/strong&gt;
I love the atmosphere here. There is a lot to learn from a team. With a team by your side, you have a lot of support. There is a pool of information and experience you have access to that as a single agent you wouldn’t have access to. What’s even better, it’s a lot of fun being on a team!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for Keli’i or need help buying or selling, please feel free to give us a call or shoot us an email. We look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2016 10:08:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/have-you-met-kelii-lum.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://realestatecareerhawaii.com/have-you-met-kelii-lum.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
