<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Ultimate Referral Agent Real Estate Video Career and Training Blog with Willie Miranda</title>
    <description>Our mission at The Ultimate Referral Agent is to be your best resource for Capital Region real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The The Ultimate Referral Agent, your professional Capital Region Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://www.williemirandacoachingblog.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.williemirandacoachingblog.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 14:33:31 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 14:33:31 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>I Broke My Rule</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/yv0FUzwngAk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I broke one of my cardinal rules over the weekend. Here’s where I messed up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Questions about your Real Estate Career?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:Wmiranda@mrgteam.com&quot;&gt;Click here to send me a private email.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a rule that I broke last week: Never do a listing presentation without all decision-makers in attendance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, I was called in by one of my agents to help assist her with a listing appointment. The husband and wife were interviewing nine different agents. &lt;strong&gt;As they were showing us the house, the wife had to take a call. We got into the listing presentation, but I asked the husband if he wanted to wait for his wife.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said to go ahead and start without her. Right at that point, I wanted to reschedule, but he said that they really wanted to make a decision that weekend. We went ahead and did it and at the end of the presentation, he said they would talk about it over the weekend and get back to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=YOU NEVER WANT TO PRESENT TO JUST ONE DECISION MAKER.%20http://www.williemirandacoachingblog.com/i-broke-my-big-rule.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“YOU NEVER WANT TO PRESENT TO JUST ONE DECISION MAKER.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We got a call back over the weekend saying they decided to go with someone else.&lt;/strong&gt; When we asked what the determining factor was, he said it was the commission. He went with an agent who had a lower commission so they could get every penny they could out of their home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You never want to present to just one decision maker. Whoever is going to assist in the final decision needs to be present. Every time I break this rule, there’s a much higher chance I don’t get a listing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me about your career or the real estate business in general, give me a call or send me an email. I would love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 13:05:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.williemirandacoachingblog.com/i-broke-my-big-rule.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.williemirandacoachingblog.com/i-broke-my-big-rule.html</guid>
        
        <category>Expert Advice</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Real Estate Agents Should Use Video</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/BXwK9oFqwOA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is video so important when it comes to engaging with your real estate clients? I’ll explain today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Questions about your Real Estate Career?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:Wmiranda@mrgteam.com&quot;&gt;Click here to send me a private email.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m here at The Wynn in Las Vegas for a Leading Real Estate Companies of the World Conference. The top real estate companies in the world are here, along with over 3,000 agents who are attending five days of masterminding and networking. It’s been incredible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In one of the sessions, they talked about the importance of using videos. &lt;strong&gt;The open rates, engagement levels, and response rates videos have are higher than email—even text.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A representative from BombBomb talked about how most people know the importance of video but just don’t do it. They may not like the way their voice sounds, the way they look, or they may want to lose 20 pounds before they start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His point was, you just have to get over it. People love you for who you are and they do business with who they know, like and trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=JUST START MAKING VIDEOS.%20http://www.williemirandacoachingblog.com/the-importance-of-video.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“JUST START MAKING VIDEOS.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We work with BombBomb and we’ve been doing videos for a couple of years. We get great responses from buyers, sellers, and even prospects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think of all the prospects that you call and you can’t get them on the phone. You can actually create an evergreen video to send them as a follow-up. This is a generic video that just says, “Hi, I see you visited my website. I tried reaching out but couldn’t get ahold of you, so I wanted to shoot a quick video. I have some important information for you, so please respond back.” Your engagement will be much better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just try it. If you don’t want to get into BombBomb, you can shoot a video on your phone, upload it to YouTube, create a link, and send it out from there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are many ways to do video, but the point is to get started now!&lt;/strong&gt; You can even send me your first video if you want a few pointers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please don’t hesitate to reach out to me with any questions you may have. I would be happy to help you! Please call/text me at 518-376-1073 or email me at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:wmiranda@mrgteam.com&quot;&gt;wmiranda@mrgteam.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 12:08:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.williemirandacoachingblog.com/the-importance-of-video.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.williemirandacoachingblog.com/the-importance-of-video.html</guid>
        
        <category>Expert Advice</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Webinar to Help You Achieve Your Goals in 2018</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/x-M9DNyK4jE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join author Paul Cummings and I in my latest webinar where we discuss how to plan and execute all of your goals in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Questions about your Real Estate Career?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:Wmiranda@mrgteam.com&quot;&gt;Click here to send me a private email.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read an article recently that said less than 10% of all people have written goals of any kind, and 90% of the population is walking around every single minute on everyone else’s agenda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same article stated that 80% to 85% of all New Year’s resolutions made at the beginning of the year are totally gone by now because people don’t have the structures and systems in place to execute their goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can you be a part of the percentile that makes goals and achieves them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=THIS WEBINAR WILL BRING YOUR 2018 GAME TO THE NEXT LEVEL.%20http://www.williemirandacoachingblog.com/learn-how-to-execute-your-goals.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“THIS WEBINAR WILL BRING YOUR 2018 GAME TO THE NEXT LEVEL.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This week, I hosted a webinar where I interviewed Paul Cummings&lt;/strong&gt;, author of the book “It All Matters: 125 Strategies to Achieve Maximum Confidence, Clarity, Certainty, and Creativity.” I asked Paul some really neat questions about what you need to have in order to engage and execute your goals. He put together a 10-step process on how to build your goals, and he included nine area goals as well that you need to have to create a great work-life balance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To watch the full webinar, &lt;a href=&quot;https://register.gotowebinar.com/recording/recordingView?webinarKey=6463891808849661443&amp;amp;registrantEmail=victoria@woople.com&amp;amp;assets=true&amp;amp;utm_content=buffere7c64&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter.com&amp;amp;utm_campaign=buffer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are you going to do differently this year? If you keep doing the same thing, you’ll get the same results. By implementing the strategies Paul talks about in his book and outlines in this webinar, you’ll be able to bring your 2018 game to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this webinar, how to set goals, or you have any other real estate needs, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be glad to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 15:21:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.williemirandacoachingblog.com/learn-how-to-execute-your-goals.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.williemirandacoachingblog.com/learn-how-to-execute-your-goals.html</guid>
        
        <category>Goals</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Broken Windows, Broken Business: A Book to Improve Your Customer Service</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qdU1Qco9iK4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently picked up a great book called “Broken Windows, Broken Business”. It helped me improve my business practices, and it can help you, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Questions about your Real Estate Career?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:Wmiranda@mrgteam.com&quot;&gt;Click here to send me a private email.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each and every month, I have a goal to read two books, usually about growth, personal development, and leadership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month, I read a great book titled &lt;strong&gt;“Broken Windows, Broken Business” by Michael Levine.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s a great book that every business owner should know about. It spells out all the different factors in business that could have major short-term and long-term impacts if not handled properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It opened my eyes to some of the “broken windows” my own company has—things that we need to check up on in order to make sure they’re corrected right away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;He gave some examples of broken windows you might find in various businesses&lt;/strong&gt;, like uncleanliness in restaurants. What does the kitchen look like? Is the food fresh? If a person leaves that restaurant because of dirty conditions, they’ll likely tell other people about it, which would damage that establishment’s reputation, and ultimately harm their business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=CUSTOMER SERVICE IS THE NO. 1 BROKEN WINDOW IN BUSINESS.%20http://www.williemirandacoachingblog.com/books-to-improve-your-business.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“CUSTOMER SERVICE IS THE NO. 1 BROKEN WINDOW IN BUSINESS.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my main takeaways from the book was that customer service is the No.1 broken window in business. &lt;strong&gt;If you have someone in your company who isn’t giving great customer service, they shouldn’t be with your company.&lt;/strong&gt; It reflects not only on the owner, but on the entire organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The author gave a few ways that you can use to find what broken windows your business may have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Mystery shop your business.&lt;/strong&gt; Using real estate as an example, you could go online and create a fake lead to see how long it takes for your company to follow up with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Call the office directly&lt;/strong&gt; to see how long it takes for them to answer. What’s the agent’s tone like? It works a lot like curb appeal for a home; if you come to a home with garbage all over the place, it tends to push people away. Customer service, similarly, needs to be good from the first encounter in order to keep clients coming back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Walk-ins.&lt;/strong&gt; Have someone physically come into the business and see how they’re treated from beginning to end.
In the end, you need a way to determine what you’re doing wrong, what you’re doing well, as well as if you’re hiring the right people to give the level of service you can be proud of. I know that I’ll be going back to talk to my staff about our broken windows, and it might be a good idea for you to do the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me about books for business owners, or about real estate in general, feel free to reach out to me. I’d be glad to talk with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 12:27:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.williemirandacoachingblog.com/books-to-improve-your-business.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.williemirandacoachingblog.com/books-to-improve-your-business.html</guid>
        
        <category>Books</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Can You Sort Your Database?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/pWIteC3vhE4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How should you sort your database? We use five distinct tags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Questions about your Real Estate Career?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:Wmiranda@mrgteam.com&quot;&gt;Click here to send me a private email.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question of how to qualify or sort your database comes up a lot. I always say that your success or failure in real estate is in direct proportion to the number of people that think of you when they think of real estate. It’s important to reach out to them consistently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For our database, we use Top Producer. Regardless of what you use, you need to create tags. &lt;strong&gt;We use five different tags&lt;/strong&gt; for every client or prospect that goes into our database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=REGARDLESS OF WHAT YOU USE, YOU NEED TO CREATE TAGS FOR YOUR PROSPECTS.%20http://www.williemirandacoachingblog.com/capital-district-real-estate-how-to.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“REGARDLESS OF WHAT YOU USE, YOU NEED TO CREATE TAGS FOR YOUR PROSPECTS.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The first category is my raving fans VIP list&lt;/strong&gt;; people who trust me, know who I am, and whom I’ve sold multiple homes to or have given me multiple referrals. The second category is ‘A clients,’ or those who have referred business to me or would in the future. The goal is to get every level of client to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next group, ‘B clients,’ are people who would do business with you in the future when they have a need or would refer you business. Then, a ‘C client’ is someone who hasn’t done any business with you or referred you any leads. They might be an Internet lead or someone you met at an open house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the last category is the ‘D prospects,’ or people you just don’t want to work with. You might have had a bad experience with them or they just don’t return your calls. We have this category for tracking purposes only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about sorting your database or you’d like a copy of how we break down our categories, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I’d be glad to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 15:17:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.williemirandacoachingblog.com/capital-district-real-estate-how-to.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.williemirandacoachingblog.com/capital-district-real-estate-how-to.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate Coaching</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Farming Strategies Work Best for Us?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/S5KoDgIZ8o4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can you get more business in the neighborhoods you are targeting? Don’t be afraid of snail mail!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Questions about your Real Estate Career?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:Wmiranda@mrgteam.com&quot;&gt;Click here to send me a private email.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a conversation with an agent a few weeks ago who was working with some out-of-town buyers. He was working in a few different neighborhoods, but felt bad because he wasn’t doing enough prospecting in order to find more listings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When he ended up driving through one of those neighborhoods, he was sad to see two yard signs on two different properties. They weren’t his signs however. They were from his competitors. That tends to make any agent feel crappy. However, I told him not to lose sight of his goals and I offered him a few tips on how to better market to different neighborhoods he was working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One of the things that works best for me and my team is a monthly newsletter.&lt;/strong&gt; I present a lot of different information from housing market statistics to community updates and even recipes. I also include testimonials, data from recently sold homes, and information about any special events we have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By getting in front of our geographic farm areas with a newsletter like this, we are always top of mind with homeowners. &lt;strong&gt;This helps us get more listings, more buyers, and more business in general.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another way we like to reach out to entire neighborhoods is by sending out mailers for different charity events we do. For example, we had a canned food drive for the local food pantry and it was a huge success. We gave away free ice cream to everyone who came and donated a can. &lt;strong&gt;We only spent a few hours and a few hundred dollars, but it was a great way to give back to the community and keep us top of mind.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, “just listed” and “just sold” postcards are alway a smart idea. It lets people know what their neighbors’ homes are selling for and it’s a great way to insert testimonials into your marketing material. People always trust referrals, so this is an important step to building up a good reputation in an area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=“Just listed” and “just sold” postcards are alway a smart idea.%20http://www.williemirandacoachingblog.com/capital-district-real-estate-farming.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;““Just listed” and “just sold” postcards are alway a smart idea.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are just a few of the ways you can up your marketing in geographical farms to attract more buyers and sellers. If you have any questions for us, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I would love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2017 17:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.williemirandacoachingblog.com/capital-district-real-estate-farming.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.williemirandacoachingblog.com/capital-district-real-estate-farming.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate Coaching</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
