<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Treu Group - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 13:22:36 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 13:22:36 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Things to Know About the Palm Beach County Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/PzqeHzODsAE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real estate market can be a little bit confusing, especially if you’re getting your information from friends, family, or the news. So I wanted to give you some accurate information about the Palm Beach County market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last month, we had 5.1 months of inventory. &lt;strong&gt;That means we’re still in a seller’s market.&lt;/strong&gt; If you’re looking to buy, you’re going to need to be prepared, and if you’re looking to sell, you’re going to be pretty happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;35.7% of all transactions that closed last month were cash. There were no appraisal contingencies and no financing in these transactions. The median price was $327,000 and that number keeps rising. We still have room to grow, as the number when we were at the height of our market was around $375,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A question frequently asked is this: “Are you buying or selling in a buyer’s market or seller’s market?” It depends on two things: the area and the price range that you’re in. For example, if you’re buying or selling a single-family home in the $200,000 to $250,000 range, then you’re in a very strong seller’s market. There are only about two months inventory in this price range.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=THERE’S ALWAYS AN OPPORTUNITY IN THE MARKET.%20localhost:4000/things-to-know-about-palm-beach-county.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“THERE’S ALWAYS AN OPPORTUNITY IN THE MARKET.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you increase your budget and you’re buying or selling in the $300,000 to $400,000 range, then you’re still in a seller’s market and there’s only about three months of inventory. Sellers are receiving multiple offers for these homes and buyers are going to have a hard time beating out the competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you move into the luxury market ($600,000 to $1 million range), you’ll see we’re in a buyer’s market. We have nine months of inventory in this market, so if you’re looking to buy then you’ll have plenty to choose from. The same goes for homes that are priced at $1 million or more. We have 16 months of inventory available in this market, making it a strong buyer’s market as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s always an opportunity in the market. The question is how do you capitalize on that? Here at True Group Real Estate, we’ve been helping buyers in the seller’s market get the home of their dreams. If you’re selling, we want to help you get the most money for your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re in the luxury market and you’re frustrated because your home isn’t selling, we have the right formula to get a sold sign in the yard and you to the closing table. The formula is simple, but it isn’t easy; you need &lt;strong&gt;the right price, the right condition, and the right marketing.&lt;/strong&gt; We can help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about real estate, or you’re looking to buy or sell a home, please give a call or shoot us an email. We’d love to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2017 10:31:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/things-to-know-about-palm-beach-county.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/things-to-know-about-palm-beach-county.html</guid>
        
        <category>2017 Real Estate Market</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tips for Buying a Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe frameborder=&quot;no&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/328848407&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buying your first home can be an intimidating process. Lisa Treu, of Treu Group Real Estate, talks about everything you should know before making your first real estate purchase. Did you know that most people underestimate their ability to buy a home? From tips on saving up for that down payment, to advice on building your credit score, Lisa covers everything first time homebuyers need to take into consideration before selecting their home.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 11:44:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/tips-for-buying-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/tips-for-buying-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>WJNO Radio show</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Does Zillow Hurt Your Chances of Buying or Selling? </title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/sAG3BlI4Jkg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sites like Zillow, Realtor.com, and Trulia can be a challenge for buyers and sellers. Why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say that you are buying a home and looking for your dream home on these sites. If you call the listing agent, &lt;strong&gt;you will probably hear that the property has already sold.&lt;/strong&gt; That’s because there is a delay between what you see on those websites and what professional agents see. As real estate agents, we actually get a head start of up to seven days on the best properties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, how can you find a listing online that hasn’t already gone under contract?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can do one of two things. First, you can search on a site like ours, which pulls information directly from the MLS. That way, when a home hits the market, you will know right away. The other option is to allow us to do all of the hard work for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=OUR WEBSITE PULLS INFORMATION DIRECTLY FROM THE MLS.%20localhost:4000/the-truth-about-websites-like-zillow.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“OUR WEBSITE PULLS INFORMATION DIRECTLY FROM THE MLS.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last few buyers we’ve worked with only viewed four homes until they found their dream home. That might not seem very impressive, but one of those buyers had been searching with another agent and on their own for two long years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are selling your home, are those websites your friends? Not really. It’s important to understand how Zillow impacts your pool of buyers. If Zillow has a wrong Zestimate or other incorrect information, it can cost you thousands of dollars. &lt;strong&gt;It may even cost you the home sale.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to understand how these sites work and competitively list your home in the right place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Treu Group real estate, we understand how to help you buy, sell, and, most importantly, how to help you win. If you have any questions, we are here to help you. Just give us a call!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 14:06:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/the-truth-about-websites-like-zillow.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/the-truth-about-websites-like-zillow.html</guid>
        
        <category>Zillow</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What's your Word? Discover your Word with Chris Pan from MyIntent.org.</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe frameborder=&quot;no&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/326206974&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lisa discussed how she met Chris Pan and discovered MyIntent.org and the power of Treu Group Real Estate’s Word. The 2017 Word is Commitment. It is a constant reminder that they will Say What needs to be said, Do whatever needs to be done and Go where they need to go to help them accomplish their clients and team goals. Chris Pan, the founder of myintent.org, shares that bracelet product that is more than just a fashion piece. Chris talked about the bracelet not as jewelry but as a reminder of one’s idea of what he/she wants more from life, what challenges he/she wants to overcome, or what is something he/she is really passionate about in life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chris was kind enough to offer a 20% discount code which you get by listening to the show. These are great gifts or can be used for your personal or corporate Word.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 09:53:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/whats-your-word-discover-your-word-with.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/whats-your-word-discover-your-word-with.html</guid>
        
        <category>WJNO Radio show</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>International Interest In South Florida Is An Opportunity For You</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe frameborder=&quot;no&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/325706360&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of all 50 states, Florida has the most international buyers. This means more opportunities for you! This means more potential buyers for your home and an active real estate market. Most international buyers pay cash for vacation homes, and add to the local economy when they come to visit. Understanding which countries are interested in Florida is important, and at Treu Group Real Estate we stay informed of what’s happening abroad. Our understanding of the international market helps us better navigate our local real estate markets, and help you make an informed decision when making your next big real estate transaction.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2017 10:06:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/international-interest-in-south-florida.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/international-interest-in-south-florida.html</guid>
        
        <category>WJNO Radio show</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What's Happening with PBC Real Estate Right Now</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe frameborder=&quot;no&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/321591037&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lisa Treu shares the low down on what’s happening right now in the real estate market of Palm Beach County. Are we currently in a buyer’s or seller’s market; and what’s the difference? Tune in to hear Lisa’s expert advice on how to go about selling or buying your home in today’s market. Get the latest scoop on everything from luxury real estate to active adult communities.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 12:10:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/whats-happening-with-pbc-real-estate.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/whats-happening-with-pbc-real-estate.html</guid>
        
        <category>WJNO Radio show</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We Dont Play Games When It Comes to Achieving Results for You</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/siNoGpmg9cU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Playgrounds are a lot of fun for kids. They can be fun for us, too. However, you don’t want the job of helping you buy or sell a home becoming a game for your agent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking to buy or sell here in Palm Beach County, you probably know about some of the many challenges that could cause the deal to fall apart. There are issues with financing and inspections that may need to be solved. Lack of experience could play a role as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=GAMES ARE FUN, BUT SO IS A SUCCESSFUL REAL ESTATE TRANSACTION.%20localhost:4000/we-dont-play-games-when-it-comes-to.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“GAMES ARE FUN, BUT SO IS A SUCCESSFUL REAL ESTATE TRANSACTION.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Treu Group Real Estate, we want you to have a professional on your side that is going to be there for you to help you overcome all of the challenges you might face in order to get you to the closing table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Experience matters, and experts say that it takes 10,000 hours to master a skill. We have mastered the skill of doing business in the real estate market, and we’d love to share that skill with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t monkey around with your real estate transaction. If you have any questions or need any help, our team is just a phone call or email away. We look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 15:35:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/we-dont-play-games-when-it-comes-to.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/we-dont-play-games-when-it-comes-to.html</guid>
        
        <category>treu group real estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Treu Solutions To Avoid The 5 Biggest Real Estate Pitfalls</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe frameborder=&quot;no&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/318815549&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It takes 10,000 hours to master something. Having the right agent who knows what to do when dealing with a unique contract is essential in avoiding a real estate pitfall. At Treu Group Real Estate, our team of experts works together to help you avoid pitfalls, and to work through them when they do arise. Listen in for details on how to close your real estate deal and avoid the pitfalls.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 11:28:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/treu-solutions-to-avoid-5-biggest-real.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/treu-solutions-to-avoid-5-biggest-real.html</guid>
        
        <category>WJNO Radio show</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Steps To Buying Success</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe frameborder=&quot;no&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/317029726&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s more to buying a home than just buying. Do you know the difference between pre-qualified and pre-approved? When you’re buying a home, the deal isn’t done until all the paperwork is signed. Treu Group Real Estate has broken down the buying process into 5 simple steps so you can know what to expect throughout the buying process.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 13:42:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/5-steps-to-buying-success.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/5-steps-to-buying-success.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Unique Opportunities in the Market Today</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Y36GwtfZey4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are opportunities in every real estate market, and I want to share three of them with you today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, a recent study revealed that almost 50% of all millennials in south Florida live at home. If you want to build wealth in the United States, &lt;strong&gt;the first step in creating wealth is to own your own home.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this may not be possible for all millennials right now, some millennials should definitely consider packing up and buying their first home. If you have a great job, a steady income, and you’ve saved some money or have access to gift money, then now is a great time to get into a new property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me tell you a quick story: When I first purchased a home, I got a 13.5% adjustable mortgage rate. Compared to today’s low interest rate, you can see that homes are more affordable. You can ask your friends and your parents what their first home’s interest rates were, and I think you will agree that even a 4% interest rate is an absolute gift to the real estate market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=OWNING A HOME IS THE FIRST STEP IN CREATING YOUR OWN WEALTH.%20localhost:4000/3-unique-opportunities-in-market-today.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“OWNING A HOME IS THE FIRST STEP IN CREATING YOUR OWN WEALTH.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, if you already own your first home, &lt;strong&gt;now is a great time to upgrade to your next home or maybe even your dream home.&lt;/strong&gt; Why? If you sell your current home, you are probably selling in a seller’s market. Depending on what price range you are moving up to, you will likely be buying in a buyer’s market. So, the market currently allows you to sell in the best position possible and have more options when you go to buy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, if you are ready to retire and want top dollar for your home, you can definitely win in this market, especially if your home lines up with what millennials are interested in. Why? Right now, we have a shortage of great homes in certain price ranges. Anything under $500,000 often receives multiple offers, great prices, and great terms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, it is time to capitalize on these three great opportunities in our current market. If you have any questions about buying or selling a home, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 11:36:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/3-unique-opportunities-in-market-today.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/3-unique-opportunities-in-market-today.html</guid>
        
        <category>2017 Real Estate Market</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
