<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Utah Homes Team - your professional Utah County Real Estate Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 10:03:17 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 10:03:17 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Buying an older home? Check for water-wasters</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’re buying an older home, you may be shocked the first time you receive a water bill. Older homes don’t always have the latest in water-saving devices. Some even have a few water-gobbling features!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good news? A lot of these problems can be fixed quickly and cheaply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what to look out for:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Little leaks.&lt;/strong&gt; Always keep an eye for a leak! A dripping faucet can send up to 20 gallons of water down the drain every day. This is the first place to start when checking for waste. Change the washers on your sinks or keep the old ones but make sure that they are all well-maintained.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inefficient shower heads.&lt;/strong&gt; Putting in new, water-saving shower heads can have a big impact on your bill. Look for low-flow shower heads that average 2.5 gallons or less per minute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Problem toilets. &lt;/strong&gt;Do this food coloring test. In your toilet tank, put some drops of food coloring. If the color begins to appear in the bowl within 30 minutes without flushing, you have a leak that should be repaired immediately. Older toilets can use a lot more water than newer models, especially if an older one has a leak. Take a few minutes to inspect each toilet; you can typically hear and see evidence of leaks. Dual-flush and low-flush toilets can save a great deal of water and money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Check the water meter.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there is no water being used, the water meter should have the same reading after two hours.  If the meter does not read exactly the same, there is a leak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another good way to save?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talk to your water company. Many municipalities have water-saving programs and incentives that can save you money. In some cases, they may be able to determine if you need a water pressure regulator, which could help cut down on your water use.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/buying-an-older-home-check-for-water-wasters.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/buying-an-older-home-check-for-water-wasters.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Interest Rates: Where To, Now?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WHERE ARE INTEREST RATES HEADED?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are considering moving up to your dream home, it may be better to do it sooner than later. The two components of your monthly mortgage payment (home prices and interest rates) are both projected to increase as the year moves forward, and interest rates may increase rather dramatically. Here are some predictions on where rates will be by the end of the year:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HSH.com:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“We think that conforming 30-year fixed rates probably make it into the 4.625 percent to 4.75 percent range at some point during 2017 as a peak.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Svenja Gudell, Zillow’s Chief Economist:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I wouldn’t be surprised if the 30-year fixed mortgage rate hits 4.75 percent.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mark Fleming, the Chief Economist at First American: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“[I see] mortgage rates getting much closer to 5 percent at the end of next year.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lawrence Yun, NAR Chief Economist:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“By this time next year, expect the 30-year fixed rate to likely be in the 4.5 percent to 5 percent range.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bottom Line&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are feeling good about your family’s economic future and are considering making a move to your dream home, doing it sooner rather than later makes the most sense!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/interest-rates-where-to-now.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/interest-rates-where-to-now.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Power of Interest Rates</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Can low interest rates affect your purchasing power? How exactly?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Freddie Mac’s latest Primary Mortgage Market Survey, interest rates for a 30-year fixed rate mortgage are currently around 4%, which is still very low in comparison to recent history!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interest rate you secure when buying a home not only greatly impacts your monthly housing costs, but also impacts your purchasing power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Purchasing power, simply put, is the amount of home you can afford to buy for the budget you have available to spend. As rates increase, the price of the house you can afford will decrease if you plan to stay within a certain monthly housing budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The chart below shows what impact rising interest rates would have if you planned to purchase a home within the national median price range, and planned to keep your principal and interest payments at or about $1,100 a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/versions/3---x----956-585x---.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With each quarter of a percent increase in interest rate, the value of the home you can afford decreases by 2.5%, (in this example, $6,250). Experts predict that mortgage rates will be closer to 5% by this time next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It will be really wise to act NOW and get that dream house for your hard-earned money.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2017 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/the-power-of-interest-rates.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/the-power-of-interest-rates.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Myths About Buying A Home: Debunked, Explained, Unmasked!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are the 2 myths that may be holding you back from buying. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fannie Mae’s article, “What Consumers (Don’t) Know About Mortgage Qualification Criteria,” revealed that “only 5 to 16 percent of respondents know the correct ranges for key mortgage qualification criteria.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Myth #1: “I Need a 20% Down Payment” &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fannie Mae’s survey revealed that consumers overestimate the down payment funds needed  to qualify for a home loan. According to the report, 76% of Americans either don’t know (40%) or are misinformed (36%) about the minimum down payment required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many believe that they need at least 20% down to buy their dream home, but many programs actually let buyers put down as little as 3%.
&lt;br /&gt;On the right are the results of a Digital Risk survey of Millennials who recently purchased a home. As you can see, 64.2% were able to purchase their home by putting down less than 20%, with 43.8% putting down less than 10%!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Myth #2: “I Need a 780 FICO® Score or Higher to Buy” &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The survey revealed that 59% of Americans either don’t know (54%) or are misinformed (5%) about what FICO® score is necessary to qualify.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many Americans believe a ‘good’ credit score is 780 or higher. To help debunk this myth, let’s take a look at Ellie Mae’s latest Origination
&lt;br /&gt;Insight Report, which focuses on recently closed (approved) loans. As you can see on the right, 54.7% of approved mortgages had a credit score of 600-749.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bottom Line&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether buying your first home or moving up to your dream home, knowing your options will make the mortgage process easier. Your dream home may already be within your reach!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2017 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/myths-about-buying-a-home-debunked-explained-unmasked.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/myths-about-buying-a-home-debunked-explained-unmasked.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>4 Steps to Selling Your Home</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The best part in homeownership is the one where you and your loved ones create lifetime memories together. It is your own sanctuary of emotions and experiences. But there will come a time when you’ll be in great need to move on in life, and selling your beloved home which mirrors who you will be fundamental.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Selling your home is saying goodbye to an irreplaceable part of you. As difficult as it may be, you have to go through it. So how to do it? Here are some tips:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;* &lt;strong&gt;Price&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;- Pricing you home too high will do the opposite of attracting potential buyers. Pricing too low might take away the rightful profit you deserve.
&lt;br /&gt;- The key here is to price it not too high and not too low, base it on the current market. You need someone to help you with this. To know for sure you can check in with us to fully valuate your property. We determine market value based on comparable sales in the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;* &lt;strong&gt;Condition&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;- Making sure your home is in it’s best state is an art. It takes a few easy, basic tips and tricks to get you there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;* &lt;strong&gt;Marketing&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;- Take good photos, and we’re not only talking about the resolution but also the angle of each shot. We want buyer gasping in AWE - not restraining themselves from screaming “What are they thinking?”.
&lt;br /&gt;- Suggest an open house to your agent.
&lt;br /&gt;- Make sure to ask your agent to create a video of your home to be uploaded online. A lot of buyers spend majority of their home search online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;* &lt;strong&gt;Hire a Professional&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;- Agents save you on the hassles of spending time, money, and effort on selling your house.
&lt;br /&gt;- Studies have shown that homes typically sell for more money when handled by a real estate  professional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy selling!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/versions/whats-your-home-worth-1024x512---x----1022-354x---.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/4-steps-to-selling-your-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/4-steps-to-selling-your-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Expectation In Home Inspection</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So you made an offer, it was accepted, and  now your next task is to have the home  inspected prior to closing. More often than  not, your agent may have made your offer  contingent on a clean home inspection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This contingency allows you to renegotiate  the price paid for the home, ask the sellers  to cover repairs, or even, in some cases, walk  away. Your agent can advise you on the best  course of action once the report is filed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, what to expect when home inspecting?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to Choose an Inspector&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your agent will most likely have a short list of inspectors that they have worked with in the  past that they can recommend to you. Realtor.com suggests that you consider the following 5  areas when choosing the right home inspector for you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Qualifications&lt;/strong&gt; – Find out what’s included in your inspection &amp;amp; if the age or location of your home may warrant specific certifications or specialties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sample Reports&lt;/strong&gt; – Ask for a sample inspection report so you can review how thoroughly  they will be inspecting your dream home. The more detailed the report the better in  most cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References &lt;/strong&gt;– Do your homework. Ask for phone numbers and names of past clients that  you can call to ask about their experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Memberships &lt;/strong&gt;– Not all inspectors belong to a national or state association of home  inspectors, and membership in one of these groups should not be the only way to  evaluate your choice. Often membership in one of these organizations means that there is  continued training and education provided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Errors &amp;amp; Omission Insurance&lt;/strong&gt; – Find out what the liability of the inspector or inspection company is once the inspection is over. The inspector is only human after all, and it is possible that they might miss something they should have seen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ask your inspector if it’s okay for you to tag along during the inspection. That way they can point out anything that should be addressed or fixed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t be surprised to see your inspector climbing on the roof, crawling around in the attic,  and on the floors. The job of the inspector is to protect your investment and find any issues  with the home, including but not limited to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;roof&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;plumbing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;electrical components&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;appliances&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;heating &amp;amp; air conditioning systems&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ventilation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;windows&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;fireplace &amp;amp;  chimney&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the foundation &amp;amp; so much more!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bottom Line&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They say ‘ignorance is bliss,’ but not when investing your hard-earned money in a home of  your own. Work with a professional you can trust to give you the most information possible  about your new home so that you can make the most educated decision about your purchase.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/expectation-in-home-inspection.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/expectation-in-home-inspection.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Closing Costs: Who's Paying How Much?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have you put aside enough for closing costs?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many potential homebuyers, and even sellers, who believe that you need at least a  20% down payment in order to buy a home, or move on to their next home. Time after time,  we have dispelled this myth by showing that there are many loan programs that allow you to  put down as little as 3% (or 0% with a VA loan).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have saved up your down payment and are ready to start your home search, one other  piece of the puzzle is to make sure that you have saved enough for your closing costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Freddie Mac defines closing costs as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Closing costs, also called settlement fees, will need to be paid when you obtain a  mortgage. These are fees charged by people representing your purchase, including  your lender, real estate agent, and other third parties involved in the transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Closing costs are typically between 2 and 5% of your purchase price.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve recently heard from many first-time homebuyers that they wished that someone had  let them know that closing costs could be so high. If you think about it, with a low down  payment program, your closing costs could equal the amount that you saved for your down  payment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a list of just some of the fees/costs that may be included in your closing costs,  depending on where the home you wish to purchase is located:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Government recording costs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Appraisal fees&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Credit report fees&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lender origination fees&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Title services (insurance, search fees)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tax service fees&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Survey fees&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Attorney fees&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Underwriting fees&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is there any way to avoid paying closing costs?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work with your lender and real estate agent to see if there are any ways to decrease or defer  your closing costs. There are no-closing mortgages available, but they end up costing you  more in the end with a higher interest rate, or by wrapping the closing costs into the total  cost of the mortgage (meaning you’ll end up paying interest on your closing costs).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Home buyers can also negotiate with the seller over who pays these fees. Sometimes the seller will agree to assume the buyer’s closing fees in order to get the deal finalized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bottom Line&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speak with your lender and agent early and often to determine how much you’ll be  responsible for at closing. Finding out you’ll need to come up with thousands of dollars right  before closing is not a surprise anyone is ever looking forward to.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/closing-costs-whos-paying-how-much.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/closing-costs-whos-paying-how-much.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2017: Great Housing Year, Will It Be?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We’re going to have a good year. The question is: will it be a great year?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consumer confidence is through the roof. That means people are feeling good about the economy. They’re feeling good about their own personal finances. And that means that people are going to be moving out of the house they’re currently in, moving into a bigger home, maybe downsizing where they are and buying a vacation home, either in the mountains or on the water. Things are going to… People just feel good right now. Now, part of the reason, as we’ll explain in some of these news clips, that people are feeling good, is that after the election, they see the country going in a very positive direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consumer confidence is at a good place. People feel good about their own finances. People feel good about making a move right now. People feel good about where they stand, better than… better since 2004.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;American households are expecting a Donald Trump administration to deliver. Consumers are more upbeat about the prospects of the economy, labor market, and their incomes. It’s a time right now that people are going to be &lt;strong&gt;making moves&lt;/strong&gt;. They’re going to jump into their first house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest challenge we have going into 2017 is a whole bunch of people that want to buy a home. And not enough homes to sell. It’s crucial…  It has been said now for eight months, that if, unless the housing inventory will be fixed, we’re not going to be able to take full advantage of the market we’re in right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prices are continuing to escalate. It means people have more equity. And the equity in their home is something they should be able to do something with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s equity in a house. That equity they could use. They can use that equity to move down to where they currently are living where they might still have family or finishing up the last couple of years of the job and take the additional equity and buy that vacation home that eventually will be their retirement home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of people did refinance, some to a fifteen-year loan.  That means they’re building more equity every single month. And that equity is important for what reason? That means that they will sell their house and make a good financial decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They can make the move now that they planned to make in retirement. And now is a better time than waiting until then. If we look at the percentage of homes with positive equity by state, we can see that 93.7% of all the homes in this country with a mortgage on it… Remember one third don’t even have a mortgage on it. We’re talking about the other close to 70%. Ninety-three-point seven percent of that other 70% have positive equity now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;There’s enough equity in your home, that if you ever dreamt about moving. Instead of living around the corner from the water,  but moving to the water. Instead of staying in the four-bedroom colonial now that the kids have moved out, you can downsize and use that additional equity, either to put it into the stock market or put it into another piece of real estate that you’re going to use later in your life.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What people believe their house is worth and what they’re getting appraised for are much, much closer now. So, we don’t really have to worry about pricing. People have got the right price. The sellers got the right price in their head. There’s plenty of buyers out there. What we need to watch out for is the number of  listings the market needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Foot traffic is an indicator of how many houses people actually will go to see. The reason foot traffic is down is not because there’s less people going out. And the challenge is the buyers don’t have any houses to go see in some markets or very few. That’s why that number is down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://smartasset.com/mortgage/real-estate-trends-2017&quot;&gt;SmartAsset.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, just this past month, had an article about housing. And this is what they said, whether you’re preparing to purchase a new home or sell an old house in the new year, it’s important to know how housing trends could affect you. Keeping your finger on the pulse of the market can prevent you from being left out of the cold by rising interest rates or a widening gap between supply and demand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to know! Whether you want to buy or sell, you need to know exactly what’s happening. That’s why we do. You need someone you can trust for up-to-date information, and we are here to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2017 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/2017-great-housing-year-will-it-be.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/2017-great-housing-year-will-it-be.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Importance Of &quot;Access&quot; In Getting Your House Sold</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Role Access Plays In Getting Your House SOLD!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you’ve decided to sell your house. You’ve hired a real estate professional to help you with the entire process and they have asked you what level of access you want to provide to potential buyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are four elements to a quality listing. At the top of the list is Access, followed by Condition, Financing and Price. There are many levels of access that you could provide to your agent to be able to show your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are five levels of access that you could provide to a buyer with a brief description:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;• Lockbox On the Door &lt;/strong&gt;– this allows buyers the ability to see the home as soon as they are aware of the listing, or at their convenience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;• Providing a Key to the Home&lt;/strong&gt; – although the buyer’s agent may need to stop by an office to pick up the key, there is little delay in being able to show the home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;• Open Access with a Phone Call &lt;/strong&gt;– the seller allows showing with just a phone call’s notice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;• By Appointment Only (example: 48 Hour Notice)&lt;/strong&gt; – Many out-of-town/state buyers and relocation buyers visit an area they would like to move to and only have the weekend to view homes. They may not be able to plan that far in advance, or may be unable to wait the 48 hours to be shown the house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;• Limited Access (example: the home is only available on Mondays or Tuesdays at 2pm or for only a couple of hours a day)&lt;/strong&gt; – This is the most difficult way to be able to show your house to potential buyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a competitive marketplace, access can make or break your ability to get the price you are looking for, or even sell your house at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you’ve decided to sell your house. You’ve hired a real estate professional to help you with the entire process and they have asked you what level of access you want to provide to potential buyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are four elements to a quality listing. At the top of the list is Access, followed by Condition, Financing and Price. There are many levels of access that you could provide to your agent to be able to show your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=%20localhost:4000/importance-of-access-in-getting-your-house-sold.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/importance-of-access-in-getting-your-house-sold.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/importance-of-access-in-getting-your-house-sold.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How To Make An Effective And Irresistible Offer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;READY TO MAKE AN OFFER? 4 TIPS FOR SUCCESS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you’ve been searching for that perfect house to call a ‘home’ and you finally found one! The price is right, and in such a competitive market you want to make sure you make a good offer so that you can guarantee your dream of making this house yours comes true!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Freddie Mac covered “4 Tips for Making an Offer” in their latest Executive Perspective. Here are the 4 tips they covered along with some additional information for your consideration:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Understand How Much You Can Afford&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“While it’s not nearly as fun as house hunting, fully understanding your finances is critical in making an offer.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This ‘tip’ or ‘step’ really should take place before you start your home search process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting pre-approved is one of many steps that will show home sellers that you are serious about buying, and will allow you to make your offer with the confidence of knowing that you have already been approved for a mortgage for that amount. You will also need to know if you are prepared to make any repairs that may need to be made to the house (ex: new roof, new furnace).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Act Fast&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Even though there are fewer investors, the inventory of homes for sale is also low and competition for housing continues to heat up in many parts of the country.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inventory of homes listed for sale has remained well below the 6-month supply that is needed for a ‘normal’ market. Buyer demand has continued to outpace the supply of homes for sale, causing buyers to compete with each other for their dream home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure that as soon as you decide that you want to make an offer, you work with your agent to present it as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Make a Solid Offer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Freddie Mac offers this advice to help make your offer the strongest it can be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Your strongest offer will be comparable with other sales and listings in the neighborhood. A licensed real estate agent active in the neighborhoods you are considering will be instrumental in helping you put in a solid offer based on their experience and other key considerations such as recent sales of similar homes, the condition of the house and what you can afford.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider ways of making your offer stand out! Many buyers write a personal letter to the seller letting them know how much they would love to be the new homeowners. Your agent will be able to help you figure out if there are any other ways your offer could stand above the rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Be Prepared to Negotiate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s likely that you’ll get at least one counteroffer from the sellers so be prepared. The two things most likely to be negotiated are the selling price and closing date. Given that, you’ll be glad you did your homework first to understand how much you can afford.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your agent will also be key in the negotiation process, giving you guidance on the counteroffer and making sure that the agreed-to contract terms are met.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your offer is approved, Freddie Mac urges you to “always get an independent home inspection, so you know the true condition of the home. If the inspection uncovers undisclosed problems or issues, you can typically re-negotiate the terms or cancel the contract.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bottom Line&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether buying your first home or your fifth, having a local real estate professional who is an expert in their market on your side is your best bet to make sure the process goes smoothly. Let’s talk about how we can make your dreams of homeownership a reality!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2017 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-to-make-an-effective-and-irresistible-offer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/how-to-make-an-effective-and-irresistible-offer.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
