<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from John McAdams Real Estate - your professional Ocean City Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://johnmcadamshomes.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://johnmcadamshomes.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2017 11:49:25 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2017 11:49:25 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>I'm Here to Help You Navigate Real Estate Like a Pro</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/muLAATGd0Qg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m excited to let you know that starting now, I’ll be sharing my real estate expertise with you through my new video blog! Each month, I’ll send out two emails talking about the local real estate market here in Greenville. I’ll also address topics in lending and title, which are important components of the real estate world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Additionally, I’ll provide plenty of tips for how to best navigate the world or real estate.&lt;/strong&gt; All of these industries tie together, so to truly get the most out of the real estate market, you need to be in tune with all of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=To truly get the most out of the real estate market, you need to know all these fields.%20http://johnmcadamshomes.com/im-here-to-help-you-navigate-real-estate-like-a-pro.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“To truly get the most out of the real estate market, you need to know all these fields.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than just guessing which topics you want to learn more about, &lt;strong&gt;I encourage you to reach out to me with any questions you have.&lt;/strong&gt; Are there topics you’re confused about or want to know more about? Maybe you’d like to know more about a particular area? I’d love to answer any and all questions in my videos so that other people with similar questions can benefit as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions at all or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home in the Greenville area, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email today. I’d be more than happy to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://johnmcadamshomes.com/im-here-to-help-you-navigate-real-estate-like-a-pro.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://johnmcadamshomes.com/im-here-to-help-you-navigate-real-estate-like-a-pro.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
