<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Dave Friedman Team - your professional Charleston Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>davefriedmantv.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="davefriedmantv.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 13:48:56 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 13:48:56 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>You Could Work With a Team of Agents for the Same Price as Just One</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/hWX4pehmZf0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, I’ve noticed that a lot of people are curious as to whether working with a team is truly better than hiring an individual agent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These days, the truth is that most people undergoing a real estate transaction tend to utilize a team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a great option since a team costs the same as an individual agent but provides you with more services for your money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hiring multiple professionals for the same price as you would pay for one simply makes more sense. &lt;strong&gt;Working with a team means you will have access to a higher level of communication, better marketing, and a wider base of expertise.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently pulled a report from the multiple listing service to help illustrate this point. According to these statistics, the average days on market for a listing sold with a single agent was typically greater than 50. Also, listings sold with a single agent tend to sell for 5% less than list price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Getting more service for the same price is always the obvious choice.%20davefriedmantv.com/you-could-work-with-a-team-of-agents-for-the-same-price-as-just-one.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Getting more service for the same price is always the obvious choice.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you look at my team’s statistics for this year so far, it’s a very different story. &lt;strong&gt;With us, a home’s average days on market is five, and all of our listings sell for 100% of asking price.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think of it this way: if you needed surgery, would you rather trust a single surgeon working out of his car, or go to the hospital under the care of a professional team? Getting more service for the same price is always the obvious choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buying or selling a home is a huge life event—that’s why it’s critical to work with the right people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in working with us, have any other questions, or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 04:52:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>davefriedmantv.com/you-could-work-with-a-team-of-agents-for-the-same-price-as-just-one.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">davefriedmantv.com/you-could-work-with-a-team-of-agents-for-the-same-price-as-just-one.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Top 10 Reasons to Sell During the Fall and Winter</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_I90hm0exuw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of people have been asking me if the fall and winter are good times to sell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My answer is, “Yes!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today let’s go through the top 10 reasons why I think fall and winter are great times to get your home sold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. You will be a non-contingent homebuyer.&lt;/strong&gt;This gives you much more leverage as a purchaser in the market when you do have a home to sell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. There are a lot of rental vacancies&lt;/strong&gt;, which will make it easier if you have to do a double move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. You can restrict showings during the holidays.&lt;/strong&gt; It is perfectly acceptable to restrict showings to accommodate any holiday plans you might have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. January is the biggest month for transferees&lt;/strong&gt;. A lot of big companies will end up hiring and transferring employees during this month, so those employees will begin house hunting in November and December.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. People are looking to buy for tax purposes&lt;/strong&gt;, especially investors. By purchasing before the end of the year, these buyers can enjoy tax benefits for the 2017 tax year, instead of waiting for those benefits to apply to the 2018 tax year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Buyers have more time to look for homes.&lt;/strong&gt; Things may be slower at their workplace, or they may have more time off to dedicate to searching for a house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Buyers are more emotional.&lt;/strong&gt;A lot of buyers will make decisions based on emotion, so the holidays are great for appealing to a buyer’s sentimental side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. Homes will show better.&lt;/strong&gt;Decorating a house for the holiday season will help buyers fall in love with it, enabling them to imagine themselves living there with their families during the holidays. Again, this time can really appeal to a buyer’s emotions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. Supply will dramatically increase&lt;/strong&gt; in February and March, so you’ll have more competition at that time when it comes to selling your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10. Buyers are more serious and have fewer options&lt;/strong&gt;. People also have a limiting belief that there aren’t as many buyers in the market during the holidays. There may not be as many lookers, but the buyers in the marketplace are more serious. Additionally, the lack of supply suggests that your home could sell for more money since buyers will have fewer options to select from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=It’s impossible to time the market perfectly, but don’t be gun-shy when it comes to listing during the holidays.%20davefriedmantv.com/top-10-reasons-to-sell-during-the-fall-and-winter.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“It’s impossible to time the market perfectly, but don’t be gun-shy when it comes to listing during the holidays.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, the best time to sell is when it makes the most sense to you. It’s impossible to time the market perfectly, but I wouldn’t be gun-shy when it comes to listing during the holidays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, don’t hesitate to reach out to us.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 03:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>davefriedmantv.com/top-10-reasons-to-sell-during-the-fall-and-winter.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">davefriedmantv.com/top-10-reasons-to-sell-during-the-fall-and-winter.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>You're Invited to Our Great Pie Giveaway</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/E-49ZGtPWYU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to say thank you so much for the wonderful year that we’ve had. We couldn’t have done it without you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a token of our gratitude, we’re once again holding our &lt;strong&gt;Great Pie Giveaway&lt;/strong&gt;. We’ve given away hundreds of pies each year for the last three years, with this year being our fourth giveaway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should have received a postcard in the mail, so if you do want a pie, we’d like to encourage you to &lt;strong&gt;RSVP for yours by Thursday, November 16th,&lt;/strong&gt; by emailing me or calling the number provided. We want to serve you and your family over the holidays the way that you’ve helped us over the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=As a token of our gratitude, we’re once again holding our Great Pie Giveaway.%20davefriedmantv.com/youre-invited-to-our-great-pie-giveaway.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“As a token of our gratitude, we’re once again holding our Great Pie Giveaway.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re going to order enough pies for everybody who wants one for their family. You can pick up your pie at our office in Mt. Pleasant on &lt;strong&gt;Monday, November 20th, from 9 a.m. to 3 p.m., or Tuesday, November 21st, from 1 p.m. to 5 p.m.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, thank you so much for supporting us and our business. If there’s anything we can do for you, just let us know.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 06:03:47 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>davefriedmantv.com/youre-invited-to-our-great-pie-giveaway.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">davefriedmantv.com/youre-invited-to-our-great-pie-giveaway.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Latest Real Estate News in Charleston</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/usfqwh9xnFU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we head into the last few months of the year, I wanted to give you an update on the Charleston market for the end of October. Here’s what we’ve been seeing lately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This might be the first year that we surpass 18,000 home sales in the Charleston Tri-County area.&lt;/strong&gt; Buyer activity is up 3.3% over the last month and our median sale price is up 4.1% to $254,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Each pocket of the market is a little different.%20davefriedmantv.com/the-latest-real-estate-news-in-charleston.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Each pocket of the market is a little different.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, the market average for inventory is just 3.1 months. That puts us in a pretty strong seller’s market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the numbers above are an average of the entire Tri-County area, they don’t tell the full story of the market. Each little pocket of the market has its own unique set of characteristics. There are about 20 of those pockets that are in seller’s markets right now. Another nine pockets are seeing a bit more of a balanced market and there are three pockets out there that are in buyer’s markets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you want to know what’s going on in your specific pocket of the market, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email.&lt;/strong&gt; We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 09:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>davefriedmantv.com/the-latest-real-estate-news-in-charleston.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">davefriedmantv.com/the-latest-real-estate-news-in-charleston.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>You're Invited to Our First-Ever Great Pumpkin Giveaway</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/grHSdCQ3mgQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m excited to invite you to our first-ever Great Pumpkin Giveaway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This community appreciation event is going to take place on &lt;strong&gt;Sunday, October 8th between 11 a.m. and 3 p.m.&lt;/strong&gt;, and you aren’t going to want to miss it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event will take place at 99 Harry M. Hallman, Junior Boulevard, Mt. Pleasant, SC 29464.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We’ve got 1,200 pumpkins to give away&lt;/strong&gt;, so invite all of your friends and family to come out for the fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We’ve got 1,200 pumpkins to give away, so invite all of your friends and family.%20davefriedmantv.com/youre-invited-to-our-first-ever-great-pumpkin-giveaway.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We’ve got 1,200 pumpkins to give away, so invite all of your friends and family.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be something for everyone. We’ll have a professional fall photographer to help you capture memories with loved ones, as well as a bouncy house and face painting for the kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope to see you there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 08:25:31 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>davefriedmantv.com/youre-invited-to-our-first-ever-great-pumpkin-giveaway.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">davefriedmantv.com/youre-invited-to-our-first-ever-great-pumpkin-giveaway.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Incredible Story of a Family We Helped in Houston</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/anfmtjNo204?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, my team and I are in Houston, Texas, where we’ve been helping with flood relief efforts in the wake of the recent storm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During our time here, we’ve had some amazing experiences. Overall, one experience in particular has stood out in my mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, we went into the home of one family we helped and had to remove a huge amount of drywall, flooring, and furniture from the house. This was done to help decrease the amount of mold growing inside their home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this process, we began to talk to the family about what had happened. According to the family, it was late at night when they found out the levees were going to be opened near their home. Progressively throughout that evening, water levels began to rise in their neighborhood. &lt;strong&gt;By about 4 a.m. there was approximately six feet of water on the street and six inches of water in their home.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=This was an absolutely incredible experience and we’re so humbled to help.%20davefriedmantv.com/the-incredible-story-of-a-family-we-helped-in-houston.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“This was an absolutely incredible experience and we’re so humbled to help.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point the family was forced to evacuate by boat, only to return to their home two days later with nowhere else to go. The water had receded, but the damage was done. So many families are going through such terrible hardship right now, and it is absolutely tragic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The family we’ve been speaking about today has actually filed four insurance claims already. &lt;strong&gt;Within the last two weeks, all four of these claims have been lost by the insurance company.&lt;/strong&gt;With so much having befallen her family, the matriarch of the family said that she was beginning to lose her faith. On the same day she was telling this to her family, though, we showed up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They had absolutely no idea we were coming. According to the wife and mother, it was us showing up that helped to restore her faith. This was an absolutely incredible experience and we’re so humbled to have been able to help them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is hard to describe the feeling of seeing the things we’ve seen here. Imagine opening a cabinet to find fish sitting in pots and pans. Some homes were filled with mud while others were just completely destroyed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is exactly why we thought it was so important to help. We’ve supplied some manpower and made donations toward the relief effort.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you have any goods or supplies to donate, we’re shipping supplies out from our Charleston area. Monetary donations are encouraged, as well. We’ve already raised about $10,000, and we’re still raising more. &lt;strong&gt;Anything you can give, even if it’s only a dollar, is appreciated.&lt;/strong&gt; You can find the link to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kwrelief.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;donation page here&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 10:00:50 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>davefriedmantv.com/the-incredible-story-of-a-family-we-helped-in-houston.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">davefriedmantv.com/the-incredible-story-of-a-family-we-helped-in-houston.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Changes Are We Seeing in the Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/QeMBj7u6i70?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some big changes happening right now in the Greater Charleston area. We usually see a bit of a shift around this time of year, but some of the things we are noticing are pretty atypical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last three months, we’ve had 5,200 homes come on the market. However, our pending listings have dropped from 3,500 to 3,000 in that same time frame. That’s a significant difference. In addition to that, the price per square foot is in the high $160s right now, but homes are selling for about $134. &lt;strong&gt;It tells me that there are a lot of homes on the market right now that are overpriced.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Whether this shift continues or not depends on buyer confidence.%20davefriedmantv.com/what-changes-are-we-seeing-in-the-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Whether this shift continues or not depends on buyer confidence.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of the reason buyer activity has slowed down is because buyers are deciding that homes aren’t just worth what sellers are asking for them and it’s causing a bit of a shift. Will it continue? I have no idea, but it depends on where buyer confidence is above all else. &lt;strong&gt;If buyers continue to not buy and decide homes are overpriced, the market will slow down.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been thinking about selling your home, right now is the perfect time. In fact, this is one of the best seller’s markets I’ve ever seen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me or want any buying or selling advice, give me a call or send me an email. I would love to hear from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>davefriedmantv.com/what-changes-are-we-seeing-in-the-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">davefriedmantv.com/what-changes-are-we-seeing-in-the-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Shockingly High Margin of Error With Zestimates</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/uK5pd2OcE4w?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How accurate are Zillow’s Zestimates? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zestimates are within 20% of a home’s sale price 80% of the time, which is a huge margin of error. &lt;strong&gt;For a $300,000 home, that margin of error could swing from $240,000 to $360,000. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zestimates are within 10% of the sale price just 70% of the time as well. In our $300,000 example home, the Zestimate could be off by $30,000 on the high or low side seven out of 10 times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Zestimates are within 5% of a home's actual value less than half the time.%20davefriedmantv.com/the-shockingly-high-margin-of-error-with-zestimates.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Zestimates are within 5% of a home’s actual value less than half the time.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, Zillow’s Zestimates are within 5% of the sales price just 45% of the time. That’s still a $30,000 margin of error, and that’s as accurate as they get. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a professional real estate agent, &lt;strong&gt;I would have been out of the business a long time ago if I was off by 5% on home value estimates that often.&lt;/strong&gt; That would mean I either overprice the home and it won’t sell, or I underprice it and leave thousands and thousands of dollars on the table!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about how to find your home’s actual value or about using Zillow, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I’m always happy to help.
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2017 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>davefriedmantv.com/the-shockingly-high-margin-of-error-with-zestimates.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">davefriedmantv.com/the-shockingly-high-margin-of-error-with-zestimates.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Do Homebuyers Need to Work With a Buyer’s Agent?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/KmORiAKtF7U?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of people have been asking me recently, “What’s up with the buyer agency agreement? What does it even mean?”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;When you call the number on a ‘For Sale’ sign inquiring about the home that’s for sale, you end up talking to the listing agent that the seller has hired. That person has a legal obligation to sell that person’s home for the most amount of money in the least amount of time.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Is that the person you want to work with? The person who has a direct responsibility to the seller to fulfill those obligations? I don’t think so.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;That’s why the state came up with buyer representation. In the words of a good friend of mine, “It’s the best money you haven’t spent.” It doesn’t cost you anything to work with a buyer’s agent, so why wouldn’t you?
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are many benefits to working with a buyer’s agent, such as:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We make sure you don’t overpay for a home.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We shop interest rates for you to make sure you have the best financing available.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We negotiate the best deal for you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We find the best home inspector to make sure the home doesn’t have any problems. If it does, we have the seller fix them for you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Furthermore, there are other guarantees packaged into our team’s buyer agency agreement.&lt;/strong&gt; For example, you can cancel our agreement at any time. Most Realtors want to lock you into a late fee contract, but not us. We want to hold ourselves accountable to you because we know for a fact that as long as you’re happy, you’ll have no reason to work with anybody else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Working with a buyer’s agent is the best money you haven’t spent.%20davefriedmantv.com/why-do-homebuyers-need-to-work-with-a-buyers-agent.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Working with a buyer’s agent is the best money you haven’t spent.”&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Even if you walk into a home and immediately fall in love with it, we’ll give you reasons why you shouldn’t buy it. We don’t want you to make a bad decision, which alludes to our second guarantee: if you buy a home and you’re dissatisfied with it for whatever reason within the first 24 months, I’ll come over and sell it for free. Lastly, if we can’t negotiate a home warranty into the contract for you, then we’ll buy the house for you.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;If you have any more questions about the legal obligations and requirements of the buyer’s agency agreement, don’t hesitate to give me a call. I’d be more than happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>davefriedmantv.com/why-do-homebuyers-need-to-work-with-a-buyers-agent.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">davefriedmantv.com/why-do-homebuyers-need-to-work-with-a-buyers-agent.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Let Us Take You Out to the Ballgame at Riverdog Stadium</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ep2TWepfgV4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re hereby invited to our annual community appreciation event &lt;strong&gt;at the Riverdog Stadium on June 7th at 7:05 p.m.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a very special event in which we’ve teamed up with ServiceMaster Lawton Hayes to host it for the last three years. We’ll have drinks, food, and for every person who attends the game, I’ll donate $10 to the Burned Children’s Fund at MUSC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This fund is truly amazing, and I know for a fact that all the money that was raised at this same event last year was used to install 3,000 smoke detectors into homes that needed them. Two different people have even confirmed for a fact that their lives were saved based on this event and everybody showing up and contributing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We’d love for you to join us at the ballpark.%20davefriedmantv.com/let-us-take-you-out-to-the-ballgame-at-riverdog-stadium.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We’d love for you to join us at the ballpark.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best part? It’s 100% free. &lt;strong&gt;If you’re interested in attending, just reply back to our email and let me know how many ticket vouchers you need. &lt;/strong&gt;Look for me in front inside the Dave Friedman Team tent where you can exchange your vouchers for tickets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this event, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I look forward to seeing you soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>davefriedmantv.com/let-us-take-you-out-to-the-ballgame-at-riverdog-stadium.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">davefriedmantv.com/let-us-take-you-out-to-the-ballgame-at-riverdog-stadium.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
