<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Culhane Premier Properties</title>
    <description>Our mission at Culhane Premier Properties is to be your best resource for  real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Culhane Premier Properties, your professional  Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 13:38:55 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 13:38:55 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Loan Officer Is Key to Closing on Your Home </title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/G-I127TZyNU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re excited to announce our partnership with Chris Motal from Loan Depot. After all, the loan officer is a key player in your real estate purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you purchase residential real estate, the lender or loan officer you work with can be very important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you sign an agreement to buy a piece of property from a seller, you are agreeing to a roadmap. The purchase agreement says that you are going to do all of the critical things from the inspection to the appraisal in order to close on a certain date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, the lender is the most important person in this process. We are here to guide you through this process and help you but ultimately, &lt;strong&gt;closing is up to the lender or loan officer.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why I couldn’t be more excited to introduce you to our new partnership with Chris Motal of Loan Depot. Chris is going to serve alongside us and help our clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Chris and his team have great people, great products, and great values.%20localhost:4000/the-loan-officer-is-key-to-closing-on.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Chris and his team have great people, great products, and great values.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chris and his team have great products, great people, and great values. They are just plain fun to work with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if you have already bought a house, Chris and his team can help you. If you plan on making some changes, renovations, or remodeling, let Chris and his team know. He has an amazing product suite that you can use to fulfill any of your dreams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you are moving up, down, or across town, let Chris know. “I have a great loan product that’s perfect for this market with great rates and a low fee structure,” says Chris. “And I’ve got one that I’m really proud of: a zero down VA renovation mortgage.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a veteran and want to buy a home with zero down, &lt;strong&gt;you can get the home of your dreams as well as up to $35,000 to renovate the property before you move in.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, you can reach Chris at 512-485-7970 or cmotal@loandepot.com. As always, if you have any real estate questions, just give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 15:46:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/the-loan-officer-is-key-to-closing-on.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/the-loan-officer-is-key-to-closing-on.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Some of the Best Lakefront Properties in Texas</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/vlRnOhsxRNw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lakefront properties are a passion of ours. Here are a few that we just listed on the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have a passion for helping people buy and sell waterfront property here in Central Texas. We’ve got four amazing properties on the shores of Lake Travis and Lake Austin that we’d like to talk to you about today. We also want to talk about where home values are going, what trends we are seeing in the real estate market, and what’s changed in the last few years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first property is located at 17216 Northlake Hills Dr. in Jonestown. It’s located within the gated community of Northlake Hills and is just a quick 20-minute drive to the new Whole Foods in Cedar Park. This home is just over 10,000 square feet with eight bedrooms, 10 bathrooms, multiple pools, a detached guest house, and an income-producing 22-slip marina.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second one is also located in Jonestown in The Hollows, one of the top communities in Lake Travis and one of the best marinas on the lake. This home is located at 17607 Breakwater Drive. If you want an 11,000 sq. ft. home with one of the best views of the lake, this is it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Some of the best views on the lake.%20localhost:4000/some-of-best-lakefront-properties-in.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Some of the best views on the lake.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third property we have is at 21902 Briarcliff Drive in Spicewood, where some of the best water on Lake Travis is. There is a main house with three bedrooms and a guest quarters with one bedroom and a full kitchen and bath. &lt;strong&gt;This is great for short-term rentals or guests.&lt;/strong&gt; Right now, the owner is leasing this property out for $16,000 in the month of July.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last but not least is 13240 Shore Vista. It sits just under three acres and just over 7,000 square feet. It’s located in an area with some of the most private water and private estates on Lake Austin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Values can vary immensely, depending on the lake and the area within the lake that we are talking about. When the drought came in 2011, the levels of Lake Travis dropped significantly. People started shifting their purchases more towards Lake Austin. We saw a low point for values in 2014, but they have since recovered. &lt;strong&gt;There has been a slight dip in values in both lakes in 2017, so we’re keeping a close eye on that.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for us about any of these properties or want to know anything else about this kind of real estate, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 10:46:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/some-of-best-lakefront-properties-in.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/some-of-best-lakefront-properties-in.html</guid>
        
        <category>Austin Real Estate Other</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Things Youre Doing to Sabotage Your Listing</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/coOE5kfriMA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seeing a home sit on the market can be frustrating, but there are a few ways to help get it moving. Here are five tips that could make the difference in selling your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seeing a home sit on the market for too long can be a frustrating and confusing ordeal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a seller, there a few key things to check when you notice that your home isn’t moving as quickly as you’d like it to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, you want to look at the price for which you’re listing the home. &lt;strong&gt;Both over- and underpricing your home can have undesirable effects.&lt;/strong&gt; When it comes to overpricing, the result could be that your home will receive fewer showings, sit longer on the market, and may compromise your final sales price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, underpricing your home may leave you with less money than your home is worth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, there are a number of things we can do to help to help you maximize your return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your price isn’t the problem, consider taking a look at the condition of your home and how, or if, you have it staged for potential homebuyers. Homebuyers want to see a clean, uncluttered home with good curb appeal when they turn up for showings. Staging your home is one of the best ways to make it look its best in showings and photos alike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our highly digital age, listing your home is a much different experience than it once was. This brings us to our next point, which is marketing. Is online content about your home accurate? Is it painting a good picture for potential buyers? &lt;strong&gt;Proper marketing is one of the best ways to generate demand for your property.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Even if your home is otherwise perfect, it simply won’t sell if it can’t be shown.%20localhost:4000/5-things-youre-doing-to-sabotage-your.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Even if your home is otherwise perfect, it simply won’t sell if it can’t be shown.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another factor that can impact the amount of time a home spends on the market is convenience and showability. Having your agent readily available to show your home is extremely important to ensuring that potential buyers don’t feel hassled by the experience of visiting the property. Even if your home is otherwise perfect, it simply won’t sell if it can’t be shown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last thing that can help to move a home off the market is style and finish. For example, if all the other homes in the area come equipped with certain updates, like granite countertops, but yours does not, buyers may overlook your home in lieu of a more recently renovated property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want more information, have questions, or have any real estate needs in our Central Texas area, feel free to get in touch by sending me an email or giving me a call. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 14:53:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/5-things-youre-doing-to-sabotage-your.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/5-things-youre-doing-to-sabotage-your.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Key to Pricing Your Austin Home for the Highest Net Profit</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/t57UJ4zMlI0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ve probably heard that old real estate myth that when you sell your house, you should price it above market value to ‘leave room for negotiation.’ I have two examples today that show why that’s a terrible idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When homeowners sell their house, one of the most common questions they have for real estate agents is how to price it properly to sell. I think many people believe the myth that in order to sell something, you need to elevate the price to ‘leave room for negotiation.’ &lt;strong&gt;It sounds logical on the surface, but it can actually be one of the worst things you can do.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we help people sell their house, we analyze what’s currently active on the market, home sales that are pending, and recent sales to give them a number or range for the current market value of their property. That’s the first step. The second step is to determine the marketing and pricing strategies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider West Lake and Lakeway as an example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Lakeway between the $1 million and $2 million price points, there have been 38 properties that sold in the last 365 days. Of those 38 homes, 17 elevated their price to leave room for negotiation and sold for an average of $1.358 million. The other 21 sellers were more aggressive with their pricing and averaged $1.329 million, which is $29,000 less.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, the value of the property and the pricing of the property are two very different conversations. Just by elevating their price, those 17 sellers netted almost $30,000 more on average.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In West Lake, we can look at homes in the same price range and see that the &lt;strong&gt;sellers who priced their homes aggressively made $125,000 more on average than those who elevated the price of their home to leave room for negotiation.&lt;/strong&gt; This is just a small example of what we see all around the Austin area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Consider West Lake and Lakeway as an example.%20localhost:4000/the-key-to-pricing-you-austin-home-for.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Consider West Lake and Lakeway as an example.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of the selling process, we’ll help you make sure you price your home well to maximize your bottom line. It’s something we enjoy doing, and we know that the numbers don’t lie. We even use special software that helps us analyze pricing to help you find the best price for your home. To boot, we’ve added a third office in San Antonio to help serve you at an even higher level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about pricing your house to sell or you’re thinking about buying a home in the Austin or San Antonio area, give us a call or send us an email. We’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 14:25:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/the-key-to-pricing-you-austin-home-for.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/the-key-to-pricing-you-austin-home-for.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Have Lakefront Home Values Gone Up? </title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/v3vqpFE360E?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have lake property values gone up now that Lake Travis is back to full pool? We’ll break down the numbers today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for sending us your questions. Today, we’ll answer Rebecca, who asked, “Have lake property values accelerated now that Lake Travis is full?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lake Travis dropped to its lowest point in 2011 thanks to the drought.&lt;/strong&gt; In May of 2015, the rains came, and the lake went back to full pool in about a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Home values did slide in 2011, when the lake was at its lowest point. Then, home values proceeded to bottom out in 2014. That year, the median price for a Lake Travis waterfront property was $565,000. In 2015, the rains came and the median price rose to $675,000. At the end of 2016, home values made a full recovery with a median price of $774,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The water levels in Lake Travis also impacted the number of home sales.&lt;/strong&gt; In 2014, Lake Travis only had 63 closed transactions. That number went up to 93 home sales in 2015, and in 2016, 157 lakefront properties sold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, lakefront properties are now back to pre-drought values. However, just because Lake Travis has seen an increase in home values doesn’t mean that your home has seen the same rate of appreciation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Lakefront home values have made a full recovery.%20localhost:4000/have-lakefront-home-values-gone-up.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Lakefront home values have made a full recovery.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Home values vary from property to property and from area to area. The Austin area Board of Realtors says that from November 2015 to November 2016, home values in Austin grew by 7%. If you break that down, though, you’ll see that Williamson County appreciated by 12%, Travis County appreciated by 1%, and Hays County appreciated by 8%.
If you have any other questions you would like us to answer or if you want to know what your home is worth in today’s market, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 15:38:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/have-lakefront-home-values-gone-up.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/have-lakefront-home-values-gone-up.html</guid>
        
        <category>Austin market update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Where Is the Austin Market Headed?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/CIvp1lGK0aQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever a client asks me how the market is doing or where it’s headed, I usually have one answer for them: it depends on where you look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’d like to answer a question that I get frequently from many of our clients: where is the market going?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My answer to this question is usually, “It depends on where you look.” We’ve put together some specific market stats that help us align where different price points of certain areas of town are either appreciating or depreciating; however, &lt;strong&gt;it’s important to realize that every area is appreciating or depreciating at a different rate.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=How the market is doing depends on a lot of specific factors.%20localhost:4000/austin-real-estate-where-is-austin.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“How the market is doing depends on a lot of specific factors.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter what neighborhood you live in, whether you have a waterfront property or a condo or any other kind of property, the market can vary drastically from area to area. For this reason, it’s important to be educated on the microeconomic concepts that we’re discussing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When somebody asks us where the market is going, we can usually give them a general answer, but after that, we have to get very specific with the types of properties and locations that we’re talking about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re curious about what’s going on in your particular neighborhood or you have any questions about buying or selling real estate in the Austin area, give us a call or send us an email. We’d be happy to point you in the right direction!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 16:07:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/austin-real-estate-where-is-austin.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/austin-real-estate-where-is-austin.html</guid>
        
        <category>Austin market update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Maintaining Your Heating and Cooling Systems</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/81p44lOiMf4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With summer nearly over, I’m sure you (like me) have been reminded just how much we use our air conditioning. Soon, in the winter, you’ll also be reminded of how often you use the furnace, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s one of the major systems in your home, and a surprise issue with one of these systems can be a nightmare if handled improperly. That’s why I wanted to share a video from Angie’s List that I recently saw about proper maintenance of your heating and cooling systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If either unit is having issues, &lt;strong&gt;did you know you can actually hire technicians who are specially trained to work on certain brands?&lt;/strong&gt; For example, if you have a Trane system, you can find a tech who is trained specifically to work on Trane products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, always remember to get a second opinion when someone recommends that you replace a system because oftentimes a repair will do. You want to be certain when it comes to a part of your home that should last 20 years, especially considering the cost of a replacement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=...be proactive with service on these systems.%20localhost:4000/maintaining-your-heating-and-cooling.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“…be proactive with service on these systems.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, as the video points out, there are a lot of people out there in that deal in these systems and prey on customers that don’t know any better. If you’re hiring a company, you should investigate them by checking out their web reviews or social media pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, be proactive with service on these systems. If you wait until the system is broken down and needs repair to get it checked out, you’re now at their mercy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, for any real estate questions, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I’d be happy to answer them for you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 14:36:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/maintaining-your-heating-and-cooling.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/maintaining-your-heating-and-cooling.html</guid>
        
        <category>Austin Real Estate Other</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Handle Appraisal Issues </title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ighjbpf-QAU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buying an Austin Home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.culhaneproperties.com/&quot;&gt;Search all Homes for Sale&lt;/a&gt;
Selling an Austin Home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shawnculhane.com/radio.php&quot;&gt;Check out our FREE Home Value Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On average, about 1 in 10 real estate transactions will have an appraisal that does not meet the home’s market value. That can be a messy situation when you have certain deadlines and contingencies involved. &lt;strong&gt;Luckily, there are a few options for buyers and sellers in this situation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to know &lt;strong&gt;there’s not an exact science for appraisals.&lt;/strong&gt; You can hire 10 different appraisers and get a 10% to 15% difference in value on either end of the spectrum. The appraisal is only another person’s opinion of your property’s value, anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A buyer will pay true market value for your home. However, a bank can’t lend on whatever a buyer is willing to pay. The bank needs some way to protect itself in the instance a buyer defaults on the loan and can not make the payments. Appraisers are hired mainly to protect the bank.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an example of an appraisal gone wrong.  A few weeks ago, an appraiser valued a property much lower than the actual market value should have been according to the comparable homes in the neighborhood. &lt;strong&gt;The appraiser was from Dallas and trying to appraise a property in the Austin area.&lt;/strong&gt; That doesn’t make any sense, does it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=True market value is what a buyer is willing to pay.%20localhost:4000/buying-austin-home-search-all-homes-for.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“True market value is what a buyer is willing to pay.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were plenty of comps in the neighborhood and he used comps outside the neighborhood. In this case, &lt;strong&gt;the buyers had to switch lenders and get a new appraisal done.&lt;/strong&gt; There are other options if something similar happens to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a buyer, depending on the loan, you can &lt;strong&gt;make up the difference, renegotiate with the seller, or terminate the contract.&lt;/strong&gt; On the seller side, &lt;strong&gt;you can’t terminate the contract&lt;/strong&gt;. However, you can negotiate or drop the purchase price down to the appraised value. You can also decide to proceed with the agreed upon price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sometimes we can get the appraiser to correct the report if something is blatantly wrong.&lt;/strong&gt; Other times, the appraiser won’t admit a mistake. I’ve seen an appraiser not include the value of a pool on the property. That’s a lot of money that went unaccounted for. Sometimes, the bank will reject a report that is obviously wrong, but more often than not, they’ll go ahead and accept the appraisal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some things we can do up-front to prevent any appraisal issues, so give us a call if you’re concerned about appraisal issues or if you have any other questions. We would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2016 15:46:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/buying-austin-home-search-all-homes-for.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/buying-austin-home-search-all-homes-for.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
