<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Realty One Centre of Boise - your professional Boise Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 10:39:44 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 10:39:44 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Remember These Key Tips Before Closing</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-8cQA0Dy8tI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a buyer, there are a few issues you can run into throughout the process of your transaction. Many of these problems can manifest right before closing, so it’s important not to overlook any last-minute details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For one thing, always remember to do a final walkthrough. With a couple days before closing you should &lt;strong&gt;meet with your agent and walk through the home to ensure the property is in the same condition as it was when you made your offer.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes certain items, like refrigerators or playground equipment, will be included in the sale. During the final walkthrough, check to ensure that the items you agreed upon have been left behind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By doing your final walkthrough a couple of days before closing, you will have ample time to remind the seller of any items they may have accidentally taken with them that were included in your contract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, look out for lender problems. Once you’ve got your pre-approval letter, you’ve found the right house, and you’re ready to close, you may think you’re in the clear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=It’s important not to overlook any last-minute details.%20localhost:4000/remember-these-key-tips-before-closing.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“It’s important not to overlook any last-minute details.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, things can still go awry. Just prior to closing, a lender will perform a final credit search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your credit score or job status has significantly changed since when you first began the process, this could cause big issues. &lt;strong&gt;Anything that could incur monthly payments, like a car, could cause you to become ineligible for the home purchase.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Larger purchases are often best left until after you’ve already closed on a home. You always need to be careful not to ruin your debt-to-income ratio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 07:54:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/remember-these-key-tips-before-closing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/remember-these-key-tips-before-closing.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
