<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND -- Career and Training Video Blog</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Keller Williams Park City - your professional Park City Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://parkcityrealestatecareers.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://parkcityrealestatecareers.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 09:26:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 09:26:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>4 Tips for Helping Your Buyers in Our Highly Competitive Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/DSJk9AlkGmM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Summertime is here, which means it’s an active buying season in our industry and inventory is tight in the marketplace. Here are a few tips to help guide your buyers through this highly competitive market:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Make sure your buyer is pre-approved if they won’t be paying in cash.&lt;/strong&gt; Also, make sure they’re pre-approved with a local lender. Sellers today are very savvy, and they won’t necessarily view an approval from an out-of-state lender as desirable as a local lender with a track record of being able to close loans in that neighborhood. Counsel your buyers that this step is necessary before they even begin to look at properties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Talk to them about their responsiveness.&lt;/strong&gt; If it’s a couple, will they both be available to respond to and sign documents in short order? It’s likely you will have a tight time frame dictated by the seller, so you need to be able to respond quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Preparation is key in this marketplace.%20http://parkcityrealestatecareers.com/4-tips-for-helping-your-buyers-in-our-highly-competitive-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Preparation is key in this marketplace.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Coach your buyer about the reality of multiple offers.&lt;/strong&gt; If they’re making an offer on a property in a high-demand neighborhood, it’s very likely they’ll have to deal with multiple offers. Before you show them any properties, familiarize them with the “Seller’s Notice to Buyers of Multiple Offers” form and the addendum you’ll have to add to the purchase contract. Show them hard copies of these forms so they can read through them and understand what’s expected of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Make sure your buyer is aware of the escalation clause.&lt;/strong&gt; This isn’t an approved form by the division of real estate, but it’s particularly useful for clients who might be traveling who want to put their highest, best offer out there as a percentage over any other price that might come forward. If you do use this clause, though, make sure you’re heeding the advice of an attorney or the blessing of your principal broker. If used properly, this tool can be really helpful in a highly competitive market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about how to guided buyers through a multiple offer situation, feel free to give me a call or shoot me an email. I’d be happy to speak with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 22:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://parkcityrealestatecareers.com/4-tips-for-helping-your-buyers-in-our-highly-competitive-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://parkcityrealestatecareers.com/4-tips-for-helping-your-buyers-in-our-highly-competitive-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Your Clients Should Hire a Certified Inspection Expert</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/1DYviR_GCkw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve all been trained to give the names of three home inspectors when your clients ask for a referral, but I suggest that you &lt;strong&gt;highly encourage them to seek out a certified inspections expert.&lt;/strong&gt; Since home inspectors are not regulated by the department of commerce, so this certification provides valuable benefits to your clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For starters, they provide a &lt;strong&gt;90-day warranty&lt;/strong&gt; for any items that were inspected and deemed to be in good order. This is important because not all of your clients will buy a home warranty plan, even though you recommended it. That 90-day window is critical because many things that can go wrong will go wrong during those first 90 days in the home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=CERTIFIED INSPECTIONS COME WITH A NATIONAL RESOURCE LINE THAT HOMEOWNERS CAN CALL FOR ANY QUESTIONS.%20http://parkcityrealestatecareers.com/why-your-clients-should-hire-certified.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“CERTIFIED INSPECTIONS COME WITH A NATIONAL RESOURCE LINE THAT HOMEOWNERS CAN CALL FOR ANY QUESTIONS.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a certified inspection, your clients can also get sewer and septic inspections that use cameras to inspect the pipes and other areas. They can also bridge the gap between the inspection warranty and home warranty, which is another nice added benefit. Additionally, they have a national resource line that homeowners can call with questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They also have specific coverages pertaining to mold, which can be an issue sometimes up here in the mountains. They also have very specific &lt;strong&gt;roof leak protection&lt;/strong&gt; that I haven’t seen in the general home inspection process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this topic or you’d like to talk further about how it can benefit your clients, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I’d love to talk and help you with your career however I can.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 16:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://parkcityrealestatecareers.com/why-your-clients-should-hire-certified.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://parkcityrealestatecareers.com/why-your-clients-should-hire-certified.html</guid>
        
        <category>Park City Real Estate Agent</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Embrace the Zestimate</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_3agy4NNh3Y?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As most of you know, Zillow is by far the largest consumer facing web portal out there for real estate. Many of your clients use it as they are contemplating selling their homes. &lt;strong&gt;Instead of fully rejecting Zillow and their Zestimate, I challenge you to embrace the concept and allow Zillow to be your friend rather than your foe.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Zillow’s home page, you can find what they call their “data accuracy table.” It gives you several points that they use to assess the valuation. This table is your best friend when dealing with sellers who want to take Zillow’s word as law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here in Utah, one key thing to note is that we are a non-disclosure state. In other states, Zillow looks at the deed transfer information to get home sale prices. In Utah, they don’t have access to that information. &lt;strong&gt;This means their accuracy will be off significantly, adding more value to your listing presentation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=UTAH IS A NON-DISCLOSURE STATE.%20http://parkcityrealestatecareers.com/embrace-zestimate.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“UTAH IS A NON-DISCLOSURE STATE.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you go on a listing presentation, check out the Zestimate for that particular property. Be prepared for the seller to bring that value up, and be prepared to rebut it with facts from the data accuracy table. Show them that Zillow doesn’t take upgrades to their home into account nor does it differentiate between properties with different locations and amenities. &lt;strong&gt;Zillow’s algorithm treats them all the same.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All you need to do to embrace Zillow is understand what it does and does not do when it comes to determining a home’s value. If you have any questions for me in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. We look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 13:22:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://parkcityrealestatecareers.com/embrace-zestimate.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://parkcityrealestatecareers.com/embrace-zestimate.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate Career Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Helping Your Buyers Avoid Down Payment Pitfalls</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ToifAxfDyz0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you’re beginning to work with buyers who you know will require a loan to purchase a home, typically 90 days before closing, &lt;strong&gt;talk to them about their fund’s availability.&lt;/strong&gt; If they’re going to be pulling together funds to come up with a down payment, which might include a gift from their parents, they need to do that outside the 60-day window because lenders will typically look at two months worth of bank deposits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if the down payment is going to be a gift from a family member, or, say an engaged couple is going to be putting their funds together for a down payment, **make sure all of that is done outside of the 60-day window. **&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, if they are for some reason stashing cash in their home instead of putting it in the bank, &lt;strong&gt;they need to start depositing that money in small deposits on a regular basis.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=THERE WILL BE FINAL CREDIT CHECK SO DON’T MAKE ANY UNWISE PURCHASES.%20http://parkcityrealestatecareers.com/helping-your-buyers-avoid-down-payment.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“THERE WILL BE FINAL CREDIT CHECK SO DON’T MAKE ANY UNWISE PURCHASES.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the engaged couple might be splitting the down payment, they both need to qualify, so funds should be in both accounts. They also shouldn’t wait until the last minute to consolidate their funds. Liquidating assets takes time, and they want to make sure they have the funds for their part of the down payment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, &lt;strong&gt;counsel your buyers not to buy something like a car or furniture until after the closing.&lt;/strong&gt; There will be a final credit check, so they need to wait until after the home is bought to make those kinds of purchases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about avoiding down payment pitfalls, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I would be happy to assist you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 09:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://parkcityrealestatecareers.com/helping-your-buyers-avoid-down-payment.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://parkcityrealestatecareers.com/helping-your-buyers-avoid-down-payment.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Staging is Crucial When Listing Your Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/XaJVFkvNUfk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What makes staging so important? The simple answer is that staged homes sell quicker and for more money. So, what can you do to make sure your home is staged and ready to be put on the market?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inside, you want to make sure you &lt;strong&gt;depersonalize and edit your home to appeal to a wide variety and large number of buyers.&lt;/strong&gt; Buyers really want an emotional connection to a home, which they can achieve if it’s easy to picture their things in your home. You want to make sure your home is clean, functional, and above all, welcoming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the kitchen, you need to declutter. Get rid of dated accessories and things you don’t need and make sure you have nice, clean countertops&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the living areas, you need to declutter and get rid of extra furniture to make the room feel more inviting. Stage it nicely by adding a focal point on a coffee table. Felicity puts groups of three or five accessories of various heights, widths, and materials in a room to really make the area pop. She is a big fan of using sparkly accessories that catch the eye and help open up space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=STAGED HOMES SELL QUICKER AND FOR MORE MONEY.%20http://parkcityrealestatecareers.com/why-staging-is-crucial-when-listing.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“STAGED HOMES SELL QUICKER AND FOR MORE MONEY.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll also want to clear the clutter from the laundry room, clear off countertops, and put laundry away. If you have a pet, you should pack away pet toys and the pets themselves. Many people are allergic and some people find pet things off-putting. Get rid any unwanted smells and stains caused by your pets as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the master bathroom, &lt;strong&gt;you want to make it look as much like a spa as possible.&lt;/strong&gt; Clear off the countertops, add contemporary accessories, and maybe even put on some soothing spa music. Everything left out in the bathroom needs to be pristine, which means watered plants and clean towels. Also it’s a good idea to remove any bathmats or fuzzy toilet covers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The outside of the home is just as important as the inside. After all, &lt;strong&gt;your curb appeal is the first impression.&lt;/strong&gt; You’ll want to powerwash your siding, clean the windows, make sure the lawn is nicely mowed, plant flowers for a pop of color, powerwash the path, and check to see if the garage and front door could use a spruce. In the backyard, powerwash your patio area and consider getting some great patio furniture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Felicity Gardner is available to assist your clients whose homes need editing.  She is available on an hourly or project basis. Please contact her at &lt;a href=&quot;tel:435-640-4174&quot;&gt;435-640-4174&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:felicity@gardnergroup.com&quot;&gt;felicity@gardnergroup.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any questions about real estate, please feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 13:35:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://parkcityrealestatecareers.com/why-staging-is-crucial-when-listing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://parkcityrealestatecareers.com/why-staging-is-crucial-when-listing.html</guid>
        
        <category>Staging Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Maximize the Value of Your Marketing With Follow Up</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/sPTIzx1wbSg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you sell real estate, it’s important to maximize the value of your marketing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of us use email consistently to communicate with our clients, and that’s a good thing. With many of our clients having a high net worth, though, they get a lot of emails. You probably have a communication schedule that follows a marketing calendar as part of your business plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you deploy a message, you’ll get a response from maybe 2% to 5% of the recipients if you’re lucky—but what about the rest of them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=DON'T JUST RELY ON MARKETING, BE PURPOSEFUL IN YOUR FOLLOW UP.%20http://parkcityrealestatecareers.com/how-to-maximize-value-of-your-marketing.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“DON’T JUST RELY ON MARKETING, BE PURPOSEFUL IN YOUR FOLLOW UP.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When you deploy a piece of marketing, set a reminder for yourself on your calendar for two to three days after to call the recipients.&lt;/strong&gt; Be very purposeful about these calls and pick out a piece of content from what was deployed that you can use to start a dialogue. You want a good reason to start a conversation over the phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They might not have a current real estate need, but they might know somebody who does. They might have a real estate need in the near future. We all know that one-on-one time is the most productive time to spend with a client, and we’re challenged by that since many of our clients don’t live here. That’s why being able to get them on the phone is important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, don’t just rely on the marketing to do all the heavy lifting. Be purposeful about your follow up!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any more questions about how to do this or about your real estate career, give me a call or send me an email. I’d love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2017 13:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://parkcityrealestatecareers.com/how-to-maximize-value-of-your-marketing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://parkcityrealestatecareers.com/how-to-maximize-value-of-your-marketing.html</guid>
        
        <category>Growing Your Business</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Get Your Clients Home Sold Fast Using These 2 Tips </title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/KcHrQwsXpGM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that warmer weather is fast approaching, you’re probably anxious to start listing homes for your spring clients. Luckily, I have two tips to share with you today that will reduce your days on  market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suggest that your client get two reports that are really going to help you narrow down the pricing and expedite the sale: a home inspection and an appraisal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your client is probably going to tell you that they’ve maintained their property beautifully. However, you need to know what’s behind the walls and how the roof is looking, not to mention making sure all the major systems like the A/C unit and furnace are working. Any issues with the home are going to come up during the buyer’s due diligence period anyway, so the seller might as well get out in front of that. Having that information will also help you price the home accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=MAKE SURE YOUR CLIENTS GET A RADON INSPECTION ALONG WITH A HOME INSPECTION.%20http://parkcityrealestatecareers.com/get-your-clients-home-sold-fast-using.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“MAKE SURE YOUR CLIENTS GET A RADON INSPECTION ALONG WITH A HOME INSPECTION.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with the home inspection, make sure your clients go ahead and do a radon inspection as well. Most home inspectors have an add-on which isn’t that expensive, and it’s important to many buyers that the radon inspection is done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The appraisal is going to be the best tool you can use for pricing the home. Prices have increased fairly quickly in the last month, so keep in mind that the appraisal might be a bit off as they haven’t caught up yet. You can factor in a little bit for appreciation and take a good look at what’s been happening in the neighborhood to come to a fair market price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about pricing a home for a quick sale or if you are curious about other real estate topics, please feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 15:03:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://parkcityrealestatecareers.com/get-your-clients-home-sold-fast-using.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://parkcityrealestatecareers.com/get-your-clients-home-sold-fast-using.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Social Media Marketing Tips for 2017</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/nVJTne_yLG0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of you are probably looking to social media as a marketing channel as you finalize your plans for 2017. I absolutely encourage you to do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you know that 75% of adults are active on some social media channel? The trick is finding out which one. Here are five tips to avoid when it comes to social media:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No free-wheeling is allowed!&lt;/strong&gt; You’ve got to have a plan or it can become very time-consuming. Plan out where you’re going to be in terms of budgets for things like paid ads and what you’ll hold that budget accountable to—how much business do you expect it to generate? Have a plan and content strategy for what’s going to be your key messaging.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t put all your eggs in one basket.&lt;/strong&gt; Even if you love Pinterest, don’t put 80% of your focus there and spread 20% across all the remaining platforms. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://Hootsuite.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Hootsuite.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is a great scheduling program that allows you to push out the same content on multiple social media channels. It takes some time to schedule, but I suggest you spend about six hours a month mapping out your schedule. From there, it’s basically set it and forget it. You also need to allow time to be spontaneous for things like big news. You want to be able to jump in with timely content on social media.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=YOU'VE GOT TO HAVE A PLAN OR IT CAN BECOME VERY TIME-CONSUMING.%20http://parkcityrealestatecareers.com/5-social-media-marketing-tips-for-2017.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“YOU’VE GOT TO HAVE A PLAN OR IT CAN BECOME VERY TIME-CONSUMING.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t wait for the bugs to be worked out.&lt;/strong&gt; There are constantly new social media platforms coming out, and as soon as you start hearing about them, it is too late! You want to be an early adopter because there are usually benefits associated with being an early adopter. Applications like Hootsuite will keep you informed of this news.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be prepared to embrace rapid change.&lt;/strong&gt; The world of social media constantly evolves, so I like to stay abreast with a site called &lt;a href=&quot;http:/Mashable.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mashable.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a good general clearinghouse for information about social media where you can get quick updates on things you need to be aware of.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep an eye on your analytics.&lt;/strong&gt; Google Analytics, for example, is a great way to stay on top of your site’s traffic and to see where it’s coming from. Facebook has a great analytics tool, as well.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good luck with your social media strategy in 2017! If you have any other questions, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I’d be glad to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2017 11:39:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://parkcityrealestatecareers.com/5-social-media-marketing-tips-for-2017.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://parkcityrealestatecareers.com/5-social-media-marketing-tips-for-2017.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate Career Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>4 Major Trends for Millennial Home Buyers</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/WeYVn0MipCw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Millennials (people under 35) are finally hitting the real estate market. It’s important to understand these four trends when working with a millennial on a home sale:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They love mobility.&lt;/strong&gt; They are not very loyal in the job market; millennials are constantly looking for their next opportunity, so they move frequently. When you talk to them about purchasing real estate, they don’t want a place where they can live for 10 years and raise a family. Instead, focus on the investment value of the property. Choose homes with good rental histories in high demand areas. That way, when a millennial hops into a new job, they can easily transition that property into a rental property.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They really love cities.&lt;/strong&gt; When millennials move to Park City, focus on high-density areas like Redstone, Lower Pinebrook, and Old Town. Millennials want to be where the action is. They are accustomed to walking everywhere. They don’t like jumping into a car and driving around.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=MILLENNIALS ARE NOT NECESSARILY LOOKING TO SETTLE DOWN.%20http://parkcityrealestatecareers.com/4-major-trends-for-millennial-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“MILLENNIALS ARE NOT NECESSARILY LOOKING TO SETTLE DOWN.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They love incentives.&lt;/strong&gt; Incentives can be hard to come by with our huge resale market, but if you are helping a millennial buy a new construction property, look for builders that offer strong incentives.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They tend to have a lot of student loan debt.&lt;/strong&gt; When you work with buyers in this age group, make sure that they are pre-qualified. There is an income-based repayment program available for millennials to use as well. Who knows what will happen to it under our next president, but for now, the program allows them to rework their loan payments over a longer period of time. That way, they have more disposable income to put toward their mortgage payment.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you understand these trends, you will be able to help your millennial buyer find the right home. If you have any questions for me, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 12:53:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://parkcityrealestatecareers.com/4-major-trends-for-millennial-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://parkcityrealestatecareers.com/4-major-trends-for-millennial-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate Career Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Marketing Tips for New Construction</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ucX1nyijIQE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are excited to be joined today by Heather Feldman, who is going to talk to us about marketing as it relates to new construction and new home sales. Heather has been doing new home sales since 1998 and she has a lot of knowledge and experience in this market. She knows how homes are built and what to expect through the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There has been a spike in new construction in our area recently, which opens the door to a lot of fabulous properties and a lot of fabulous opportunities. Here are the top three things agents should consider when they go down the new construction road:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Find a great general contractor.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s important to find one who has subcontractors that they have worked with and vetted as well.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Know the numbers that are in front of you in regard to the new build and know what they mean.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be ahead of schedule.&lt;/strong&gt; Things will sneak up on you and you don’t want your build to fall apart because you haven’t made the necessary decisions to proceed.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=THIS CAN BE A STRESSFUL PROCESS.%20http://parkcityrealestatecareers.com/marketing-tips-for-new-construction.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“THIS CAN BE A STRESSFUL PROCESS.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**This is a stressful process, and when buyers have someone like Heather who can keep them on track and keep things manageable, it’s a lot easier. The build process is also very complex. Things will come up and buyers will have to decide if they want one option over another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You also want to have a good idea of what the budget will be ahead of time. You can build a really nice home for around $300 per square foot. Work with your architect during the process and ask them what you can control during the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you all enjoyed hearing from Heather today. If you have any questions for her or me, give us a call, send us an email, or fill out the form below and we’ll follow up with you. We look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 15:03:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://parkcityrealestatecareers.com/marketing-tips-for-new-construction.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://parkcityrealestatecareers.com/marketing-tips-for-new-construction.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate Career Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
