<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Salt Lake City Real Estate Video Blog with Joshua Stern</title>
    <description>Joshua Stern leads The Joshua Stern Team, a full-service real estate team that has helped sell and purchase thousands of Salt Lake City area homes since 2002. For the last few years, they have sold about a property a day! If you are looking to buy or sell a Utah home and would like to receive all of the latest market updates, tips, and tricks, make sure to follow The Stern Team, your best Salt Lake City area real estate agents.</description>
    <link>http://sternteam.org/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://sternteam.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 13:53:35 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 13:53:35 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Need to Dispute Your Property Tax Assessment?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/VWFiH5Oi574&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Utah, July is known for many things. One of the lesser-known things is the fact that it’s also the month we get our property tax assessment notices in the mail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not an expert as to how the county calculates property tax values, but I do know one thing: they’re not always on the mark. The assessment is comprised of your proposed tax assessment for 2016 and the change in value from 2015 to 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been helping our clients dispute these tax evaluations for years, so &lt;strong&gt;if you feel like your 2016 property tax assessment is too high, send us the front part of your notice.&lt;/strong&gt; We’ll take a look at the value and provide you with three to five comparable sales to your property that may show a lower value. You can then fill out the official appeal form and send it in by September 15th along with the comparable sales we provided you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=This is a free service we offer.%20http://sternteam.org/need-to-dispute-your-property-tax-assessment.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“This is a free service we offer.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you purchased your property in the past year and the purchase price was less than the assessed value, you can simply fill out the appeal form and send in the HUD settlement statement you signed at the title company. To get the process started click &lt;a href=&quot;http://slco.org/tax-administration/how-to-file-an-appeal/&quot;&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Joshua+Stern/ValuationNotice2015f.pdf&quot;&gt;Sample Property Valuation Form&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you had an appraisal done in 2016 or early 2017 that came in lower than the tax assessed value, you can send in a copy of that appraisal with your appeal form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a free service we offer to our past clients, current clients, and anyone who’s sent us a referral. &lt;strong&gt;Once you’ve sent in your appeal, you should know where you stand.&lt;/strong&gt; Hopefully, the final decision rendered by the county is one that benefits you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about disputing your property tax assessment or you’re looking to buy or sell a home in our market, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d be happy to assist you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/need-to-dispute-your-property-tax-assessment.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/need-to-dispute-your-property-tax-assessment.html</guid>
        
        <category>Tax Assessment</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Does Gary LeVox of Rascal Flatts Trust The Stern Team?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/uaczutVKF-A&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, my team and I received a fantastic endorsement from Gary LeVox, lead singer of the Grammy award-winning country music group, Rascal Flatts. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gary is a respected artist who approaches his craft with the same heart and passion that my team and I have for each real estate transaction. Here is what Gary had to say: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When ‘I’m Moving On’ won the award for ACM song of the year, it struck a chord with folks who understand the challenges that come with life’s big changes. For many, that time comes when they sell their home. If you’re moving on, you want a real estate agent who will make selling your home easy and stress-free.” - Gary LeVox &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=It is our goal to make your transaction a smooth one.%20http://sternteam.org/why-does-gary-levox-of-rascal-flatts-trust-the-stern-team.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“It is our goal to make your transaction a smooth one.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It is always our goal to make your transaction a smooth one&lt;/strong&gt;. If we can’t sell your home at a price and deadline that we both agree to, we will buy it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please check out the video above for the complete endorsement. If you have any real estate questions, give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/why-does-gary-levox-of-rascal-flatts-trust-the-stern-team.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/why-does-gary-levox-of-rascal-flatts-trust-the-stern-team.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Did Our Wasatch Front Market Do in the 1st Quarter?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/QmSgc4o_gd4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How does the first quarter of 2017 compare to the first quarter of 2016 along the Wasatch Front?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, our average sold home price is at $308,000, which is up 11% from the $277,000 mark set last year. The average days on market decreased 10% from 59 days to 53 days. We’re seeing the number of available homes to sell also decrease, as our inventory—which was already low in 2016—has decreased another 4.25%. As a result, the average price for listings is up 8.5%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s interesting is that the number of properties in the “pending” status—meaning the offer has been accepted between the buyer and seller and is waiting for closing—exceeds the number of properties actively for sale. The failure rate of pending properties is also higher than in years past, which means we’re having more appraisal issues and buyers getting cold feet or finding a property they like better and canceling the contract. Either way, as a buyer in this market, it’s a good idea to consider placing a backup offer on a property you want because there’s a 24% chance you’ll win it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Take advantage of this market while you can.%20http://sternteam.org/how-did-our-wasatch-front-market-do-in-the-1st-quarter.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Take advantage of this market while you can.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the $350,000 price point, there is less than a two-month supply of inventory, which means &lt;strong&gt;it’s a great time to be a seller and the waters are a little bit testier for buyers.&lt;/strong&gt; If you’re a buyer, make sure you have a winning strategy before entering this market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on my experience coaching other top agents across the country, the market in Utah is similar to the markets all across the nation. &lt;strong&gt;Inventory is tight, prices have risen, interest rates are still very low,&lt;/strong&gt; and I suspect we’ll see this type of market throughout the summer and fall and perhaps the rest of 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about our market or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home, don’t hesitate to give me a call or shoot me an email. I’d be glad to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/how-did-our-wasatch-front-market-do-in-the-1st-quarter.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/how-did-our-wasatch-front-market-do-in-the-1st-quarter.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Buying a Salt Lake City Home With High Student Loan Debt</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/KTVNplLKWhQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m here with Jayson Kisselburg from Veritas Funding with some good news for those buying a home with a lot of student loan debt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Student loan debt in America is incredible, as college is not cheap. If you have a lot of student debt, it can be daunting to purchase a home. However, Fannie Mae, one of the mortgage giants in our country, &lt;strong&gt;actually allows you to do a cash-out loan on your property.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, your home will be appraised and then you can take out a substantial amount of equity to pay off those student loans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you pull the equity out to pay off your student loans, the loan is then tied against the house, which turns it into a tax deduction. When the time comes to sell your house, you can actually sell your home student-loan free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=This Fannie Mae program will help more people with student debt qualify for home loans.%20http://sternteam.org/buying-a-salt-lake-city-home-with-high-student-loan-debt.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“This Fannie Mae program will help more people with student debt qualify for home loans.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another benefit of this program is that if you qualify for another Wasatch Front home now, then &lt;strong&gt;you don’t have to report that debt against your income. &lt;/strong&gt;Before, you would have to include a payment all the way up to 1%, no matter what the credit bureaus were reporting. Now, we can go off the exact payment from your student loan company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a loan officer, Jayson sees a lot high student loan debt. Fannie Mae offers a way for more people to qualify to buy a home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is great because student loan debt is a real problem in the U.S. Finally, the government stepped in with the Fannie Mae program to actually help people with student debt get into a home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about how to qualify for a home loan, make sure you contact Jayson at 801-638-1005 or &lt;a href=&quot;javascript:void(location.href='mailto:'+String.fromCharCode(115,116,101,114,110,116,101,97,109,108,101,110,100,105,110,103,64,118,102,117,110,100,46,99,111,109))&quot;&gt;sternteamlending@vfund.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any Salt Lake City real estate questions, please don’t hesitate to reach out to the Stern Team. We would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/buying-a-salt-lake-city-home-with-high-student-loan-debt.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/buying-a-salt-lake-city-home-with-high-student-loan-debt.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Agents Choose to Work on The Stern Team</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7owEQzxCjYE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At The Stern Team, we believe that when we take care of other people’s needs, our own needs are taken care of too. We have a big focus on making sure our client experience is exceptional. We do the same for our agents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With The Stern Team, you’ll get one-on-one mentorship, coaching, consulting, training, leadership, and motivation.&lt;/strong&gt; Our culture is open, welcoming, and inviting. All of our training information and education is available to our agents daily. We are focused on taking care of people’s needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not just our clients’ needs, but the needs of each member on our team as well. Their business needs, their personal needs, and their financial needs. With a team, together everyone achieves more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The Stern Team is simply the best choice.%20http://sternteam.org/why-agents-choose-to-work-on-the-stern-team.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The Stern Team is simply the best choice.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t just take our word for it, however. &lt;strong&gt;Here is what a few Stern Team agents had to say about working on this team.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Who wouldn’t want to be on the number one real estate team in Utah? The Stern Team has the most amazing people. They’ve been super open to me, very welcoming and make me feel like I’m really part of the team.”&lt;/em&gt;- Tara Horton&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“As a seasoned agent, I thrive in a supportive environment with coaching and accountability. If I was going to join a team, I wanted to make sure I joined the best team around in Salt Lake County and I feel like The Stern Team is the best choice.”&lt;/em&gt; - Cyndi Shelton&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“What I love most about being on the Stern Team is that I have this vast resource of people who have been in the business for such a long time. All the training, all the information and education that I gain daily from being on the team is priceless.”&lt;/em&gt; - Jacquie Reagh&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to learn more about joining The Stern Team, one of the top real estate teams in Salt Lake County, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/why-agents-choose-to-work-on-the-stern-team.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/why-agents-choose-to-work-on-the-stern-team.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Answering Some Important Questions About Radon Gas</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jKzdXozJ6wg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is radon gas and where does it come from?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Radon gas is a colorless, odorless, tasteless, radioactive gas that is formed during the natural breakdown of uranium in soil, rock, and water. Radon exits the ground and can seep into your home through cracks and holes in the foundation. Radon gas can also contaminate well water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Radon gas is the second leading cause of lung cancer in the United States. The first leading cause of lung cancer is of course smoking, which kills 120,000 people every year. Radon kills anywhere from 20,000 to 22,000 people per year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At what level should you be concerned about radon gas? There is no safe level of radon gas. However, the U.S. EPA has indicated that any home that tests four picocuries per liter should be mitigated. If there are less than four picocuries, you are still at risk for lung cancer. Again, there is no safe level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=There is no safe level of radon gas.%20http://sternteam.org/answering-some-important-questions-about-radon-gas.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“There is no safe level of radon gas.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can you test for radon gas? Testing for radon gas is very simple. You can test the home yourself, or you can have a professional test the home. When selling a home, a third-party tester is recommended to get a non-partial, certified test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are there any myths about radon gas people should be aware of? There are actually a number of myths and misinformation out there. For example, people will say they did a radon test but the home was closed up for a month, giving them an inaccurate test. However, radon has a half-life of three-and-a-half days, so even if a home is vacant for a month, the test will be accurate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for Dave you can send him an email at &lt;a href=&quot;javascript:void(location.href='mailto:'+String.fromCharCode(100,97,118,101,64,104,111,109,101,116,101,107,117,116,97,104,46,99,111,109))&quot;&gt;dave@hometekutah.com&lt;/a&gt; or give me call at (801) 673-5050.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any questions for me or are looking to buy or sell a home, please don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I’m always happy to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/answering-some-important-questions-about-radon-gas.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/answering-some-important-questions-about-radon-gas.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>6 Home Selling Mistakes That Can Sink Your Sale</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/3cbowysht4g&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you sell your house, there are six mistakes that can sink your sale. Here’s how to avoid them:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Don’t go it alone:&lt;/strong&gt; Use a Realtor to help you because 90% of home sales in 2016 took place with one. The National Association of Realtors found last year that homes sold by their owner fetched an average of $210,000 while homes sold with a Realtor sold for $249,000. They sold faster, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Don’t decide on an agent based on the price they tell you they’ll sell your house for:&lt;/strong&gt; Instead, ask them their strategy for marketing your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Don’t trust automated values:&lt;/strong&gt; They’re easy to find on Zillow or Trulia, but since Utah is a non-disclosure state, it’s impossible for them to see comparable home sales. We often find these values are much higher or lower than your home’s true market value, so make sure you get a complete equity evaluation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Buyers are sensitive to a home’s presentation.%20http://sternteam.org/6-home-selling-mistakes-that-can-sink-your-sale.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Buyers are sensitive to a home’s presentation.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Have professional photos of your home taken:&lt;/strong&gt; 100% of buyers will decide whether they want to see your home in person based on what they see online, and they gravitate toward great photos. Don’t try to take listing photos with an iPhone! Waiting an extra week for a professional photographer is well worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Don’t ignore your agent’s request for some fixes around the home:&lt;/strong&gt; You might want to consider staging as well, or at a minimum, a deep clean. Buyers are sensitive to a home’s presentation and they have no imagination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Don’t refuse to negotiate:&lt;/strong&gt; You might receive low offers and it’s easy to get offended, but always send a counteroffer, even if it’s just $100 off of your list price. You always want to keep things moving forward. Drawing a line in the sand sends a message to the buyer that you’re not really interested in selling. Instead, say something like, “I really appreciate you taking the time to put an offer together, but unfortunately, it doesn’t allow us to exit the property with what we need. So, we’d like to give you a counteroffer back at XX.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, give me a call or send me an email if you have any questions or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home in Salt Lake County. I look forward to helping you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/6-home-selling-mistakes-that-can-sink-your-sale.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/6-home-selling-mistakes-that-can-sink-your-sale.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Sets Realtors Apart From Normal Agents?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/RU9FadJqO3Y&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people think that all real estate agents are Realtors. What makes a Realtor different than a real estate agent?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A career in real estate is complicated enough, and many brokerages require their agents to become Realtors, but it’s not legally required. So, &lt;strong&gt;your Realtor is a real estate agent or an affiliated professional who is also a member of the National Association of Realtors,&lt;/strong&gt; or the NAR for short. Realtors are located all across the world, and if you ask them what sets them apart from a regular real estate agent, they’ll point out being held to a higher standard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That higher standard is called the Realtor Code of Ethics. If you can believe, real estate agents were considered peddlers way back in the early 1900s. When they agree to become a Realtor, they must agree to conduct their business in a way that adheres to &lt;strong&gt;the NAR Code of Ethics, which covers ethical requirements that deal with all aspects of the job from working with consumers and fellow agents to creating truthful advertising.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Multiple listing services (or MLS) are groups of local agents who have banded together in order to share listings more effectively. Most of these groups are affiliated with their state and national Realtor associations, and typically require all MLS agents to become members of both those groups. Agents pay dues to their state and to local Realtor organizations, and they may also pay fees to maintain their membership with local MLSs. Realtors can also be held accountable for their actions; you can file a complaint against another Realtor, and the organization accepts complaints from consumers, as well. Complaints can affect membership status, and at times, fines can be levied against members who have been involved in wrongdoings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Realtors are held to a higher standard and a code of ethics.%20http://sternteam.org/what-sets-realtors-apart-from-normal-agents.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Realtors are held to a higher standard and a code of ethics.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Licenses in the U.S. are granted by each state and only the state can revoke it. Complaints are first assessed by a grievance committee, which is made up of volunteers. The group doesn’t establish whether the complaint is valid or true, but rather determines if the facts as stated are true and whether there could be a violation or the Code of Ethics. If the answer is yes, a hearing date is established. A complaint is generally based on a possible violation of an article of the Code of Ethics. During the hearing, the Realtor can obtain legal counsel and will get an opportunity to present their side. The verdict is final and if the Realtor is found guilty, the punishment can include temporary or permanent revocation of benefits or could include a monetary fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, Realtors also have to continue their education—all licensed agents are required to take continuing education courses approved by their state licensing board, and to retain membership in the NAR, Realtors must take additional continuing education classes, which are often focused on ethical work habits and other consumer protection topics. Realtors must complete an ethics course every two years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about what sets Realtors apart from regular real estate agents, don’t hesitate to give us a call. We’d be glad to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/what-sets-realtors-apart-from-normal-agents.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/what-sets-realtors-apart-from-normal-agents.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Freshen Your Home up After the Winter Months</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/BV5qdVlk9p4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spring’s nearly here and as a homeowner, it’s an exciting time to get your home ready. Many parts of the house might have been neglected or unused over the winter since you’re staying inside for most of the season, so it’s important to get out and check on these things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The first thing you should check on is your hose bibs.&lt;/strong&gt; If you left your hose open over the winter, you could have frozen or cracked pipes. Before you turn the bib back on, remove the hose and turn on the water—if no water comes out, you could have an issue with a cracked or broken pipe, which could leak into your house. You can also have someone inside the house look at the spot where the bib comes into the house while you turn the water on to make sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside your home, take a look at any caulking around the windows and doors, as well as the condition of the weather stripping around windows. Now is also a good time to wash away any winter muck from the windows as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Spring is a great time for your annual HVAC service, which you may need to maintain the warranty.%20http://sternteam.org/how-to-freshen-your-home-up-after-the-winter-months.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Spring is a great time for your annual HVAC service, which you may need to maintain the warranty.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While you’re at it, take a look at your shingles and roof. If you noticed any big icicles in any areas of your house during the wintertime, it could be a sign of ice damming. In that case, you might want to put additional insulation around the eaves where the icicles occurred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also take a look to see if your gutters need to be re-secured to your house or cleaned. Finally, put some accordion-style downspout extenders on to keep the water away from the foundation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inside your home, now is a great time to change your HVAC filter and have the system serviced. &lt;strong&gt;Many people don’t realize that if you don’t have them serviced annually, you can actually void the warranty.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, take a look in your attic for any water stains on the sheathing. You could have cracked or corroded vent pipes, or you might need to add flashing to your roof where two gable ends meet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about refreshing your home this spring or you’re thinking of selling your home in the Salt Lake area, give me a call or send me an email. I’d be glad to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/how-to-freshen-your-home-up-after-the-winter-months.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/how-to-freshen-your-home-up-after-the-winter-months.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How We Do Things at The Stern Team</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/N9Cqt1aUQQI&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“People don’t care how much we know until they know how much we care.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since 2002, that’s been our motto at The Stern Team. Today we asked our own employees how we uphold this motto. In the video above, you can get an idea of what it’s like to work for us in their own words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We are proud of our guaranteed sale program.%20http://sternteam.org/how-we-do-things-at-the-stern-team.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We are proud of our guaranteed sale program.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of them are former clients of ours who appreciated our service so much that they decided they wanted to be a part of our team. Some wanted to learn from the best. Others wanted to maximize their potential and knew we had the ability to train them to take their careers to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can we take your career to the next level just like we did theirs? We offer a great platform to build your own business and reach your goals in a much faster way than you could on your own with &lt;strong&gt;structure, mentorship, training, and accountability.&lt;/strong&gt; Between our employees, the theme isn’t competition—it’s contribution. We’re invested in your happiness and your success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or are looking to buy, sell, or invest in real estate, please don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We look forward to helping you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/how-we-do-things-at-the-stern-team.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/how-we-do-things-at-the-stern-team.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
