<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Dave Hooke Team LLC - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 13:19:25 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 13:19:25 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Creating a For-Profit Business With a Nonprofit Purpose</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/JWNRzu4pVYo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome back to our business-building blog for high-producing agents on fast-growing teams. Today we’re here to answer the question, &lt;strong&gt;“How do you have a for-profit business with a nonprofit purpose?”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been selling homes for a while like I have, you’ve probably been wondering about how you can have a bigger impact on your community. After about a decade in the business, I wasn’t sure if this is what I wanted to do with my life and I was questioning what I wanted to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After talking with my wife and a few other close friends and family members, I came to the realization that I’m uniquely positioned in real estate to learn about people’s needs and serve them on a really deep level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to start a new referral program. I always ask my clients if they know of anybody who is thinking about buying or selling, but I never ask them if they know anyone who might be going through a tough time that we could serve in an anonymous way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=This referral program has brought joy to many people.%20localhost:4000/creating-a-for-profit-business-with-a-nonprofit-purpose.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“This referral program has brought joy to many people.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That idea led me to developing the Community Appreciation Program&lt;/strong&gt; that allows us to serve others in the community by using our database as leverage to find them. Here’s how we did it, in five easy steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Open up a separate checking account.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Put a percentage of every commission check in there.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ask every client this question: “Who do you know in the community with a random, urgent need whom we might be able to serve?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have the client enter the person’s information in a Google survey or spreadsheet.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once you’ve picked someone, call the person who gave you the referral and ask them to partner with you to give the gift. Ask them how it went afterwards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just one easy way to bring purpose back into your real estate business. If you have any questions, or if you have an example of another way you or your team is giving back, give me a call or send me an email. I would love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/creating-a-for-profit-business-with-a-nonprofit-purpose.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/creating-a-for-profit-business-with-a-nonprofit-purpose.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2 Questions to Double Your Business</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/3Y46VOUASGI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you interested in doubling your business?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I’ve got two questions you can ask that can help you do just that. When done at the right time with a genuine attitude, asking these questions can go a long way in developing deep relationships with your customers. It will also help you with future referrals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, as a buyer consultation is coming to a close, ask your buyer the following before either of you leave: &lt;strong&gt;“What are your biggest fears or concerns in the upcoming transaction?”&lt;/strong&gt; In this sometimes intimidating process, people want to feel understood and reassured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a common belief that being a good listener is the best sales skill you can have. Personally, I believe that having empathy is a close second to that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As professionals, we deal with the stress and uncertainties that come along with real estate transactions every day—but this likely isn’t the case for your client.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Put yourself in your client’s shoes.%20localhost:4000/2-questions-to-double-your-business.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Put yourself in your client’s shoes.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being able to genuinely listen and take a sincere interest in their concerns will not only help to assuage your client’s fears, but also build a better relationship between you in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put yourself in your client’s shoes—doing so will make a huge difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second question you should ask should also be posed at the end of a buyer consultation. That question is: &lt;strong&gt;“Is there anything unrelated to real estate that I can help you with?”&lt;/strong&gt; By asking your client this, you are showing a level of service that extends beyond what they likely expect of you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it’s true that an agent’s job is not to be a therapist, the reality &lt;strong&gt;is that going out of your way to do something nice for your client can really make an impact.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After posing this question, listen to their response and consider taking notes. Empathizing with and caring for your clients will foster strong relationships and build a strong referral business for the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/2-questions-to-double-your-business.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/2-questions-to-double-your-business.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What to Look for in a Potential Brokerage</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8b43qsT0ahw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes down to it, we are all independent contractors and like small business owners in many ways. I run into a lot of agents who only focus on gross volume, income, and commission splits as financial indicators of their career. In reality, there are seven key variables to consider that will affect your bottom line when it comes down to deciding where you will practice real estate. &lt;strong&gt;Here are those seven things to pay attention to when looking at brokerages:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Commission splits. &lt;/strong&gt;This is a fairly obvious one. Different brokerages have different splits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Occupancy cost.&lt;/strong&gt; Some brokerages charge expensive desk fees, some have cheap fees, and some have no fees at all. Neither is right or wrong, but it’s important that you understand what kind of support you’re looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Brand recognition. &lt;/strong&gt;This is a little less tangible, but still very important. A company with strong brand recognition in your market will make it easier for you to do more business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Do a thorough job at researching and vetting brokerages.%20localhost:4000/what-to-look-for-in-a-potential-brokerage.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Do a thorough job at researching and vetting brokerages.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Administrative support.&lt;/strong&gt; A brokerage could have compliance officials, service coordinators, or even full-time transactional support. When you have a brokerage who focuses on the basics, you can spend more time on the dollar-producing activities that will grow your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Lead generation.&lt;/strong&gt; Do they provide leads or not? Do they offer scripts? Both are important questions to ask.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Technology.&lt;/strong&gt; Some charge for the best tech, some provide it for you, and some don’t provide it at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Leadership and accountability. &lt;/strong&gt;It has been proven that coaching programs affect an agent’s bottom line as much as anything else. Some brokers provide this kind of support on their own, while others will point you to a coach and still others won’t offer anything at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answers to each of these questions will affect where you practice. Make sure you do a thorough job at researching and vetting brokerages before you make your decision. If you have any other questions about any of these variables or how it could affect your bottom line, give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/what-to-look-for-in-a-potential-brokerage.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/what-to-look-for-in-a-potential-brokerage.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Steps to Build a Referral-Generating Machine</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0tWNr3aJuZM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a well-known fact that one of the most productive activities in real estate is building relationships with the people we know, like, and trust. This is known as cultivating our sphere of influence, or SOI. Here are five simple steps to make sure those people are referring you business:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Make a list of everyone you trust.&lt;/strong&gt; Write down their names and contact information, including email and phone number. This list should have anywhere from 50 to 300 people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Highlight the top 10 to 20 contacts that are most likely to refer you business.&lt;/strong&gt; These people should be labeled or noted as “SOI-A+” and everyone else on the list should be noted as “SOI.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Bring an item of value to your meetings with your contacts.%20localhost:4000/5-steps-to-build-a-referral-generating-machine.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Bring an item of value to your meetings with your contacts.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Be sure to contact everyone on that list at least 30 times a year.&lt;/strong&gt; They should hear your voice through either a phone call, an image through direct mail or email, and/or a handwritten note.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Meet in person with those highlighted as “A+”&lt;/strong&gt; over lunch or coffee three to four times a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. When you touch in with anyone on your list, make sure you bring them an item of value.&lt;/strong&gt; This is usually a piece of important information, but can also be an actual item of value. Make sure they’re aware that you’re in real estate and you’d love to hear from anyone they know who might be buying or selling in the next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this topic or you’re looking to buy or sell a home, please give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 20:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/5-steps-to-build-a-referral-generating-machine.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/5-steps-to-build-a-referral-generating-machine.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Simple Ways to Double Your Productivity in Real Estate</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/x0GimVpfyV8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can’t control the amount of time we have as real estate agents, but we can control how we spend that time. I’m here to tell you that if you can improve that control, you can double your productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To do this, you need to focus on the actions and tasks that give you the highest return on the investment of your time. &lt;strong&gt;These are activities like following up with leads and prospecting.&lt;/strong&gt; They are very important, but we often don’t treat them that way. We tend to procrastinate on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=I have time set aside each day for money-producing activities.%20localhost:4000/3-simple-ways-to-double-your-productivity-in-real-estate.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“I have time set aside each day for money-producing activities.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To manage your time more wisely, I recommend using activity blocking to make sure you have specific times set aside in your calendar each day where you can focus on those money-making activities. As you can see in my calendar in the video above, I have time set aside each day for specific tasks and time set aside for focusing on things other than work. Here are my three steps to doubling your productivity:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Block time out in your schedule each day where you are specifically not working.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Block time out in the morning for a specific task, whether it be prospecting, business building, or something else.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Protect those time blocks with a vengeance.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By following these three steps, you can use the remaining time in your schedule to accomplish the rest of the things you need to do. Setting up your schedule like this will ensure you devote plenty of time to the right things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me about your career or you just want to have a quick conversation about the business, give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2017 09:40:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/3-simple-ways-to-double-your-productivity-in-real-estate.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/3-simple-ways-to-double-your-productivity-in-real-estate.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Can You Ensure All Your Clients Are Serviced Equally?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ju46zjeWhUc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you ensure all of your clients are treated with the same level or service, whether it’s you providing that service or someone else?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a loaded question because the more people doing business on your team means the more variation there will be within the service provided, &lt;strong&gt;but we use a system called Top Producer.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With Top Producer, we break down every action step in the sales process&lt;/strong&gt; to a specific action item and then to a specific person so all of our processes are repeatable and orchestrated properly. So, whether I’m providing the service or someone else is, the client will receive the exact same level of service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, in the video above, we have listing plans that have specific action items for specific people. If you were to click on that action item, you’d also see specific notes we’ve typed up explaining how that person is supposed to complete that action item. We also set a timer so every action item listed is completed at the exact same time in the transaction right up until the property goes under contract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Action items are there to make our processes repeatable.%20localhost:4000/how-can-you-ensure-all-your-clients-are-serviced-equally.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Action items are there to make our processes repeatable.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If one of our buyers or sellers goes under contract, we also have a closing plan for them. This breaks down the entire closing process so each client gets the exact same treatment, whether they’re working with me directly or someone else on our team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can do all sorts of action items—both for business and personal use.&lt;/strong&gt; Again, they’re there to make sure the process is repeatable. Just like a chef at a 5-star restaurant has a recipe that breaks down every part of the meal they’re going to cook, it’s helpful to us real estate practitioners to do the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this topic, please feel free to reach out to me. I’d love to brainstorm with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2017 07:25:58 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-can-you-ensure-all-your-clients-are-serviced-equally.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/how-can-you-ensure-all-your-clients-are-serviced-equally.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Critical Technologies You Need to Grow Your Business</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wghy7LyiLls?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an agent, I’m a big advocate of not getting distracted by shiny objects. Think of all the things presented to us real estate agents that we could easily go after and spend our money on. With that in mind, here are five critical technologies to grow your business that are tried and tested for solo agents, small teams, and teams with as many as 30 agents handling 1,000 transactions:
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Google Apps for Work.&lt;/strong&gt; The Google suite provides a collaborative office suite with Gmail, Google Calendars, and shared calendars with all sorts of notifications settings and appointment tracking for your team members. Also included is Google Docs, which offers sharing settings, storage, and collaboration within Google Sheets and Google Docs. There’s a whole other suite of applications within the Google Apps for Work suite. It’s a great piece of technology that’s essential for any team in the real estate world.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Top Producer.&lt;/strong&gt; Top Producer has a reputation for being clunky, but the truth is that it’s great to use as a CRM as well as for listing and closing plans. There is no better way to ensure that all your clients are treated the exact same way and they’re treated up to the service standard they have come to expect from you.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Buyer side CRM.&lt;/strong&gt; In a world of Internet technology and website leads, it’s important you’re able to both create a funnel for prospects coming into your world and organize those prospects so a system can prompt you to follow up with them.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. A call recording and tracking system.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s important that you track your business as you grow it so you can decide what’s worth spending money on and what’s not. A call recording and tracking system can help you improve quality control for training purposes and ensure that your team members treat your clients in the most effective and personable way possible. It can also track where you’re getting your leads from.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. A business tracking system.&lt;/strong&gt; There are all kinds of business tracking systems out there in the real estate world, but something on an Excel spreadsheet works as well as anything. Make sure that every lead source that brings a prospect into your world has a tracking code on it and every appointment that’s set contains that tracking code. At the end of that month, do a reconciliation to figure out where your business is coming from and what the return on each of those advertising investments has been.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=These five technologies will help your business immensely.%20localhost:4000/5-critical-technologies-you-need-to-grow-your-business.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“These five technologies will help your business immensely.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about any of these technologies, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 07:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/5-critical-technologies-you-need-to-grow-your-business.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/5-critical-technologies-you-need-to-grow-your-business.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Our Key to Time &amp; Task Management Success</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/yDJvJIdtkPw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to time management and planning your week, there’s one critical tool you must have. We call it the “Dominate Your Day, Win Your Week” worksheet and we fill one out every morning to stay focused on growth activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see on the sample sheet in the video above, we put ‘on business’ projects on top. We consider ‘on business’ things to be systems and other things that will grow the business like projects and lead generation. &lt;strong&gt;You should always be working on two or three projects in 90-minute time chunks each week&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;to grow the business.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below that is a breakdown of the top six money-making activities for a given day. For example, prospecting to 20 people or hand writing two notes could be a top task every single day. Then, you can categorize other tasks that are good to get done each day, but aren’t completely necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You should always work on a few projects in 90-minute chunks each week to grow the business.%20localhost:4000/our-key-to-time-task-management-success.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You should always work on a few projects in 90-minute chunks each week to grow the business.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Then at the bottom of the list, you can write down miscellaneous action items that you know you need to finish each day.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s pretty much a laundry list of errands and other things related to the business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, since I’m big on gratitude and having a positive focus, we have a list for these items to make sure things are looking forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to talk more about how we use this tool or why we’ve had success with it, or you’d like a copy, just give me a call or send me an email. I’d love to speak with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 05:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/our-key-to-time-task-management-success.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/our-key-to-time-task-management-success.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>This Document Is the Key to Ensuring Your Business Is Growing</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2NXMmoWZJjk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s one critical tool you need to use every day to assure you grow your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are plenty of quick fixes and shiny objects out there that you’ve probably been tempted to spend a lot of time and money on to grow your business, but as we all know, to grow a sales business, you have to be in contact with a lot of people. There a lot of ways to do this, but one phrase that stands out to me is, “We respect what we inspect.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There’s no better thing to inspect than our critical activities used to get in touch with people. And that’s why my agents and I carry a document called the &lt;strong&gt;Weekly Critical Activities Success Tracker&lt;/strong&gt; every day. You can take a look at this document in the video above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=This document tracks everything we do on a daily basis.%20localhost:4000/this-document-is-the-key-to-ensuring-your-business-is-growing.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“This document tracks everything we do on a daily basis.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It tracks everything we do every day and puts it on a worksheet. For example, the middle of that page has prospecting and follow-up calls because we know we should make between 15 and 30 prospecting and follow-up calls every single day. We can also notch off referrals and new contacts added to our database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I encourage you to set a goal for yourself for the amount of outbound touches you want to make every day&lt;/strong&gt; and record them on this document. Then, set yourself up with a Google Form like we do and it will come to your inbox every Monday to help you stay accountable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about growing your business or you’d like a copy of our activities tracker, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I’d love to hear from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 10:54:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/this-document-is-the-key-to-ensuring-your-business-is-growing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/this-document-is-the-key-to-ensuring-your-business-is-growing.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Indicators of When It's Time to Hire an Assistant</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/U42PJXSM-5Q?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At some point, the time may come when your best move will be to hire a real estate assistant. If you’re doing 15 to 20 transactions without an assistant, you’re probably having trouble finding balance in life. An assistant can not only give you an opportunity to find that balance, but increase your productivity at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How will you know it’s time to hire an assistant? &lt;strong&gt;There are three qualifiers we look for before making a hire:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Your transaction count:&lt;/strong&gt; If you’re looking to do 25 or more transactions, your count is probably at or over capacity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Your income:&lt;/strong&gt; If you’re in the $4.5 million to $6 million annual production range, it might equate to about $130,000 to $150,000 GCI. If you’re at that level or more, you should consider hiring an assistant because you likely have the financial capacity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Your savings:&lt;/strong&gt; The conservative in me thinks it’s important to have an emergency fund. If you have between three and six months of an assistant’s potential income saved in a separate account, then you have the financial reserves to be able to afford an assistant. That way, if you have a slow period, you’ll have a bucket of reserves you can pull from without getting too stressed. We all know we can have slow times of a month or two at a time, so this is really valuable to have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Your transaction count can be a good indicator that it's time to hire an assistant.%20localhost:4000/3-indicators-of-when-its-time-to-hire-an-assistant.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Your transaction count can be a good indicator that it’s time to hire an assistant.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If any or all three of these qualifiers relate to you, it might be time to really think about whether you should hire an assistant. I can say with certainty that every time we’ve hired an assistant or agent to help us grow our business, we’ve never regretted it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to discuss these qualifiers further, I’d love to sit down and speak with you about your best course of action. Just give me a call or send me an email and we’ll talk soon&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 06:34:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/3-indicators-of-when-its-time-to-hire-an-assistant.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/3-indicators-of-when-its-time-to-hire-an-assistant.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
