<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bigfork Real Estate Video Blog with Scott Hollinger</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Hollinger Team - your professional Bigfork Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://blog.flatheadrealestate.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.flatheadrealestate.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 14:50:10 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 14:50:10 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Few Ways to Get Rid of All Your Clutter During a Move</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_IKOMooZmWY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Whether you&amp;rsquo;re buying, selling, downsizing, or just doing some spring cleaning, there are a few ways you can get rid of your extra stuff.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do you do with all that stuff?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might be asking yourself this question if you’re a seller and you’re packing your things in anticipation of moving, you’re getting ready to close on a home and have thing to pack as well, you’re downsizing or helping someone downsize and they have a lot of personal items, or you’re just doing some spring cleaning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I myself recently experienced this type of situation when I had to help my wife’s parents downsize out of their previous home. There are a few options to consider, and each one has its own share of pros and cons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First, you can simply pack everything up.&lt;/strong&gt; This involves getting a lot of boxes, and I recommend you buy boxes that are all uniform in size. This will make them easier to stack and easier to handle. There are some great online resources for gathering boxes, including U-haul and Craigslist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also &lt;strong&gt;bring in your own dumpster.&lt;/strong&gt; This might sound a little rash, but if you’re downsizing and collecting things that have accumulated over many years, a lot of those things will probably end up in a dumpster. Many dumpster services offer and deliver dumpsters that come in different sizes. The cost difference between a large and a small dumpster isn’t great, so it’s better to have a little extra room available just in case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, you can try Craigslist to post your items on there for free or advertise them and sell them for a fee. This should only be used for just a few items, though. You don’t want to spend a lot of time posting items to this site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also charities that will pick your stuff up. The catch here, though, is they won’t accept anything and everything, so you may have to figure out how to dispose of anything that’s not wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=These options will help you be economical in getting rid of your extra stuff.%20http://blog.flatheadrealestate.com/a-few-ways-to-get-rid-of-all-your-clutter-during-a-move.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“These options will help you be economical in getting rid of your extra stuff.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doing an auction&lt;/strong&gt; is an option you can use for furniture and other things of that nature. In this case, an auction house will come and tell you what they can take and what will actually sell. The downside is that, again, some personal items will get left behind that you’ll have to figure out what to do with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A garage sale&lt;/strong&gt; is another thing you can do. They’re a little bit long and tedious though, and when it’s done you typically won’t be able to find a charity that will accept what’s left over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lastly, you can have an estate service come in&lt;/strong&gt; and conduct an estate sale on the property and either sell or dispose of everything in it. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gone4good.com/&quot;&gt;Gone4Good&lt;/a&gt; is a service that does this that we highly recommend. They’ll literally come to your house and clean out everything. They’ll dispose of anything that has little or no value and sell anything that does have value at their store. They sell larger items on a commission basis. Their fee is negotiable based on how big your home is, how many items they take, and a few other factors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some links related to the options and services listed above that you might find useful:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://gardnerauction.com/&quot;&gt;http://gardnerauction.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://kalispell.salvationarmy.org/&quot;&gt;https://kalispell.salvationarmy.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uhaul.com/Locations/Truck-Rentals-near-Kalispell-MT-59901/842071/&quot;&gt;https://www.uhaul.com/Locations/Truck-Rentals-near-Kalispell-MT-59901/842071/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.evergreengarbage.com/services.aspx&quot;&gt;http://www.evergreengarbage.com/services.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any more questions about what to do with your extra stuff, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 16:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.flatheadrealestate.com/a-few-ways-to-get-rid-of-all-your-clutter-during-a-move.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.flatheadrealestate.com/a-few-ways-to-get-rid-of-all-your-clutter-during-a-move.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Great Resource for Tracking Your Mail</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/lu3FcVSCiZg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;With a lot of seasonal buyers, dealing with the mail in our market can get tricky. Here&amp;rsquo;s a tip to help.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have a lot of seasonal buyers in our market. With so many people constantly coming and leaving, I’m constantly getting questions about mail delivery. &lt;strong&gt;For those of you living here now, I have a great resource to share with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s called informed delivery and it’s really easy to set up on the USPS website. You can go &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://reg.usps.com/entreg/RegistrationPortalAction_input?&amp;amp;iom=B808-82ID-USRS-PS-USP-GO-XXX-AW-XX-X-INF&amp;amp;utm_source=google&amp;amp;utm_medium=search&amp;amp;utm_content=b808_82id&amp;amp;utm_campaign=informeddelivery2018&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, set up an account, and then you can track all of your mail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if you’re expecting a package, you can track it every step of the way. Each time the package is processed by a USPS employee, you will get an immediate email letting you know the package’s status. &lt;strong&gt;You can even arrange to receive your package without being there to sign or reschedule your delivery time.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=This is an easy way to keep track of your mail.%20http://blog.flatheadrealestate.com/a-great-resource-for-tracking-your-mail.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“This is an easy way to keep track of your mail.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just wanted to give you a quick tip to help you keep track of your mail, especially if you’re coming and going or changing homes on a seasonal basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me about this topic or anything else in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 10:51:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.flatheadrealestate.com/a-great-resource-for-tracking-your-mail.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.flatheadrealestate.com/a-great-resource-for-tracking-your-mail.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Have You Felt an Earthquake in Montana?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/3kovmLRHeDA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Many people have asked me about how dangerous earthquakes in Montana are. Here&amp;rsquo;s what you should know.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are &lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mbmg.mtech.edu/quakes/quake-seismicity.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;earthquakes in Montana&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt; something to be worried about?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having been born and raised here in Montana, I’ve felt a few earthquakes every now and then, but nothing severe. At most, you might experience one that rattles something off a shelf in a grocery store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, I was sitting at home the other day when I felt a loud thud. I thought it was snow falling off a tree and onto our deck, but there was no snow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure enough, &lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://earthquake.usgs.gov/earthquakes/eventpage/us2000cjje#executive&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;it had been an earthquake&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Deadly earthquakes aren’t impossible in Montana, but are very unlikely.%20http://blog.flatheadrealestate.com/have-you-felt-an-earthquake-in-montana.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Deadly earthquakes aren’t impossible in Montana, but are very unlikely.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A belt of seismicity (seismic or earthquake activity) actually runs through the western portion of Montana, called the Intermountain Seismic Belt. It extends into Idaho, Wyoming, Utah, and southern Nevada.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a portion of the Belt called the Centennial Tectonic Belt that has &lt;strong&gt;eight active faults which have produced a few major earthquakes in history,&lt;/strong&gt; although it’s been 40 years since an earthquake produced by this region has been destructive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So in general, no, you don’t have much to fear from earthquakes in Montana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For any other questions about real estate, feel free to reach out to me. I’d be happy to talk with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 08:48:48 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.flatheadrealestate.com/have-you-felt-an-earthquake-in-montana.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.flatheadrealestate.com/have-you-felt-an-earthquake-in-montana.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lakefront Properties in 2017</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/bwb3p02IXOo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’d like to share a recap of all the different waterfront real estate markets in 2017. We’ll start with Flathead Lake and go down the line all the way to McGregor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, we’ll take a look at Flathead Lake. There are a ton of condos selling in this market, which is bringing down the average sale price. In places like Echo and Swan Lake, we’re seeing quite a few sales over that $1 million mark. To get all the latest details on your specific waterfront market, click the corresponding video below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/flathead-lake-properties-2017-recap.html&quot;&gt;Flathead Lake&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/swan-echo-blaine-properties-2017-recap.html&quot;&gt;Swan, Echo, and Blaine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/ashley-bitterroot-mcgregor-properties-2017-recap.html&quot;&gt;Ashley, Bitterroot, and McGregor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 10:17:31 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.flatheadrealestate.com/lakefront-properties-in-2017.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.flatheadrealestate.com/lakefront-properties-in-2017.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Flathead Lake Properties 2017 Recap</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/n48h-x11Vb4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Flathead Lake, we saw 46 sales in 2017. That’s down from the 52 we saw the year before, but it’s up from the 44 we saw in 2015. &lt;strong&gt;The median price in Flathead Lake is up to $689,000 right now and there are seven pending sales on the lake as well. Each of these pending sales is below the $900,000 mark.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 85 active listings right now in Flathead Lake. Of those 85, 31 are listed under $1 million and 54 are listed over $1 million. Properties here are currently spending an average of 449 days on the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as vacant land sales go, everything’s pretty flat in Flathead Lake (no pun intended). The median price for those plots is sitting at $480,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We actually see a big chunk of Flathead Lake sales in the condo market. &lt;strong&gt;They fill in those gaps in the lower price ranges.&lt;/strong&gt; The average sale price of condos in Flathead Lake is $380,000. Sales are down quite a bit from last year, but there are still 38 active listings right now with a $462,000 median list price. The sold condos on Flathead Lake averaged about 243 days on the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a detailed overview, check out the documents below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Scott+Hollinger/2017+Yr+End+-+Flathead+Lake+notes.pdf&quot;&gt;2017 Recap of Flathead Lake&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Scott+Hollinger/2017+Yr+End+-+Flathead+Lake+Condominium+notes.pdf&quot;&gt;2017 Recap of Flathead Lake Condominiums&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 10:09:06 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.flatheadrealestate.com/flathead-lake-properties-2017-recap.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.flatheadrealestate.com/flathead-lake-properties-2017-recap.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Swan, Echo, Blaine Properties 2017 Recap</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0rgLvcwZDoQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s look at Swan Lake, Echo Lake, and Lake Blaine. In Swan Lake, there were eight home sales this year, up from the five we saw the year before. We also saw two vacant land sales in 2017.There is one pending sale there right now, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Echo Lake saw two sales this year, down from the three they had the year before. An interesting thing to note is that one of those two sales was for $1.8 million.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve seen just one sale on Lake Blaine this year. There just isn’t that much out there. We won’t ever have very high numbers there. There are seven vacant land plots and 11 active listings here. There is one pending sale for $1.5 million.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a detailed overview, check out the document below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Scott+Hollinger/2017+Yr+End+-+Smaller+Lakes+notes.pdf&quot;&gt;2017 Recap of the smaller NW Montana Lakes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 09:59:47 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.flatheadrealestate.com/swan-echo-blaine-properties-2017-recap.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.flatheadrealestate.com/swan-echo-blaine-properties-2017-recap.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ashley, Bitterroot, McGregor Properties 2017 Recap</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/movU-ZKUjVU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ashley saw a big jump in vacant land sales, Bitterroot saw a big jump in residential home sales, and McGregor stayed pretty flat with four total residential sales. There are 15 vacant land lots in these three areas total, with nine of them being in McGregor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a detailed overview, check out the document below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Scott+Hollinger/2017+Yr+End+-+Smaller+Lakes+notes.pdf&quot;&gt;2017 Recap of the smaller NW Montana Lakes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 09:50:38 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.flatheadrealestate.com/ashley-bitterroot-mcgregor-properties-2017-recap.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.flatheadrealestate.com/ashley-bitterroot-mcgregor-properties-2017-recap.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Closer Look at the Waterfront Market in 2017</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ef9jjcQKcxE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What’s happening in the waterfront market? Here are the latest numbers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’d like to share a recap of all the different waterfront real estate markets in 2017. We’ll start with Flathead Lake and go down the line all the way to McGregor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Flathead Lake, we saw 46 sales in 2017. That’s down from the 52 we saw the year before, but it’s up from the 44 we saw in 2015. &lt;strong&gt;The median price in Flathead Lake is up to $689,000 right now and there are seven pending sales on the lake as well. Each of these pending sales is below the $900,000 mark.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 85 active listings right now in Flathead Lake. Of those 85, 31 are listed under $1 million and 54 are listed over $1 million. Properties here are currently spending an average of 449 days on the market. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as vacant land sales go, everything’s pretty flat in Flathead Lake (no pun intended). The median price for those plots is sitting at $480,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We actually see a big chunk of Flathead Lake sales in the condo market. &lt;strong&gt;They fill in those gaps in the lower price ranges.&lt;/strong&gt; The average sale price of condos in Flathead Lake is $380,000. Sales are down quite a bit from last year, but there are still 38 active listings right now with a $462,000 median list price. The sold condos on Flathead Lake averaged about 243 days on the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now let’s look at Swan Lake, Echo Lake, and Lake Blaine. In Swan Lake, there were eight home sales this year, up from the five we saw the year before. We also saw two vacant land sales in 2017. There is one pending sale there right now, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Echo Lake saw two sales this year, down from the three they had the year before. An interesting thing to note is that one of those two sales was for $1.8 million.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We only saw one sale on Lake Blaine this year.%20http://blog.flatheadrealestate.com/a-closer-look-at-the-waterfront-market-in-2017.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We only saw one sale on Lake Blaine this year.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve seen just one sale on Lake Blaine this year. There just isn’t that much out there. We won’t ever have very high numbers there. There are seven vacant land plots and 11 active listings here. There is one pending sale for $1.5 million. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last but not least, let’s look at Ashley, Bitterroot, and McGregor. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ashley saw a big jump in vacant land sales, Bitterroot saw a big jump in residential home sales, and McGregor stayed pretty flat with four total residential sales.&lt;/strong&gt; There are 15 vacant land lots in these three areas total, with nine of them being in McGregor. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To learn all the details about these different markets, check out the video above. If you have any other questions for me, don’t hesitate to reach out. I’d be glad to elaborate on these numbers for you and answer any questions you may have.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 08:27:40 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.flatheadrealestate.com/a-closer-look-at-the-waterfront-market-in-2017.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.flatheadrealestate.com/a-closer-look-at-the-waterfront-market-in-2017.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Should a Seller Do a Home Inspection?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Lbn31RKgZ8U?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should a seller do a home inspection when they list? This question crops up quite a bit from sellers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I’d say the answer was yes, unless it’s brand new or there’s some other reason why defects wouldn’t crop up. There are three reasons why we encourage people to do inspections:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To save money.&lt;/strong&gt; It seems counterintuitive to spend money on an inspection in order to save money. However, sometimes the inspection comes through and all of the sudden you’re pushing up against closing dates or some other plans, and things still need to be done. Those fixes are done in a hurry, or a seller ends up crediting money to a buyer to get them done. If you do it ahead of time, it shows that you’re proactive about taking care of a home that you’re aware of the condition of the home.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It helps you close faster&lt;/strong&gt; because a lot of the time, an appraisal won’t even get ordered for financing until after the home inspection is completed. If you can make the inspection period short, it will help shorten the time span between you and the close, as well as take away the contingency sooner.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It can save a sale.&lt;/strong&gt; Sometimes people see certain issues on an inspection and run for the hills. Having the inspection done in time to get those problems fixed can sometimes be the difference between a sale and a huge disappointment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Even if you don’t do the inspection, it can help to give your seller’s disclosure statement.%20http://blog.flatheadrealestate.com/should-a-seller-do-a-home-inspection.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Even if you don’t do the inspection, it can help to give your seller’s disclosure statement.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if you don’t do the inspection, it can help to give your seller’s disclosure statement. That way, whatever issues you’ve discovered over time are made known during the sales negotiation, not afterward, which would open up the opportunity for renegotiation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for the great question—I hope this answer was helpful. If you have any additional questions about this or other topics, always feel free to contact us by phone or email. We’d love to help you out.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 08:18:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.flatheadrealestate.com/should-a-seller-do-a-home-inspection.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.flatheadrealestate.com/should-a-seller-do-a-home-inspection.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are Zillow Zestimates Actually Accurate?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ffp_F5opIdM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Just how accurate is Zillow’s Zestimate feature? Today, I’ve got some information you need to know before relying on this website.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people are curious about the true credibility of Zillow’s Zestimate feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, the Zestimate relies only on data because it is computer-generated. Nothing else can be taken into account. This becomes even more of an issue because Montana is a non-disclosure state, meaning that &lt;strong&gt;real estate transactions are not public information and cannot be pulled up through databases.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Zestimate also has the disadvantage of there being no personal viewing of the property. The Zestimate is based strictly off of numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also isn’t bankable. You can’t walk into a bank or lender with a Zestimate and expect it to count as an appraisal. In order to move forward, you will need a real appraisal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A major reason for this is that Zestimates can be very inaccurate. &lt;strong&gt;The CEO of Zillow himself sold his home for $750,000 below his Zestimate, which was almost 50% of the sales price.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see for yourself how reliable Zillow is based on some of the information included &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zillow.com/zestimate/#acc&quot; class=&quot;blue-link&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The best way to value your property is to work with an agent who is experienced in your area and with your type of property.%20http://blog.flatheadrealestate.com/are-zillow-zestimates-actually-accurate.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The best way to value your property is to work with an agent who is experienced in your area and with your type of property.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, the best way to value your property is to work with an agent who is experienced in your area and with your type of property. The right Realtor will also have a strong pulse on the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 05:56:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.flatheadrealestate.com/are-zillow-zestimates-actually-accurate.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.flatheadrealestate.com/are-zillow-zestimates-actually-accurate.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
