<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Valley of the Sun Real Estate Careers and Training Video Blog with Nate Martinez</title>
    <description>A Video Blog about Valley of the Sun Real Estate; It's industry, and the people working in it. Whether you're just starting out, aspiring to begin, or been working in the field for a few years, tune in to get updates, tips, tricks and more!</description>
    <link>http://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 12:58:08 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 12:58:08 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>What You Need to Know About Radon Gas</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/5k7lwWDdV8M?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last couple of months, I’ve heard the word “radon” too many times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s interesting because whenever I talk to other real estate professionals, I ask them how many of the homes they’ve dealt with have had radon in them, and they always say, “None.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some buyers from the East Coast have some knowledge about radon, as do a few homeowners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Radon came to my attention when I was representing a buyer during a transaction on a house in Scottsdale. This house had fallen out of escrow because the radon test came back two points higher than the national standard of 4%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If the house has a basement or underground air units, order a radon test.%20http://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/what-you-need-to-know-about-radon-gas.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If the house has a basement or underground air units, order a radon test.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Radon is an odorless, poisonous gas that can cause lung cancer over long periods of exposure. As I’ve learned more about radon, I’ve found that &lt;strong&gt;the reason most people don’t find it in our area is that hardly anyone looks for it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was always taught that radon tests are necessary in mountainous regions because radon comes from granite in the ground. However, this Scottsdale house was on a flat piece of dirt and ended up having a high radon content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We made the offer contingent on the seller getting radon levels down. At first, the seller paid $5,000 to fix the problem. The radon levels did not go down. The seller then spent another $5,000. After all the work they did and money they spent, the radon levels actually went higher, which was no good, and the buyer walked away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just want to make sure that people are aware that radon is out there. If you are buying a home, ask for a radon test. They only cost $300 to $350. &lt;strong&gt;If the house has a basement or underground air units, then you definitely need to order a radon test.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about radon or buying a home, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 07:27:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/what-you-need-to-know-about-radon-gas.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/what-you-need-to-know-about-radon-gas.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>14 Activities Every Real Estate Agent Should Master: Part Two</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/tuEfQAN78HQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 14 vital activities that every real estate agent should do. Last time, we focused on the seven things you need to do to help sellers. Today, we’ll focus on what you need to do to master representing buyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Lead generation.&lt;/strong&gt; Again, you need to be constantly generating new leads through open houses, Zillow, yard signs, and referrals from past clients, family, and friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Have a conversion process.&lt;/strong&gt; What do you do to convert this person from a name and number into a buyer and broker contract?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Paperwork.&lt;/strong&gt; Get that agreement signed and take care of agency disclosures and buyer advisories while you are in the beginning stages of working with the buyer.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Finding and showing the perfect home.&lt;/strong&gt; This is the fun part. You get to guide the buyer through their home search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You need to be able to write an offer that will get accepted.%20http://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/14-activities-every-real-estate-agent-should-master-part-two.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You need to be able to write an offer that will get accepted.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Writing and negotiating the best purchase agreement.&lt;/strong&gt; You need to be proficient in making sure that your offers protect the buyer’s best interests. You also need to make sure that the buyer understands all of the inspections and finance contingencies. The bottom line is that you need to be able to write an offer that will be accepted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Closing.&lt;/strong&gt; Again, it’s important to make sure that the closing process goes smoothly. Be there with your buyer at the closing table in case they have any questions or concerns. You are there to be their advocate. Let them know that you care by showing up to closing. Then, when everything has been done, you can ask if there is anyone they can refer you to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Post-closing activities.&lt;/strong&gt; In my 31 years of real estate, I’ve noticed that this step gets skipped the most. What are you doing to develop a deep relationship with this client after you close escrow? After all, they may be a client who will bring you business for the rest of your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to have detailed plans in place to make sure that you are relevant in their mind. Call them up every now and then, invite them to sporting events, or host annual client appreciation events. You can also check to see how they like the house. If they have any challenges or need a repairman, you can put them in touch with one. You will position yourself as a great real estate resource.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope these 14 activities will help you grow your business. If you have any questions, please don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 07:45:55 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/14-activities-every-real-estate-agent-should-master-part-two.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/14-activities-every-real-estate-agent-should-master-part-two.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Don’t Skip These 14 Activities Every Real Estate Agent Should Master</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/QRtdlZqHK4A?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 14 vital activities that each Realtor should do. I’ll go over the first seven for you today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Lead generation.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s so important to constantly generate leads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Converting leads.&lt;/strong&gt; Turn those leads into appointments and then into contracts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Administrative work.&lt;/strong&gt; Most Realtors don’t like paperwork, which is why we have transaction coordinators to help us out. Administrative paperwork is a vital activity that we must do ourselves or delegate to others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Have good presentation.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s important to present at listing appointments, in front of buyers, and in the negotiation of contracts. Whether you are representing the buyer or seller, you have to be able to negotiate on their behalf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Marketing.&lt;/strong&gt; You need to have a strategic marketing plan in place. Whether you are trying to connect with people through farming, Zillow, or wherever it may be that you are spending money to generate leads, marketing is a highly important function of being a Realtor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=There are many components that you need to master, but the closing component is extremely important.%20http://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/dont-skip-these-14-activities-every-real-estate-agent-should-master.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“There are many components that you need to master, but the closing component is extremely important.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Closing.&lt;/strong&gt; All of your hard work goes into the closing day. You want to make sure that you are able to get the closing done right. There are many components that you need to master, but the closing component is extremely important. Make sure you go to closings so that you can represent your client. By going to the closing, you will also be present in your client’s mindset and they will be more likely to send your information to their friends and family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Post-closing activities.&lt;/strong&gt; What do you do once the house is closed? Do you just cash the check and never talk to those people again? Or do you want these people to become part of the fabric of your life? It’s very important to have an ongoing follow-up plan for everyone you represent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all, if you had a good transaction, then they know, like, and trust you. They also know what to expect by working with you. Now it’s up to you to stay in constant contact with them. If they need help with the house, finding contractors, or dealing with home warranty issues, you should be their advocate. Invite them to dinner, call on them cordially after closing, or invite them to client events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for the next seven tasks that every real estate agent should do. In the meantime, if you have any questions, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 06:08:55 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/dont-skip-these-14-activities-every-real-estate-agent-should-master.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/dont-skip-these-14-activities-every-real-estate-agent-should-master.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We Want to Teach You How to Build Your Wealth</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/5ebEUOMEZbo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you a real estate agent who wants to build wealth? I want to let you know that you’re invited to our next training session, where you’ll learn how to do exactly that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.joinrmxprofessionals.com/Join-Today&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Join RE/MAX Professionals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you a real estate agent who wants to build wealth? I want to let you know that you’re invited to our next training session, where you’ll learn how to do exactly that. You’ll learn how to embrace the habits and mindsets of the wealthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You’ll also learn the seven pillars of wealth-building from none other than the guy who wrote the book—literally.&lt;/strong&gt; We’re flying in “Wealth Can’t Wait” author David Osborn. We’re going to give away all of our strategies and systems so you can build a profitable business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the event is over, you’ll leave with not only the knowledge to build wealth, but also a copy of David’s book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=WE’RE GIVING AWAY ALL OF OUR STRATEGIES AND SYSTEMS SO YOU CAN BUILD A PROFITABLE BUSINESS.%20http://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/we-want-to-teach-you-how-to-build-your.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“WE’RE GIVING AWAY ALL OF OUR STRATEGIES AND SYSTEMS SO YOU CAN BUILD A PROFITABLE BUSINESS.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, space is limited so only the first 200 in attendance will receive this free copy. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.joinrmxprofessionals.com/Registration&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;To RSVP for this free event, click here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there is one catch after you register: you have to show up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We hope to see you there on Thursday, November 2nd starting at 8:30 a.m.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 12:38:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/we-want-to-teach-you-how-to-build-your.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/we-want-to-teach-you-how-to-build-your.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate Coaching</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Did You Sell Any of the 14,904 Homes Yesterday?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/TZ51hnsctPg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only a small percentage of agents make the most sales. Our team is part of that small percentage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.joinrmxprofessionals.com/Join-Today&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Join RE/MAX Professionals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you know that 14,904 homes sold yesterday alone? That’s straight from the National Association of Realtors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the Phoenix area, there are about 88,000 home sales per year. That breaks down to 7,400 each month and 275 each day. With over 35,000 Realtors in the Valley of the Sun, &lt;strong&gt;there are at least 26,000 Realtors who didn’t even sell a home last month.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How does this happen? As you may or may not know, a lot of licensed agents around here only work in real estate part-time. At Re/MAX Professionals, we focus on real estate as a full-time career. &lt;strong&gt;This is one of the reasons why our agents are able to sell 24 homes per year on average, the highest average in the Valley.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=THERE ARE AT LEAST 26,000 REALTORS WHO DON’T SELL A HOME EACH MONTH.%20http://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/did-you-sell-any-of-14904-homes.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“THERE ARE AT LEAST 26,000 REALTORS WHO DON’T SELL A HOME EACH MONTH.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We train well, we pay well, and we support well. We have several events coming up soon. For one, we offer two real estate classes, called Momentum, each week. Momentum is all about mastering the basics. To learn more about Momentum, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.joinrmxprofessionals.com/Momentum-Complete-Agent-Development&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;click here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.joinrmxprofessionals.com/Momentum-Complete-Agent-Development&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/momentum.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;post-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I wan to remind you that I’m bringing in David Osborn, one of the authors of “Wealth Can’t Wait” on November 2nd. You’ll learn a lot and walk away with a free hardcover copy of David’s book. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/events/1621981244508240/?active_tab=about&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Learn more about the event here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/events/1621981244508240/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/facebook.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;post-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions for us in the meantime, don’t hesitate to reach out and give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 10:31:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/did-you-sell-any-of-14904-homes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/did-you-sell-any-of-14904-homes.html</guid>
        
        <category>Valley of the Sun Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Recent Trends in Hispanic Homeownership</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/kle6pxzdoLA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s pretty amazing to see some of the home buying numbers in the Hispanic community. Here are a few that stick out to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.joinrmxprofessionals.com/Join-Today&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Join RE/MAX Professionals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The National Association of Hispanic Real Estate Professionals has recently published a report that I wanted to talk about today. There are a lot of interesting numbers in here that point to an upward trend in Hispanic homeownership that no other demographic is seeing. Here’s what’s been going on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• In 2016, there were 7.3 million Hispanic homeowners in the U.S.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Also in 2016, there were 209,000 new Hispanic homeowners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Hispanic people account for 60% of the U.S.’s overall growth in homeownership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Hispanic people will account for 52% of new homeownership between 2010 and 2030.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• From 2010 to 2015, Hispanics accounted for more than half the population growth in the U.S. according to the U.S. Census.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Six out of 10 Hispanic homebuyers are millennials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• The Hispanic purchasing power was $1.4 trillion in 2016—more than the entire country of Australia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Hispanic people account for 76.4% of labor growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to these numbers, you can see a graph in the video above that shows the growth in owner-occupied units. You can see the Hispanic population of homeowners start to increase over the last decade or so now that growth has outpaced that of non-Hispanic homeowners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another graph in the video above shows the net homeownership change. It’s interesting to note that Hispanics had an additional 1.1 million homeownership changes from 2010 to 2016, while non-Hispanic homeownership changes went down by 2.2 million.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=HISPANIC HOMEOWNERSHIP IS AT AN ALL-TIME HIGH.%20http://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/recent-trends-in-hispanic-homeownership.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“HISPANIC HOMEOWNERSHIP IS AT AN ALL-TIME HIGH.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of these stats just absolutely blew me away. After reading into them more, it makes sense. &lt;strong&gt;As far as Hispanic attitudes toward homeownership are concerned, raising a family and wealth creation have proven to be the primary drivers. It appears that trend is likely to continue.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I go, I wanted to quickly remind you that I’m bringing in David Osborn, one of the authors of “Wealth Can’t Wait” on November 2nd. You’ll walk away with a free hardcover copy of David’s book. Learn more about the event here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/events/1621981244508240/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/facebook.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;post-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At RE/MAX Professionals, we have several events coming up, ourselves. For one, we offer two real estate classes, called Momentum, each week. Momentum is all about mastering the basics. To learn more about Momentum, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.joinrmxprofessionals.com/Momentum-Complete-Agent-Development&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;click here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.joinrmxprofessionals.com/Momentum-Complete-Agent-Development&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/momentum.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;post-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about that or about real estate in general, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 15:43:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/recent-trends-in-hispanic-homeownership.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/recent-trends-in-hispanic-homeownership.html</guid>
        
        <category>Valley of the Sun Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Can You Master Your Craft?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/JXGvxxy-YUg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does it take to master your craft? Today, I’ve got a few stories on this subject as well as a few opportunities you should know about that can help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.joinrmxprofessionals.com/Join-Today&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Join RE/MAX Professionals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, my family and I are taking a trip up to Jackson Hole, Wyoming for the total solar eclipse. But today, I wanted to talk to you about something different—mastering your craft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to mastering your craft, one story that comes to mind for me is that of my mentor: Howard Brinton. When it comes to becoming a surgeon, mastering your craft is an absolute necessity. Between college, med school, and practicing on cadavers, a lot of time and hard work goes into it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, there are many ways you can master your craft. When it comes to real estate, &lt;strong&gt;the 90 minutes it takes to get your license isn’t where the fine-tuning ends.&lt;/strong&gt; In real estate, experience with real clients is the best way to master your craft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, experience is a great way to hone your skills in any endeavor. As a kid, Kurt Warner, who was just inducted into the NFL Hall of Fame, would practice every single day. He continued this through high school, college, and beyond. Even still, success doesn’t always come that simply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kurt was cut after being drafted by the Green Bay Packers. He didn’t make the team, but kept practicing anyway. After gaining even more experience through arena football and even playing in Europe, he was contacted by the St. Louis Rams. Then when he started playing with them, he took the team to the Super Bowl—and they won.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter what your passion is, it will take a lot of time to master it. As a real estate agent, you can master your craft by practicing scripts, listing presentations, and buyer presentations. &lt;strong&gt;If you want to be great at what you do, you’ve got to practice daily.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to help. If you’re looking to further yourself in your real estate career, I’d like to sit down with you and speak one-on-one about how you can master your craft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, becoming skilled at what I do is something I’ve always strived for. As a child my hero was Bruce Lee. Seeing his statue was one of the reasons I took my recent trip to Hong Kong. Bruce Lee has been an inspiration to me, and many of the things he’s said still resonate with me, today. One quote of his in particular stands out: &lt;strong&gt;“I fear not the man who has practiced 10,000 kicks once, but I fear the man who has practiced one kick 10,000 times.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=EXPERIENCE WITH REAL CLIENTS IS THE BEST WAY TO MASTER YOUR CRAFT.%20http://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/how-can-you-master-your-craft.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“EXPERIENCE WITH REAL CLIENTS IS THE BEST WAY TO MASTER YOUR CRAFT.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is true not just of martial arts, but of any skill. To become truly masterful over what you do, you must put in a lot of time. As a real estate professional, there are a lot of events out there designed to help you master your craft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At RE/MAX Professionals, we have several events coming up, ourselves. For one, we offer two real estate classes, called Momentum, each week. Momentum is all about mastering the basics. To learn more about Momentum, click here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.joinrmxprofessionals.com/Momentum-Complete-Agent-Development&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/momentum.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;post-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re also excited to announce that we will be hosting a special guest speaker, David Osborn, on November 2nd, 2017. David is going to share his story with us. After college, he took a year off to backpack around the world. After coming back to help his mom with her real estate endeavors, David now owns one of the nation’s largest real estate firms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with his story, David will also be speaking about his most recent book, “Wealth Can’t Wait.” On that note, we have exciting news. &lt;strong&gt;The first 200 people who sign up will receive a copy of David’s book on us.&lt;/strong&gt; For more information about this event, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/events/1621981244508240/?active_tab=about&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;click here. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/events/1621981244508240/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/facebook.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;post-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve got any questions you’d like me to answer, send it in. If we use your question in one of our videos, I’ll send you out a $50 gift certificate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 13:31:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/how-can-you-master-your-craft.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/how-can-you-master-your-craft.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate Coaching</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Statistics About Real Estate in the Valley</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/NGZkUktcdso?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I have some interesting statistics about real estate agents in the Valley, and an opportunity for those Realtors who want to improve their numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.joinrmxprofessionals.com/Join-Today&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Join RE/MAX Professionals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are almost 38,000 active licenses in the Valley today that are Realtors, plus additional non-Realtor licenses as well. There are over 4,200 real estate offices in the Valley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One interesting statistic that stands out to me is that 15% of active agents have left the business after just one year. That’s about 5,700 agents who no longer have a license.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10% of agents, or about 3,800, are only in business for 24 to 36 months. After three years in the business, an additional 5% of the remaining agents leave. So once you’ve made it past four years in the business, you can expect to be doing pretty well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=ONCE YOU’VE MADE IT PAST FOUR YEARS, YOU CAN EXPECT TO BE DOING PRETTY WELL.%20http://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/statistics-about-real-estate-in-valley.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“ONCE YOU’VE MADE IT PAST FOUR YEARS, YOU CAN EXPECT TO BE DOING PRETTY WELL.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout 2016, the number of homes sold in the Valley was 88,713. Given the current number of agents that are active, that’s only 2.36 homes per agent! &lt;strong&gt;Our agents at RE/MAX Professionals sell 10 times that average.&lt;/strong&gt; Some of our agents have sold over 100 homes in the last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you have any questions on how to become a better real estate agent, we offer free training to anyone interested. You don’t have to join our company, but we would love to see you come through. We’ve created a better business model that focuses on helping regular agents become legendary agents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about our free training, please give me a call or shoot me an email. I’d be happy to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 14:38:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/statistics-about-real-estate-in-valley.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/statistics-about-real-estate-in-valley.html</guid>
        
        <category>Valley of the Sun Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>7 Common Habits of Wealthy Individuals</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/BZ0vJMniVo4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone’s life is a different journey. However, if you start forming these habits now, your journey will lead to wealth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.joinrmxprofessionals.com/Join-Today&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Join RE/MAX Professionals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today’s topic is right out of the book &lt;strong&gt;“Wealth Can’t Wait”&lt;/strong&gt; by David Osborn and Paul Morris. I know these gentlemen personally and was very excited to read their book. In it, I found a ton of helpful, useful information on creating wealth. One of the things that stuck out to me the most was the list of seven habits that create wealth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Live by design.&lt;/strong&gt; Think about how you want your life to be and create a plan to get there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Make business decisions based on a solid foundation and solid fundamentals.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Stick with what you know and drill in deep.&lt;/strong&gt; Our wealth should be built through our biggest competency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Earn more by learning more.&lt;/strong&gt; I probably go to more seminars than most Realtors, and I believe they have helped me immensely in my career. There’s always something new you can learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=MY CONSTANT EDUCATION HAS HELPED ME IMMENSELY IN MY CAREER.%20http://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/7-common-habits-of-wealthy-individuals.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“MY CONSTANT EDUCATION HAS HELPED ME IMMENSELY IN MY CAREER.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Break down your big goals into smaller ones and add accountability.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Spend less than you earn and invest the rest.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Let go of the small stuff.&lt;/strong&gt; We need to think and act bigger than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just one of the many helpful passages I picked up by reading “Wealth Can’t Wait.” If you have any questions about the book, would like to discuss it further, or want to discuss your real estate career, give us a call or send us an email today. We look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 13:08:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/7-common-habits-of-wealthy-individuals.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/7-common-habits-of-wealthy-individuals.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate Coaching</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Internet Companies That Are Interrupting the Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/pi9spSu-TYE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Property acquisition companies have been around for a long time in our market, but we are just now starting to see more online-only companies. Today, I’ve listed three of the most popular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.joinrmxprofessionals.com/Join-Today&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Join RE/MAX Professionals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I wanted to talk to you about three companies based solely online that are interrupting our real estate market in the Phoenix metro area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Open Door&lt;/strong&gt; has been around for the last couple of years, and it’s a pretty fascinating company to say the least. I can tell you that they aren’t going away anytime soon. They have an extraordinary management team and are valued at $550 million. They have $110 million in cash equity to buy properties, and have in total $180 million to acquire properties and run this platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m currently representing a buyer who is looking to purchase a home through this site and it’s been an interesting experience. As far as I know, Phoenix was one of their first test markets, and they seem to be successful so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. OfferPad&lt;/strong&gt; is an online application that helps you sell your home quickly and efficiently. It was started by a local Realtor and a gentleman from Blackstone in 2005, and they have $260 million in debt acquisition money and $30 million in equity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to one of the founder’s developed business models, this company is expanding to multiple cities at a faster rate than Open Door. They’ve captured a 2% market share in the Phoenix metro area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Zillow&lt;/strong&gt; is a well-known company that has seen a lot of controversy over their Zestimate feature. They also have an Instant Offer Program that is being tested in Las Vegas and Orlando. It’s set up for big investor pools to directly buy homes from homeowners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=THESE COMPANIES HAVE BEEN AROUND FOR A LONG TIME.%20http://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/3-internet-companies-that-are.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“THESE COMPANIES HAVE BEEN AROUND FOR A LONG TIME.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s been some play to keep the agent involved in these transactions, but I’m sure that at some point those parties will work to find a way around paying a commission to the agent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both Open Door and OfferPad are buying houses and advertising their ease of use. They claim to take the pain out of selling your home, and their popularity speaks for itself. What’s interesting is that &lt;strong&gt;both those apps also charge a commission for acquisitions&lt;/strong&gt; that sits between 6% and 10%, depending on the risk factor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These types of companies have been around for a long time in the direct investor-to-homeowner market. We’ve seen their yellow signs at street lights that say “I’ll buy your house for cash,” or something similar. We’re just now seeing the online model move forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d love to have your opinion about these online real estate companies. Do you think they’re going to “Uber-ize” the market? Will there be less need for agents? Shoot me an email or leave a comment below with your thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about this or any other real estate topics, give me a call. I’d be happy to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 10:41:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/3-internet-companies-that-are.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/3-internet-companies-that-are.html</guid>
        
        <category>Valley of the Sun Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
