<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Wicker Homes Group - your professional Loudoun County Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 17:56:45 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 17:56:45 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>4 Key Factors to Focus on for a Top-Dollar Sale</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/MFt4L_0Mvn0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re selling your home, there a few things you can do to help yourself get top dollar in today’s market here in Virginia. When selling, pay attention to these factors:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preparation before a photo shoot is absolutely essential. Our team provides a consultation with a professional stager to help you get insight on how to get your home ready for the camera. After all, the camera is the only eye we have to please. Many people don’t want to pay for a stager or think they’ll need to buy new furniture, but remember, a stager will help you take advantage of things you already own. They’ll help you decide how to place furniture and what to take out of a room to showcase your home to the fullest.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pricing. Even though it’s a seller’s market, pricing definitely matters, especially if you want multiple offers for your home. Focus your price on where it will sell and it will pull the trigger on a lot of interest in your property.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drive exposure with all the buyers out there. Take advantage of all the tools in our toolkit like our ‘coming soon’ listings. We market these properties to get a little advanced buzz before it even goes active on the market. We’ve been able to sell properties before they even went active on the MLS with this method. We also have a full-time marketing specialist who exposes your house to more than 300 websites. It’s not just about Zillow and Realtor.com; we want to maximize the eyeballs on your house.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make sure you work with a Realtor who can negotiate top dollar for your property. With more than 30 years in the business, I’d be honored to show you what it’s all about and how our team can help you get the most for your home.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or you’d like to learn more about how we can help you get the most for you home, give me a call or send me an email any time. I’d love to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 12:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/virginia-real-estate-4-ways-we-help-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/virginia-real-estate-4-ways-we-help-you.html</guid>
        
        <category>Loudoun County Real Estate Seller tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Multiple Offer Tips for Homebuyers</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8dvuLNDsj_I?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking to buy a home in the current market, you should be prepared to face a multiple offer situation. Today I’ll give you some great tips on how to make sure your offer is the one accepted and you end up in your dream home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting an offer accepted isn’t always about the price of the house. There are other factors that go into winning a multiple offer situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, you need to consider the seller’s time frame. Find out what their ideal time is to move out of the home and craft that into your offer along with the price. The more you play into the seller’s needs, the better off you will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The listing agent is also going to want to know that they are working with a seasoned agent who has a good reputation and a great lender who can get things done on time. Make sure you choose people who are well known and respected to represent you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, please feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I’m always happy to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 11:29:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/virginia-real-estate-multiple-offer-how.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/virginia-real-estate-multiple-offer-how.html</guid>
        
        <category>Loudoun County Real Estate Agent</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Do Buyers Need to Know About Our Current Market? </title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/AzN6QZ_guUE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is happening out there in the marketplace and how does it relate to you as a homebuyer?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, the Fed is committed to raising interest rates in 2017. Rates will go up anywhere from 0.5% to 0.75%. We can no longer keep interest rates at the historic lows that we’ve seen the last couple of years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you know that for every 0.25% increase in interest rates, buyers lose $25,000 of buying power? That’s a lot of money. So, if rates go up by either 0.5% or 0.75% this year, that could affect your buying power by $50,000 to $75,000 in terms of the total mortgage amount.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does that mean for you? Ultimately, it could mean the difference between buying a single-family home and buying a townhouse. Interest rate increases can negatively impact your ability to buy a home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if you are a buyer in today’s market, what are you waiting for? Now is the time to make a move so that you can take advantage of these historically low interest rates. I don’t believe that we will ever see these kinds of rates again in our lifetimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about buying a home or about real estate in general, give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 11:55:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/virginia-real-estate-how-interest-rates.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/virginia-real-estate-how-interest-rates.html</guid>
        
        <category>Loudoun County Home Owner Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Is the 2017 Market Shaping Up for Sellers?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/KTogoX-9B1s?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been experiencing historically low interests rates, but that’s going to change moving forward in 2017. The Federal Reserve has already announced that they will raise interest rates this year by 0.5% to 0.75%. For every quarter of a percent rise in interest rates, that decreases a buyer’s ability to buy a mortgage by $25,000. This means we could see buyers losing purchasing power by $50,000 to $75,000 in the upcoming year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For you as a seller, this means that as the year progresses and interest rates rise, you’ll find buyers who have less ability to buy. For some people, it will make the difference between being able to afford a single-family home versus a townhouse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve had any thoughts of selling, 2017 is the year to do it, and you should put your home on the market as soon as possible. Buyers want to take advantage of these interest rates, and because we’re also experiencing a depletion of inventory, they don’t have much to choose from. That means there’s a significant chance that your home will generate multiple offers, which almost always translates into more money in your pocket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in putting your home on the market or have any other questions, please don’t hesitate to give me a call. My team and I would be happy to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 10:17:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/virginia-real-estate-is-now-time-to.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/virginia-real-estate-is-now-time-to.html</guid>
        
        <category>Loudoun County Real Estate Agent</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We Hope You Have a Great 2017</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/5ozH0okraL0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we begin 2017, we wanted to take a moment to thank you for your business and your support in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you know, we are passionate about serving clients at the highest possible level and helping them buy and sell homes. Wonderful clients and friends, like you, make it all possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wish you a new year filled with great opportunities, new adventures, happiness and love. May 2017 be your best year ever!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From all of us at the Wicker Homes Group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Debbie, Tad, Sara, Jen, Mike, Alexandra, Marie, Dylan, Julie &amp;amp; Allyson&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S. If you haven’t seen our &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wickerhomesgroup.com/&quot;&gt;new website&lt;/a&gt; yet, check it out! And feel free to share it with your friends.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2017 16:25:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/virginia-real-estate-wishing-you-best.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/virginia-real-estate-wishing-you-best.html</guid>
        
        <category>Special Annoucement</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title> Looking Beyond Virginia Real Estate</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZTgyzHxgXMg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you know anyone in need of great real estate service anywhere in the country, we can help. We have great real estate contacts all over the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a matter of fact, we make it a specific mission to travel on business several times a year to network with top agents in the U.S. No matter where you are, there is a very good chance that we personally know someone who serves that area with the same top-level service that we do here in Virginia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just recently, a friend of mine who lives in another state had to move. She didn’t call me ahead of time before she started her housing search in a major metropolitan U.S. area. I checked in with her over the summer to say hello, and she confessed that she was having a miserable real estate experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only that, she was experiencing loan problems that never should have happened. Please make sure you contact us for recommendations before making a move. Some of our lenders service other areas of the country as well, and can help you with loans anywhere. We can put you in touch with very trusted resources to ensure that you have a smooth ride on the lending side as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just wanted to let you know that we can help you connect the dots for terrific real estate service anywhere in the United States. If you have any questions or need to contact an out-of-state agent, give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 12:54:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/virginia-real-estate-we-can-help-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/virginia-real-estate-we-can-help-you.html</guid>
        
        <category>Virginia real estate buyer tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Exceptional Tools Do We Have for Sellers?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/kyR1F6knqpE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does your agent have cool tools to keep you in touch with your home sale every step of the way? We wanted to give you a little information today about one of the tools we have in our toolbox right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are implementing a program that will provide sellers with a weekly report letting them know exactly what we have done to get their home sold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we go under contract, we keep our sellers in the loop every stage of the way from contract negotiations to settlement details. We don’t want to leave anything to chance and we want our clients to be informed every step of the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for us, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. After 29 years in the business, we have a lot of experience that we are excited to share with you. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 13:37:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/virginia-real-estate-our-newest-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/virginia-real-estate-our-newest-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Loudoun County Real Estate Agent</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What a Marketing Specialist Can Do to Sell Your Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/G0kkFEYp9oo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you hire an agent to sell your home, you should be sure that the agent has a full-time marketing specialist devoted only to that agent’s clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are some of the benefits that an exclusive, full-time marketing specialist can provide? As an example, I’d like to talk about our marketing specialist, Mike Hauptman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mike has been our marketing specialist for the past two and a half years, and he is a marketing and internet guru. He manages our Facebook, Tumblr, Pinterest and blog accounts for our listings, and is fantastic at taking the information and the professional photography for all of our sellers and using it to provide top-notch marketing all over the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a matter of fact, our team has actually sold four homes online over the last 18 months, without buyers having even seen them in-person!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mike is also a Zillow virtuoso. This is important to us because Zillow has really become the national MLS, and Mike has managed our account beautifully. He even provides integrated marketing, like ‘coming soon’ teasers for homes that haven’t been listed yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps most importantly, Mike has also been great at placing sellers at the top of national search sites, ensuring premiere placement everywhere exclusively for our clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about what else a great marketing specialist can do get your home maximum exposure, or you have any other real estate-related questions, give me a call or send me an email. I’d be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 14:45:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/virginia-real-estate-what-can-good.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/virginia-real-estate-what-can-good.html</guid>
        
        <category>Loudoun County Real Estate Agent</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Communication Is Key When Selecting an Agent</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/xlw1wHD1PKA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I wanted to talk about two tools that real estate teams can use to communicate with their clients. Be sure that the agent you hire has exceptional communication skills to keep you in the loop!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One tool we use for that kind of communication is a showing service. This service helps the seller approve showings and know what days and times an agent might be showing your home. There’s also an online journal for feedback on your home compared to others in the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should also look for a team that uses an interfacing system that allows you to see what that team is doing at all times when it comes to necessary activities for generating a smooth transaction for you. In our case, my Listing manager, my Transaction manager, and I use an online service to give you a sense of what we do on a daily and weekly basis. You should work with a team that constantly gives you the chance to know what’s going on with your transaction!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since it’s such a big transaction, the importance of great communication with your agent and their team can’t be understated. If you have questions about finding the right agent for you, give us a call or send us an email. We’d love to help you out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 14:35:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/virginia-real-estate-communication-is.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/virginia-real-estate-communication-is.html</guid>
        
        <category>Virgina Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Are Renters Losing Ground in the Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/PlRPP64KQKs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we are going to discuss why renters are continuing to lose ground in today’s real estate market. There are some interesting trends at play here that you should be aware of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rental properties are not going down on a monthly basis, they are only going up in price. Instead of papering the pockets of your landlord with rental money each month while helping them develop their equity. It may be time for you to start thinking about developing some equity of your own, and saving on your income taxes through a mortgage interest rate tax deduction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second point I have for you is that you will either spend more and get less as time goes by, or if you choose to be a homeowner, you can take advantage of that equity and an appreciating market, which is a huge financial benefit over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After 28 years in the business, we are always open and willing to chat about your specific situation. If you have any questions for me, give us a call or send us an email. We would love to hear from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 14:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/why-are-renters-losing-ground-in-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/why-are-renters-losing-ground-in-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Virginia Real Estate Other</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
