<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Canovo Group - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://www.canovogroup.tv/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.canovogroup.tv/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 15:52:32 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 15:52:32 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>STUDY: For Sale by Owners Don't Save Money</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/X8LkMVClFoE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, Collateral Analytics conducted a study that compared homeowners who list For Sale By Owner against those who list with an agent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Michael Sklarz, the CEO of Collateral Analytics, co-authored the study with Dr. Norman Miller—a real estate professor at the University of San Diego.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because the full study was very lengthy, we’ve included it in a PDF that you can find &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/viewerng/viewer?url=https://www.inman.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/CA-RESEARCH-Saving-Real-Estate-Commissions-at-Any-Price-1.pdf&amp;amp;hl=en_US#101922730&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=For Sale By Owner listings are more work and net less money.%20http://www.canovogroup.tv/study-for-sale-by-owners-dont-save-money.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“For Sale By Owner listings are more work and net less money.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there was one main point uncovered by this study that I want to share with you. According to this study, &lt;strong&gt;For Sale By Owner listings sold for 5.5% less on average when compared to listings sold with a real estate agent.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most homeowners who try to list on their own are doing so because they believe it will save money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What many people fail to realize is that listing this way is not only much more work, it also nets less money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.canovogroup.tv/study-for-sale-by-owners-dont-save-money.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.canovogroup.tv/study-for-sale-by-owners-dont-save-money.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Does Our Current Utah Market Look Compared to 2016?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/MrhcK5cw6x0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do the latest statistics say about our Utah market compared to 2016?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, our average days on market is 14 days, which is a slight drop from the 15-day average that was recorded this time last year. It’s still amazing that homes are selling this fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number of homes that have sold is down 3%. What’s surprising, though, is that compared to 2011, the number of home sales is up 60%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The median sale price has increased 8%. &lt;strong&gt;Compared to 2011, it’s increased by—get this—51%!&lt;/strong&gt; This means if you bought a home in mid-2011, you’re in really good shape right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you bought a home in mid-2011, you’re in really good shape right now.%20http://www.canovogroup.tv/how-does-our-current-utah-market-look-compared-to-2016.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you bought a home in mid-2011, you’re in really good shape right now.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our level of inventory—or the number of new listings that have come on the market—is down 1%. Compared to 2011, though, it’s up 14%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, prices continue to go up, and the average days on market is still really low. Not only that, but interest rates are also really steady. &lt;strong&gt;Overall, the market continues to head in the right direction.&lt;/strong&gt; We believe that in the next 12 to 24 months, though, we will see a leveling out. In the meantime, the shortage of available homes should continue to drive prices up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re curious about what your home’s worth or you’re thinking about buying or selling a home right now, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 04:56:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.canovogroup.tv/how-does-our-current-utah-market-look-compared-to-2016.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.canovogroup.tv/how-does-our-current-utah-market-look-compared-to-2016.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why a Discount Brokerage Isn't the Best for Selling Your Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/DzCW6OByqxc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m with my good friend Ali Garbero, who is a listing specialist on our team. She’s been a good friend for a long time, knows the business very well, and is one of the top agents in our market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Awhile back, we did a &lt;a href=&quot;http://canovogroup.tv/the-risks-of-selling-your-home-without-a-professional-agent.html&quot;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; talking about Homie and some of the services they provide, as well as the advantages and disadvantages of working with them. There have been a few recent developments involving Homie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you know, they have been promoting working with their service over using a real estate agent to buy or sell property and, in an ironic twist, they just became a real estate brokerage. As far as I understand, they were under investigation by the Division of Real Estate—who was trying to determine if they were practicing real estate without a license—and now they’re a real estate brokerage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So today, I’ve brought Ali on to talk about the benefits of working with a professional real estate agent or team rather than working with any one of these discount brokerages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“People need people, and when you’re selling a home, it’s more than just the very black and white transaction,” Ali says. Selling a home involves a lot of emotion—you’re negotiating one of your largest if not the largest asset that you have, and it affects your bottom line financially.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having someone to walk you through the process step-by-step, especially if you’ve never sold your home or it’s your second time going through it, will make the entire transaction easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working with a professional real estate agent means you also have access to a network of professional vendors. “Getting a home sell-ready is also going to be a process,” Ali says, is a valuable asset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, it’s an emotional process selling your home. Having a trusted advisor to help you make decisions is a welcome thing. Additionally, she says, “We’re so confident we’re going to sell your home for top dollar and the least amount of time, that we really charge no upfront costs to start working with us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The discount brokerages will charge you upfront, and then they really have no skin in the game.&lt;/strong&gt; If your home sells for top dollar or for rock bottom price doesn’t matter— they’ve already been paid. When you work with a professional agent, you can rest assured that they only get paid when the home sells.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Professional agents only get paid when the home sells.%20http://www.canovogroup.tv/why-a-discount-brokerage-isnt-the-best-for-selling-your-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Professional agents only get paid when the home sells.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here at the Canovo Group, we don’t charge any upfront fees. We have a very flexible commission structure and a cancellation guarantee. &lt;strong&gt;If you’re not happy with our services, you can cancel our agreement with you at any time, for any reason, and without any repercussions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our flexible commission structure works like this: we have a 7% commission structure on the high end, which is usually for homeowners who have a huge remodel or another project that needs to be done on their home, but don’t want to deal with contractors personally. So we’ll take that on with the commission and manage the entire transaction for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another part of our commission structure is the more traditional 6% commission, where we represent the seller exclusively and another agent represents the buyer. In this transaction, we would share 3% of our commission with the buyer’s agent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, if we have a client who is interested in just having us manage the transaction itself—they’ve already found a buyer and just need help getting through all the paperwork—then we will service that client for 1% of the sales price of the property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me or Ali about this topic, or you’re looking to buy or sell a home, please give us a call. We would love to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 06:46:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.canovogroup.tv/why-a-discount-brokerage-isnt-the-best-for-selling-your-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.canovogroup.tv/why-a-discount-brokerage-isnt-the-best-for-selling-your-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What’s the Biggest Challenge Facing Sellers in Our Utah Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Jdzd15wZ3Qw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are some of the challenges sellers currently face in our market?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Dane Hill, our director of operations who has extensive experience in transaction management, one of the biggest challenges is &lt;strong&gt;appraisal issues.&lt;/strong&gt; There is a lot of demand but not a lot of track record of homes being sold for the prices which the current market warrants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, we can encourage a client of ours to list a home at $375,000 and they can get an offer for $395,000, but once the buyer tries to get an appraisal done to satisfy their financing obligations, the appraiser won’t have enough track record of other sales at that price to warrant that $395,000 offer. The lender will only lend at what the home appraises for, so in this situation the buyer has to come up with the extra cash to close the difference or both parties have to renegotiate the sale price so the buyer can close on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each home sale is unique, but &lt;strong&gt;the most common way to settle a low-appraisal situation like this is for the buyer and seller to meet in the middle&lt;/strong&gt; between what the offer price is and where the appraisal came in at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The seller typically loses some concessions during this process. If they’re paying the buyer’s closing costs, then they’ll remove those from the contract and/or drop the home warranty or other repairs they’d previously negotiated. In return, they’ll drop the price so the buyer can get the loan and close on the property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If both parties can’t find some common ground to make the sale work, the buyer will usually cancel their offer and the seller will relist their property for another buyer who perhaps has more cash or is in a better financial situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to give special thanks to Dane for joining me today to discuss this topic. There are other potential solutions to this problem that we didn’t get into, so if you have any questions about this topic or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d be glad to help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The buyer and seller usually meet somewhere in the middle to resolve a low appraisal.%20http://www.canovogroup.tv/whats-the-biggest-challenge-facing-sellers-in-our-utah-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The buyer and seller usually meet somewhere in the middle to resolve a low appraisal.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.canovogroup.tv/whats-the-biggest-challenge-facing-sellers-in-our-utah-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.canovogroup.tv/whats-the-biggest-challenge-facing-sellers-in-our-utah-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Risks of Selling Your Home Without a Professional Agent</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/EX4qt2HXbyk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently had a conversation with a group of my top agents about some of the big challenges they have been facing in helping their buyers find good properties at good prices. &lt;strong&gt;The dialogue shifted to where they were finding the best opportunities to find the lowest priced properties and the easiest deals.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;There were two sources in particular that they mentioned where they were having the most success at getting good deals. One was FSBO homes, which makes sense because the people selling like this are most likely not real estate professionals. The other was homes that were using Homie.com to help sell their home. Homie is a Utah startup that claims to be the solution to all your real estate problems. They say they can save you more than $10,000 on your transaction while giving you all the tools you need to sell your home without an agent.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Why are the homes listed with Homie such easy pickings for our agents? &lt;strong&gt;In many cases, they are finding that sellers are drastically underpricing their homes.&lt;/strong&gt; Homie doesn’t have the tools and technology necessary to help sellers value their property the same way a professional, experienced agent can. These homes don’t get nearly as much exposure either, and oftentimes have to suffer through price reductions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=These homes don’t get nearly as much exposure as they should.%20http://www.canovogroup.tv/the-risks-of-selling-your-home-without-a-professional-agent.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“These homes don’t get nearly as much exposure as they should.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many homes on the market today receive multiple offers and sell over asking price when they are listed with an agent. This doesn’t happen nearly as much with homes listed with Homie. Sometimes, it doesn’t happen at all.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;I don’t want to corner Homie into a box and say that everyone that uses them is sabotaging their transaction, because there’s definitely a place for their services in our market. However, it’s very important that if you are considering selling you are comfortable with pricing and marketing your home so you don’t leave tens of thousands of dollars on the table. It’s one thing to save 3% on commission, it’s another to leave 10% in value on the market.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;If you have any questions about Homie, selling your home on your own, or anything else related to real estate, give me a call or send me an email today. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 04:05:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.canovogroup.tv/the-risks-of-selling-your-home-without-a-professional-agent.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.canovogroup.tv/the-risks-of-selling-your-home-without-a-professional-agent.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Agent Highlight: Meet Brandon Evans</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Jmr3Maj1fiA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I’m excited to introduce you to Brandon Evans, one of our real estate agents. The Agent Highlight series will help you get to know some of the agents that you’re working with.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Brandon worked as a police officer for about five years. “I have a lot of respect for police officers, but it just wasn’t my area of expertise,” says Brandon. “I had some good learning experiences, but it just wasn’t my thing.”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;“I came across the Keller Williams website, started inquiring more about it, and met with someone in the Riverton office,” Brandon adds. “She sent me down here, and I had several positive conversations that let me know that &lt;strong&gt;this is the place where I wanted to work.”&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Brandon continued working graveyard shifts while he went through real estate school. “Then I got set up with David and the rest is history,” Brandon says. “I found the right home.”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;One of the biggest challenges Brandon faced when he dove in as a full-time real estate agent was the financial aspect. “I spent 20 years working hourly jobs and getting a paycheck every two weeks, and this job is sales,” says Brandon. “I got one deal in three months and it wasn’t that big—I only got $1,200 from it—but everything counts. Then, it started clicking, things started rolling, and I’ve had a pretty steady paycheck since then.”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;One of the things I’ve noticed over the years is that agents get into real estate for two reasons: an unlimited income ceiling and flexibility. However, those are also the two reasons why people leave. They think they will immediately make money and that there won’t be any lag between your efforts and your results.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The truth is that you will work for at least 90 days before you see any income,&lt;/strong&gt; and it will take about six months before you start to see consistent income. If you work through that, you can be a successful agent.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;The freedom and flexibility is great, but many agents leave because they are not used to holding themselves accountable. As a result, they don’t keep up with the tasks they need to generate the kind of results that will provide for themselves and their families.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Family is very important to Brandon. “I’ve been married for eight years now, and we have four kids,” says Brandon. “We like to get out and do some motorcycle riding, and I’m a fan of all sports. I love football, and I am a Seahawks fan. Plus, we’re in the process of building our own home, so we’ve got our hands full right now.”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;According to Brandon, the best thing about working in real estate is that you have the potential to provide a lifestyle for your family. “I never thought I would be able to come out and build on property,” says Brandon. “Police officers aren’t paid very much. They aren’t paid enough. We see that all the time and it’s unfortunate, but I wanted to be able to build a home and provide a life for my kids. I don’t want to have to say no when they ask to play this sport or go to dance school. &lt;strong&gt;My family is my driving force to get out there, work hard, and be successful.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=My family is my driving force to get out there, work hard, and be successful.%20http://www.canovogroup.tv/agent-highlight-meet-brandon-evans.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“My family is my driving force to get out there, work hard, and be successful.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brandon is a great person and a great real estate agent. I hope this has given you some insight into who he is. If you have any questions about real estate, please don’t hesitate to reach out to Brandon or anyone else on our real estate team.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;If you are interested in learning more about getting into the real estate business or if you are curious about joining our team, simply &lt;a href=&quot;http://unbouncepages.com/join-canovo/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fill out this form.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; We look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 14:05:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.canovogroup.tv/agent-highlight-meet-brandon-evans.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.canovogroup.tv/agent-highlight-meet-brandon-evans.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Have You Met New Agent Daniel Pust?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/eFfRd8isnpc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today it’s my pleasure to introduce you to one of the new agents on our team, Daniel Pust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daniel is happily married with a young son in 1st grade. He grew up in the Santaquin/Payson area and still lives there because he loves it. He worked in law enforcement for seven years and eventually became a detective before transitioning into real estate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ironically enough, he came into his new profession through a failed transaction, which inspired him to educate himself about our line of work. When he bought his first home in 2004, the market was so hot he hardly remembers even talking to his agent at the time. Three years later, he and his wife had built up quite a bit of equity in that home, and when they found their dream home up in the Santaquin mountains, they decided they wanted to buy it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the two agents who worked on that transaction didn’t know what they were doing and it cost them that home purchase. That experience inspired Daniel to take it upon himself to treat his clients with professionalism, stay on top of what’s going on, and provide them with whatever they need, whether they’re buying a home or selling one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daniel chose Keller Williams because of the education we provide. As a detective, his job was very demanding, and KW offered training sessions that were compatible with his schedule. He also credits his mentor for taking time out of her busy schedule and encouraging him to stay involved. He ended up here at the Canovo Group through knowing someone who also worked here whose life was transformed positively because of the experience. Working with fellow agents Dane Hill and Ali Garbero on a transaction, which he describes as an “amazing experience,” also sealed the deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daniel’s goal is to establish our brand in South Utah County. He works hard every day and has run into quite a few people who want to move but haven’t put much thought in how they’re going to do it. He enjoys being able to provide a resource for them. Daniel is a person who has both his clients’, friends’, and family’s best interests at heart. He’s full of integrity and will do the right thing regardless of how it impacts him and his business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=DANIEL ALWAYS HAS HIS CLIENTS’ BEST INTERESTS AT HEART.%20http://www.canovogroup.tv/utah-real-estate-agent-meet-one-of-our.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“DANIEL ALWAYS HAS HIS CLIENTS’ BEST INTERESTS AT HEART.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re certainly excited to have him on our team. If you’d like to contact him, you can reach him at (801) 850-5656. If you have any other questions, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. We look forward to serving you in the future!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 14:05:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.canovogroup.tv/utah-real-estate-agent-meet-one-of-our.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.canovogroup.tv/utah-real-estate-agent-meet-one-of-our.html</guid>
        
        <category>The Canovo Group</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Has the Utah Real Estate Market Improved over Last Year?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/92i7N5Ko0Wg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first quarter of the year has nearly come and gone, so I wanted to show you some of the most recent numbers from the Utah market and compare them to what we saw in the first quarter of 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The average days on market for homes listed for sale stayed pretty steady. We went from an average of 33 days in 2016 to an average of 34 days in 2017. Homes are still selling really fast. Home sales have gone down from 6,300 at this point last year to just 6,000 this year. However, inventory is down by around 10% too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, let’s talk about home appreciation. It seems to be the one thing everyone asks about. To determine this, we’ll look at the median sale price in our market. At this point in 2016, it was $230,000. There has been a significant jump since, and the median sale price in our market right now is $251,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we have predicted in the past, the market remains strong. As long as rates remain relatively low, we’ll continue to see this trend and we will see anywhere from 4% to 7% appreciation again this year. Some of the top economists in the country have made predictions on the higher end of that spectrum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=AS LONG AS RATES STAY LOW, OUR MARKET WILL CONTINUE ITS RISE.%20http://www.canovogroup.tv/utah-real-estate-agent-comparing-utah.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“AS LONG AS RATES STAY LOW, OUR MARKET WILL CONTINUE ITS RISE.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are thinking about taking advantage of current market conditions by buying or selling a home, give me a call or send me an email. I would love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 15:22:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.canovogroup.tv/utah-real-estate-agent-comparing-utah.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.canovogroup.tv/utah-real-estate-agent-comparing-utah.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Buying Just Got Easier With the NHF Sapphire Program</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8UE2VkAVmFI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, a good friend of mine and my preferred lender, Austin Ingersoll with Academy Mortgage, is joining me to have a chat about a new program that just became available for buyers in our market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s called the NHF Sapphire Program and it’s a true grant program, which means you don’t have to repay the funds that are given to you. You can use the program for a VA, USDA, or an FHA loan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depending on your credit score, you can get all the way up to 4.5% of your loan amount given to you. To put that into perspective, on a $300,000 loan, that’s $13,500 which can be used for your down payment and closing costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as requirements go for qualifying, they mirror the loan you are applying for whether it’s an FHA, VA, or a USDA loan. However, to get the most out of this program, you want to have a credit score of at least 680, but you can go as low as 620.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=This program can help get buyers off the sidelines and into their new homes.%20http://www.canovogroup.tv/utah-real-estate-agent-how-nhf-sapphire.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“This program can help get buyers off the sidelines and into their new homes.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all this program is great for buyers out there who are sitting on the sidelines because they may think they don’t have enough money for a down payment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To see if you qualify for this program or if you have any other real estate questions, give me a call or send me an email. I would be more than happy to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 16:52:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.canovogroup.tv/utah-real-estate-agent-how-nhf-sapphire.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.canovogroup.tv/utah-real-estate-agent-how-nhf-sapphire.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Can You Expect From the 2017 Real Estate Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/QlGkZbezss0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How did our market do in 2016? What can you expect from the 2017 market?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get a sense of how the market did overall last year, I wanted to compare some key statistics from the year before. Here’s what happened between 2015 and 2016:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• The average days on market dropped 45% from 53 days to 29 days.
• The number of homes sold rose by 1.7% from 8,400 to 8,550.
• The median sale price increased by 6.9%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We had a great 2016, and it’s all thanks to you.%20http://www.canovogroup.tv/utah-real-estate-agent-2017-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We had a great 2016, and it’s all thanks to you.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, it was a great year for real estate. What about 2017?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, I believe the average days on market will gradually creep back up. I don’t foresee a significant increase, but I do think homes will stay on the market slightly longer than they did in the recent past. Sales, on the other hand, should remain fairly steady and may even drop slightly due to the predicted rise in interest rates and how that will remove a portion of buyers from the market. Overall, though, I predict that we’ll still see some appreciation of between 4% and 7%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The market is looking strong for 2017, so if you have any real estate needs at all, please don’t hesitate to reach out to me or anyone on my team. We look forward to helping you and we hope you have a great year!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 19:17:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.canovogroup.tv/utah-real-estate-agent-2017-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.canovogroup.tv/utah-real-estate-agent-2017-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
