<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>Our mission at Damon Gettier &amp; Associates is to be your best resource for Roanoke real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Damon Gettier &amp; Associates, your professional Roanoke Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 13:09:58 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 13:09:58 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Unexpected Costs Could Leave You Reeling</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/pdqR-PcFhEk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t go into a transaction unprepared. There is a difference between closing costs and the total cost to close, and it could be thousands of dollars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to Sell Your Home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.damongettier.com/list/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get the Value of Your Central or Southwest Virginia Home&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Looking to Buy a Home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.damongettier.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search All Homes on the MLS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’re going to discuss some of the unexpected costs you may run into when purchasing a home, specifically regarding closing costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Closing costs are different from the cost to close.&lt;/strong&gt; A lot of people think closing costs are everything they’ll need to close on a home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=THE DIFFERENCE BETWEEN SPECIFIC CLOSING COSTS AND THE TOTAL COST TO CLOSE COULD BE THOUSANDS OF DOLLARS.%20localhost:4000/unexpected-costs-could-leave-you-reeling.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“THE DIFFERENCE BETWEEN SPECIFIC CLOSING COSTS AND THE TOTAL COST TO CLOSE COULD BE THOUSANDS OF DOLLARS.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our area, however, closing costs are strictly defined in the contract, so the difference between specific closing costs and the total cost to close could be thousands of dollars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your annual homeowners insurance is not a closing cost—it is a cost to close, as are property taxes. Things like that can run up your cost to close very quickly, so &lt;strong&gt;when you’re getting a quote for closing costs, make sure it’s not just for closing costs, but how much money you will actually need in total to be able to close on the home.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need any information about this or other topics, please feel free to contact us.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 15:54:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/unexpected-costs-could-leave-you-reeling.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/unexpected-costs-could-leave-you-reeling.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Do Speedy Visits Spell Disinterest for Your House?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/xI-hVYc3r48?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a buyer makes a speedy visit to your house, they’re probably not interested in it. Here’s why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to Sell Your Home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.damongettier.com/list/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get the Value of Your Central or Southwest Virginia Home&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Looking to Buy a Home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.damongettier.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search All Homes on the MLS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a prospective buyer zips in and out of your house, they’re probably not a serious buyer—at least not for your house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are a variety of reasons why a buyer would make a speedy visit.&lt;/strong&gt; Maybe when they drove up to your home, they didn’t like the landscaping, the exterior, or just the neighborhood in general. Perhaps when they walked into the house there was a smell or odor they didn’t like. Maybe it just wasn’t the right house for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A SPEEDY VISIT MEANS THAT BUYER PROBABLY ISN’T INTERESTED IN YOUR HOUSE.%20localhost:4000/do-speedy-visits-spell-disinterest-for.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A SPEEDY VISIT MEANS THAT BUYER PROBABLY ISN’T INTERESTED IN YOUR HOUSE.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A serious buyer, on the other hand, will stop and envision themselves in your house. They’ll take the time to imagine where their furniture would go and mentally pick out rooms for their children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s very rare that a buyer zips in and out of your house and then comes back to make an offer on it. &lt;strong&gt;If they make a speedy visit, you pretty much have your answer whether they’re interested in your house or not.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about speedy visits or you’re thinking of buying or selling a house in our Roanoke market, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to work with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 14:04:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/do-speedy-visits-spell-disinterest-for.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/do-speedy-visits-spell-disinterest-for.html</guid>
        
        <category>Tips for Sellers</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Type of Loans Exist for Renovations?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Oiokc64EsdI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are there any loan options for home renovations out there? There are two, but one is better than the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to Sell Your Home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.damongettier.com/list/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get the Value of Your Central or Southwest Virginia Home&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Looking to Buy a Home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.damongettier.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search All Homes on the MLS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two types of loans that you can get to help fund your renovation project: &lt;strong&gt;the FHA loan and conventional loan.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conventional loan is the more difficult of the two to get approved for. You need more money down than the other one, and we don’t use that one very often for renovation projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The FHA 203K loan has two different options, depending on the size of your renovation project. There’s a streamlined loan that is for repairs that are $30,000 or less and a full FHA 203k that is for as much as you need, &lt;strong&gt;as long as the house appraises as repaired.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=ON A FULL FHA LOAN, YOU CAN DO WHATEVER YOU WOULD LIKE TO THE HOME, AS LONG AS IT APPRAISES.%20localhost:4000/what-type-of-loans-exist-for-renovations.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“ON A FULL FHA LOAN, YOU CAN DO WHATEVER YOU WOULD LIKE TO THE HOME, AS LONG AS IT APPRAISES.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you apply for the loan, you need to have two separate contractors come out to the house and write a bid for the repairs that they see that need to be done. &lt;strong&gt;These two bids need to match—not on the dollar amount but on what needs to be done to the home.&lt;/strong&gt; Those bids are then sent to the lender so they can approach for the requested amount.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the streamlined FHA loan, those repairs can only go up to $30,000 and can’t be on anything structural, so no walls can be knocked out or rooms added. On a full FHA loan, you can do whatever you would like to the home—add or take out walls, add a new master bedroom or bathroom—as long as the house appraises with those items included and it’s under the lending limit, which in our area is $271,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about renovation loans, feel free to give me a call. I’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 14:04:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/what-type-of-loans-exist-for-renovations.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/what-type-of-loans-exist-for-renovations.html</guid>
        
        <category>Renovations</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Do Open Houses Really Work?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/pdB5imY5C0o?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few things you need to know about open houses, and whether they are truly worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to Sell Your Home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.damongettier.com/list/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get the Value of Your Central or Southwest Virginia Home&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Looking to Buy a Home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.damongettier.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search All Homes on the MLS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A question my team and I often get is, “What happens when my agent meets a buyer at my open house?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The first thing to know is that nationally, less than 7% of open houses sell.&lt;/strong&gt; In fact, the purpose of an open house is not typically to sell. The point is to acquire buyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To tell the truth, open houses don’t work as well now as they used to for one simple reason: the internet. Most people find a large portion of their information about a given home online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With things like the floor plan, 3D images, and videos available, physically visiting the home often doesn’t come until the point where a buyer is fairly serious about making an offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=DON’T PUT TOO MUCH STOCK IN THE BUYERS WHO SHOW UP TO AN OPEN HOUSE.%20localhost:4000/do-open-houses-really-work.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“DON’T PUT TOO MUCH STOCK IN THE BUYERS WHO SHOW UP TO AN OPEN HOUSE.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But where they lack in successful selling power, open houses are still effective in attracting buyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with those buyers, though, &lt;strong&gt;an open house can also draw out a lot of nosy neighbors.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if your agent does do an open house, don’t put too much stock in the buyers who show up there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 11:39:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/do-open-houses-really-work.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/do-open-houses-really-work.html</guid>
        
        <category>Open House</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Should You Bring an Architect in on a Home Inspection?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/FyrjDG1aAmw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can you bring an architect or engineer with you to a home inspection? When should you do that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to Sell Your Home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.damongettier.com/list/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get the Value of Your Central or Southwest Virginia Home&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Looking to Buy a Home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.damongettier.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search All Homes on the MLS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lately, a lot of homebuyers have asked me, “Can I bring an architect or engineer with me on a home inspection? Should I make the house purchase subject to an architectural review or have an engineer look at it?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you really want to talk to an engineer or architect,&lt;/strong&gt; the only way you can ask is to write it into the contract. Make the offer subject to an architect or engineer reviewing the home plans. Your agent will help you with the exact language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=IF YOU PLAN ON DOING A HUGE REMODEL, IT’S A GOOD IDEA TO BRING IN AN ENGINEER.%20localhost:4000/should-you-bring-architect-in-on-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“IF YOU PLAN ON DOING A HUGE REMODEL, IT’S A GOOD IDEA TO BRING IN AN ENGINEER.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t always need an engineer to look at a home before you buy it. If you are buying a house and you want to blow out the walls and open up the floor plan, then it would be a good idea to have an architect or engineer check the property. They will let you know which walls are load-bearing, and &lt;strong&gt;then you can make an educated buying decision.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The worst thing you can do is buy a house, blow out the wrong wall, and have the house implode on you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about buying a home or the home inspection process, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2017 15:11:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/should-you-bring-architect-in-on-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/should-you-bring-architect-in-on-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Inspections</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>When to Take a Buyer Seriously in This Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/BRuTaYxxjCE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When someone says they are just beginning their home search, they could mean a number of different things. Here’s a better question to ask a buyer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to Sell Your Home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.damongettier.com/list/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get the Value of Your Central or Southwest Virginia Home&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Looking to Buy a Home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.damongettier.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search All Homes on the MLS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does it mean when someone says they are “just starting” their home search? Well, it can mean a lot of things. Your home may actually be the first home they have looked at, or it could be the 50th. There’s a better way to tell if a buyer is serious about buying a home or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If the buyer you talk to is pre-approved for a mortgage and working with a real estate agent, I would take them very seriously.&lt;/strong&gt; They could give you your highest offer and if nothing else, they will give you good feedback about your home so you can improve it for the next buyer who comes through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=SERIOUS BUYERS WORK WITH AN AGENT.%20localhost:4000/when-to-take-buyer-seriously-in-this.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“SERIOUS BUYERS WORK WITH AN AGENT.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the buyer you talk to isn’t working with an agent, doesn’t have a pre-approval, and is just beginning their search, I wouldn’t take them as seriously. It’s likely they wouldn’t be able to make a strong offer anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me about selling your home or anything else related to real estate, give me a call or send me an email. We look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2017 15:33:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/when-to-take-buyer-seriously-in-this.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/when-to-take-buyer-seriously-in-this.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Should You Get an Inspection Before Making Renovations?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8awul5R1SCQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting a home inspection offers many benefits if you’re thinking of buying an as-is property and making renovations to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to Sell Your Home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.damongettier.com/list/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get the Value of Your Central or Southwest Virginia Home&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Looking to Buy a Home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.damongettier.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search All Homes on the MLS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking about buying an as-is property and making some renovations, do you need an inspection?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Absolutely. We always suggest getting a home inspection, especially if you plan on doing a renovation. &lt;strong&gt;It gives you a starting point of things you need to fix.&lt;/strong&gt; Otherwise you might ask your contractor to make certain fixes without even knowing about other fixes that could be huge issues if left unresolved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A HOME INSPECTION GIVES YOU A STARTING POINT FOR YOUR RENOVATIONS.%20localhost:4000/should-you-get-inspection-before-making.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A HOME INSPECTION GIVES YOU A STARTING POINT FOR YOUR RENOVATIONS.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting a home inspection also means you can give it to your contractor and include both your ‘have-to’ fixes and your ‘want-to’ fixes’ so when you get a bid, you get a complete bid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any more questions about renovations, home improvements, contractors, or anything else of that nature, feel free to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 13:08:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/should-you-get-inspection-before-making.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/should-you-get-inspection-before-making.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Should You Be Wary of Solo Buyers?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/gwf050K8L08?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beware of solo buyers. If they don’t have an agent representing them, they probably don’t know what they’re doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to Sell Your Home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.damongettier.com/list/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get the Value of Your Central or Southwest Virginia Home&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Looking to Buy a Home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.damongettier.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search All Homes on the MLS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why should you be hesitant to trust a solo buyer? There are a number of different reasons, but let me start with this. A solo buyer could be anyone. &lt;strong&gt;You don’t know whether they are qualified, whether they want to buy now or later, or whether they can even afford what they’re looking at.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If someone is actually serious about buying a home in this market, they will hire an agent. I can’t ever recall seeing a serious or committed buyer who hasn’t worked with one. It’s like treating yourself instead of letting a doctor do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=SERIOUS BUYERS HIRE AN AGENT.%20localhost:4000/why-should-you-be-wary-of-solo-buyers.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“SERIOUS BUYERS HIRE AN AGENT.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever a buyer who isn’t working with an agent comes to your house, don’t take it too seriously. &lt;strong&gt;They probably aren’t a serious buyer.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me about real estate or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home, give me a call or send me an email today. I would love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 11:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/why-should-you-be-wary-of-solo-buyers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/why-should-you-be-wary-of-solo-buyers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>When Is the Right Time to Renovate Your Home?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/dgRL3cWG-hw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking about renovating, when should you do it? Here’s what we recommend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to Sell Your Home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.damongettier.com/list/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get the Value of Your Central or Southwest Virginia Home&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Looking to Buy a Home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.damongettier.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search All Homes on the MLS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people think they need to renovate their house. How do you know if that’s the right choice or when the right time to do it is?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My suggestion is that if you are going to renovate, &lt;strong&gt;do it when you buy the house.&lt;/strong&gt; Contrary to what you see on TV or read in magazines, you don’t get your $10,000 you spend on the kitchen back. You might get it back five or 10 years from now as the house appreciates, but renovations won’t bring you an instant dollar-for-dollar return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=RENOVATING EARLY MAKES YOUR HOME MORE SELLABLE.%20localhost:4000/when-is-right-time-to-renovate-your-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“RENOVATING EARLY MAKES YOUR HOME MORE SELLABLE.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also recommend renovating when you move in rather than when you move out because you at least get to enjoy your renovations. It also makes the house much more sellable for a Realtor when the time comes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about renovations or homes in general here in the Roanoke market, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I’d be happy to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 14:58:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/when-is-right-time-to-renovate-your-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/when-is-right-time-to-renovate-your-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Need to Give a Spare Room a Purpose?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jH6VLkoRWVk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m going to tell you the best way to give an empty room a purpose when selling your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to Sell Your Home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.damongettier.com/list/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get the Value of Your Central or Southwest Virginia Home&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Looking to Buy a Home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.damongettier.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search All Homes on the MLS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When selling your home, the last thing you want to show is a room that appears to have no use. I have the perfect solution to share with you today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what can you do with a spare room? &lt;strong&gt;Put a bed in it. It’s that simple.&lt;/strong&gt; Putting a bed in a spare room will make it look occupied and lived in. It doesn’t matter what floor the spare room is on or if it has windows. Put a bed in it. That’s the best way to give an empty room a purpose and you’ll have the use of a guest room in the meantime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=PUT A BED IN IT. IT'S THAT SIMPLE%20localhost:4000/need-to-give-spare-room-purpose-put-bed.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“PUT A BED IN IT. IT’S THAT SIMPLE”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Questions about staging? Reach out to me. I can answer any questions you may have about preparing to show your home. If you have any other questions, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 13:06:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/need-to-give-spare-room-purpose-put-bed.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/need-to-give-spare-room-purpose-put-bed.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
