<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Dave Hooke Team LLC - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 16:47:55 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 16:47:55 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>4 Ways to Determine Home Value</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/gW_TsSgb5bU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you determine your home’s value? Today, we’ll be going over four different ways to do so. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Assessed value.&lt;/strong&gt; Simply go into your county’s tax assessment database. If you live in Cumberland County, for example, the website is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.CCPA.net&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.CCPA.net&lt;/a&gt;. In most counties, the database will give you a summary of the tax assessment you’re paying your property taxes on. However, there is typically a margin of error involved in the county-assessed tax value of your home. Thankfully, it is possible to dispute your taxes and get them lowered if you can provide evidence that you are being overcharged. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=While online valuation tools are commonly used to determine value, they do possess a margin of error.%20localhost:4000/4-ways-to-determine-home-value.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“While online valuation tools are commonly used to determine value, they do possess a margin of error.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Online valuation tool.&lt;/strong&gt; This common method of determining home value, which includes tools like Zillow’s Zestimate feature, has a significant margin of error. However, these online tools can be a good place to start if you’re simply looking for an estimate. Along with Zillow, you can also visit the valuation tool on my website. You can do so by visiting &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ViewCentralPAHouses.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.ViewCentralPAHouses.com&lt;/a&gt; and clicking on the “What’s Your Home Worth?” link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Appraisal.&lt;/strong&gt; Unlike the first two methods I listed, this option is not free. However, appraisals will provide you with a much more accurate result. Nevertheless, an appraisal is still only an opinion. If 10 different appraisers were to give you their opinion on your property, you would receive 10 different answers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Comparative market analysis.&lt;/strong&gt; Like an appraisal, a comparative market analysis is an opinion of value. Instead of an appraiser, though, the opinion you receive using this method will come from a Realtor. When an agent performs this typically free service, they will review the interior of your home and then compare your property to similar homes in the surrounding area. It’s based on this information that they will determine your home’s value. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 17:00:42 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/4-ways-to-determine-home-value.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/4-ways-to-determine-home-value.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Does the Housing Shortage Mean to Buyers and Sellers?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/VxyTrPoK4Vw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you live in South Central Pennsylvania, or in a number of different markets across the country, you’re probably experiencing a low-inventory market right now. Right now, we have about 40% less home inventory than we had at this point last year. &lt;strong&gt;That’s a significant shortage and something we haven’t seen in quite some time.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a number of reasons for this shortage. One that comes to mind is the recession’s effect on home building. It now takes builders and developers more time to get permits and construction can be slow to start out. &lt;strong&gt;If demand has eaten up the available inventory already, that could really affect the supply.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=This presents a fantastic opportunity for home sellers.%20localhost:4000/what-does-the-housing-shortage-mean-to-buyers-and-sellers.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“This presents a fantastic opportunity for home sellers.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The shortage means different things to you if you’re a buyer than if you’re a seller. If you’re a seller, this is a fantastic opportunity to get your home on the market. You can get closer to your asking price than ever before and have a quick closing, too. As long as your home isn’t overpriced, that is. Overpriced homes don’t sell in any kind of market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re a buyer on the other hand, there will be some challenges no doubt.&lt;/strong&gt; When you find the right home, however, you should be prepared to act quickly or else someone will get the property before you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking about selling your home in the spring market, I’d be happy to offer you a free, personalized home value estimate for the entire month of February. Just give me a call or send me an email and I’d be glad to help you out. If you have any other questions in the meantime, don’t hesitate to contact me.  I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 09:25:34 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/what-does-the-housing-shortage-mean-to-buyers-and-sellers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/what-does-the-housing-shortage-mean-to-buyers-and-sellers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Things You Can Control to Make Your House Saleable</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/lQlEsVBAAKU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three factors that are within a seller’s control that, if unaddressed, could prevent their home from selling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Whether or not you’ve hired a broker or you’ve hired the right broker.&lt;/strong&gt; If nobody knows that your home is for sale, nobody is going to buy it. The marketing of your property is what the broker should be doing to get your listing in front of as many consumers as possible. The quality of their marketing strategy matters as well, so evaluate exactly what it is your broker is doing to market your property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. The condition of your home.&lt;/strong&gt; Not every house needs to be upgraded. You could have a house that’s well maintained where increasing the condition might make it sell for more money, but you won’t actually get a return on that investment. There are certain things you can do with regards to the condition that will improve the likelihood of your home’s sale, such as cosmetic repairs, staging, and professional cleaning. Ask your agent whether or not the project you want to begin will actually be worth the investment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If your property sits too long beyond the average days on market, studies show that you can end up with a below-market value sale.%20localhost:4000/3-things-you-can-control-to-make-your-house-saleable.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If your property sits too long beyond the average days on market, studies show that you can end up with a below-market value sale.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Price or patience?&lt;/strong&gt; If you have a low motivation and don’t really care whether or not your home will sell, you can always wait long enough for the market to appreciated up to your price. Here’s a warning, however: if your property sits too long beyond the average days on market, studies show that you can end up with a below-market value sale. People will start to look at that property with suspicion—what’s wrong with it?—and it will stagnate. With that in mind, we always counsel people to price their property correctly to begin with, which increases the probability of an at-market or even above-market sale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about these factors or anything else to do with real estate, including a free home value estimate or consultation, feel free to reach out to us. One of our team members will follow up as quickly as possible. Have a great day!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 06:08:58 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/3-things-you-can-control-to-make-your-house-saleable.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/3-things-you-can-control-to-make-your-house-saleable.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Does a Day in the Life of a Real Estate Agent Look Like?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ixh5kKYdgUg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does a typical day in the life of a real estate agent look like?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It really depends on whether the agent is a part-time agent or a full-time agent who is always busy. Today, I’ll give you a snapshot of the life of a full-time agent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing most agents do is wake up and go to the office. Agents can go to the office as early as 7 a.m., or they may get to the office at 9 a.m.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the first things they do when they get there is return any urgent emails or things that have come in from the night before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As soon as they get through those, they will start generating more leads. Like any small business owner, &lt;strong&gt;the most important thing a real estate agent can do is keep their client base growing.&lt;/strong&gt; Otherwise, they’ll run out of business. A typical agent spends about an hour and a half or two hours prospecting for new business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Agents don’t just show homes all day every day.%20localhost:4000/what-does-a-day-in-the-life-of-a-real-estate-agent-look-like.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Agents don’t just show homes all day every day.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prospecting can take 10 or 12 different forms, from calling past clients to check in or asking for referrals all the way down to handwritten notes or marketing activities, like social media posts and website inquiry follow-up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once that’s done, the agent will get back to returning emails, phone calls, and text messages from clients, title companies, lenders, home inspectors, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If they have time, the agent will take a lunch break. It can be hard to take a lunch as a full-time agent because our days tend to be a little chaotic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lunch, the agent will return remaining phone calls and emails before going on appointments. &lt;strong&gt;Appointments and showings are usually reserved for afternoons and evenings.&lt;/strong&gt; If there aren’t any appointments until the evening, we might do some research. We might figure out the market value of a home or do analytical offer research, where we figure out what the house is worth before we help a buyer structure an offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, we go and do what everyone thinks agents do all day: We show homes or go on listing appointments. We don’t have showings or listing appointments every day, but we do have a few throughout the week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, agents are able to get home at a reasonable hour for dinner with the family. However, we often have to meet clients in the evening or on weekends for showings and listing appointments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a full-time agent, you have to be super flexible with your schedule. It’s important to have conversations with your spouse to make sure that you are both on the same page and can handle that flexible schedule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 10:14:53 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/what-does-a-day-in-the-life-of-a-real-estate-agent-look-like.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/what-does-a-day-in-the-life-of-a-real-estate-agent-look-like.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Should You Budget Your Monthly Housing Allowance?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/b-wVppA5MSs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What percentage of your monthly income should you be spending on housing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the thing: When you get pre-approved for a home loan or you talk to a bank about a mortgage, &lt;strong&gt;they’re typically going to figure out the maximum that they can approve you for.&lt;/strong&gt; To calculate that, they’ll take your total monthly debt obligations and add that to your proposed monthly payment, which is principal interest, property taxes, and insurance (PITI).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When they get those two numbers and add them up, they like to see those two numbers be less than about 42% of your gross monthly income. That depends on your credit and a number of other variables, so talk to your mortgage broker to find out exactly what that percentage is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use that 42% as a rule of thumb—&lt;strong&gt;42% of your monthly income can be allocated for housing and debt obligations monthly.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you can stay below 32% of your gross monthly income, you’ll generally have some margin to plan for things that can’t be planned for.%20localhost:4000/how-should-you-budget-your-monthly-housing-allowance.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you can stay below 32% of your gross monthly income, you’ll generally have some margin to plan for things that can’t be planned for.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next question is: Is that helpful for you and your family in the future? &lt;strong&gt;I always suggest that our clients don’t go up to that 42% mark.&lt;/strong&gt; If you do, you’re typically going to have trouble saving and creating an emergency fund if something were to go wrong. It’s easy to get stressed out if you don’t have any margin in your budget at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We typically advise our clients, even though they may be pre-approved up to 42% of their gross monthly income, to &lt;strong&gt;keep their monthly debt obligations and housing allowance below about 32%.&lt;/strong&gt; Way back in the 80s, the number was actually 25%. Its gone up for a number of reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can stay below 32%, you’ll generally have some margin to plan for things that can’t be planned for. Obviously this differs from person to person; some people may expect to get a raise in the near future or pay off a loan. &lt;strong&gt;You should talk to your accountant or financial advisor just to make sure you run a budget before you make a final decision.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about real estate or anything at all, reach out to us by phone or email. We’ll follow up and take great care of you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 09:20:09 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-should-you-budget-your-monthly-housing-allowance.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/how-should-you-budget-your-monthly-housing-allowance.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Steps Can You Take to Protect Yourself Against the Equifax Hack?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/XAeP4nOhY1w?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roughly 143 million Americans were affected by the recent Equifax hack. If you’re like many of these people, you might be concerned enough about your personal data to have already taken steps to limit the damage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what if you’re entering the home buying process or, worse yet, have already signed a contract or applied for a loan?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If this is the case, the fallout could be extensive.&lt;/strong&gt; For example, if you’ve signed a contract to buy a house and have applied for a mortgage and a fraudulent account starts to add a significant amount of debt in your name, that could negatively affect your credit score, delay your settlement, or cancel the loan altogether.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=There are three possible steps you can take to ensure your financial security.%20localhost:4000/what-steps-can-you-take-to-protect-yourself-against-the-equifax-hack.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“There are three possible steps you can take to ensure your financial security.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three possible steps you can take to ensure your financial security if you’re considering buying a home now or you’re in the home buying process:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Check your information.&lt;/strong&gt; Even if you never used Equifax directly, they could still have your personal information. You can visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.equifaxsecurity2017.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;this website&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to see if you’ve been affected. You also have the option to enroll in their TrustedID Premier credit monitoring service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Call your lender right away&lt;/strong&gt; and let them know you may have been affected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Consider doing a “credit freeze.”&lt;/strong&gt; This is the most extreme method of preventing your information from getting stolen, but it’s also the most effective. If you don’t want to lock out all creditors, you can place a 90-day fraud alert on your credit that tells creditors to verify your identity before issuing any credit in your name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this or any other real estate topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 04:28:14 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/what-steps-can-you-take-to-protect-yourself-against-the-equifax-hack.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/what-steps-can-you-take-to-protect-yourself-against-the-equifax-hack.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The 3 Steps to Buying and Selling at the Same Time</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-SDv4KHAGeY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are the three steps to buying and selling a home at the same time?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First, call a real estate agent&lt;/strong&gt; so they can do a market analysis and give your home a value estimate. That will lay the foundation for what kind of equity you have to work with and help you determine if you can afford to buy a home before you sell your current one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Before you do anything, call a real estate agent.%20localhost:4000/the-3-steps-to-buying-and-selling-at-the-same-time.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Before you do anything, call a real estate agent.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second step is to talk to a trusted mortgage advisor to determine what mortgage financing options are out there for you and you can know what your down payment and closing costs expenses will be (or your cash outlay) when you make your purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third, reconsult with that same Realtor and give them the information you received about your down payment and closing cost expenses so you can compare it to the equity you have in your current home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there, you can make a final decision about what to do. &lt;strong&gt;There are two main options you can choose from.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first is to buy a new home before selling your current one. Typically, you’ll use the equity in your home to cover the down payment and closing costs expenses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your next option is to sell your current home before you buy your next one. If you do this, your Realtor might advise you to add a contingency to the listing that makes the sale contingent on you finding suitable housing. This will ensure you’re not left without a place to stay in between transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, this gives you some context on buying and selling at the same time. If you or someone you know has any questions about this or any other real estate topic, don’t hesitate to give me a call or shoot me an email. I’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 06:43:26 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/the-3-steps-to-buying-and-selling-at-the-same-time.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/the-3-steps-to-buying-and-selling-at-the-same-time.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Should I Buy or Rent?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/g8O8yN-0rt0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’d like to help you answer the question, “Is it better to buy or rent a home?” Generally speaking, there are obvious benefits to homeownership. For example, The Fed recently issued their &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/scfindex.htm&quot;&gt;Survey of Consumer Finances,&lt;/a&gt; in which they observed that homeowners on average have a net worth 36 times higher than that of home renters. From that perspective, the sooner you move into homeownership, the better!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, there are other factors to consider. We’d like you to ask yourself three specific questions in determining whether this is the right time for you to buy a home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Is it affordable?&lt;/strong&gt; You can get a sense of affordability by examining your debt and income. If you add up your monthly debts (car and phone payments, credit card and utility bills, etc.) plus your projected house payment (monthly insurance, taxes, principle and interest) and then divide that by your gross income, you will get a percentage. In considering you for home financing, most banks will want that percentage to be below 42%. The lower this percentage, the better, as with a wider margin you will be able to save more of your income for emergencies. Another factor to consider regarding affordability is whether you have enough savings to cover the down payment plus the closing costs. While it’s better to have that money on hand, keep in mind there are creative mortgage programs that offer 0% down and 100% financing. We can help you explore those options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The Fed recently issued their Survey of Consumer Finances, in which they observed that homeowners on average have a net worth 36 times higher than that of home renters.%20localhost:4000/should-i-buy-or-rent.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The Fed recently issued their Survey of Consumer Finances, in which they observed that homeowners on average have a net worth 36 times higher than that of home renters.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. How’s my credit? &lt;/strong&gt;Finding your credit score is easy. There are a lot of credit reporting agencies out there. If you’d like help in choosing a credit agency to work with, contact us and we can introduce you to an agency that will provide a credit check. We can introduce you to a credit lender who will provide a free credit check and help you determine if your credit is healthy enough to make a home purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Is the timing right?&lt;/strong&gt; In considering homeownership, there are personal factors that may make buying a home difficult. For example, if it’s likely you may be moving again in three to five years, it may not be a good time to buy because you probably won’t recoup your closing costs when you resell your new home. But if you’re planning on staying for seven (or more) years, there’s a really good chance that the average annual appreciation is going to overcome your initial closing cost expense and leave you in a good financial position when you resell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about renting versus owning a home, or any other questions at all, please feel free to contact us. We offer free consultations and would love to talk to you at (717) 216-0860 or online at &lt;a href=&quot;javascript:void(location.href='mailto:'+String.fromCharCode(100,97,118,101,64,104,104,97,110,100,101,46,99,111,109))&quot;&gt;dave@hhande.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 05:50:04 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/should-i-buy-or-rent.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/should-i-buy-or-rent.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Has Our Local Market Changed Since 2016?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/W7KKDHXZUCY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s been going on in the South Central Pennsylvania real estate market? Today, let’s take a look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To see where we are, I’d like to compare the current numbers to what we saw last year. It’s actually a great time to be a seller in our area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, &lt;strong&gt;there were about 8,600 properties listed in our area between January and August of this year.&lt;/strong&gt; Last year, that number was 9,200.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That isn’t the only number that has changed. In that same period in 2017, 6,466 properties were sold, compared to 6,399 properties from January through August of last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=It’s a great time to be a seller in our area.%20localhost:4000/how-has-our-local-market-changed-since-2016.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“It’s a great time to be a seller in our area.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This shows us that there’s been an increase in demand but also a decrease of supply. Also, the number of sold homes has increased to 75%, meaning there’s been a 7% increase in sales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next comes my favorite statistic of those I’ve listed so far. &lt;strong&gt;Last year, the average sale price was $191,000, but this year it has increased to $201,000.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the average days on market has declined. Now, the average is 72 days in South Central Pennsylvania.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a final note, the number of expired listings has decreased by 10%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 07:18:40 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-has-our-local-market-changed-since-2016.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/how-has-our-local-market-changed-since-2016.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Reasons Your Home Isn’t Selling</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Jn8SZXf8Jzg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of things can prevent a home from selling, but there are three of them that are within your control:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Marketing.&lt;/strong&gt; This is our specialty. If you don’t have a broker or agent who is marketing your property, it’s likely not going to attract enough demand to sell. Even if you price it extremely low, the home still might not sell if the right buyer doesn’t see it. The higher quality marketing you have, the more reach your listing will have. If your home is out there on a ton of different websites and advertised with professional photography, it will drive demand and encourage more offers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You need all three of these things working together.%20localhost:4000/3-reasons-your-home-isnt-selling.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You need all three of these things working together.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Condition.&lt;/strong&gt; You can have the best marketing in the world but if your home is in poor condition, it’s not going to sell. Decluttering and staging are important tasks to complete. Touching up paint, patching holes, and deep cleaning are also must-dos. The more desirable the condition, the more desirable the home is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Price.&lt;/strong&gt; If you’ve got good marketing and good condition but a ridiculously high price, the home won’t sell. It will just sit on the market. You can reduce the price, or you can wait a few years for a different market and (possibly) more appreciation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These three things affect your home sale as much as anything else. If you have any questions at all, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We would love to hear from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/3-reasons-your-home-isnt-selling.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/3-reasons-your-home-isnt-selling.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
