<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>House to Home Nashville</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from House to Home Nashville - your professional Nashville Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://housetohomenashblog.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://housetohomenashblog.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 15:02:32 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 15:02:32 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>7 Ways to Save Money This Summer</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_tqghBi9QiM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just wanted to stop by quickly today and offer you a few tips to help you save on your energy bills this summer. Sometimes all it takes is a little fix to bring that bill way down. Here are seven things for you to consider:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Plug and fill any holes.&lt;/strong&gt; Seal those window or door gaps with caulk or foam. If you have an external A/C unit, make sure that’s sealed tight as well. Fewer leaks will allow your HVAC system to run a lot more efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Close your shades.&lt;/strong&gt; Sunlight heats your home when it doesn’t need to be, especially while you’re gone during the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Make sure your air filters are cleaned every 30 days.&lt;/strong&gt; This will ensure that your air flow isn’t restricted in any way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Program your thermostat.&lt;/strong&gt; Getting a smart or programmable thermostat can save you a ton. Whenever you aren’t home, you can keep the home at more energy-efficient temps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A smart thermostat is a wise investment.%20http://housetohomenashblog.com/7-ways-to-save-money-this-summer.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A smart thermostat is a wise investment.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Unplug unused appliances.&lt;/strong&gt; They still use energy even if you aren’t technically using them. Turn them off to save a bit of coin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Switch out old light bulbs for new, energy-efficient ones.&lt;/strong&gt; They don’t use as much energy or put off as much heat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Look at the Energy Star ratings of your new appliances before you buy them.&lt;/strong&gt; This can save you a lot of money over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are just a few of our tips for lowering those bills and making the summer a bit more affordable for you. If you have any questions in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://housetohomenashblog.com/7-ways-to-save-money-this-summer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://housetohomenashblog.com/7-ways-to-save-money-this-summer.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Things You Should Know About the Home Flipping Craze</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Myl1I9g81ts?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Home flipping is usually defined as buying a home and then reselling it soon after for a higher price. 10 years ago, it was a mainstay of the real estate boom that led to the financial crash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some years of lower activity, it’s back in full force, thanks in part to popular TV shows such as “Flip or Flop” and “Flipping the Block.” If you’re curious about home flipping, here are three facts you should know right now:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Home flipping is more profitable than ever.&lt;/strong&gt; A recent Waco home that appeared on HGTV’s show “Fixer Upper” was originally bought for $28,000. It was thoroughly renovated and is now being listed for $950,000—over 30 times its original price. In 2016, &lt;strong&gt;the median flipped home sold for $189,900, which is $62,624 over the median purchase price&lt;/strong&gt; of $127,276. That’s a 49.2% return, the most profitable return since 2000—the first year for which such data is available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Home flipping is caused by different factors than 10 years ago.&lt;/strong&gt;Back then, many flipped homes were speculations. In other words, investors would buy a home and then just wait, hoping that the price would go up so they could sell. The current flipping trend appears to be a positive response to current market conditions, such as the overall shortage of homes for sale, a lack of new construction, and a steady rise in home prices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Demand still outstrips supply, for now.%20http://housetohomenashblog.com/3-things-you-should-know-about-the-home-flipping-craze.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Demand still outstrips supply, for now.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Home flipping affects all home buyers and sellers.&lt;/strong&gt; If you’re a buyer, you can clearly benefit from the home-flipping craze. Flipped homes are &lt;strong&gt;available at all price ranges, from entry-level to luxury homes.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a seller, then the boom in home flipping means you might face tougher competition when the time comes to sell your home.The good news is that demand still strongly outstrips supply for now. These conditions won’t last forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or you’re even considering investing in a home you can flip yourself, get in touch with me by giving me a call or sending me a quick email. I’d love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://housetohomenashblog.com/3-things-you-should-know-about-the-home-flipping-craze.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://housetohomenashblog.com/3-things-you-should-know-about-the-home-flipping-craze.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thinking About Investing in an Airbnb Rental?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/tdynL9k0hCM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste present-before-paste&quot;&gt;How do you know if a short-term rental like Airbnb is right for you? This is a hot topic here in the Nashville area right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;First, be aware that &lt;strong&gt;you need a permit to have an Airbnb property.&lt;/strong&gt;Visit the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nashville.gov/Codes-Administration/Construction-and-Permits/Short-Term-Rentals.aspx&quot;&gt;Nashville metro government website’s page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;to learn what you’ll need to apply for one. It will cost you $50 and you’ll want to download the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.qless.com/L&quot;&gt;QLESS app&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, which will allow you to get in line at the office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;You also want to be sure you have insurance for it. Airbnb offers you a $1 million per occurrence once you put your house on their site, which you’ll need to apply for a permit. Be prepared for a lengthy process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;You also only have to apply for an owner-occupied permit right now, meaning you have to live in the home. There’s a vote coming up to get rid of all non-owner-occupied permits by the end of 2019, so you can’t even apply for one at this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You can only seek an owner-occupied property permit.%20http://housetohomenashblog.com/thinking-about-investing-in-an-airbnb-rental.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You can only seek an owner-occupied property permit.”&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep the taxes in mind&lt;/strong&gt;too, as you’ll have to pay hotel occupancy taxes and some others; there are monthly and quarterly taxes to pay. It’s a lot of paperwork, so it can be helpful to hire someone to help you stay on top of it all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;Finally, you need to consider the logistics of how it will actually work with your home. As an owner-occupied short-term rental property will you rent out a room, or leave when you have guests? Will you rent it out for CMA Fest or the Stanley Cup next year when the Predators make it back again? Will you rent it only when you’re on vacation yourself? The best case scenario is having a house with basically a basement apartment and a second entrance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;This kind of rental can really help bring in some extra income to help pay for things like your mortgage or vacations. If you have any questions about this or any other topics in the real estate world here in Nashville, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email soon. I’d be glad to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://housetohomenashblog.com/thinking-about-investing-in-an-airbnb-rental.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://housetohomenashblog.com/thinking-about-investing-in-an-airbnb-rental.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>You’ve Got Multiple Offers on Your Home—Now What?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/932xqBq9KD4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our market is crazy right now, and multiple offer situations are becoming more and more common. Sellers are really in the driver’s seat, so you have a great chance to get the price and terms that you want in this market.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;However, if you receive multiple offers on your home, there are a few things to consider in order to pick the best one:
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Is the highest offer always best?&lt;/strong&gt; Price is obviously an important factor to consider, but you need to look at how much money the buyer is bringing to the table. Is the buyer using 100% financing with no money down? Are they an FHA buyer who can offer 3.5% down? Or is the buyer using a conventional loan with 5% or 20% down? Look at those down payments because that will tell you how much buying power the buyers actually have.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Will your home appraise for the price being offered?&lt;/strong&gt;Look at the market around you to see what similar houses have sold for in the last six months. If you choose an offer that is too high and the appraisal comes in low, then the buyer will likely ask you to reduce the sales price to the appraised value. That’s just another reason why it’s not always best to take the higher offer.
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Higher offers may not appraise.%20http://housetohomenashblog.com/youve-got-multiple-offers-on-your-homenow-what.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Higher offers may not appraise.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. What type of contingencies are in the contract?&lt;/strong&gt; You want to find a clean offer. Are they asking for a 30-day closing or 60-day attraction? Do they need to sell their home in order to purchase yours? If so, make sure their home is already on the market and find out what the average days on market is for their neighborhood. We just had one prospective buyer who offered a high sales price but since their offer was contingent on the sale of their home, our seller went with a lower offer in order to avoid dealing with that.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Once you review all of the offers, you can decide whether you want to go into a multiple offer situation. You can tell all of your prospective buyers to send in their best and final offers by a certain time of day. However, keep in mind that not all buyers will want to be in a bidding war, so you may lose a few offers. If you don’t want to go this route, you can pick one offer and counter. Either way, we can still help you get the highest and best offer for your home.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;If you have any other questions about selling your home in this crazy market, just give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://housetohomenashblog.com/youve-got-multiple-offers-on-your-homenow-what.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://housetohomenashblog.com/youve-got-multiple-offers-on-your-homenow-what.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Win a Nashville Home Bidding War</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/oy5L4H3_VvY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re trying to buy a home here in Nashville, how do you compete against multiple offers on the same home?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The home’s listing agent will usually tell you that there are multiple offers and ask everyone for the best and final offer. You’ll have no idea what the other buyers have offered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The first thing I recommend is to keep your offer clean&lt;/strong&gt; with as few contingencies as possible. For example, don’t ask the seller to cover closing costs if you’re able to cover them. Don’t ask for a home warranty either, as you can always pay for one of your own. You could also refrain from asking the seller to pay title fees, which can cost up to $2,500 depending on the price of the home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously the purchase price is a big deal too, so you want to go in with the strongest price you can.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Secondly, I recommend putting down as much money on your home loan as possible.&lt;/strong&gt; Putting down 5% instead of 3.5% or 20% instead of 10% makes your offer stronger, especially if you’re competing against any cash offers. You can also put down more trust money, which would go toward closing in the end anyway. This shows the seller that you have a lot of buying power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Price is always a big part, so come in with your strongest offer price.%20http://housetohomenashblog.com/how-to-win-a-nashville-home-bidding-war.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Price is always a big part, so come in with your strongest offer price.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You could also use an escalation clause,&lt;/strong&gt; which is becoming so popular in the Nashville market that I’d say about half the offers in multiple offer situations have them. It’s a stipulation in an offer that says you’re willing to pay a certain amount more (say a $500 increment) than the next highest offer up to a certain amount. That way you don’t have to bid all the way up to the absolute highest amount you’re willing to pay right away, but $500 over the next highest bidder, up to a maximum point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, you can write a personal letter to the seller about how much you love the house and how you and your family would use it. You can really pull at their heartstrings with a personal letter.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;If you have any other questions about winning a home in a multiple offer situation, you can always give me a call or send me an email. I’m here to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://housetohomenashblog.com/how-to-win-a-nashville-home-bidding-war.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://housetohomenashblog.com/how-to-win-a-nashville-home-bidding-war.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Can You Trust Zillow’s Zestimates?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/AwgS2WMHhSc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just how accurate are Zillow’s home value estimates, or Zestimates?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You first have to understand where Zillow gets its data for the Zestimates from. Public tax records show things like the number of bedrooms and bathrooms and the square footage. &lt;strong&gt;If you own a home, you can also log into Zillow and manually update information about it.&lt;/strong&gt; You can enter if you have granite countertops or new hardwood floors and they’ll increase your Zestimate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zillow combines this into a general value of your home in your neighborhood. However, people don’t always go on Zillow and enter what they’ve done to their home. If not, Zillow has no way of knowing if you added 500 square feet, for example. They can’t keep up with the exact data. They can’t account for your neighbor’s home, either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Zestimate can be a good general starting point to get an idea of what your home is worth, but it’s not an appraisal or an exact price.&lt;/strong&gt; You don’t want to use it to price your house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The Zestimate can be a good general starting point, but it’s not an appraisal.%20http://housetohomenashblog.com/can-you-trust-zillows-zestimates.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The Zestimate can be a good general starting point, but it’s not an appraisal.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how far off are they really? The median error is 5%, so half of the homes on Zillow will be under 5% off the sales price. The other half are off by more than 5%. It may not seem like much, but for a $350,000 house, the sales price could be off by $17,500.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get a true market value of your home, you need to consult a real estate professional who does it every day. We look at all the specific data, not just general tax records. We consider the age, size, condition, updates, materials, and other similar homes in the area, to name a few details. The smaller details are how we keep from overpricing or underpricing your home.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;If you’d like to know what your home is worth or you’re thinking about buying or selling a home the Nashville market, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I’d be glad to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://housetohomenashblog.com/can-you-trust-zillows-zestimates.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://housetohomenashblog.com/can-you-trust-zillows-zestimates.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What If You Sell Your House Before Buying the Next One?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/lG_E5MfjwvQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What happens if you sell your house before you find your next one? It’s a tough situation that can happen to almost anyone since most people need to sell their current house in order to buy the next one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a seller’s market like we’re currently seeing in Nashville, the problem is that if your offer on a home has a sale contingency and you’re competing against three or four other offers, the others might have an advantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few ways we help buyers avoid this issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first is to go out and start looking at properties so you can be sure there are a few things out there that you like. &lt;strong&gt;That way, you won’t have to hesitate when the time comes to write an offer.&lt;/strong&gt; From there, my next recommendation is to put your house on the market and try to get a contract. The good thing about a seller’s market is that you as the seller have a little bit more control over the contract. That means you can dictate those terms better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You'll have extra leverage as a seller in our market, which helps you get the terms you want.%20http://housetohomenashblog.com/what-if-you-sell-your-house-before-buying-the-next-one.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You’ll have extra leverage as a seller in our market, which helps you get the terms you want.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since you have extra leverage, I recommend that my clients push closing out 45 or 60 days rather than the usual 30. That’ll give you more time and less stress when finding your next home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Another option to bridge this gap would be a short-term rental, like Airbnb or VRBO.&lt;/strong&gt; These are great options if you need to stay somewhere for a month or two while you find your next house, and they’re furnished. This will help you avoid having to move twice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My least favorite option is to ask the buyer of your home for a temporary occupancy agreement. You would close on the house but then stay in it for a specified amount of time. You’ll want to get renter’s insurance for your belongings since your homeowner’s insurance won’t cover your personal items once you close on the home. It can get messy, but it can work if you truly need that extra time to get into your new place.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Each case is different, so don’t hesitate to give me a call if you have any questions. I’m always happy to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://housetohomenashblog.com/what-if-you-sell-your-house-before-buying-the-next-one.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://housetohomenashblog.com/what-if-you-sell-your-house-before-buying-the-next-one.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Can You Expect From the 2017 Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZS2B5up4Bxg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that 2017 is underway, I want to go over a few things you can expect to see in our real estate market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We are still in a strong seller’s market&lt;/strong&gt;, which means we have more demand than supply. We’re seeing rising prices, multiple offer situations, and homes selling the second they hit the market. Sometimes, multiple offers can cause a home to sell for well above asking price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We saw a rise in interest rates around the election and my lender tells me we are right around the 4% to 4.5% range, which is still very low.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what does this mean for buyers and sellers?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=As a buyer, be smart, be quick, and be aggressive.%20http://housetohomenashblog.com/what-can-you-expect-from-the-2017-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“As a buyer, be smart, be quick, and be aggressive.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a buyer, &lt;strong&gt;you’ll want to be knowledgeable about the market.&lt;/strong&gt; You’re going to want to keep a close eye on what’s hitting the market so you can get there quickly to see it and make an offer if you like it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You also have to be very aggressive as a buyer in this market. If there are not multiple offers on a property right away, there probably will be, so you want to make your first offer your best. You don’t want to spend time trying to negotiate as that would give other people time to send an offer in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a seller, &lt;strong&gt;right now is a great time to list your home.&lt;/strong&gt; In fact, there are fewer than 2,000 homes for sale in Davidson County. You can price it in a great range and it will more than likely sell quickly with multiple offers on the table. Our market is projected to be one of the hottest in 2017.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;If you are looking to buy or sell a home, or if you have any other questions, please feel free to reach out to me with a phone call or a quick email. I look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2017 01:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://housetohomenashblog.com/what-can-you-expect-from-the-2017-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://housetohomenashblog.com/what-can-you-expect-from-the-2017-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
