<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Scott Fuller Team - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 11:00:09 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 11:00:09 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Should Real Estate Be Part of Your Retirement Plan?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/s4SO7FosQmE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should you invest in real estate as part of your retirement plan? It’s a good idea, but you need to make sure it’s right for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should real estate be part of your retirement plan?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, including real estate in your retirement plan is a great way to &lt;strong&gt;diversify your portfolio.&lt;/strong&gt; Most financial planners agree that diversification reduces the risk in your retirement plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, investing in real estate may not be right for everyone. It does require you to set a lot of money aside in case something happens in the property. For example, the air conditioning may go out, you could lose a tenant, or you may need to take care of deferred maintenance items. When you invest in real estate, you need to have an emergency fund to take care of those things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Real estate is a big commitment.&lt;/strong&gt; Unlike other kinds of investments, real estate is not necessarily liquid. It can be difficult or expensive to get rid of your real estate investment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=INVESTING IN REAL ESTATE IS A BIG COMMITMENT.%20localhost:4000/should-real-estate-be-part-of-your.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“INVESTING IN REAL ESTATE IS A BIG COMMITMENT.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, before you take the plunge, make sure you do your research. First, find out how much money you need to put down. Also, decide who will manage the property. If it’s a local property, you may be able to manage it on your own. If the property is in another city or state, then you need to find someone you trust to manage the property for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about investing in real estate, just give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 11:18:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/should-real-estate-be-part-of-your.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/should-real-estate-be-part-of-your.html</guid>
        
        <category>East Bay Real Estate Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why You Should Run Comparables Before Submitting an Offer</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Gg5Q74vIwaM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;When you’re looking at buying a home, it’s very important to have your agent run comparables on the home before you decide on making an offer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we’re seeing more and more in this area is listing agents are purposely pricing the home low to get multiple offers. In many situations, we are seeing a $1 million home being priced at $600,000. It creates a craze among buyers who are looking at this $1 million home and thinking they can get it for $600,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea behind this strategy is that the listing agent and the seller want to create a multiple offer situation in which &lt;strong&gt;the potential buyers are trying to outbid each other and end up going over the actual price of the home.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=RUNNING COMPS BEFORE SUBMITTING AN OFFER WILL HELP YOU ANTICIPATE WHAT OTHER OFFERS WILL BE.%20localhost:4000/why-you-should-run-comparables-before.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“RUNNING COMPS BEFORE SUBMITTING AN OFFER WILL HELP YOU ANTICIPATE WHAT OTHER OFFERS WILL BE.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comparables, or “comps,” are properties that have sold that are like-kind in your area in the last 60 to 90 days. If you’re buying a home in the area and you want to make sure you’re putting in your highest and best offer, make sure you have your agent run the comps on that home to know what it will actually sell for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doing this also helps you anticipate what kind of offers you may be competing against&lt;/strong&gt; for the home and helps establish a reasonable market value for the property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To set yourself up to get the best outcome as a buyer or a seller, make sure you’re doing your homework and having your agent working for you to find these things out ahead of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking to buy or sell a home or you have any other real estate questions, please don’t hesitate to give me a call. I’d be happy to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 13:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/why-you-should-run-comparables-before.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/why-you-should-run-comparables-before.html</guid>
        
        <category>East Bay Real Estate Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Handle Multiple Offers on Your Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qfn8z9kMo28?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To maximize the return on your investment, here are five things you need to consider when reviewing your offers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have your home on the market, you have a due date for offers, and you’re starting to receive them. What do you do when you find yourself in a multiple offer situation?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, have your agent confirm with the other agents that their clients have submitted their highest and best offer, and make sure that all the documents are completed with all the information you need to make the best decision. &lt;strong&gt;Remember that the highest price isn’t always going to be the best offer.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=REMEMBER THAT THE HIGHEST PRICE ISN’T ALWAYS GOING TO BE THE BEST OFFER.%20localhost:4000/how-to-handle-multiple-offers-on-your.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“REMEMBER THAT THE HIGHEST PRICE ISN’T ALWAYS GOING TO BE THE BEST OFFER.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To maximize the return on your investment, here are five things you need to consider when reviewing your offers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Timeline.&lt;/strong&gt; What is their time frame to close escrow? Is it too soon for you or will the timing take too long?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contingencies.&lt;/strong&gt; There will be inspection, appraisal, and loan contingencies written into most offers you receive. Review these carefully; they should be reasonable for the buyer but you want to make sure that they will be able to follow through with what they’ve promised in the offer.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Type of financing.&lt;/strong&gt; Cash isn’t always going to be the best option, so be sure to carefully consider the other financing options that buyers include in their offers.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The down payment.&lt;/strong&gt; How much is their deposit and down payment?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rent-back agreement.&lt;/strong&gt; A rent-back agreement may be necessary if you need time to find another house after you make the sale.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As your agent, I take the time to interview each buyer and buyer’s agent to ensure that the offers they present are solid. I want to know what their motivations are in purchasing the home, both emotionally and financially. This will help you make a better decision in a multiple offer situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions regarding this or any other topic, please reach out to me. I would be happy to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 14:35:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-to-handle-multiple-offers-on-your.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/how-to-handle-multiple-offers-on-your.html</guid>
        
        <category>East Bay Real Estate Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Busting One of Real Estate's Biggest Myths</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/yv-g_ELoOZ4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people incorrectly think that price per square foot will be the same for all homes in an area, but it’s just not that simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a major misconception out there in real estate that price per square foot will be the same in all homes in a neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You have to consider adjustments in each unique home for the features, benefits, amenities, lot size, and other things.&lt;/strong&gt; You can see a comparison of this in the video above. The three homes in the example range from 1,407 to 1,954 square feet but the price per square foot goes up as the total square footage goes down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=MANY FACTORS GO INTO PRICE PER SQUARE FOOT OTHER THAN THE AREA.%20localhost:4000/busting-one-of-real-estates-biggest.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“MANY FACTORS GO INTO PRICE PER SQUARE FOOT OTHER THAN THE AREA.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This pretty much holds true in most markets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re building a home and you have a square or rectangular foundation, the price to continue to make it larger actually decreases. Price per square foot simply isn’t always the same across the board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you sell your house and you’re assigning a price, you need to consider all the features and adjustments. If you’d like to know what your home is worth, we’re always happy to come out and give you an assessment and full market evaluation to let you know what your home’s price per square foot is. This will help you make sure you don’t make any mistakes when you price your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or you’re thinking about buying or selling a home here in the East Bay, give me a call or send me an email. I’m here to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 13:49:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/busting-one-of-real-estates-biggest.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/busting-one-of-real-estates-biggest.html</guid>
        
        <category>East Bay Real Estate Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Do Home Prices Differ Along the BART Lines?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/4ZDRTKW2N2U?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Bay Area is a great place to live. However, it can get pretty expensive depending on where you choose to buy a home.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome back to another edition of the East Bay Market Minute, the fastest 60 seconds in real estate. We’ve got an interesting topic for you today. We’re going to take a look at the cost of homes in terms of average price per square foot along the BART lines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**If you’re not from the Bay Area, BART stands for Bay Area Regional Transit and the BART lines are basically the mass transit system around here. **&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The graphic in the video above shows you where the BART lines go and what the average price per square foot is in each of those areas. The lines go up into the Richmond area in the northwest and North Concord in the east, and as far down as Millbrae in the southwest and Fremont in the southeast. As you can see, the price per square foot varies quite a bit. &lt;strong&gt;As you get into the city of San Francisco, the price goes up over $1,000 per square foot!&lt;/strong&gt; At the same time, homes in Oakland are much more affordable at an average of $300 square feet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=IT MAKES SENSE THAT A LOT OF PEOPLE ARE MOVING OUT TO THE EAST BAY.%20localhost:4000/how-do-home-prices-differ-along-bart.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“IT MAKES SENSE THAT A LOT OF PEOPLE ARE MOVING OUT TO THE EAST BAY.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not surprising that we’re starting to see people living in San Francisco move out to the East Bay. Obviously, the price per square foot is advantageous out here, but when you combine that with good schools and good communities, a lot of people from the city are moving here and increasing demand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want a copy of the graphic in the video above for yourself, let me know and I’d be happy to send it over. If you have any other questions for me, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 15:58:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-do-home-prices-differ-along-bart.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/how-do-home-prices-differ-along-bart.html</guid>
        
        <category>East Bay Real Estate Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Important Differences Between Price and Value</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/UlwpgdSctqo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;When you sell your home, you need to understand the difference between its value and its price. Here’s how.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you sell your house here in the East Bay market, it’s important to understand the difference between value and price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Value is merely a function of supply and demand, while pricing is a function of how to market a property based on the value.&lt;/strong&gt; Take a car for example; buyers go to Kelly Blue Book to get the value. They aggregate different sales of comparable cars and consider all the features, age, mileage, and benefits to give you a value range of what the car might be worth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Translating it to real estate is the exact same concept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A HOME'S VALUE IS DETERMINED BY RECENT COMPARABLE SALES.%20localhost:4000/the-important-differences-between-price.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A HOME’S VALUE IS DETERMINED BY RECENT COMPARABLE SALES.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get the value of a property, we consider how it compares to other properties that have recently sold, the current supply and demand, and other similar items. The value is based off other comparable properties that have sold, just like cars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there, you’ll use this knowledge as a marketing strategy to determine what you’ll actually list the home for. To determine the value range you should list it, you want to determine what’s going on in the current market. How much demand is there and how much inventory is there? &lt;strong&gt;This will help you determine whether you should market the home on the lower end of the value range or the higher end.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking of selling your home this year and you’d like to discuss the value of your home and the best way to market it from a pricing standpoint, give me a call or send me an email. I’d be glad to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 11:44:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/the-important-differences-between-price.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/the-important-differences-between-price.html</guid>
        
        <category>East Bay Real Estate Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Will Changes in New Construction Affect Buyers and Sellers?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jLtWTOzJxbI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Changes in new construction could have a pretty significant impact on the real estate market. I’ll go over what to expect today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How are changes in new home construction going to affect the market?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you look at the chart above, you’ll see what builders are expecting in 2017 compared to what they actually faced in 2016. &lt;strong&gt;This year one of their biggest concerns is building material prices.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=IF YOU’RE LOOKING TO BUY NEW CONSTRUCTION, BE PREPARED FOR AN UPTICK IN PRICES.%20localhost:4000/how-will-changes-in-new-construction.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“IF YOU’RE LOOKING TO BUY NEW CONSTRUCTION, BE PREPARED FOR AN UPTICK IN PRICES.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason for this is that the United States has a softwood lumber agreement with Canada and they are at a stalemate in negotiations pertaining to unfair import practices for lumber. Until that gets resolved, &lt;strong&gt;we are likely to see much higher prices&lt;/strong&gt; for lumber and other building materials. In fact, from February 3rd to February 10th, the framing lumber composite price rose from $366 to $391, which is the largest weekly price jump since August of 2003.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When the builders have to take on these costs, they have to pass it on to the consumer.&lt;/strong&gt; So, if you are looking to purchase a new construction home, you’ll want to keep in mind that prices of new construction homes will likely be going up. If you’re a seller, the uptick in new construction prices could bode well for you too, as that might increase the value and demand for your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, please don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 15:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-will-changes-in-new-construction.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/how-will-changes-in-new-construction.html</guid>
        
        <category>East Bay Real Estate Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Steps to a Quick, Lucrative Home Sale</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/TShIdIc9xYk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doing these three things will get your home sold quicker and for the best price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking to sell your home in 2017, there are three things you can do to sell for the most money in the shortest amount of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, &lt;strong&gt;price it right from the beginning.&lt;/strong&gt; Home values are in a certain range and if you go just a little bit below the median of that range, it will be the price that brings the most interest in the shortest amount of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=DOING THESE THREE THINGS WILL GET YOUR HOME SOLD QUICKER AND FOR THE BEST PRICE.%20localhost:4000/3-steps-to-quick-lucrative-home-sale.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“DOING THESE THREE THINGS WILL GET YOUR HOME SOLD QUICKER AND FOR THE BEST PRICE.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you price your home at the top of the value range, other homes might sell before yours if they offer similar benefits but are priced more competitively. You don’t want to end up sitting on the market for two or three weeks. If you do, you’ll have to keep dropping your price and buyers will sense the desperation to get your home sold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, &lt;strong&gt;have all of your repairs completed before you put it on the market.&lt;/strong&gt; It would also be a good idea to get a pest report done. That way you show the buyer a finished product and let them know you have done your due diligence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, &lt;strong&gt;make sure you declutter.&lt;/strong&gt; Some houses need to be staged and some don’t, but every home needs to be decluttered and depersonalized before going on the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions, please feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I’m happy to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 14:47:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/3-steps-to-quick-lucrative-home-sale.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/3-steps-to-quick-lucrative-home-sale.html</guid>
        
        <category>East Bay Real Estate Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Shouldnt You Work With an Agent Who Practices Dual Agency?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/6Hk421p3D1U?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re selling your house, you shouldn’t ask any agent that practices dual agency to represent you. Here’s why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is dual agency?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dual agency is when an agent represents both the buyer and the seller in the same home sale. Why should you avoid this situation when selling your house?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me put it this way: &lt;strong&gt;how can an agent equally represent both sides when the seller is trying to sell the house for the highest price they can and the buyer is trying to buy it for the lowest price they can?&lt;/strong&gt; If I’m representing a seller and I get a call from a buyer who’s interested in that seller’s house and also wants me to represent them in purchasing that house, that’s a problem because the seller has already hired me to look out for their best interests. They have my fiduciary duty to sell their home and get the most money in the shortest amount of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=DON’T WORK WITH AN AGENT WHO PRACTICES DUAL AGENCY.%20localhost:4000/why-shouldnt-you-work-with-agent-who.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“DON’T WORK WITH AN AGENT WHO PRACTICES DUAL AGENCY.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking about selling your home this year, you should ask every agent that you interview if they practice dual agency. You need to find out whether your agent will also represent a buyer that comes directly too them, or just you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My suggestion is to only work with an agent who doesn’t practice dual agency. &lt;strong&gt;Not only can a dual agency situation cost you money when you’re trying to negotiate the price up front, but it can also cost you money when negotiating repairs and other terms during the transaction process.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this topic or are thinking of buying or selling in the East Bay market, feel free to give me a call or shoot me an email. I’d be happy to speak with you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 13:07:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/why-shouldnt-you-work-with-agent-who.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/why-shouldnt-you-work-with-agent-who.html</guid>
        
        <category>East Bay Real Estate Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>10 Simple Ways to Add to Your Home's Value</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;According to recent data from Redfin, homes sold during the winter are 9% more likely to sell than homes listed during other times of the year. In addition to this, &lt;strong&gt;homes sold in the winter sell for 1.2% more money.&lt;/strong&gt; With the 2017 winter home selling season upon us, we are getting a lot of questions as to the best ways to prepare a home in order to get the MOST money when selling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trulia came out with a great article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#10 simple ways to add $30 - $50K to your home’s value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the top ten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goal: Spend less than $10,000 and attract buyers who are willing to pay $30,000-$50,000 more for “move-in ready.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have A Professional Come Out: Free&lt;/strong&gt;
An agent will help guide you through the right steps to make your home sell for the most amount of money. Make sure your agent doesn’t want to “expedite” your home sale before you have a chance to make the simple fixes to increase the value of your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deep Clean: $300&lt;/strong&gt;
Make sure your home is spotless. This includes places most overlooked like the oven, grease on the range hood, and baseboards. Consider hiring a cleaning company for a few hundred dollars to come out and make your house shine. While a super clean home does not literally boost your home’s value as much as other things, it will make a great first impression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;De-Clutter: $150&lt;/strong&gt;
Clutter and clunky furniture make a home feel small. Less is more when it comes to selling your home, so consider making room in your garage or rent a storage unit and get rid of any extraneous furniture items.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paint: $1500&lt;/strong&gt;
Only paint the walls that need it, and clean the others if needed. If you have baseboards, definitely paint those. Go through your home and decide which rooms will need paint and which should just be cleaned or left alone. Don’t get too carried away because many new homeowners will decide to paint anyways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fixtures, doorknobs, light switches, outlets, and other small repairs: $500&lt;/strong&gt;
Make sure that every little fixture, door knob, light switch, and outlet are all intact, clean, and in working order. On their own, these small repairs may not seem important, but those small things will add up to create the impression that your home has been neglected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=HOMES SOLD IN THE WINTER SELL FOR 1.2% MORE MONEY.%20localhost:4000/10-simple-ways-to-add-to-your-homes.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“HOMES SOLD IN THE WINTER SELL FOR 1.2% MORE MONEY.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Basic Gardening: $500&lt;/strong&gt;
For a few hundred dollars, you can hire a gardening service to come out and remove weeds, clean up planters, plant some flowers, throw down some lawn seed + fertilizer, and make the outside area look great and presentable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ditch The Popcorn Ceilings: Avg. $2500&lt;/strong&gt;
Popcorn ceilings are very outdated and may contain asbestos. Buyers already know this and can easily be turned away because of potential hazards. It’s recommended that you hire a company to do this because it can get very messy and possibly dangerous. Most companies charge $1-$3 per square foot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Small Bathroom Upgrades: Avg. $2000&lt;/strong&gt;
One bathroom can be upgraded for around $750 and can add much more value to your home. Make sure to go simple here because you’re just looking to upgrade your bathroom to look new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clean Carpets: $200&lt;/strong&gt;
Some real estate agents advise against replacing your carpets because those are the first thing new homeowners change. At the same time, old dirty carpets are a turn off. Consider hiring a carpet cleaning company for a couple hundred dollars to come out and clean the carpets. Or even better, rent a rug cleaner machine from your local supermarket for under $100 and do it yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inspections: $750&lt;/strong&gt;
Not every home improvement is cosmetic. Deteriorating roofs, termite infestation or outdated electrical systems — you can’t fix it if you don’t know it’s broken. Hire an inspector to check out the areas of your home that you don’t normally see. They may discover hidden problems. Small problems (such as a hidden water leak) can become big, expensive problems quickly; the longer you put off repairs, the more expensive those repairs will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pricing mentioned in this article has been adjusted to reflect typical East Bay market costs for standard home preparation services.&lt;/em&gt; To read the full article please &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.trulanding.com/home/simple-ways-to-increase-the-value-of-your-home/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;click here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, if you ever have any questions, you can give me a call at (925) 855-3432.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2016 09:21:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/10-simple-ways-to-add-to-your-homes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/10-simple-ways-to-add-to-your-homes.html</guid>
        
        <category>East Bay Real Estate Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
