<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Limbird Real Estate Group - your professional Northwest Arkansas Real Estate Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://limbirdteamblog.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://limbirdteamblog.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 11:00:36 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 11:00:36 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Northwest Arkansas Market Update</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-76mqYTPvJ8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot going on in the Northwest Arkansas market this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The market is booming and there are a lot of great things happening.&lt;/strong&gt; According to the Northwest Arkansas Council, there are 31 people moving in every day and research from the University of Arkansas shows that the average age of residents here is 33.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for market activity, I wanted to look at things in terms of Benton County and Washington County.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are currently about 1,500 homes for sale in Benton County and roughly a quarter are new builds. In Washington County, there are 738 homes for sale with 149 being new builds. Through the first five months of the year in Benton County, 2,375 homes have sold compared to 2,279 during the same period last year. In Washington County, 1,406 homes sold in the first five months of 2017. That number last year was 1,341.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Prices are definitely up.%20http://limbirdteamblog.com/northwest-arkansas-market-update.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Prices are definitely up.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, prices are definitely up. In Benton County, price per square foot rose about $8. The number of days it takes to sell a home on average has held steady in Benton County, but in Washington County, homes are selling in an average of about 30 days faster than last year. Prices in Washington County are also up by about $7 per square foot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New construction home sales are up by about 80 this year in Benton County and up by about 60 in Washington County. Prices are also up about $8 a square foot for such homes. If you thought about buying a home last year but waited until this year, it will cost you about $20,000 more on average.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interest rates are still low for homes, making it still a great time to buy. March marked the 31st consecutive quarter of incline in the economy, tying for third-longest in the history of the U.S. economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in buying a home or you have any other questions, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We’re here to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 07:57:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://limbirdteamblog.com/northwest-arkansas-market-update.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://limbirdteamblog.com/northwest-arkansas-market-update.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Limbird Real Estate Group Is Investing in the Future</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/yJ22zgyxyeQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the Limbird Real Estate Group, we are proud to always be on the cutting edge of technology. This is why we are thrilled to announce our adoption of 3-D home tours. Buying a home can be a taxing process, especially for out-of-town buyers. Typically, Realtors use still photos and some use video to market their homes to buyers. This is only a 2-D experience, however.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are investing in a three-dimensional experience for our buyers and sellers. Open houses are usually only held for a few hours each week. With our easy-to-navigate 3-D tours, however, your home can be open 24/7, 365 days a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=With these tours, you have a 360-degree view of each room.%20http://limbirdteamblog.com/the-limbird-real-estate-group-is.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“With these tours, you have a 360-degree view of each room.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We take you beyond the real world with a complete digital scan that gives buyers an unprecedented insight into your home like never before. With the use of lasers and high-tech cameras, potential buyers can select any room to view and instantly place themselves inside that space with the ability to maneuver inside the room and view it in 360 degrees. Buyers will be able to virtually walk through your home, get a feel for its layout, and notice details and features that they typically wouldn’t with still images.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you combine the fact that the majority of homebuyers start their search online with the power of photos being shared on social media, this is an amazing tool for a seller like yourself to take advantage of. Our team currently advertises on more than 100 websites and we’re ready to put our state-of-the-art technology to work for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for us, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We would love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 13:50:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://limbirdteamblog.com/the-limbird-real-estate-group-is.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://limbirdteamblog.com/the-limbird-real-estate-group-is.html</guid>
        
        <category>Best Northwest Arkansas Real Estate Team</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Now Is a Good Time to Sell in Our Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Xg4EUwyH_sY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time of year, we get a lot of people telling us they are going to wait to sell until spring or summer because there will be more buyers. While it’s true that there are a larger number of buyers in spring and summer, there is also a lot more inventory for buyers to choose from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our market, we have a large relocation of clients that move in and out of the area each year. These people usually make their moves toward the end or beginning of the year. We also have a situation where sellers who took their homes off the market during the holidays are mostly waiting until spring to list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You have a window of opportunity right now.%20http://limbirdteamblog.com/why-now-is-good-time-to-sell-in-our.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You have a window of opportunity right now.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This gives you a window of opportunity now in which there isn’t a lot of inventory, but you also have a ton of buyers looking and a time of year where people are getting their tax refunds or bonus checks. When buyers have extra money burning a hole in their pocket, they are ready to spend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There aren’t a whole lot of homes for them to look at right now. The chances of selling your home more quickly and for a higher price are very good right now. It all depends on your situation, but things look good overall. Interest rates are also expected to go up three separate times this next year. That will further affect the number of buyers that look at your house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for us or want to sell your home, give us a call or send us an email. We would love to help you out and give you the straight answer. We look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 12:01:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://limbirdteamblog.com/why-now-is-good-time-to-sell-in-our.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://limbirdteamblog.com/why-now-is-good-time-to-sell-in-our.html</guid>
        
        <category>Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Come to Our 3rd Annual Valentine's Day Celebration!</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wr8eS2OYuCg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s that time of year—the time for our Valentine Love Fest for our clients (past and present), our friends, and our family! This year marks the third annual appreciation party for members of our loyalty club.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you might remember, we’ll give you a big box of chocolates that you can keep for yourself or give to your sweetheart as an early Valentine’s Day gift.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We'll have chocolate, cocktails, and champagne%20http://limbirdteamblog.com/come-to-our-3rd-annual-valentines-day_25.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We’ll have chocolate, cocktails, and champagne”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The party is coming up on Tuesday, February 7th from 4 p.m. to 7 p.m. Other than your big box of chocolates, we’ll also have drinks, champagne, and chocolate-covered strawberries. It’ll be a great time to come by after work and unwind with some chocolate and champagne.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All we ask is  that you fill out this form so we can be sure we have enough candy for everyone!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, we will have two locations to make it even more convenient for you to pick up your gift! You can either come to our Benton County pickup location at 5247 W. Metro Park Crossing, Rogers, AR 72758 or our Washington County pick up location at 3291 S. Thompson Street Suite D104 in Springdale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We look forward to seeing you there!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 13:16:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://limbirdteamblog.com/come-to-our-3rd-annual-valentines-day_25.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://limbirdteamblog.com/come-to-our-3rd-annual-valentines-day_25.html</guid>
        
        <category>Valentine's day</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Not One, but Two Fun Video Updates</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/4fFPfbVz3MY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I have not one, but two fun videos that I wanted to share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you may remember back in November, we gave away pies to our loyalty club members for Thanksgiving and gave you a chance to vote on which of our team members deserved a pie in the face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Check out the fun things that've happened with our team.%20http://limbirdteamblog.com/not-1-but-2-fun-video-updates.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Check out the fun things that’ve happened with our team.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, yours truly was lucky enough to be one of them. You can see me get pied in the face here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also gave away a trip to one lucky client, and you can see their video here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a lot of fun in the last few weeks and we’re really looking forward to a great 2017. If there’s anything you have questions about in real estate or you’re thinking about buying or selling a home, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We’d love to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2016 13:08:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://limbirdteamblog.com/not-1-but-2-fun-video-updates.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://limbirdteamblog.com/not-1-but-2-fun-video-updates.html</guid>
        
        <category>Northwest Arkansas Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Outsell Your Neighbors With These 4 Tips</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/J8i_qizmllY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re selling your home, there are four things that you can do to sell your home faster than anybody else in your neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Update the landscaping. Curb appeal is huge. If buyers don’t like what they see on the outside, they may never come in and see the inside. Trim your shrubs, pick your weeds, and put a layer of fresh mulch down to make your landscape look new again.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Paint. Nothing will make a home feel brand new like new paint on the walls. In the grand scheme of things, paint is relatively inexpensive but can pay huge dividends when it’s time for buyers to make an offer.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Move out of the house. Make it appear as though you’ve moved out. If you’re still living in your home, get rid of as much as you can. Like we always say, “Clutter eats equity.” Clutter can make buyers think that the house is smaller than it is or has less storage than it does. The more you can get rid of, the easier it will be to get the home ready for showings, and homes that show well tend to get more offers.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Price your home correctly the first time. We analyze price changes and days on market for homes that have sold recently, and most of the time we’ve found that the homes that were priced right the first time sold quicker and for more money than the homes that reduced their price. Even if you’re not in a hurry to sell your home, a home that is priced correctly will net you more money on the bottom line in the end, so it’s important to get out onto the market with the right price the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Homes that sell faster sell for more money.%20http://limbirdteamblog.com/outsell-your-neighbors-with-these-4-tips.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Homes that sell faster sell for more money.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow these four tips, and you’ll sell your home faster than anybody else on your block. If you have any other questions about buying or selling a home in the Northwest Arkansas market, give me a call or send me an email. I’d be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 12:29:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://limbirdteamblog.com/outsell-your-neighbors-with-these-4-tips.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://limbirdteamblog.com/outsell-your-neighbors-with-these-4-tips.html</guid>
        
        <category>Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Use Technology to Draw Buyers to Your Home </title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/3b8PAvQfQoY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can technology attract high-end buyers to your home? HGTV actually said that 46% of consumers think technology is very important for their current or future residencies. In fact, Digital Interior said that 94% of buyers surveyed would sacrifice 1,000 square feet of living space for new technology in their new home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, technology is important to home buyers. One of the latest trends in home technology that will draw high-end buyers is the smart thermostat. Smart thermostats allow you to control the temperature in your home from your smartphone. You can change the temperature from your couch or your car while going to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Home surveillance technology is also very important. Cameras can be mounted discreetly on the walls and ceilings. Buyers will appreciate that they can check in on their home even if they are at work or on vacation. Not only that, you will feel more secure knowing that you can see what is going on in your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=About 94% of buyers would sacrifice 1,000 sq ft of living space for new technology.%20http://limbirdteamblog.com/use-technology-to-draw-buyers-to-your.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“About 94% of buyers would sacrifice 1,000 sq ft of living space for new technology.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should also pay attention to technological developments in the kitchen. There are touchless water faucets that come on with just a hand motion, and there are also smart refrigerators. Smart refrigerators will alert you when you’re running low on groceries so that you know when it’s time to head to the store. You can also get a Bluetooth thermostat so that your meals will be perfectly cooked all the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, luxury entertainment is always a big draw for home buyers. Flat screen TVs and home theaters are fantastic. Not only that, you can control your entertainment system, your security system, and your thermostat from one remote control by Savant!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about the latest trends in home technology or want to know more ways to prepare your home for the market, give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 14:17:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://limbirdteamblog.com/use-technology-to-draw-buyers-to-your.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://limbirdteamblog.com/use-technology-to-draw-buyers-to-your.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tips to Win in a Seller's Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/VRL3fRscuVQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you may have heard, the real estate market is incredibly busy. A lot of our buyers are running into multiple offer situations. How do you win?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, make sure you are pre-approved and that you have a letter in hand. If a seller receives two offers and only one has a pre-approval letter, they will obviously go with the pre-approved buyer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say you have two offers and both have been pre-approved. One buyer got pre-approved through a local bank, and the other worked with an out-of-town bank. Any Realtor will tell you that working with a local lender is incredibly important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our team works with several lenders on a daily basis, and we definitely trust them. It is much easier to get things done when you work with someone local. Local lenders close loans faster, and there aren’t as many headaches during the closing process. Why complicate the biggest purchase you will ever make by working with someone from out of town?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Make sure you are pre-approved%20http://limbirdteamblog.com/tips-to-win-in-sellers-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Make sure you are pre-approved”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another tip for buyers in multiple offer situations is to be flexible. Sellers don’t necessarily go for the offer with the best price. Other factors often come into play. Some sellers might not want to move until school is out, so if you can be flexible with your closing date, you will have the advantage over other buyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main thing you can do to win in a multiple offer situation is work with a professional real estate agent. There are a lot of new agents in the market and selling real estate can be a complicated process. Last year, our team sold over 500 homes, so we have lots of experience negotiating the right deal and helping buyers get the keys to their brand new home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 14:29:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://limbirdteamblog.com/tips-to-win-in-sellers-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://limbirdteamblog.com/tips-to-win-in-sellers-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Can We Guarantee that Your Home Sells?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/lvqTG5F_9p8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that people always wonder about our guaranteed sale program and how it works. It’s a big promise to make, and I’d like to explain how we manage to keep this promise for our clients who qualify for this program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most sellers are often uneasy about the selling price of their home and if a buyer will be found for it. However, with our Guaranteed Sale Program, we agree on a price and a time frame immediately. In the last two years, we have only had to buy one property from our clients using this program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have used this program with many of our clients, and it’s worked very well for almost all of them. As you can see, these two people that we helped in the past also thought that the Guaranteed Sold Program was too good to be true. However, their home did sell and they walked away very happy and willing to recommend us to their friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind that the Guaranteed Sale Program is only available in Benton and Washington Counties, but that covers a majority of Northwest Arkansas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re selling your home, you owe it to yourself to come down and meet us. We would love the opportunity to help you buy or sell a home!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 16:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://limbirdteamblog.com/how-can-we-guarantee-that-your-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://limbirdteamblog.com/how-can-we-guarantee-that-your-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Northwest Arkansas Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Important Questions to Ask Before Buying a Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jCRM4V-zIgI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choosing to buy a home is an important decision, and one you shouldn’t make without doing proper research. Today, we’ve got some tips for you on the types of questions you should be asking the homeowner or your Realtor about a potential home purchase. Proper preparation is the key to getting what you want in a home. Here’s where you should narrow your focus:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Neighborhood&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The location of your home is very important. How close are you to different stores, gas stations, or other amenities? Would you rather be in a bustling area or a quieter part of town? Is there any new construction going on in your neighborhood? If so, how will this affect your home’s value? These are all different questions you should be asking when determining where you want to live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schools&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another equally important topic to learn about is your potential home’s proximity to different schools. Find out what district your home is in. Even if you don’t have any kids, being in a good school district increases your home’s value when it comes time to sell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Little things&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a ton of different, little things you need to check up on when researching potential homes. Ask about the little things like electric and utility bills, the age of the roof, hot water heater, and other appliances. If you have a lot of maintenance to do on a home, that will impact the kind of offer you make on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are just a few of the questions you should be asking when researching homes. If you have any questions for us, or want to learn some more of the questions you should be asking when looking for a home, give us a call or send us an email. We would love to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2016 10:53:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://limbirdteamblog.com/arkansas-real-estate-agent-questions.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://limbirdteamblog.com/arkansas-real-estate-agent-questions.html</guid>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
