<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Don Williams Realty Group</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Don Williams - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 11:12:35 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 11:12:35 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are You Ready to Enter the Spring Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/JJWw6-0s_rI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can you make your home ready to list this spring?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Winter is obviously a very hard time to list your home. A lot of things can be left unkempt. However, if you’re ready to list your home this spring, here are some pointers you might want to consider in preparation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Curb appeal.&lt;/strong&gt; Your yard is the first impression buyers will have when they pull up to your home. Rake up all those dead leaves and grass and spruce up your yard. Utilize the weather becoming warmer to plant some flowers. You might also consider power washing your sidewalks to clean up the grime and salt that the melting snow left behind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The very best thing you can do to list your home this spring is find the right Realtor.%20http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com/are-you-ready-to-enter-the-spring-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The very best thing you can do to list your home this spring is find the right Realtor.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Spring cleaning.&lt;/strong&gt; Clean up both the interior and exterior of your home. For the inside, declutter your space and organize the items that you leave in place. For the outside, clean the mildew from your roofs and wash your windows. We have a list of recommended local vendors that can help you with these spring cleaning projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, the very best thing you can do to list your home this spring is find the right Realtor. That’s where we step in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have questions or need assistance, feel free to give us a call today. We’d be happy to help you get your home sold.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 12:26:39 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com/are-you-ready-to-enter-the-spring-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com/are-you-ready-to-enter-the-spring-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Things a VA Loan Can Do for You</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/PM-LAJ61QA4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a veteran of the armed forces, you’re active duty personnel, you’re a part of the National Guard, or you’re military reserve, you can apply for a VA loan to buy a home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are five great advantages that come with this particular loan:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) You don’t need a down payment. Most people consider a down payment a huge hurdle to homeownership because it sometimes requires you to put up to 20% of your overall loan amount down. With a VA loan, you get to bypass that hurdle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) It has more lenient requirements. For example, most people need a credit score of around 650 or 700. With a VA loan, you only need to have a credit score of 620 or above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=There are several great reasons to apply for a VA loan if you qualify.%20http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com/5-things-a-va-loan-can-do-for-you.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“There are several great reasons to apply for a VA loan if you qualify.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) You don’t need mortgage insurance. The only thing they require is an upfront funding fee, but that can be rolled into your payments, and it’s tax deductible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) It limits your closing costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) It provides appraisal assistance. They can notify your agent and give you 48 hours to provide any additional information you might need to boost the appraisal value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, &lt;strong&gt;the VA loan is our society’s way of saying thank you to all the men and women who have served our country.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any more questions about how a VA loan can benefit you or you have any other real estate needs, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d be glad to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 06:43:04 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com/5-things-a-va-loan-can-do-for-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com/5-things-a-va-loan-can-do-for-you.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Reasons to Have a Pre-Listing Home Inspection</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/dDyvLFrxcfk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although you are not required to get a pre-listing inspection on your home before it hits the market, there are a few advantages of doing so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First of all, a pre-listing inspection will uncover any issues with your house before it goes up for sale.&lt;/strong&gt; This saves you a lot of time because contracts often depend on whether or not you can repair certain items in your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A pre-listing inspection will give you more credibility with future buyers.%20http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com/3-reasons-to-have-a-pre-listing-home-inspection.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A pre-listing inspection will give you more credibility with future buyers.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting the inspection in advance gives you a little more time to repair those things in your home and save you money in the long run. By making repairs before the home hits the market, you won’t have to worry about buyers reducing their offer price after they order an inspection on your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finally, a pre-listing inspection can boost your marketability.&lt;/strong&gt; People want transparency. They want to know what’s wrong with the house up front. Even if you don’t have the money to fix everything before you list your home, you will be able to say, “We know that there are some issues with the house, and those issues were taken into account when we created the listing price.” That will give you a lot more credibility with future homebuyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about pre-listing inspections or selling your home, just give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 10:48:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com/3-reasons-to-have-a-pre-listing-home-inspection.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com/3-reasons-to-have-a-pre-listing-home-inspection.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Do You Need a Real Estate Agent When Buying New Construction?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/m7B51w7CXGg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why should you have a buyer’s advocate with you when you look at new construction homes? Why not just work with the builder’s agent? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to remember that the agent at the new construction site is there to protect the builder’s best interests, not yours. &lt;strong&gt;Your buyer’s agent will have your best interests at heart. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A buyer’s agent will negotiate the best deal possible for you.%20http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com/do-you-need-a-real-estate-agent-when-buying-new-construction.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A buyer’s agent will negotiate the best deal possible for you.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A buyer’s agent will help you with any hiccups in the process. We will also negotiate the best deal possible for you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The best part is that we do all of this for free.&lt;/strong&gt; You can work with a buyer’s agent at no cost to you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or need help buying a home, just give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 04:23:54 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com/do-you-need-a-real-estate-agent-when-buying-new-construction.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com/do-you-need-a-real-estate-agent-when-buying-new-construction.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Check Out These Upcoming Holiday Events</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/6CcbmBGrQ9I?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re in the Delaware Beach area, here’s a list of some awesome holiday events we have coming up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Winter Wonderfest:&lt;/strong&gt; Take pictures with San ta, visit his workshop, ice skate, and more at the Lewis Ferry Terminal Grounds on November 17 through January 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Join us for some holiday fun!%20http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com/check-out-these-upcoming-holiday-events.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Join us for some holiday fun!”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rehoboth Beach Hometown Christmas Parade:&lt;/strong&gt; December 5 at 6:30 p.m. Santa’s Christmas Party will take place afterward at the Rehoboth Beach fire station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope to see you out there! If you have any questions about buying or selling real estate at the Delaware Beaches, please reach out to us. We’ll be happy to help you out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 08:44:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com/check-out-these-upcoming-holiday-events.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com/check-out-these-upcoming-holiday-events.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Busting the Myth That Fall Isn't a Good Time to Sell</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/EaCODpz3JUc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, let’s dispel the myth that fall isn’t a good time to sell your home. It’s a common belief that couldn’t be more wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of people think that the best time to sell their home is in the spring or summer, and while that may be true, it’s also true that you can sell your home just as well in the fall. Let’s talk about why selling in the fall can work for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.) Depending on when you close—for example, if you close before December 31—there’s a chance &lt;strong&gt;you could get some awesome tax breaks and write-offs for the next year.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2.) It’s a wonderful idea that &lt;strong&gt;you could be in a brand-new home for the holidays.&lt;/strong&gt; There’s nothing more special than spending the holidays in the home that you’re going to live in and build memories in with your family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=There’s nothing more special than spending the holidays in the home that you’re going to live in and build memories in with your family.%20http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com/busting-the-myth-that-fall-isnt-a-good-time-to-sell.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“There’s nothing more special than spending the holidays in the home that you’re going to live in and build memories in with your family.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3.) It might be &lt;strong&gt;the right time to get just the right price for your property&lt;/strong&gt; because there is less competition on the market during the fall season. Your home could definitely stand out in the crowd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4.) It’s a great time to fix up your home to sell because there are awesome holiday sales everywhere you look, Black Friday prominent among them. &lt;strong&gt;It’s an opportune time to fix up any areas that you’ve been wanting to tweak a little bit&lt;/strong&gt; so that it would be even more of a great buy for someone who’s interested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about how to sell your home this fall, feel free to contact our group at any time. One of our agents would be happy to call you and set up a personalized home-selling plan just for you. We look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 08:55:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com/busting-the-myth-that-fall-isnt-a-good-time-to-sell.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com/busting-the-myth-that-fall-isnt-a-good-time-to-sell.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Is Your Home Ready for Trick-or-Treaters?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_0KccdtM06Q?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re coming to you during the scary month of October with a few tips to prepare your home for trick-or-treaters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Decorate your door&lt;/strong&gt; so that trick-or-treaters know they are welcome. There is nothing more exciting than coming up to a door that’s been decked out in Halloween decor and hoping to find candy on the other side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Make sure your property is well lit&lt;/strong&gt; to prevent any kind of injuries. Try to light up your yard so that people can safely walk from the sidewalk to your front door and back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Don’t forget your own costume!%20http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com/is-your-home-ready-for-trick-or-treaters.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Don’t forget your own costume!”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Try to hide valuables from your front porch or yard. &lt;/strong&gt;We’re not worried about a robbery. This is simply about preventing any accidental damage. Someone might knock into an important valuable on the porch and, suddenly, it’s broken. Remove anything of great value until Halloween is over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Stock up on candy.&lt;/strong&gt; We also suggest getting candy for kids with allergies, and maybe even some sugar-free candy that’s friendly to everyone, no matter what kind of candy they can have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Don’t forget a costume!&lt;/strong&gt; Dressing in costume just helps seal the whole experience when you open the door decked out in your own character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you are preparing for Halloween or going to fall festivals this October, we hope you enjoy the season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any real estate questions, just give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 05:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com/is-your-home-ready-for-trick-or-treaters.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com/is-your-home-ready-for-trick-or-treaters.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Stage Your Home for Success</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/uny2hZdsKPg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of things to think about when staging your home for sale. Today, I’ve got a few staging tips that can help you sell for top dollar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, you need to think about curb appeal. &lt;strong&gt;How does the front of your home look?&lt;/strong&gt; A few changes here and there can really set your home apart. Consider a welcome mat to make buyers feel more at home as they enter your property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, &lt;strong&gt;make sure that your yard is clean and well-kept, and that all of your exterior lights are in working order.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The goal is to showcase your home’s potential.%20http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com/how-to-stage-your-home-for-success.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The goal is to showcase your home’s potential.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another tip to consider is creating an inviting ambience in your home. This means you should think about smell, sound, and taste as well as sight. You can engage buyers beyond the visual level by leaving out cookies, playing soft, instrumental music, and having an air freshener plug-in in each room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, &lt;strong&gt;embrace floor space to make rooms appear as large as possible.&lt;/strong&gt; Moving furniture away from the centers of rooms, and adding mirrors to smaller spaces can really open things up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t forget to embrace any unusual or quirky parts of your property. Why not turn a smaller space into a reading nook? The goal is to showcase your home’s potential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, play up the lifestyle surrounding your home. With our area being so near the beach, &lt;strong&gt;we like to play up this surf and sand lifestyle by adding beach decor to a home.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions, would like more information, or want to know how we can offer you a professional consultation with a home stager, feel free to give me a call or send me an email.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 07:02:30 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com/how-to-stage-your-home-for-success.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com/how-to-stage-your-home-for-success.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>4 Tips for Selling Your Home This Fall</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/SWmn7wd6lkA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fall is here, which means—among other things—pumpkins are everywhere! As a homeowner, it can be enticing to get into the spirit of things and do something like let your home overflow with pumpkins, but if you’re selling your home this fall, there are certain points you need to remember.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, &lt;strong&gt;consider your curb appeal.&lt;/strong&gt; Make sure your yard is free of leaves. When prospective buyers view your home, they want to see it in the best shape possible. Keep your fall decor to a minimum and don’t overdo anything because everyone has different tastes and styles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, &lt;strong&gt;avoid any gory decorations.&lt;/strong&gt; Not everyone celebrates Halloween with ghosts, goblins, blood, and gore. While you may think it’s fun to have zombies hanging from tree limbs, you don’t want to upset or scare any buyers when they’re looking at your house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you follow these tips, we guarantee your home will be a top contender to sell this fall.%20http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com/4-tips-for-selling-your-home-this-fall.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you follow these tips, we guarantee your home will be a top contender to sell this fall.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third, &lt;strong&gt;let in a lot of natural light.&lt;/strong&gt; Our days are getting shorter, so clean your windows, pull back the shades, and do everything you can to let natural light in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, &lt;strong&gt;make your space inviting.&lt;/strong&gt; Consider placing a few plush, fall-themed pillows on the couch or a few throws on the bed. You might even consider making some homemade cookies and leaving them on the counter for buyers to see when they walk through the home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you follow these tips, we guarantee your home will be a top contender to sell this fall. If you have any questions or you’d be interested in letting us help you list your home, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com/4-tips-for-selling-your-home-this-fall.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com/4-tips-for-selling-your-home-this-fall.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Consider a Move to Delaware?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jQBXYLtPT9Q?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The coastal communities in Delaware have experienced unprecedented growth over the past few years. The reasons why are plain to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you and your spouse are nearing retirement or are empty nesters looking to downsize, coming here to the Delaware coast is a great option.  Delaware has some of the lowest real estate taxes in the country. &lt;strong&gt;There’s no sales tax here, either. This is one of the primary reasons that retirees look for homes here.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=It's plain to see why people are moving to the Delaware coast.%20http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com/why-consider-a-move-to-delaware.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“It’s plain to see why people are moving to the Delaware coast.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you combine the value proposition of owning a Delaware home with the fact that there are so many different affordable options, it makes perfect sense for someone who wants a coastal home with a low cost of ownership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our team is full of experts in Delaware real estate and we can help make your dream home a reality.&lt;/strong&gt; If you have any questions for us, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com/why-consider-a-move-to-delaware.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com/why-consider-a-move-to-delaware.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
