<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Make The Move To Florida Real Estate Video Blog</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Wendy Reinhardt Realty - your professional Florida Coastal Communities Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://makethemovetoflorida.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://makethemovetoflorida.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 10:42:18 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 10:42:18 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>From Us to You: Happy Holidays</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/5T-64p7ZazE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’re joining you from the beach to wish you a very Merry Christmas and a Happy Holiday season. In the spirit of the season, we want to thank all of our friends, family, and clients for all of your support over the past year. 2017 wouldn’t have been the same without you. We hope you’ve had a fantastic year, too. To hear our full holiday message, watch this short video.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://makethemovetoflorida.com/from-us-to-you-happy-holidays.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://makethemovetoflorida.com/from-us-to-you-happy-holidays.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Trouble With Getting Fixer-Upper Financing</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/r_WZGQgB3_c?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why can’t you get traditional financing if you want to buy a bank-owned REO property?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Institutional lenders have very strict underwriting guidelines&lt;/strong&gt;, and they have a four-point inspection that any bank-owned property would have to pass wherein each of the following points would have to function properly and be up to code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;numbered-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The HVAC System&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The electrical systems and electrical panel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The plumbing and fixtures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The roof&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oftentimes, homes coming through foreclosure have been subject to what I call “duct tape maintenance.”&lt;/strong&gt; They’ve gone through many years of decline because whenever something broke and the owner was having financial problems, they used duct tape maintenance because they didn’t have the money to get it repaired properly. Because of this, these properties will fail one—if not all—of the criteria in the four-point inspection. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Occasionally, I’ll see some of these listings that say they accept cash or conventional financing. Here’s the problem, though: &lt;strong&gt;If you put in an offer on one of those listings with a financing contingency,&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;it will go right to the bottom of the offer pile&lt;/strong&gt; because that home likely has other cash buyers interested in it who can close much more quickly. By the time you’d be able to get that contingency satisfied, that property will be long gone. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Homes coming through foreclosure have often undergone “duct tape maintenance.”%20http://makethemovetoflorida.com/the-trouble-with-getting-fixer-upper-financing.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Homes coming through foreclosure have often undergone “duct tape maintenance.””&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some exceptions. FHA offers a 203(k) loan that provides for the purchase and repairs of the home, but you have to jump through a lot of hoops to get that finished, and I rarely see those examples make it to closing because, again, you get beat out by people who have cash offer who can move quickly and don’t have any contingencies. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Private money lenders will also lend on these properties, but that’s a subject I’ll talk more about after the first of the year. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, if you have any other questions about this topic or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home in our market, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://makethemovetoflorida.com/the-trouble-with-getting-fixer-upper-financing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://makethemovetoflorida.com/the-trouble-with-getting-fixer-upper-financing.html</guid>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>4 Things Sellers Can’t Afford to Slack On</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-fzoAMEgo28?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we approach selling season here in Florida, there are four things that sellers must require of themselves and their listing agents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. You must have professional photos&lt;/strong&gt;. Don’t settle for your listing agent to come through and take grainy cell phone pictures. Also, wait until you have the entire photo portfolio ready to go; don’t let your agent go live on the multiple listing service with only a couple photos, with the rest to follow at a later point. The full photo package will help your home pop right as it hits the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Your home must be priced right&lt;/strong&gt;. Listen to your Realtor; they know the market and what an appropriate price would be. If you’re not sure, get an appraisal. For a relatively low cost, you can get another opinion and another idea of what the price should be. Appraisals are also useful tools for listing agents to use in selling that property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Your home must be easy to show&lt;/strong&gt;. If a buyer’s agent looks at the showing instructions and sees a complicated or limited time frame in which they can view the home, they won’t view the home if they can avoid it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. You need a listing agent who has a strong internet presence&lt;/strong&gt;. This is especially true here in Florida; most of our buyers are from other regions, so they’ll need to be able to easily find your listing, your Realtor, and your photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If your home isn’t getting showings or offers, it is due to something lacking in at least one of these four areas.%20http://makethemovetoflorida.com/4-things-sellers-cant-afford-to-slack-on.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If your home isn’t getting showings or offers, it is due to something lacking in at least one of these four areas.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will guarantee you if you have your home listed and it’s not getting showings or offers, it is due to something lacking in at least one of those four areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like I said, we are heading into selling season in Florida, so if you’re thinking about selling, give me a call or send me an email. I’d be happy to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://makethemovetoflorida.com/4-things-sellers-cant-afford-to-slack-on.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://makethemovetoflorida.com/4-things-sellers-cant-afford-to-slack-on.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Home Flipping Tips You Won't Want to Miss</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qFex5zOfacQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, a new top 10 list has come out for the most profitable cities in the US for home flipping. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wallethub.com/edu/best-cities-to-flip-houses/23158/.&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WalletHub just conducted a 150-city study&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; to get these results, so let’s dive into what they found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, coastal areas are mostly off-limits for this move. The cost of getting into these areas is generally high, so you might do better in some smaller markets. Sioux Falls, South Dakota, for example, was No. 2 on the list. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;However, one coastal city market did make the top ten list. That city was Tampa&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But on a more specific scale, location will still matter. You can fix a house up, but you can’t change the neighborhood. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people look in lower price points for homes to flip. That being said: don’t overdo it. Going overboard with renovations on a lower-end home will not be worth it. Remember, &lt;strong&gt;there won’t be any TV crew or ribbon cutting ceremony when you put these homes back on the market&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Flipping is not for the weak of heart.%20http://makethemovetoflorida.com/home-flipping-tips-you-wont-want-to-miss.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Flipping is not for the weak of heart.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look for properties that don’t need more than a single major repair. I recommend skipping over any home that you aren’t truly equipped to take on. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, consider renting out properties for a while instead of selling right away. &lt;strong&gt;Rentals are a great way to ride out appreciation&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you do sell, though, think about seller financing. This is another great vehicle for you to get some additional cash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, flipping is not for the weak of heart. You need cash, you need to move quickly, and you need to know what you’re doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a list of the top 10 cities:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;El Paso, Texas&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sioux Falls, South Dakota&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fort Wayne, Indiana&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Peoria, Arizona&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Oklahoma City, Oklahoma&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tampa, Florida&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Grand Rapids, Michigan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Boise, Idaho&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Greensboro, North Carolina&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Springfield, Missouri&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://makethemovetoflorida.com/home-flipping-tips-you-wont-want-to-miss.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://makethemovetoflorida.com/home-flipping-tips-you-wont-want-to-miss.html</guid>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Snowbird Season Is Upon Us</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/uKsmb2j7OaE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s snowbird season! That means it’s selling season here in Florida. Every year, starting around November, the snowbirds start rolling in. &lt;strong&gt;By the time the new year rolls around, the season is in full force.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Snowbirds are, of course, visitors of Florida during the winter who come from cold and snowy climates. Some stay a week or two, some stay a month, and some own homes here and stay all season. They have a big seasonal effect on our real estate market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re currently a homeowner in Florida and thinking of selling, I want to give you a word of caution about pricing.&lt;/strong&gt; There are currently 3,032 homes with pools priced under $500,000. That’s a lot of competition for you if you have a similar home. The bottom line: Listen to your Realtor’s suggestions when it comes to pricing. If you think the home is worth more than they do, get an appraisal to settle the score. The appraisal will also be a great selling tool for your Realtor down the line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Snowbirds have a big seasonal effect on our market.%20http://makethemovetoflorida.com/snowbird-season-is-upon-us.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Snowbirds have a big seasonal effect on our market.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking about buying a home down here because you’re a snowbird yourself, there is a lot of great inventory out there now. &lt;strong&gt;The seasonal peak hasn’t hit yet, so you can purchase in a much less competitive market. &lt;/strong&gt;There’s no guarantee that owning a home in Florida is going to be more affordable. Even after the recent hurricanes, our market still keeps chugging along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me about buying a home, selling a home, or about the real estate market in general, give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://makethemovetoflorida.com/snowbird-season-is-upon-us.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://makethemovetoflorida.com/snowbird-season-is-upon-us.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Useful Tips for Communicating With Your Realtor</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/1Jw-t9agubY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever gone to the doctor for an exam and not told them what’s wrong with you in the hope that they won’t tell you that you’re really sick? How well would that work out?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your Realtor is another professional who’s there to help you, but they need all the information you can give them in order to do so. Not being straight up with your Realtor may not kill you, but it may get in the way of you getting a really good real estate deal. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here are a few tips for communicating with your Realtor so the transaction goes smoothly for the both of you:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discuss your financial situation with them. If there’s a problem, talk to them about it—they may have a solution. Be candid about what you qualify for or if you do or don’t have a pre-qualification or pre-approval letter. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talk about what price range you want to shop in and what are your “must-haves” versus your “like-to-haves.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talk about your communication style. Are you a person who prefers texting, talking on the phone, or talking via email? How frequently do you prefer to communicate? This information will help you communicate in a positive way and get the job done. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bring up any expectations that aren’t being met. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be straightforward if you’re working with other Realtors. Some Realtors are OK with this, while other aren’t. Some take it as a challenge to be better than the other person you’re working with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Be respectful, be courteous, and communicate.%20http://makethemovetoflorida.com/useful-tips-for-communicating-with-your-realtor.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Be respectful, be courteous, and communicate.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike your doctor, your Realtor is working on commission, so they’ll work very hard to get the job done for you. They won’t make a penny until it is. Be respectful, be courteous, and communicate. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any further questions about communicating with your Realtor or you’re thinking about buying or selling a home in the Gulf Coast area, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be glad to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://makethemovetoflorida.com/useful-tips-for-communicating-with-your-realtor.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://makethemovetoflorida.com/useful-tips-for-communicating-with-your-realtor.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Narcissa Reviews Wendy Sells Florida!</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/342902157&amp;amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I was searching the area on Zillow about a year ago, I found a home and contacted the agents that were listed. Both agents reached out to me and one of them was Michael. When I started to ask questions Michael was the most responsive agent. He was helping me understand the area, which houses were better than the others, and answering all of my questions. So, my decision was pretty clear. I contacted him when I was ready to look for houses and he was very supportive. He found houses for me based on my criteria. Everything was done quickly and in a very professional manner. I found a home that I liked and I reached out to Michael because I thought it might be a good one. However, there were no pictures and I didn’t know what to do because I couldn’t go down and look at it. He told me that I could contact Wendy and she would help me with pro’s and con’s of the home. I put in an offer, got the approval, and a few days later I came to Florida to see the house and a few others to make sure I made the right decision. Wendy was very helpful, she was doing everything she possibly could to accommodate my needs. She was more patient than I expected and very dedicated. I really really appreciated it.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;- Narcissa Pop, Home Buyer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://makethemovetoflorida.com/narcissa-reviews-wendy-sells-florida.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://makethemovetoflorida.com/narcissa-reviews-wendy-sells-florida.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kathi Reviews the Wendy Sells Florida Team!</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/340366087&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“We bought and sold a home with Wendy Sells Florida. We met them three years prior to buying and selling our properties. We had looked a property and the deal never went through. But, we were so very impressed with them that we wanted to keep trying to work with them. That’s how it happened. We never even considered using anyone else because we were so impressed with their knowledge and integrity. They actually tried to put the deal together for us to buy our home while the other home was still on the market. They helped set us up with a financier that could help us get a loan to cover the cost of the new home so that we could go ahead and purchase our new home before the other one was sold. They truly went beyond what you would normally expect from your realtor.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;- Kathi Dorn, Home Buyer/Seller&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://makethemovetoflorida.com/kathi-reviews-the-wendy-sells-florida-team.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://makethemovetoflorida.com/kathi-reviews-the-wendy-sells-florida-team.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Don’t Let Hurricanes Ruin Your Dreams</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/h9ZMbM6wrrw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every place on Earth has weather risks; living in a tropical paradise means dealing with hurricanes. Despite this, the good news is that we always have plenty of warning, and plenty of time to get prepared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our newer homes are built at higher elevations to combat flood risks, and have very sophisticated storm standards. Most of them would have withstood whatever wind that came our way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the event of another hurricane, here’s what you need to know if you’re interested in living in the southwest Florida area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, no matter what, there will always be a vibrant real estate market. Market dynamics may have changed in the short term, but most homeowners would have been made whole, and many would have made improvements to their homes—their house would have been better in the long run. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=No matter what, there will always be a vibrant real estate market.%20http://makethemovetoflorida.com/dont-let-hurricanes-ruin-your-dreams.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“No matter what, there will always be a vibrant real estate market.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was here back in 2005 when Hurricane Charlie struck. It hit Punta Gorda very hard, but the town recovered very quickly—it is now more beautiful and better than ever, and also more in-demand than ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, your Realtor will help you through the disaster. A day after the storm, Wendy was out mapping where all of our clients’ homes were, driving by to check on homes for those out of town. My team had a response plan in place—we really hit the ground running, determining the day after what the new market conditions were, and being ready to help clients move forward through the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t let the threat of hurricanes or their portrayal on the media take away your dream of living on the coast. If a hurricane hits, expect to recover very quickly—we’ll come back better than ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to go deeper with this, please feel free to give me a call anytime! &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://makethemovetoflorida.com/dont-let-hurricanes-ruin-your-dreams.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://makethemovetoflorida.com/dont-let-hurricanes-ruin-your-dreams.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Work With Just One Agent When You Could Have a Team?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/EZa1xpmovVs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working with an experienced Realtor is always a great idea, but is there any benefit to working with someone who’s new to the business? Actually, yes. New agents have a lot of energy and enthusiasm. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if you’re going to work with a new agent, they must be part of a team. In a team environment, these new agents will have the help of other, more experienced agents. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This situation really brings you the best of both worlds. Experienced agents on the team can take care of negotiations and contracts, while the newer Realtor will provide a lot of vigor. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just like medical professionals, &lt;strong&gt;many Realtors have begun working more often in teams in order to provide a higher level of service&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A real estate team will generally consist of several professionals who each play a different role. For example, the team leader will be the one who communicates directly with you and makes sure that everything is coordinated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=When you work with a team, you have the benefit of combined experience, skills, and resources.%20http://makethemovetoflorida.com/why-work-with-just-one-agent-when-you-could-have-a-team.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“When you work with a team, you have the benefit of combined experience, skills, and resources.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Newer Realtors will often take on roles like that of a showing agent, since this will help them really become immersed in a neighborhood. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, once you start making offers you’ll generally work with someone on the team who is a little more experienced. Someone who specializes in contracts and negotiations will be a great asset in this process. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When working with a team, it’s common for you to work more closely with different agents at different points throughout the process. Try not to feel like you’re being handed off. The reason this happens is because &lt;strong&gt;different agents have different skills that are best suited for various stages of the transaction&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of feeling as if you’re being passed around, remember that when you work with a team, you’re being granted the benefit of combined experience, skills, and resources. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://makethemovetoflorida.com/why-work-with-just-one-agent-when-you-could-have-a-team.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://makethemovetoflorida.com/why-work-with-just-one-agent-when-you-could-have-a-team.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
