<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wes Peters Group Real Estate Video Blog</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Wes Peters Group - your professional Baltimore Metropolitan Area Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://wpghomeblog.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://wpghomeblog.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 14:41:41 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 14:41:41 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Spring Updates From Our Team</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/A-moy_ddbyg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I’d like to bring you just a few messages. First of all, my team and I would like to extend our sincere thanks to everyone who joined us at our recent client appreciation event. &lt;strong&gt;We collected almost 200 toys for the Cool Kids Foundation thanks to your participation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second message I wanted to share with you has to do with our current real estate market. The spring real estate market in Maryland has been very busy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With more hours of daylight than in the previous months, people have more time to spend out looking at homes. This allows buyers to visit listings during the week, instead of just on the weekends. As a result, homes stay on the market for shorter amounts of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The spring real estate market in Maryland has been very busy.%20http://wpghomeblog.com/3-spring-updates-from-our-team.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The spring real estate market in Maryland has been very busy.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, there’s one more thing I want to let you all know about. &lt;strong&gt;My team and I will be hosting a March Madness giveaway.&lt;/strong&gt; The person whose bracket gains them the highest points will become our lucky winner, so be sure to get in touch with me about how to enter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information about anything I’ve gone over today, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://wpghomeblog.com/3-spring-updates-from-our-team.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://wpghomeblog.com/3-spring-updates-from-our-team.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Newest Addition to the Wes Peters Group</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/WMLqimvhVMM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our real estate team has been servicing the Baltimore Metro area for the last 30 years or so. Although we’re based out of Columbia, we will go anywhere in the state of Maryland that they’ll let us sell homes for our clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harford County has always been an area that we’ve serviced, but it’s to the point where it’s an hour or so away from us. &lt;strong&gt;So, to better service our clients on that side of town, we have recently partnered with Rob Elliot.&lt;/strong&gt; Rob is a Bel Air and Fallston area native, and we’re really excited to combine our resources with Rob’s local knowledge and expertise on that side of town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I am excited to be a part of this team,” says Rob. “I have been a Baltimore County and Harford County resident for 47 years, and my wife and my three children reside in Bel Air. I’ve been in sales most of my adult life, and I’ve been in the real estate market as an investor. I made the decision to work with clients to help them find homes, and I look forward to working with you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Join us on Sunday, February 25 at Horizon Cinemas to watch ‘Peter Rabbit.’%20http://wpghomeblog.com/the-newest-addition-to-the-wes-peters-group.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Join us on Sunday, February 25 at Horizon Cinemas to watch ‘Peter Rabbit.’”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We are lucky to have Rob as part of our team.&lt;/strong&gt; If you would like to meet Rob, he is having a client event on Sunday, February 25 at Horizon Cinemas in Fallston at 9:30 a.m. There will be a screening of the movie “Peter Rabbit,” as well as some free breakfast (bagels, donuts, and coffee).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come on out on February 25 for a great time. We will send out Facebook invitations and other invites soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, thanks to Rob for joining our team. We look forward to working with him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any real estate questions, just give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://wpghomeblog.com/the-newest-addition-to-the-wes-peters-group.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://wpghomeblog.com/the-newest-addition-to-the-wes-peters-group.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We Have an Inventory Crisis!</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/EYs9ABmqUDY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point in the year, there are a couple of reminders and updates I’d like to share with all of you. First of all, our next client appreciation event is coming up soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We hope you’ll join us for a movie day on February 24 at 1:30 p.m. at Arundel Mills Theater.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve already sent out invitations online and through the mail, so please reach out if you haven’t already received yours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, onto a brief market update. We have somewhat of an inventory crisis on our hands right now. Right now, we’re seeing the lowest amount of homes on the market for a decade in our area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you’ve been thinking about selling your home, now is the time to do so.%20http://wpghomeblog.com/we-have-an-inventory-crisis.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you’ve been thinking about selling your home, now is the time to do so.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For example, there are 61 homes on the market in Catonsville, 74 available homes in Ellicott City, 43 in Columbia, and 74 in Eldersburg.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, our local market has just 2.9 months of inventory. This means that if no new homes came on the market, all inventory would be gone in just 2.9 months. So if you’ve been thinking about selling your home, now is the time to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://wpghomeblog.com/we-have-an-inventory-crisis.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://wpghomeblog.com/we-have-an-inventory-crisis.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We Have Investors That Will Buy Your House As-Is, Cash, No Commission or Expenses to Sell!</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8kPqQsX4uZM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you own a distressed property that’s in rough shape? Perhaps you know someone who does? If either is the case, I have three options someone in this situation may find useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Cash offer&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;quick settlements, and selling as-is.&lt;/strong&gt;This will allow the seller to list their home without worrying about financial or home inspection contingencies. If they want to leave the house full of unwanted possessions, they are free to do so. Additionally, this option requires no exposure to the market. In all these scenarios, the investor will pay all of the expenses associated with the offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A cash offer will allow the seller to list their home without worrying about financial or home inspection contingencies.%20http://wpghomeblog.com/we-have-investors-that-will-buy-your-house-as-is-cash-no-commission-or-expenses-to-sell.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A cash offer will allow the seller to list their home without worrying about financial or home inspection contingencies.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Putting the home on the market.&lt;/strong&gt;This option is for those who predict that they can find an investor or homeowner who would pay more for the property than a cash buyer off the market. However, here, you’d have to pay for such things as commission, and you may be exposed to contingencies like a financial contingency. If you can’t find a better offer on the market than you could off the market, then the off-market investor would likely still be interested in purchasing your home. This option gets the best of both worlds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Put money back into the home.&lt;/strong&gt; If you’re in a position such that you can invest some money into renovating your home, we can connect you to contractors to help you fix the property and get it to the top of the market. The downsides to this option are that you’ll have holding costs and you may have to move into temporary housing until you finish work on the property (and then again when you go to sell).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you do find yourself in a situation with a house that’s in poor condition, you do have options. If you have questions about this or would like me to come out to your property and give you my opinion about what someone might be willing to pay your distressed home, feel free to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://wpghomeblog.com/we-have-investors-that-will-buy-your-house-as-is-cash-no-commission-or-expenses-to-sell.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://wpghomeblog.com/we-have-investors-that-will-buy-your-house-as-is-cash-no-commission-or-expenses-to-sell.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Looking for a Career Change in 2018?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/yXhwGYblPGk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just wanted to let everyone know that we are hiring for 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are looking to grow our team, and there are a lot of great opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you had thought about a career in real estate and not had time to transition or are looking for a part-time opportunity, I’d love to talk to you. If you have a license and are looking for full-time opportunities, I’d love to talk to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if you are an established agent who needs more support for administrative work and marketing, I’d love to talk with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We have a good track record of getting new agents into the business&lt;/strong&gt; through different career paths, and we’re really proud of that. We are looking to grow our team, and we have a great value proposition that I’d love to talk to everyone about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 26,000 real estate agents in Maryland and the D.C. area, and about 100,000 homes sell each year in Maryland. Some might say that the industry is over-serviced, but I disagree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can tell you that only about 10% of agents renew their licenses after two years in the business. That means that 90% of agents get out of the business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a huge amount to learn, from technology to contract changes and beyond. As great as some brokerages are, it can be hard to provide everything an agent needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why teams are so prevalent now. &lt;strong&gt;Teams are able to provide training, accountability, and leadership.&lt;/strong&gt;Keller Williams has world-class training that we are really proud of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if you or anyone you know would be interested in a career in real estate, I would love to talk to them. In the meantime, I hope you have fun this holiday season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://wpghomeblog.com/looking-for-a-career-change-in-2018.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://wpghomeblog.com/looking-for-a-career-change-in-2018.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Does the Cool Kids Campaign Help Children With Cancer?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Sw6DbRXuDA8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m joined by Kristen Rutherford and Mackenzie Wieder from the Cool Kids Campaign. Kristin is the Community Relations Coordinator, and Mackenzie is the Operations Coordinator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a local charity that we partner with. We contribute a portion of our commission from every settlement at Keller Williams to the campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cool Kids Campaign helps improve the quality of life for pediatric oncology patients and their families.&lt;/strong&gt; The Cool Kids Campaign focuses on academic, social, and emotional support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They have many great programs in place. During the summer, there is a “Mommy and Me” drop-off for the kids to come and hang out. They also have a camp for all of the kids and their siblings, as well as a condo in Myrtle Beach, where they send the families for vacation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The Cool Kids Campaign helps children with cancer and their families.%20http://wpghomeblog.com/how-does-the-cool-kids-campaign-help-children-with-cancer.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The Cool Kids Campaign helps children with cancer and their families.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Cool Kids Campaign also sends care packages out across the country with all of the kids’ favorite things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a look at the video to see their great facility in Towson, Maryland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We are on track to donate $10,000 to the Cool Kids Campaign this year&lt;/strong&gt;, and we are proud to help such an amazing organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Kristen and Mackenzie for joining me today. You can learn more about the Cool Kids Campaign at their &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.coolkidscampaign.org/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, please don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://wpghomeblog.com/how-does-the-cool-kids-campaign-help-children-with-cancer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://wpghomeblog.com/how-does-the-cool-kids-campaign-help-children-with-cancer.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Team Is Putting Our Money Where Our Mouth Is for Our Sellers</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/AeUpsaOO0OI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I wanted to take a minute to tell you all about our Guaranteed Sale Program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we’re currently in a seller’s market, this isn’t something that has been coming into play all that often. Nevertheless, I wanted to give you an idea of what it is and how it works. &lt;strong&gt;I personally like to give sellers what I think are the pros and cons of their situation&lt;/strong&gt;, and what the best and worst-case scenarios are in any given circumstance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though I like to provide this information and feedback, I still want to give sellers the freedom to choose their own initial list price—within reason. Still, a lot of sellers ask me what I would do if I were in their shoes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where the Guaranteed Sale Program comes into play. This program lets me put my money where my mouth is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If we can't sell your home for you within 60 days for a price you're happy with, we will sell it for free!%20http://wpghomeblog.com/my-team-is-putting-our-money-where-our-mouth-is-for-our-sellers.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If we can’t sell your home for you within 60 days for a price you’re happy with, we will sell it for free!”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the seller lists their home at a price my team and I recommend and agree with and doesn’t sell within 30 days, the listing will undergo an agreed-upon price reduction. This reduction is usually about 3%. &lt;strong&gt;If the listing still doesn’t sell within 60 days, we will continue to market your property at no cost.&lt;/strong&gt; Though we’ll still need to pay the buyer’s agent, my team and I will basically be working for free at that point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This guarantee does not include short sales or tenant-occupied properties, and there needs to be equity in the property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pre-appraisals and pre-inspections are both required for the Guaranteed Sale Program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This allows us to be totally transparent with any potential buyers. This also allows us to take care of any issues that arise in the report ahead of time. &lt;strong&gt;With a pre-inspection, a lot of surprises are taken out of the transaction.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The program also requires that you meet with our in-house stager Rose, and agree to any of her recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://wpghomeblog.com/my-team-is-putting-our-money-where-our-mouth-is-for-our-sellers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://wpghomeblog.com/my-team-is-putting-our-money-where-our-mouth-is-for-our-sellers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Has Technology Changed the World of Lending?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/cVcN-B949Wc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m joined by a special guest, Andy Duda from Caliber Home Loans, to talk about the current state of mortgages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been in the business for 13 years, but Andy has been helping me with loans even before then. &lt;strong&gt;In the time we’ve known each other, Andy has assisted me with hundreds of loans.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a big deal for my team and I to have lenders that we trust, so professionals like Andy are a huge resource to us. We try to introduce Andy to as many of our clients as possible when they are in need of his services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lending has changed a little bit over the year. I always tell people that lending in 2017 is somewhat vanilla. Most lenders have the same products, so the real difference comes down to interest rates and customer service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Andy, the world of lending ultimately changed after the economic crisis in 2007. Ultimately, traditional financing is king. There are niche programs out there, but most people tend to go more standard routes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=As technology moves forward, so does the world of real estate.%20http://wpghomeblog.com/how-has-technology-changed-the-world-of-lending.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“As technology moves forward, so does the world of real estate.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One of the most important things is to talk to your lender early on in the process.&lt;/strong&gt; Doing so will help you determine what price range you should be shopping in and what programs will be the best fit for you. Having this information will also help your Realtor service you to the highest level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though most loan products are fairly standardized, there are some neat features available these days. For example, Caliber Home Loans has introduced the possibility of a digital mortgage for buyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This allows the company to digitally verify income and assets without the hassle of a lot of paperwork. &lt;strong&gt;People can become fully approved and can close without ever having to dig up paystubs.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While not all employers will facilitate this as a possibility, it is a great option for those who can make use of it. As technology moves forward, so does the world of real estate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://wpghomeblog.com/how-has-technology-changed-the-world-of-lending.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://wpghomeblog.com/how-has-technology-changed-the-world-of-lending.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Great News About Our Zillow Reviews and a Quick Market Update</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/aNkp5Uqul5A?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s the latest word on our Baltimore market as we head into fall?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I have some great news to share with you. Our team has reached 200 reviews on Zillow. It’s taken us years to accumulate this number, and it’s a milestone we’re extremely proud of. If you’re a past client of ours and you contributed one of those reviews, I want to personally thank you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I want to remind you &lt;strong&gt;that we’re hosting an outdoor cookout for all of our past clients on September 23rd at the Columbia Sports Park at 5 p.m.&lt;/strong&gt; My wife’s been putting a lot of effort into planning this event, so if you’re a past client and you haven’t gotten your invitation in the mail, we’d love for you to come join us. We’ll have a live DJ, an open bar, and plenty of fun activities for the whole family to enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We’ll see an uptick in the market in the next 60 to 75 days.%20http://wpghomeblog.com/great-news-about-our-zillow-reviews-and-a-quick-market-update.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We’ll see an uptick in the market in the next 60 to 75 days.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, onto the latest real estate news. The Baltimore market experienced a little bit of a slowdown this past August because of people vacationing later in the year due to a later school year start date. This has caused some frustration among the active buyers out there because of the available inventory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good news if you’re a buyer, however, is that &lt;strong&gt;you’ll see a new wave of homes coming on the market next week&lt;/strong&gt;—our team alone has about 10 homes being listed next Wednesday or Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good news if you’re a seller is that &lt;strong&gt;we’ll see an uptick in the market in the next 60 to 75 days&lt;/strong&gt;, which will provide you a great window to sell your home. It’s arguably a better time to sell during this timespan than the spring months because—from an appraisal standpoint—you have great comparables of homes that sold in May, June, and July.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about our market or you’re thinking about buying or selling a home soon, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d be glad to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://wpghomeblog.com/great-news-about-our-zillow-reviews-and-a-quick-market-update.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://wpghomeblog.com/great-news-about-our-zillow-reviews-and-a-quick-market-update.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Where Does Our Baltimore Market Stand for Buyers and Sellers?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/p9gGoP72JSY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s the latest news from our Baltimore metro area market?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let’s start by sharing some statistics from the month of June:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The median sale price was just shy of $279,000, which is the highest it’s been since July 2007.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There were 4,509 closed sales and 4,313 pending sales—the highest number for either category in a decade.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Active inventory continued to decline by double digits for the twelfth consecutive month, and ended at 11,097 homes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get a more in-depth look at how our market fared in June, check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rbintel.com/blog/baltimore-area-hits-highest-monthly-tally-decade-over-4500-homes-sold-june&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Real Estate Business Intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you’ve missed out on a home, August might be a great time to find a good value.%20http://wpghomeblog.com/where-does-our-baltimore-market-stand-for-buyers-and-sellers.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you’ve missed out on a home, August might be a great time to find a good value.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One trend I’ve noticed lately is that many buyers who’ve been trying to secure a home before summer ends and school starts have found what they were looking for. The market tends to slow down in August and then pick back up after Labor Day. I always say &lt;strong&gt;this window is the second-best time period to sell your home, after the spring market.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the buyer side, if you’ve missed out on a home in the last few months, August might present some valuable opportunities since fewer buyers will be in the marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a different note, we have a client appreciation event coming up on September 23rd at the Columbia Sports Park from 5 p.m. to 9 p.m., so keep your eyes peeled for an upcoming invitation. It should be a great time for everyone involved, so we hope to see you then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, if you have any questions about our market or are thinking of buying or selling a home, feel free to give me a call or shoot me an email. I’d be happy to speak with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://wpghomeblog.com/where-does-our-baltimore-market-stand-for-buyers-and-sellers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://wpghomeblog.com/where-does-our-baltimore-market-stand-for-buyers-and-sellers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
