<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Richardson Real Estate - your professional Milwaukee Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://navthenoise.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://navthenoise.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 16:27:44 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 16:27:44 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Can You Trust a Zestimate?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/UhlCfDgMg48?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Zestimate is Zillow’s tool for calculating home values. It gives you an instant home value based on a complex algorithm, but &lt;strong&gt;the accuracy can be spotty.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;If you’re in a neighborhood, for example, that has a lot of recent sales of similar homes, your Zestimate can be pretty accurate. However, if you’re in an area that has a new subdivision nearby or your house is a little older or a little newer than the most recently sold homes, the estimate probably isn’t very accurate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The accuracy can be pretty spotty.%20http://navthenoise.com/can-you-trust-a-zestimate.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The accuracy can be pretty spotty.”&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;No matter what, you should talk to a real estate professional if you want an accurate valuation. &lt;strong&gt;Only an expert in the market will be able to understand what your home’s value truly is&lt;/strong&gt; based on current market conditions and the most recent comparable sales data.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;If you need a professional opinion on your home’s value or if you just have any questions, you can always give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2017 05:51:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://navthenoise.com/can-you-trust-a-zestimate.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://navthenoise.com/can-you-trust-a-zestimate.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Which Is Better: Doing a Major Renovation or Some Minor Remodeling?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/1LgXFqI38ds?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One question I’ve been getting a lot lately is, “When I list my home, should I do a major renovation project or am I better off doing some minor remodeling?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Buyers are drawn to things like curb appeal and attractive landscaping.%20http://navthenoise.com/which-is-better-doing-a-major-renovation-or-some-minor-remodeling.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Buyers are drawn to things like curb appeal and attractive landscaping.”&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;The answer I give to 99% of the people I meet with is to &lt;strong&gt;do a minor type of remodeling or upgrade, as this will bring you a better return on your investment.&lt;/strong&gt;Don’t get me wrong—a brand-new kitchen or bathroom will help your home sell hand over fist, but by the time you get done with that type of project, there’s usually a lot of unanticipated costs that can also cost you time and prevent you from getting top dollar for your home sale.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Research indicates you should start your upgrades outside.&lt;/strong&gt; Buyers are drawn to things like curb appeal and attractive landscaping. Avoid getting too customized with your renovations, though. Not everybody likes a certain color or style, so you’re better off maintaining neutrality.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Lastly, do some decluttering. It’s an often-overlooked task, but it’s an easy one to accomplish. I understand if you have things you appreciate lying around the house, but clutter can become distracting to a potential buyer.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;If you have any questions about which minor upgrades you can make to increase your home’s value and sale-ability, don’t hesitate to give me a call or shoot me an email. I’d be glad to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2017 05:13:47 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://navthenoise.com/which-is-better-doing-a-major-renovation-or-some-minor-remodeling.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://navthenoise.com/which-is-better-doing-a-major-renovation-or-some-minor-remodeling.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
