<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Select Premier Properties</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Select Premier Properties - your professional San Diego Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://victoriasvideoblog.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://victoriasvideoblog.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 11:00:22 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 11:00:22 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Can You Make Your Offer Stand out to a Seller?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ydv1bRwUVQ8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to buy a home here in San Diego, getting your offer accepted can be a challenge.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;To ensure you win the home you want, the first thing you should do is &lt;strong&gt;hire an aggressive agent&lt;/strong&gt; with a history of closing at least 15 transactions per year. I’ve noticed that agents who don’t close at least 15 transactions a year haven’t really developed the negotiation skills you need to help you get your offer accepted, so do your homework and find an agent with aggressive negotiation skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A personalized letter to the seller puts a face to the name.%20http://victoriasvideoblog.com/how-can-you-make-your-offer-stand-out-to-a-seller.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A personalized letter to the seller puts a face to the name.”&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;The next thing you can do is &lt;strong&gt;write a personalized letter&lt;/strong&gt; to the seller with a family photo included that describes why you want to live in their home. It just sits well with the seller. Then, you’re not just another name putting an offer on their property, you’re a family.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Next, make sure you &lt;strong&gt;have your proof of funds&lt;/strong&gt; ready to prove your down payment and closing costs, as well as your letter of mortgage pre-approval. I’ve seen scenarios in which clients didn’t have their proof of funds available, which caused a delay that could have risked them losing the property.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;If you have any questions about making your offer on a home stand out or about anything in the home buying or selling process, give me a call or send me an email soon. I’d be glad to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 10:38:58 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://victoriasvideoblog.com/how-can-you-make-your-offer-stand-out-to-a-seller.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://victoriasvideoblog.com/how-can-you-make-your-offer-stand-out-to-a-seller.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
