<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- MARKET -- Real Estate Video Blog with -- CLIENT NAME --</title>
    <description>Our mission at Marty Millner Real Estate Team is to be your best resource for Bucks County real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Marty Millner Real Estate Team, your professional Bucks County Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://buckscountyrealestatevideoblog.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://buckscountyrealestatevideoblog.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 11:58:16 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 11:58:16 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Ways Buyers Can Win in Today's Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/m7VRI3BXGNU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buyers have been complaining recently about our market’s low supply. When buyers do find a home that interests them, they are often faced with competition. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So today, I’d like to share five strategies I’ve developed to help buyers win out in multiple offer situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The further you are in the approval process, the more advantages you’ll have over other competing buyers.%20http://buckscountyrealestatevideoblog.com/5-ways-buyers-can-win-in-todays-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The further you are in the approval process, the more advantages you’ll have over other competing buyers.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Put down as much as possible and get approved as early as you can.&lt;/strong&gt; Before you even find the right home, it’s critically important that you talk to a lender. The further you are in the approval process, the more advantage you’ll have over other competing buyers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consider offering appraisal protection.&lt;/strong&gt; For example, imagine that you are going to buy a $400,000 home with 20% down. Your lender will loan you 80% of what the home appraises for, even if the appraisal is less than the list price. If a home appraises below list price, though, you technically have the right to not go through with the purchase or ask that the seller drops the price, based on the mortgage contingency. However, you can still purchase the home if you’re willing to offer appraisal protection and make up the difference. This may not be the best choice for every buyer, but it can certainly make your offer stand out.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consider inspection flexibility.&lt;/strong&gt; Sometimes this is just a matter of having your agent communicate with the seller’s agent, indicating that you won’t nickel-and-dime the seller based on inspection results. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be creative.&lt;/strong&gt; For example, I work with a particular lender who offers a $2,500 guarantee to sellers if their buyers don’t close. For a buyer, being creative might involve writing a personal letter to the seller about your intentions for their home.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be patient. &lt;/strong&gt;I firmly believe there’s no house worth chasing through unreasonable hardships. If the trouble to secure the property is more than it’s worth, know that another home will come along. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 15:48:32 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://buckscountyrealestatevideoblog.com/5-ways-buyers-can-win-in-todays-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://buckscountyrealestatevideoblog.com/5-ways-buyers-can-win-in-todays-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Latest News From the Bucks County Real Estate Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/XHv_4KjtubI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m here with your market update to let you know whats happening all over Bucks County. Although we might get some more snow, spring is here. In real estate, the spring market actually starts right after the Super Bowl.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what’s happening in our market right now?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In Bucks County, there is a tremendous lack of housing available on the market.&lt;/strong&gt;Other than the really high-end, expensive market, this is true all over Bucks County. In virtually every market that we track, buyers are complaining because there is not much to look at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a whole, there are 15.3% fewer homes on the market in Bucks County than there were at the same time last year. At the end of February, there were only 2,495 houses on the market, which really reflects the shortage of inventory we are experiencing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The average asking price is up 5.6% from the same time last year, and we almost had 5% appreciation year over year. That is the single largest increase in price for all of 2017, and it’s the highest we’ve seen since 2004 and 2005, so prices are going up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of the end of February, the number of homes closed is down 9% and &lt;strong&gt;the average sold price is up 1.2% from the same time last year.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we look at the housing inventory as an indicator of market dynamics, do those dynamics favor buyers or sellers? If a market has less than six months of inventory, it typically favors sellers. A market with six months of inventory is considered a balanced market. During the market decline, we saw 10, 12, and even 14 months of inventory because homes just weren’t selling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Lower Makefield, there are only 3.8 months of inventory. In Newtown, there are 2.4 months of inventory. Those markets definitely favor sellers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Now is a great time to put your home on the market.%20http://buckscountyrealestatevideoblog.com/the-latest-news-from-the-bucks-county-real-estate-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Now is a great time to put your home on the market.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The numbers are a little skewed for Upper Makefield because there are more expensive homes that take longer to sell. There are 7.4 months of inventory in Upper Makefield.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the Falls Township, there are only 1.8 months of inventory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As a result, now is a great time to sell your home.&lt;/strong&gt; You can put your home on the market now and beat the spring rush. Buyers are really complaining that there aren’t enough options for them, so there will be plenty of demand for your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a buyer, keep an eye out for my next video, where I’ll go over what you can do to best position yourself to win in a multiple offer situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://buckscountyrealestatevideoblog.com/the-latest-news-from-the-bucks-county-real-estate-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://buckscountyrealestatevideoblog.com/the-latest-news-from-the-bucks-county-real-estate-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Major Impacts We Expect From the New Tax Bill</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/zyh6Zta0qpQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A happy, healthy New Year to you all! With this new year came a new tax bill that has everyone buzzing. Today, I wanted to talk about what effects this new law will have on the real estate market in Bucks County.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To preface the discussion, I’m not a tax lawyer or an accountant, so in order to understand how exactly you’ll be affected the changes, &lt;strong&gt;it’s critical that you talk to a CPA or tax attorney&lt;/strong&gt;familiar with the law since it won’t affect everyone the same way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important changes as far as homeownership goes relate to the state and local taxes. &lt;strong&gt;There is now a $10,000 limit on state and local taxes&lt;/strong&gt;, which will impact people in higher tax brackets like our neighbors in New Jersey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another key change is that mortgage interest deductions are capped for new mortgages only. This means that existing mortgages will go unaffected. The cap is now set at $750,000, so anything above that is non-deductible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=In a weird way, the tax bill could be helpful for the real estate values in Bucks County.%20http://buckscountyrealestatevideoblog.com/the-major-impacts-we-expect-from-the-new-tax-bill.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“In a weird way, the tax bill could be helpful for the real estate values in Bucks County.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The National Association of Realtors has suggested that in some high-tax states, &lt;strong&gt;there could be as much as a 10% reduction in values.&lt;/strong&gt; In a weird way, this could be helpful for the real estate values in Bucks County, Lower Makefield, Yardley, Newtown, Washington’s Crossing, and Upper Makefield.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the tax bill was passed, I received four or five calls from homeowners from the more expensive areas of New Jersey saying that, because of the bill, they’d be looking to move out of the state. In general, Bucks County is the less expensive area to live in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any further questions about this or other real estate topics, feel free to reach out to me. I’d be glad to speak with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 07:29:56 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://buckscountyrealestatevideoblog.com/the-major-impacts-we-expect-from-the-new-tax-bill.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://buckscountyrealestatevideoblog.com/the-major-impacts-we-expect-from-the-new-tax-bill.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Start Preparing for Your 2018 Home Purchase Today</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2NEkTtzIOa4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you plan on buying a home in 2018, it’s not too early to start preparing for the process. Today, I want to share seven steps that you can take right now to prepare for your home search in the new year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Check your credit score.&lt;/strong&gt; Mortgages are driven by credit scores. The stronger your credit is, the better your interest rate will be. You can check your score with any of the three credit bureaus; you get one free report from each every year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Don’t open new credit cards.&lt;/strong&gt; It may be tempting to open a new store card during the holidays, but doing so will negatively impact your credit score. If you plan on buying a house in 2018, don’t open any new accounts right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. If you are comfortable doing so, ask for financial gifts this holiday season.&lt;/strong&gt;Financial gifts from your family can help make your down payment a little easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Do not open any new credit accounts.%20http://buckscountyrealestatevideoblog.com/start-preparing-for-your-2018-home-purchase-today.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Do not open any new credit accounts.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Interview real estate agents.&lt;/strong&gt;This is an incredibly important step. I love it when prospective buyers want to talk to me so they understand how I work, how I communicate, and whether or not working together would be a good fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several years ago, a prospective buyer sent me 20 questions for me to respond to in writing. Based on those responses, she then picked three agents to interview. It was a pretty comprehensive interview, and she has since purchased a home and became a friend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Keep an eye on interest rates.&lt;/strong&gt;Rates have been pretty steady lately and are still at historic lows, but it’s important to keep an eye on them all the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Find a lender.&lt;/strong&gt;It’s really important that you start the mortgage process before you find your house, so start interviewing lenders now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Get pre-approved.&lt;/strong&gt; When you do choose a lender, make sure you get a letter of pre-approval. That way, when you do start looking and find the right house, you are prepared mentally and financially to take the next step and write an offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, those seven steps will help you get started. If you have any other questions about buying a home in 2018, please don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 05:49:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://buckscountyrealestatevideoblog.com/start-preparing-for-your-2018-home-purchase-today.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://buckscountyrealestatevideoblog.com/start-preparing-for-your-2018-home-purchase-today.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Latest Bucks County Real Estate Information</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/CIxs5kd_DQ8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latest numbers are in for Bucks County real estate. Here’s what they mean for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buying a Bucks County area home?  Perform a full home search
Selling your Bucks County home? Get a free Home Price Evaluation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m excited to share some of the latest statistics from the Bucks County real estate market. These numbers are based on what happened through the end of October. We track about 20 different individual markets throughout the county, but seeing the numbers in Bucks County as a whole is the best way to find out what’s actually going on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re continuing to see low inventory. Lower than we’ve seen in years. At the same time, homes are still selling quickly. Our absorption rate is down from 6.2 months at this time last year to 5.2 months currently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are 13% fewer homes on the market now than there were last year.&lt;/strong&gt; That means we currently have 3,189 homes on the market. This rise in demand has coincided with a rise in appreciation. The 5% appreciation we’ve seen in the past year is the most significant rise we’ve seen in any year since the market downturn in 2008 and 2009.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=WE ARE NOW IN A SELLER’S MARKET.%20http://buckscountyrealestatevideoblog.com/the-latest-bucks-county-real-estate.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“WE ARE NOW IN A SELLER’S MARKET.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The continued market activity is driving demand and putting us in this seller’s market where homes are selling, on average, eight days faster than they did last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re continuing to see a strong market here in Bucks County. &lt;strong&gt;The average asking price discount of 4% is the lowest I’ve seen in quite some time.&lt;/strong&gt; We’re also still seeing multiple offer situations from time to time. Certain homes can still sell for over asking price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we get through the end of the year, we’ll have some more specific market data for you. Until then, give me a call or send me an email if you have any questions about your specific market and I’ll be able to get right back to you. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 11:06:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://buckscountyrealestatevideoblog.com/the-latest-bucks-county-real-estate.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://buckscountyrealestatevideoblog.com/the-latest-bucks-county-real-estate.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Whats Going on in the Real Estate World of Bucks County?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/TfYVtcxyXkg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real estate world of Bucks County has been very interesting. Today, we compare the countywide market figures to some of the individual markets within the county.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buying a Bucks County area home?  Perform a full home search
Selling your Bucks County home? Get a free Home Price Evaluation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s an interesting year in the real estate world of Bucks County. &lt;strong&gt;The number of homes for sale is down 14% at the end of the third quarter compared to last year.&lt;/strong&gt; That’s a pretty significant change in terms of how many houses there are on the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve seen more significant price appreciation throughout the county this year than we have in any year since the real estate decline of 2007 to 2009. &lt;strong&gt;The average price of a house sold in Bucks County has increased 4.5%.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other dynamic that’s interesting is that we’ve actually seen fewer homes on the market, and the number of transactions closed is actually higher—&lt;strong&gt;about 3.2% more homes settled.&lt;/strong&gt; To put that in perspective, that number represents about 5,644 houses that have actually closed in the county.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The average days on market is 58 days.&lt;/strong&gt; This is a countywide figure, and some of the individual markets within Bucks County were a little bit different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s going on in Lower Makefield Township compared with the county? &lt;strong&gt;Well, the inventory level in the township is actually down over 24%,&lt;/strong&gt; which is a really significant decrease in the number of houses that are on the market. The average sale price as of the end of the third quarter is up 5.8%, a little more than what we see in the countywide figure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=WE’VE SEEN MORE SIGNIFICANT PRICE APPRECIATION THROUGHOUT THE COUNTY THIS YEAR THAN WE HAVE IN ANY YEAR SINCE THE REAL ESTATE DECLINE OF 2007 TO 2009.%20http://buckscountyrealestatevideoblog.com/whats-going-on-in-real-estate-world-of.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“WE’VE SEEN MORE SIGNIFICANT PRICE APPRECIATION THROUGHOUT THE COUNTY THIS YEAR THAN WE HAVE IN ANY YEAR SINCE THE REAL ESTATE DECLINE OF 2007 TO 2009.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The big takeaway for Lower Makefield is that there’s only 4.9 months of inventory on the market right now. We consider the market to be balanced when there are only six months of inventory, so it means it’s a seller’s market if you’re looking for a house in Lower Makefield.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difference between the days on market for Newtown Township and the countywide figure is really pronounced. &lt;strong&gt;Believe it or not, the inventory is down 40% compared to this time last year.&lt;/strong&gt; There were 112 houses on the market in Newtown last year, and this year there were 67.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s only a 2.9-month supply of inventory, which wouldn’t indicate that the dynamics are favoring sellers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another interesting dynamic in Newtown is the average sold price as of the end of the third quarter is only up about 1.2%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The average days on market is 39 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Upper Makefield, the dynamic is similar but skewed by the number of houses that are on the market for over $1 million. Inventory is down about 7%. However, there’s about a 10.7-month supply of inventory due to the number of high-priced homes there. &lt;strong&gt;In fact, there’s an almost 19-month backlog of inventory specifically for houses priced over a million dollars.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The takeaway is pretty similar to what we’ve seen through the year: low inventory with prices somewhat appreciating at a level we haven’t seen in awhile. It can be challenging for buyers, but anecdotally, I would say I’ve seen activity drop over the past several weeks with my listings. It will be interesting to see how that plays out statistically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have questions, shoot me a text or an email. I’d be happy to speak with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 10:04:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://buckscountyrealestatevideoblog.com/whats-going-on-in-real-estate-world-of.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://buckscountyrealestatevideoblog.com/whats-going-on-in-real-estate-world-of.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Are Conditions Ripe for You to Sell Your Home This Fall?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/4iLoz3_t0dU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we enter fall, we’re in a strong seller’s market. If you decide to list your home now, I have five tips that will help it get sold quickly and for top dollar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buying a Bucks County area home?  Perform a full home search
Selling your Bucks County home? Get a free Home Price Evaluation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why does it make sense for you to list your home in the fall instead of waiting until next spring?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether the market is favorable to buyers or sellers depends on whether there are more buyers or sellers in the market. **Over the past 12 months, there’s been strong buyer demand but not enough sellers to meet that demand, which has made conditions very favorable to sellers. **&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do decide to take advantage of this opportunity and put your home on the market this fall, &lt;strong&gt;here are five tips that will make your home even more attractive to all those buyers out there:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Accentuate your home’s curb appeal.&lt;/strong&gt; Fall is a great time to spruce up the exterior of your house and make a great first impression on buyers, so lay down some fresh mulch and trim back your bushes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Keep your holiday displays tasteful.&lt;/strong&gt; The approach of the holiday season makes people feel good, and that’s conducive to your home sale. That being said, make sure your holiday displays are tasteful and reasonably done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=USE THESE FIVE TIPS TO SELL QUICKLY AND FOR TOP DOLLAR.%20http://buckscountyrealestatevideoblog.com/why-are-conditions-ripe-for-you-to-sell.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“USE THESE FIVE TIPS TO SELL QUICKLY AND FOR TOP DOLLAR.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Create an inviting interior living space.&lt;/strong&gt; This is rule applies all the time, but make sure you declutter the inside of your home and make your space appear as big as possible. You also want buyers to think there is a lot of storage room in your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. If you have a fireplace, use it.&lt;/strong&gt; Fireplaces (especially gas ones) have a strong emotional appeal during the fall and winter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Enhance fall aromas.&lt;/strong&gt; There’s nothing like the scent of a great fall evening, so if you can capture that scent inside your house, that’s one more strong emotional connection you can make with buyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about any of these tips, you want to know what your home is worth, or you’re thinking about selling your home, don’t hesitate to contact me. I’d be happy to help you in any way I can.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 10:43:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://buckscountyrealestatevideoblog.com/why-are-conditions-ripe-for-you-to-sell.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://buckscountyrealestatevideoblog.com/why-are-conditions-ripe-for-you-to-sell.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Inexpensive Upgrades for You to Make</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/xpPxI_UCro8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting your home ready for sale doesn’t have to be expensive. Here are five inexpensive fixes that will add value to your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buying a Bucks County area home?  Perform a full home search
Selling your Bucks County home? Get a free Home Price Evaluation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to believe, but we’re already approaching mid-August. The Bucks County market is still quite active. We’re continuing to get complaints from buyers that there aren’t enough homes on the market. If you’ve been considering selling your home, now is a great time to accomplish that. It’s also a great time to invest a bit of money into your home in order to reap the benefits when you sell. &lt;strong&gt;Here are five ways you can increase your home’s value for under $100:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Add a light fixture.&lt;/strong&gt; If you have a room in your house that’s dark, brighten it up with one of these. It will make the home more attractive to buyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Add a new bookcase/cabinet.&lt;/strong&gt; For a relatively low price, you can use a new bookcase or cabinet to assist you with decluttering and adding to the room at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A NEW BOOKCASE CAN HELP YOU DECLUTTER AS WELL.%20http://buckscountyrealestatevideoblog.com/5-inexpensive-upgrades-for-you-to-make.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A NEW BOOKCASE CAN HELP YOU DECLUTTER AS WELL.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Paint kitchen cabinets.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s sometimes hard to justify investing in a major update or remodel. However, if your cabinetry looks bare, a coat of paint could make a huge difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Reupholster your old furniture.&lt;/strong&gt; Doing this is an inexpensive alternative to replacing your old furniture outright.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Consider a general paint touch-up in your home.&lt;/strong&gt; I work with a company who is really good at touching up spots that need it. I’d be happy to pass their information along to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each of these home improvements is inexpensive, but they each add more value to your home when it comes time to sell. If you have any questions for me or you’re thinking about selling your home, give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 09:08:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://buckscountyrealestatevideoblog.com/5-inexpensive-upgrades-for-you-to-make.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://buckscountyrealestatevideoblog.com/5-inexpensive-upgrades-for-you-to-make.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tax Appeals: Explained </title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8-5cqnstBmw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taxes always seem too high, but what do you do if they really are? Let’s take a look at the tax appeal process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buying a Bucks County area home?  Perform a full home search
Selling your Bucks County home? Get a free Home Price Evaluation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the years I’ve written a lot about the process of tax appeals. Just this week, a community member interested in learning more gave me a call.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m sure that person wasn’t the only one wondering about the process of tax appeals, though, so I wanted to explain it here too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, how do you go about appealing your taxes? Most everyone believes that their taxes are too high, so how can you make sure that you really qualify to appeal?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your property assessment is the first thing you should turn to. Here in Bucks County, &lt;strong&gt;your assessment should represent 10.4% of your property’s fair market value.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If after checking that value you feel you need to make an appeal, the first step is to go to http://www.buckscounty.org/ and fill out the assessment appeal form for a $35 charge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When making an appeal, you have a couple of options. If you choose the option of doing it yourself, you’ll first need to fill out the form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=THE PROCESS OF APPEALING IS ACTUALLY RATHER SIMPLE.%20http://buckscountyrealestatevideoblog.com/tax-appeals-explained.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“THE PROCESS OF APPEALING IS ACTUALLY RATHER SIMPLE.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the form, you can either include an appraisal or a list of three comparable properties to substantiate your claims. For a property to qualify as being comparable, &lt;strong&gt;it must be in the same municipality, be of similar size, have similar amenities, and be relatively recent.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finding these properties is something I can help with, and I’ve seen some amazing opportunities come from these appeals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, there are attorneys who will handle the appeals for you. In this case, an attorney will charge you a percentage of what your first-year savings would be in the event that they’re successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In truth, the process of appealing is actually rather simple. &lt;strong&gt;The most complicated part is gathering the data to support the appeal.&lt;/strong&gt; If you want to go through the process during this tax season, you’ll need to make the decision whether to move forward soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 16:01:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://buckscountyrealestatevideoblog.com/tax-appeals-explained.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://buckscountyrealestatevideoblog.com/tax-appeals-explained.html</guid>
        
        <category>Bucks County Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>6 Tips for Homebuyers Navigating a Sellers Market </title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/UyZz4K5sc-0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a homebuyer, how do you find a home in a seller’s market? I have six tips to help you today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buying a Bucks County area home?  Perform a full home search
Selling your Bucks County home? Get a free Home Price Evaluation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, the market conditions are somewhat difficult for buyers, as Bucks County is in a seller’s market. Our market is not as crazy as the market in other counties, but inventory levels are down and some homes are selling with multiple offers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are out there actively looking for a home, here are a few tips to help you navigate the market:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Make your initial offer your best offer.&lt;/strong&gt; This may seem counter-intuitive since buyers had more control in the past few years. It used to be that you could initially offer a lower number with the understanding that you would negotiate with the seller. However, making your first offer your best and highest offer can mean the difference between getting the house you want or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Don’t overanalyze the purchase price.&lt;/strong&gt; We are seeing some appreciation in the market, which we haven’t really seen in past years. Prices aren’t wildly escalating, but they are on the rise. So, if a home sells for a certain price in a given neighborhood and you’re looking at a similar home, that seller will probably ask for a little more money than the previous sale. If you are serious about buying, that is something you should expect given current market conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Work with an experienced agent.&lt;/strong&gt; Every agent has to start somewhere, but it can be risky for homebuyers to work with an inexperienced agent in today’s market. Work with an agent who has a good working relationship with other agents in the market. Virtually every other agent in Bucks County knows who I am because I’ve been in real estate for a long time. In a lot of transactions, that really does help. Even in multiple offer situations, my buyer may get picked over the others because I have an established connection with the listing agent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=YOUR FIRST OFFER SHOULD BE YOUR BEST OFFER.%20http://buckscountyrealestatevideoblog.com/6-tips-for-homebuyers-navigating.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“YOUR FIRST OFFER SHOULD BE YOUR BEST OFFER.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Get pre-approved before you start looking for homes.&lt;/strong&gt; Talk to a mortgage lender early on in the process and get pre-approved so that you’re prepared to buy when you find the house you want. It will save you a lot of stress and frustration down the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Be prepared for a multiple offer situation.&lt;/strong&gt; Multiple offer situations are not uncommon right now. It doesn’t happen with every house and there are many factors that lead to a multiple offer situation, but know that it’s a possibility. Don’t be shocked if someone else makes an offer on the home you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Learn from the process.&lt;/strong&gt; I take a lot of pride in my ability to educate buyers so that they understand exactly what’s happening at every step of the process. Even if you make an offer and don’t get the home, step back and learn from it. Don’t frantically chase after a house that you didn’t get and end up overpaying for it; just learn from the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are looking to buy in the current market or if you have any other real estate questions, give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 09:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://buckscountyrealestatevideoblog.com/6-tips-for-homebuyers-navigating.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://buckscountyrealestatevideoblog.com/6-tips-for-homebuyers-navigating.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
