<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- MARKET -- Real Estate Video Blog with -- CLIENT NAME --</title>
    <description>Our mission at Andy Richardson Home Selling Team is to be your best resource for Wilmington real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Andy Richardson Home Selling Team, your professional Wilmington Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 13:38:52 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 13:38:52 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Much Will You Really Have to Put Down to Buy a Home?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/AaA9g8uKzoA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are plenty of financing options available that allow you to put down less than 20% to buy a home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.searchwilmingtonhomevalues.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;How much would your Wilmington home sell for in today's market?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Want to buy a Wilmington Home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.searchwilmingtonhomesforsale.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all homes for sale.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a buyer, how much down payment money do you really need in our market?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=THE MAJORITY OF ALL BUYERS PUT DOWN LESS THAN 10%.%20localhost:4000/how-much-will-you-really-have-to-put.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“THE MAJORITY OF ALL BUYERS PUT DOWN LESS THAN 10%.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many still believe they have to put down at least 20% or more, but that’s simply not the case. According to the National Association of Realtors, from October 2016 to November 2017, the average down payment amount for first-time homebuyers was just 6%. Also, 61% of first-time homebuyers put even less than 6% down. The majority of all buyers put down less than 10%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here in the Wilmington market, we have some really great homes that qualify for 100% financing, USDA financing, and other forms of low or no down payment financing.&lt;/strong&gt; We also work with some really great lenders in the area who specialize in loan programs that require a low down payment or no down payment at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about what kind of down payment you can expect to pay in our market or you need help buying or selling a home, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 11:34:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-much-will-you-really-have-to-put.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/how-much-will-you-really-have-to-put.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Monday Market Update 2-5-18</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0nKC6_urEng?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.searchwilmingtonhomevalues.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;How much would your Wilmington home sell for in today's market?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Want to buy a Wilmington Home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.searchwilmingtonhomesforsale.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all homes for sale.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 18:57:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/monday-market-update-2-5-18.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/monday-market-update-2-5-18.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>List Now, Beat the Competition, and Get a Better Deal</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/K7Yi8Yp_Gwk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it’s time for you to sell your home, why wait? There are some great opportunities on our market for sellers right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.searchwilmingtonhomevalues.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;How much would your Wilmington home sell for in today's market?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Want to buy a Wilmington Home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.searchwilmingtonhomesforsale.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all homes for sale.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been thinking of selling in 2018, now may be the best time to get a jump on the competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People often refer to the spring market as “the selling season,” and while it is true that there are more buyers in the spring market, there is also more competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;According to the laws of supply and demand, getting on the market before other sellers do could help you earn a higher price for your property.&lt;/strong&gt; In other words, it’s a great time to put your home on the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are thinking of selling and would like a free copy of our report “How to Sell Your Home for 18% More Money,” give me a call and I would be happy to send it out. I would also be happy to drop by and give you a free home evaluation of your property before you list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=IT’S A GREAT TIME TO PUT YOUR HOME ON THE MARKET.%20localhost:4000/list-now-beat-competition-and-get.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“IT’S A GREAT TIME TO PUT YOUR HOME ON THE MARKET.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are a few, inexpensive fixes I can recommend that might help add value to your home before you sell.&lt;/strong&gt; Additionally, there may be some projects or updates you’re considering that might not be worth it. These are the kinds of things I can guide you through when you contact me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 12:10:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/list-now-beat-competition-and-get.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/list-now-beat-competition-and-get.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Take Advantage of Fall Colors When Listing Your Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/04mazE8PX7o?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t be fooled by common misconceptions; fall is a better time to sell your home than the spring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.searchwilmingtonhomevalues.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;How much would your Wilmington home sell for in today's market?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Want to buy a Wilmington Home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.searchwilmingtonhomesforsale.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all homes for sale.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people believe that spring is a better time to put their home on the market. Today, I’m here to tell you why this isn’t the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main reason to sell now rather than wait until spring is &lt;strong&gt;you’ll have more competition in the spring than you would in the fall.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s true that there are typically more buyers out in the spring, but the thing about fall buyers is that &lt;strong&gt;they’re more serious and more motivated to buy your house.&lt;/strong&gt; No one really wants to buy a house during the holidays, so the ones that are looking at houses now are going to be more motivated going into closing. That can also mean a faster sale and a higher price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=FALL BUYERS ARE MORE MOTIVATED TO BUY YOUR HOUSE.%20localhost:4000/take-advantage-of-fall-colors-when.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“FALL BUYERS ARE MORE MOTIVATED TO BUY YOUR HOUSE.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other good thing about listing in the fall is that the grass is still pretty green, and we have beautiful autumn colors, so &lt;strong&gt;it’s a great time to take pictures of your home to highlight its positive qualities.&lt;/strong&gt; If you wait until winter, you’ll find that everything is kind of dreary and brown—not a pretty backdrop for any photography. You’d then have to wait further into spring to list your house, when you could be missing a good portion of the spring market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re going to take your pictures now and get your house ready for the market, you’re probably going to experience a better selling situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about preparing your home for the fall market, feel free to give me a call or shoot me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 11:21:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/take-advantage-of-fall-colors-when.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/take-advantage-of-fall-colors-when.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How the Golden Rule Applies to Real Estate</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ta1LIRdvlXw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even when you are in a position of power as a seller, it is important to always be respectful of the buyer. After all, a buyer in the hand is worth two in the bush.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.searchwilmingtonhomevalues.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;How much would your Wilmington home sell for in today's market?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Want to buy a Wilmington Home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.searchwilmingtonhomesforsale.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all homes for sale.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve all heard the saying that a bird in the hand is worth two in the bush. However, this saying is also true when it comes to buyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In today’s competitive real estate market, there are more buyers than there are homes. As a result, sellers today tend to believe that they are in a position of power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this is true in terms of negotiation, there are still things to be careful of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, you don’t want to scare off any buyers that are interested in a home. In any real estate transaction, a lot of things can go wrong. &lt;strong&gt;Whether it is an issue with repairs, interest rates, or the appraisal, there are a lot of variables that go into the process.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should always avoid being disrespectful to interested buyers. Never assume that another buyer will come along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=ALWAYS TREAT OTHERS THE WAY YOU WANT TO BE TREATED.%20localhost:4000/how-golden-rule-applies-to-real-estate.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“ALWAYS TREAT OTHERS THE WAY YOU WANT TO BE TREATED.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this may be the case, you still want to get your house off the market as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if another buyer does come along, they will be deterred from your property if they see that a deal has fallen through in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important, therefore, &lt;strong&gt;that you do everything you can to work with an interested buyer when one comes along.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The golden rule applies in real estate as much as it does in life. Always treat others the way you want to be treated. If you have any questions about working with interested buyers or any other real estate topics, feel free to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 13:57:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-golden-rule-applies-to-real-estate.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/how-golden-rule-applies-to-real-estate.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Taking Advantage of Our Sellers Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/GegklCH3G-o?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conditions in our market have aligned to greatly favor sellers, so if you’ve been thinking about listing your home, now might be the time to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.searchwilmingtonhomevalues.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;How much would your Wilmington home sell for in today's market?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Want to buy a Wilmington Home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.searchwilmingtonhomesforsale.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all homes for sale.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve given any thought to selling your home in the next year, you might want to consider putting your home on the market right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to a recent study by the National Association of Realtors, &lt;strong&gt;there are still a lot of buyers in our market, but there aren’t a lot of homes available for purchase.&lt;/strong&gt; Any time buyers outpace the supply of inventory, it creates a seller’s market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=AS A SELLER, YOU CAN ACCEPT MORE FAVORABLE TERMS FOR YOUR HOME IN A SELLER’S MARKET.%20localhost:4000/taking-advantage-of-our-sellers-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“AS A SELLER, YOU CAN ACCEPT MORE FAVORABLE TERMS FOR YOUR HOME IN A SELLER’S MARKET.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a seller, these conditions give you more negotiation power when it comes to what offer you accept on your home and how you dictate the terms of that offer. They can also affect how many repairs you need to make on your home before you put it on the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about the current state of our market or you’re thinking of about buying or selling a home, feel free to give me a call or shoot me an email. I’d be happy to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 09:40:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/taking-advantage-of-our-sellers-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/taking-advantage-of-our-sellers-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Pre-Approval Is Critical to Any Home Search </title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Q7gQJon6jF8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m here to tell you about why getting pre-approved is so important as well as what lenders will look at when you go to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.searchwilmingtonhomevalues.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;How much would your Wilmington home sell for in today's market?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Want to buy a Wilmington Home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.searchwilmingtonhomesforsale.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all homes for sale.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any real estate purchase, pre-approval should be one of the first steps you take.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here in Wilmington, we’re currently experiencing a trend that is common throughout the country—the number of buyers is outweighing the number of available properties. Getting a pre-approval for a mortgage will give &lt;strong&gt;you not only a starting point in terms of what to search for, but it will also show the seller that you’re serious.&lt;/strong&gt; In fact, most sellers won’t even consider an offer without an attached pre-approval letter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pre-approval will make you and your offer stronger from the very start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what does a lender look at when you go to get pre-approved? We can break the factors down into Freddie Mac’s four C’s. &lt;strong&gt;The first C stands for “capacity,” which denotes a buyer’s ability to pay the monthly mortgage.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=PRE-APPROVAL WILL MAKE YOU AND YOUR OFFER STRONGER FROM THE VERY START.%20localhost:4000/why-pre-approval-is-critical-to-any.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“PRE-APPROVAL WILL MAKE YOU AND YOUR OFFER STRONGER FROM THE VERY START.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next C is your credit score. This number will help indicate to the lender how diligently you’ve paid your debts in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next are capital or cash reserves. A lender will look at sources from which you can draw money, such as savings accounts or investments, to have a better understanding of how stable your finances are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the last C stands for “collateral.” Collateral depends upon the property you’re purchasing, which will also affect the appraisal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 15:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/why-pre-approval-is-critical-to-any.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/why-pre-approval-is-critical-to-any.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Busting 2 Home Buying Myths</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/m4n6550Mxsc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Home buying isn’t as scary or expensive as you probably think. Here’s what we mean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.searchwilmingtonhomevalues.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;How much would your Wilmington home sell for in today's market?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Want to buy a Wilmington Home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.searchwilmingtonhomesforsale.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all homes for sale.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a recent Realtor.com survey, 46% of prospective homebuyers didn’t think they would qualify for a mortgage, so they didn’t even bother applying. There are two common myths behind this way of thinking, and we’re going to bust both of them today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. You need 20% for a down payment.&lt;/strong&gt; That’s not true at all. In today’s market, you can get a loan for 5%, 3%, or even 0% down. We can find a program that works for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. You need a credit score of 780.&lt;/strong&gt; This is another complete falsehood. In the same survey mentioned above, 53.2% of homebuyers had a credit score between 600 and 750. That gives you a pretty good idea right there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=YOU DON’T NEED A CREDIT SCORE OF 780.%20localhost:4000/busting-2-home-buying-myths.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“YOU DON’T NEED A CREDIT SCORE OF 780.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, this debunks those myths for you if you were under the impression that they were true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about buying a home or need any other help, feel free to give me a call or send me an email anytime. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 15:08:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/busting-2-home-buying-myths.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/busting-2-home-buying-myths.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Ways to Reduce Your Closing Costs</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/LH7FHzYCor8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is there any way to lower closing costs? There are three different strategies that you can use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.searchwilmingtonhomevalues.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;How much would your Wilmington home sell for in today's market?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Want to buy a Wilmington Home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.searchwilmingtonhomesforsale.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all homes for sale.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can you reduce your closing costs?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, closing costs generally are what they are. However, you can shop around with different closing attorneys and lenders to determine what their rates are. Whenever you talk to a lender, I recommend asking for a good faith estimate. That way, you can determine what their fees and rates are. Then, you can compare apples to apples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While you may not be able to reduce the closing costs themselves, we do have three strategies you can use to reduce the amount of money you have to pay out of pocket:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Close on the home toward the end of the month.&lt;/strong&gt; Doing so will reduce the interim interest you would pay on the closing. Let’s say you closed on the 25th of June. You would owe interim interest from the 25th to the 30th of the month. Plus, instead of having to make a July payment, you wouldn’t have to make a payment until August. Basically, closing toward the end of the month reduces the amount you have to pay out of pocket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=YOUR AGENT CAN NEGOTIATE FOR THE SELLER TO COVER A PORTION OF THE CLOSING COSTS.%20localhost:4000/3-ways-to-reduce-your-closing-costs.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“YOUR AGENT CAN NEGOTIATE FOR THE SELLER TO COVER A PORTION OF THE CLOSING COSTS.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Ask the seller to pay a portion of the closing costs.&lt;/strong&gt; We can ask the seller to pay a specific amount, like $3,500 or $4,500. The seller’s portion comes out of the proceeds of the sale, which reduces the seller’s net. You need an expert agent to negotiate for you if you want the seller to cover part of the closing costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Ask the lender to wrap the closing costs into your mortgage.&lt;/strong&gt; This option could increase the interest rate on your mortgage as well as your mortgage fees, but you would still reduce the amount that you have to pay out of pocket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about these strategies or would like to learn more about buying a home, give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 15:33:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/3-ways-to-reduce-your-closing-costs.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/3-ways-to-reduce-your-closing-costs.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Closing Costs Explained</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2iac8V4mROE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ve probably heard of closing costs before, but do you know what they actually entail?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.searchwilmingtonhomevalues.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;How much would your Wilmington home sell for in today's market?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Want to buy a Wilmington Home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.searchwilmingtonhomesforsale.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all homes for sale.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you buy a home, there are some closing costs that you should expect and be prepared to pay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Closing is defined as the time when the title is transferred from the seller to the buyer, and that’s the time when these closing costs are paid. It typically runs about 2% to 5% of the purchase price, but it can vary depending on the loan type.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Closing costs typically include an application fee with the lender, an appraisal fee, interim interest, home inspections, attorney fees, and title insurance.&lt;/strong&gt; You might also have to pay a credit certification fee and a flood determination fee to find out whether your home is in a flood zone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=CLOSING COSTS TYPICALLY RUN ABOUT 2% TO 5% OF THE PURCHASE PRICE.%20localhost:4000/closing-costs-explained.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“CLOSING COSTS TYPICALLY RUN ABOUT 2% TO 5% OF THE PURCHASE PRICE.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All these payments are made at closing, but some can be paid in advance like your home inspections and appraisal. If so, you’ll get a credit at closing for the amount you paid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about closing costs, or you’re thinking about buying or selling a home here in the Wilmington area, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I’d be glad to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 13:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/closing-costs-explained.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/closing-costs-explained.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate Tips and Tricks</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
