<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mansfield Real Estate Video Blog</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Teixeira Realty Group - your professional Mansfield Area Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://jtexvideoblog.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://jtexvideoblog.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 10:03:57 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 10:03:57 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Path to Homeownership Is Already Paved</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/NkCUHKwRCVs&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s the biggest obstacle to homeownership?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to a recent survey, “saving enough for a down payment” comes at the top of the list. A whopping 55% of prospective homebuyers cited this as their main stumbling block. With the continuing growth of home prices, things aren’t getting any easier. &lt;strong&gt;In fact, homeownership rates reached a 20-year low last November.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t always like this. A decade ago, many lenders were offering easy, no-money-down mortgages. However, after the financial crisis, mortgage standards have become more restrictive. A typical mortgage now requires a 20% down payment. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the good news. If you have decent credit and a steady income, you might be qualified for a number of specialized programs that require no or very little down payment. Here are a few of the top options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First, there’s the USDA loan&lt;/strong&gt;, which is valid for homes in certain regions, such as rural and suburban areas. With zero money down and lenient credit requirements, the USDA loan can be a great choice for many homeowners. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Second, there’s the VA loan&lt;/strong&gt;, which you can apply for if you or your spouse served in a branch of the military. It’s possibly the most generous zero-money-down mortgage because of low interest rates and low closing costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Third, there’s the FHA loan&lt;/strong&gt;. It does require a 3.5% down payment — still drastically more achievable than the 20% required for a conventional mortgage. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, there are a number credit unions and first-time homebuyer programs that might apply to your particular situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=There are many ways to make owning a home a reality.%20http://jtexvideoblog.com/a-path-to-homeownership-is-already-paved.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“There are many ways to make owning a home a reality.”&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;There’s one important thing you should know. If you get one of these no-money-down mortgages, chances are good you will be required to pay private mortgage insurance, which can drive up your monthly payments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, private mortgage insurance will disappear after your mortgage balance is under 80%. Also, the money you do pay will be tax deductible in most cases. In short, there are lots of options to make owning a home a reality for you, &lt;strong&gt;even if you haven’t saved up tens of thousands of dollars.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
&lt;br /&gt;If you have any questions for me or you’re looking to buy or sell a home in Mansfield, give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://jtexvideoblog.com/a-path-to-homeownership-is-already-paved.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jtexvideoblog.com/a-path-to-homeownership-is-already-paved.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Home Selling Tips for Pet Owners</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/LiCHlQFo-Gk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a pet and you’re looking to sell your home, we have some helpful advice for you.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The good news is, many homebuyers are looking for a pet-friendly home.&lt;/strong&gt; Two out of three of us have a pet, and 61% of pet owners say they have trouble finding a home that is a good match for their pet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, a recent survey estimates that 31% of animal owners frequently don’t put in an offer because a home would not suit their pet. This means that if your home is a good match for a pet, it will be attractive to a large pool of dedicated animal owners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, 67% of Realtors also estimate that actually having a pet in your home can make it harder for you to sell. So what can you do? Here are three things I typically recommend:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Repair any damage.&lt;/strong&gt; Floors, walls, doors, the yard — these are some typical areas that pets love to chew, scratch, and dig up. Repairing this damage is an investment that will pay for itself many times over in terms of a higher selling price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Get a professional to remove pet odors.&lt;/strong&gt; Many pet owners are less sensitive to odors in their home than prospective buyers will be. That’s why you should hire a professional cleaning crew to clean any carpets, rugs, or upholstery that have absorbed pet odors. Once you’re done with the cleaning, ask a friend or your Realtor for a sniff assessment to make sure the job is really complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Take your pet out during showings.&lt;/strong&gt; Some people are afraid of animals. Others are allergic. And regardless of the time, money, and effort you’ve put in to clean and repair your home, many buyers will be prejudiced by knowing that a pet currently lives there. That’s why I recommend taking your pet out during showings and also removing any pet objects such as toys, food bowls, or scratching posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The good news is that many buyers want a pet-friendly home.%20http://jtexvideoblog.com/home-selling-tips-for-pet-owners.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The good news is that many buyers want a pet-friendly home.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By following these three simple guidelines, you will be able to sell your home for top dollar, whether the buyer is a pet owner or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in case you have any questions or concerns about preparing your home for a sale, give me a call. I’m here to help. In the meantime, have a great day, from all of us at Teixeira Realty Group.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://jtexvideoblog.com/home-selling-tips-for-pet-owners.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jtexvideoblog.com/home-selling-tips-for-pet-owners.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Updates</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mortgage Minute: The Cost of Waiting</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/COGTqH4l15I&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mortgage interest rates are one of the hottest topics with homebuyers right now. Many buyers are currently wondering whether they should wait for interest rates to go back down, but they are only expected to go up. The Federal Reserve has already increased rates and signaled that there are more increases to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The days of 3% interest rates are gone right now, but the good news is that rates are still at historic lows at about 4% currently. Here’s an example of why it’s smart to buy now and lock in a low rate rather than waiting six months or a year. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a $250,000 house under current rates, your principal and interest payments would be about $1,189 a month. Conservatively estimating that the house will appreciate 5%, &lt;strong&gt;waiting a year would mean the same house would cost about $262,500&lt;/strong&gt;. If interest rates went up 0.5% this year as expected, the same house would cost you an additional $136 a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Both values and interest rates could tick up if you wait to buy a home.%20http://jtexvideoblog.com/mortgage-minute-the-cost-of-waiting.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Both values and interest rates could tick up if you wait to buy a home.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re selling your house, remember that as rates tick up, the buyer pool for your home shrinks since fewer people will qualify for your home at an increased price. If a buyer’s income doesn’t go up, they might be priced out of that house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buying a home sooner also means you will start building equity sooner in addition to getting it cheaper&lt;/strong&gt;. There’s really no reason to wait and watch interest rates and home values continue to go up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any mortgage or financing questions for Trever, you can call him at (972) 822-7408 or email him at Trever.Kerr@GatewayLoan.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about the Mansfield real estate market or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home, you can always give me a call or send me an email. I’m here to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://jtexvideoblog.com/mortgage-minute-the-cost-of-waiting.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jtexvideoblog.com/mortgage-minute-the-cost-of-waiting.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What You Need to Know About the Mortgage Lending Process</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/pU68b7wi0-E&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking about buying a home, your first step before actually looking at homes should be to understand the mortgage lending process. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help me broach this topic, I’m joined for the very first time today by my preferred lender, Trever Kerr of Gateway Mortgage. Trever has been in the business for 15 years, and I’ve been working with him for over 10 years. He’s the only lender I refer to my clients, and Gateway Mortgage makes many exceptions for their clients that other lenders can’t. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first part of the mortgage lending process is to &lt;strong&gt;find out whether you qualify for a loan&lt;/strong&gt;. If you don’t qualify, your lender can tell you what you need to do to get qualified down the road. In addition to knowing what you qualify for, you also have to work with your lender to know what your comfort level is as far as what your monthly payments will be. Even though you might qualify for a $300,000 home, you might only want payments on a $200,000 home. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t speak to a lender, you won’t know what your roadmap to homeownership is. Some people think they can qualify when they can’t, while others think they can’t qualify when they actually can. These people do the wrong things for their credit thinking they’re doing the right things, like paying off their collections once they think they’ll purchase a house soon. Trever and I both see this happen all the time. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you don’t speak to a lender, you won’t know what your roadmap to homeownership is.%20http://jtexvideoblog.com/what-you-need-to-know-about-the-mortgage-lending-process.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you don’t speak to a lender, you won’t know what your roadmap to homeownership is.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paying credit repair companies to help you fix your credit score isn’t necessarily the best idea, either. Many of these companies end up doing things that hurt their customers. To be clear, I’m not bashing the credit repair industry as a whole. There’s a place for it for some people, but overall, a lot of it is unnecessary, especially when you can call an expert like Trever and get his advice for free. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your loan qualification guidelines in our current market can depend on the type of loan product you intend to get, but &lt;strong&gt;you can generally qualify with a credit score as low as 600&lt;/strong&gt;. If you don’t have the cash for the down payment and closing costs, there are different gift programs available for first-time homebuyers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, your debt-to-income ratio must also be in line. As a general rule of thumb, &lt;strong&gt;a debt-to-income ratio for the purchase of a home should be 35% of your total gross income before taxes&lt;/strong&gt;. The second part of that ratio is the 45% of your total gross income you’re allowed to use to cover your house payment, taxes, insurance, and other bills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to thank Trever for helping me today. Stay tuned for more videos featuring both Trever and I where we’ll talk more in depth about credit scores, debt-to-income ratios, and other facets of the lending process. If you have any questions for him, you can call him at (972) 822-7408 or email him at &lt;a href=&quot;javascript:void(location.href='mailto:'+String.fromCharCode(84,114,101,118,101,114,46,75,101,114,114,64,103,97,116,101,119,97,121,108,111,97,110,46,99,111,109))&quot;&gt;Trever.Kerr@gatewayloan.com&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me, please feel free to give me a call or shoot me an email. I’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://jtexvideoblog.com/what-you-need-to-know-about-the-mortgage-lending-process.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jtexvideoblog.com/what-you-need-to-know-about-the-mortgage-lending-process.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Your Neighbors Can Help You Sell Your Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/O2D599uZNDE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking of selling your home, you need to immediately start preparing your neighbors. Here’s what I mean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home appraisals are 5% to 10% lower if you have a so-called “bad” neighbor&lt;/strong&gt; with an unkempt yard or poorly maintained exterior. That shouldn’t be surprising when you consider that 63% of homebuyers drive by a home before coming for a showing. Make no mistake—these potential buyers won’t just be impacted by the exterior of your home, but by the state of your neighborhood as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, your neighbors can also be your best friends in selling your home. They can provide you with free advertising, they can promote the neighborhood to inquiring buyers, and they might even actively work with you to help you achieve a higher price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are three tips on working with your neighbors to achieve a faster, more profitable sale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, &lt;strong&gt;set up a special open house just for your neighbors&lt;/strong&gt;. Many neighbors will be curious for a peek inside your home. You can make the deal even more enticing by providing some free snacks and drinks. Use this open house as an opportunity to show off your home, as well as to build better relationships with your neighbors so they’ll be more inclined to help you during the sale process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One way to do this is to be forthcoming with information, including the price you’re aiming for, renovations you’re planning, or showings that might eat up local parking for an afternoon. Get your neighbors involved, ask them for suggestions, and ask them how you can make the process easier for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Your neighbors can be your best friends when selling your house.%20http://jtexvideoblog.com/how-your-neighbors-can-help-you-sell-your-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Your neighbors can be your best friends when selling your house.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, don’t forget to mention that if you are successful in selling your home, this will positively impact the values of all homes in the neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Second, organize a neighborhood cleanup party&lt;/strong&gt;. This is an opportunity to boost the image and value of your entire neighborhood, as well as to further cement good relations with your neighbors. You can also use this as a discreet way to suggest small home improvement projects to your neighbors. Which leads me to the third and final tip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also &lt;strong&gt;offer to help with—or even pay for—any upgrades you’d like to see&lt;/strong&gt; on your neighbors’ homes. For example, if you’re having a landscaping crew come as part of your sale preparations, ask your neighbors with the overgrown lawn if they’d be ok with the landscapers also taking care of their yard for free. These kinds of small investments can be worth thousands of dollars in terms of your final sale price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to get an estimate of what your home is currently worth without any of these upgrades or you need more advice on dealing with your neighbors in preparation for a home sale, just give me a call or send me an email. I’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://jtexvideoblog.com/how-your-neighbors-can-help-you-sell-your-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jtexvideoblog.com/how-your-neighbors-can-help-you-sell-your-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to File Taxes as a Homeowner in 2017</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/GnniOb_VnH0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you bought your first home in 2016, then you are in for a very new tax experience this year. Why? After you buy a house, it makes sense to &lt;strong&gt;itemize your taxes&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good news is that itemizing your taxes is surprisingly easy to do. There are a few things you need to keep in mind in order to save the most on taxes while minimizing your filing headaches. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, you need to locate your closing disclosure agreement. This is part of your closing paperwork provided by your lender. Then, you can add up the four main real estate deductions: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loan costs and fees&lt;/strong&gt;: These are the different fees from your lender spread throughout the closing disclosure agreement. Different lenders will call them by different names, so look for terms like “application fee,” “underwriting fee,” and “loan cost.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mortgage interest&lt;/strong&gt;: You can deduct the entire interest portion of your mortgage payments. This will probably be your biggest deduction, especially at the start of your mortgage when interest rates are highest.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Property taxes&lt;/strong&gt;: You can deduct property taxes for the part of the year in which you owned the home. Amazingly, you can claim this deduction even if you managed to negotiate for the seller to pay the full year’s property taxes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mortgage insurance&lt;/strong&gt;: If you put less than 20% down when you bought the house, you probably have to pay private mortgage insurance. The good news is that PMI is tax deductible. Keep in mind that private mortgage insurance is completely different from homeowners insurance, which is not deductible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You can deduct the entire interest portion from your monthly mortgage payments.%20http://jtexvideoblog.com/how-to-file-taxes-as-a-homeowner-in-2017.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You can deduct the entire interest portion from your monthly mortgage payments.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few other items that you might be able to itemize when filing your taxes. For example, if you gave away furniture or appliances before moving in, those items can be deducted as a charitable donation. If you work from home, then you can claim additional deductions from that. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The standard deduction for individuals is $6,300 while the standard deduction for married couples is $12,600. If your total is less than the standard deduction, then congratulations; you will save more money this year by itemizing your taxes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although most of these tips are for new homeowners, other homeowners can also save money by itemizing their taxes. If you have any questions about filing taxes as a homeowner, or if you would like to know more about becoming a homeowner in 2017, give us a call. We would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://jtexvideoblog.com/how-to-file-taxes-as-a-homeowner-in-2017.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jtexvideoblog.com/how-to-file-taxes-as-a-homeowner-in-2017.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Owner Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Rising Interest Rates Will Affect the Mansfield Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/uZ4F8hd3lIY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re concerned about the recent rise in mortgage rates, I want to reassure you—things are much better than they might seem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, mortgage rates have certainly risen. From a low of 3.44% last August, the 30-year fixed mortgage rate reached 4.12% recently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This increase means that if you took out a 30-year mortgage on a $250,000 home, you’d pay almost $100 more each month. &lt;strong&gt;Your overall mortgage cost would be almost $35,000 higher.&lt;/strong&gt; That’s a sizeable change, and it’s got some people nervous about a possible slowdown in the real estate market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the current rise in rates is unlikely to affect the real estate market any time soon. The rates we saw last year were an all-time record low. Historically, rates have been far higher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ten years ago, the same 30-year mortgage rate stood at 6.34%. For much of the 90s, rates hovered between 7% and 10%. Throughout the 80s, average annual rates never dipped below 10%. In 1982, they were as high as 16%. When viewed in this context, it’s clear that current mortgage rates are still very low, and that the real estate market is actually in a very good place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what does this mean for you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, if you are looking to buy a home, &lt;strong&gt;the current low rates offer a great opportunity to afford an amazing home.&lt;/strong&gt; Second, if you’re looking to sell your home, you are in a great position to do so quickly and at top price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The current rise in rates is unlikely to affect the real estate market any time soon.%20http://jtexvideoblog.com/how-rising-interest-rates-will-affect-the-mansfield-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The current rise in rates is unlikely to affect the real estate market any time soon.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last December saw a drop in home sales, but not because of any rise in mortgage rates. Instead, this slowdown was due to a constrained supply of new homes. In fact, there are plenty of eager buyers around Mansfield and prices continue to rise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to discuss upcoming trends in mortgage rates and how they could affect you—whether you’re buying or selling a house—give me a call or send me an email. I’d be happy to help however I can.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://jtexvideoblog.com/how-rising-interest-rates-will-affect-the-mansfield-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jtexvideoblog.com/how-rising-interest-rates-will-affect-the-mansfield-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Updates</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How New Tax Rules Could Affect the Mansfield Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-8FBfx8C14U&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you heard the news?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new administration is looking to revamp the tax code in a way that affects the long-standing mortgage interest deduction (MID). Some people are concerned this might impact home sales and drive down home values. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe it will do just the opposite. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First — a bit of background. Under the current system, you can include the interest you pay on your mortgage in your itemized tax deductions. &lt;strong&gt;If your itemized deductions turn out to be more than your standard deduction, you save more on taxes. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, about 20% of homeowners who have a mortgage take advantage of the MID for an annual average savings of $2,000 in taxes. Under the proposed new tax plan, the standard tax deduction would almost double. For example, the standard deduction for a married couple would go from $12,600 to $24,000. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this happens, an estimated 84% of people who currently itemize taxes would simply go for the standard deduction, and this is the part that has some people worried. After all, if people don’t take advantage of the MID, won’t this decrease the value of owning a home?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are two reasons why that won’t happen. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First, most people do not buy a home in order to save on taxes.&lt;/strong&gt; A survey from 2015 confirms this fact. The top reasons why people buy a home include the need for change, an increase in income, or a baby on the way, but there’s no mention of saving on taxes. This bears out what most real estate professionals see in real life. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=People don’t buy a home just to save on taxes.%20http://jtexvideoblog.com/how-new-tax-rules-could-affect-the-mansfield-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“People don’t buy a home just to save on taxes.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, taxes will actually be lower under the proposed new plan. Traditional estimates of the impact of the MID assume other taxes stay the same. In this case, if the deduction goes away, home prices can indeed suffer to an extent. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But under the proposed new plan, the overall tax burden will be less than it currently is. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, most people will not lose money because they aren’t claiming the MID. Instead, they will gain money by paying less in taxes altogether. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With more disposable income, people will be free to spend more on a home. This will drive sales as well as prices. The fact is, current home prices around Mansfield keep increasing — not because of tax breaks, but because of tight supply. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about the new tax plan and how it will affect the real estate market or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home in the Mansfield area, give us a call or send us an email. We’re always happy to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://jtexvideoblog.com/how-new-tax-rules-could-affect-the-mansfield-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jtexvideoblog.com/how-new-tax-rules-could-affect-the-mansfield-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Updates</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Don’t Wait for Spring to Sell Your Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_m8d6sNtTr4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is listing your home in the winter a good idea? The answer is yes, and here’s why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Homes listed during the winter are 9% more likely to sell than homes listed during the other seasons.&lt;/strong&gt; These properties, on average, sell a week faster, sell for 1.2% more than their list price, and are more likely to sell above asking price than the homes listed in summer or fall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re surprised by these statistics, you’re not alone. Conventional real estate wisdom says to pass on the winter market and wait for the spring. However, as you can see from the numbers, &lt;strong&gt;passing on the winter market would be a mistake.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s true that there are less buyers in the winter, but that isn’t necessarily a problem as buyers during the winter are more motivated. Some of them might need to get into a new home for a job relocation, some might want to take advantage of low interest rates before another increase occurs, and some have been searching for months with no luck in finding their dream home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Homes listed during the winter sell a week faster than those listed during the other seasons.%20http://jtexvideoblog.com/dont-wait-for-spring-to-sell-your-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Homes listed during the winter sell a week faster than those listed during the other seasons.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are looking to sell your home, I would definitely recommend selling in the winter. However, keep in mind that the winter market is a whole different ballgame. &lt;strong&gt;For example, you really need to list your home as close to market value as possible&lt;/strong&gt; because an overpriced home causes low buyer interest and strips away time for any price reductions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to know the current value of your home, get advice on how to prepare your home for the winter market, or if you have any other real estate related questions, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://jtexvideoblog.com/dont-wait-for-spring-to-sell-your-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jtexvideoblog.com/dont-wait-for-spring-to-sell-your-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Quick Update on the Mansfield Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/PcQOdl2XNlQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With regards to how our market has fared since the election, there is some good news and some bad news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, the bad: mortgage rates have shot up since the election.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a low of 3.74% on November 7th, the average fixed 30-year mortgage rate increased to over 4% by the end of November.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economists are saying this kind of volatility is likely to continue, with day-to-day changes driven by the moves and statements of the new administration.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good news is that there are plenty of reasons to be optimistic down the line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Promised tax breaks for high earners could reinvigorate sales of luxury homes, which have seen a glut lately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This could have a ripple effect throughout the rest of the real estate market, spurring sales and construction of mid-level and lower-priced housing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, looser financial regulation could make it easier for buyers to obtain mortgages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One piece of good news is that the election is finally over. Also, you might have seen that the stock market has been surging in the past few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=More people are entering the market now that the election is over.%20http://jtexvideoblog.com/a-quick-update-on-the-mansfield-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“More people are entering the market now that the election is over.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That might be a vote of confidence for our President and his anticipated business-friendly policies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It certainly seems things are getting back to normal as people come to realize the world’s not ending.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, many people who were waiting on the sidelines while the election was going on are now entering the real estate market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a great time to take advantage of this if you are selling.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;If you want an idea of what your home could sell for in the current market, just send me an email to &lt;a href=&quot;javascript:void(location.href='mailto:'+String.fromCharCode(109,121,104,111,109,101,115,118,97,108,117,101,64,106,116,101,105,120,115,101,108,108,115,46,99,111,109))&quot;&gt;myhomesvalue@jteixsells.com&lt;/a&gt; with your address in the subject line and I’ll get back to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you’re looking to buy, there are two things you should know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, even though mortgage rates have gone up, they are still historically very low, and worth taking advantage of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, many new homes have entered the market since the election, and more new listings will arrive as the spring market approaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s definitely worth investigating what’s available around DFW right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, don’t hesitate to reach out and give us a call or send us an email.  We look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://jtexvideoblog.com/a-quick-update-on-the-mansfield-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jtexvideoblog.com/a-quick-update-on-the-mansfield-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Updates</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
