<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Salt Lake County Real Estate Video Blog with Joshua Stern</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a Salt Lake County home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Stern Team- your professional Salt Lake City Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>localhost:5000/</link>
    <atom:link href="localhost:5000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 16:25:46 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 16:25:46 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Costly Mistakes to Avoid This Winter </title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/pF7ZO18L4dw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s that time of year, folks — winter is coming. It’s going to get cold. Now is the time to harvest what is left of your garden, winterize your sprinklers, and cozy up at home with your friends and family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, there are three huge mistakes that can cost homeowners thousands of dollars. Luckily, you can easily avoid these mistakes by properly winterizing your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, make sure that you buy a $2 protector for your outdoor faucet. It’s amazing how much damage a little bit of ice can do. Ice can cause pipes to explode or leak into your basement. Just an inch of water in your basement can cost up to $15,000 to pump out and dry. All you have to do to prevent this disaster is buy one of those protectors and take your hoses off of your faucets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I know everyone loves Instagramming icicles, but don’t just take your pictures and leave the icicles on your roof. If there are icicles hanging off your roof, then you probably have ice damming issues. Basically, when the ice melts, the water has nowhere else to go. Ice damming can cause serious damage to your roof, which costs thousands of dollars to repair. Not only that, icicles are also safety hazards; it can be very dangerous to walk beneath some of those huge icicles we get here in Salt Lake County.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A little ice can cause a lot of big, costly problems for your home.%20localhost:5000/three-costly-mistakes-to-avoid-this-winter-49.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A little ice can cause a lot of big, costly problems for your home.”&lt;/a&gt;
If you notice that you have ice damming, you can pay a few hundred dollars to have someone come out and steam the ice away. You can even rent one of those steamers yourself. I also recommend installing a little extra insulation around the eaves of your house, which is typically where ice damming occurs. Heat tape can also help you avoid ice damming and water damage, which will save you thousands of dollars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, don’t let cold air sneak into your home. If you add up all of the cracks in the average home, it’s like having a 3x3 foot window open at all times. Not only will that make for a cold winter, it will also cost you a lot of extra money in energy bills. Fortunately, you can head to a Lowe’s or Home Depot and buy some caulk. Caulk comes in all kinds of different colors, so find the one that matches your home and fill up those exterior cracks. That way, you won’t have all of that cold air coming in through your windows, stucco, or doorframes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2016 11:07:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:5000/three-costly-mistakes-to-avoid-this-winter-49.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:5000/three-costly-mistakes-to-avoid-this-winter-49.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Tale of 2 Markets</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Bq7Jc-KBjss&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of weeks ago, I did a market update for our local radio station KNRS. As I was preparing the data for the show, I realized that we had a tale of two markets on our hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see, if we look at the availability of all the housing types across the entire Wasatch Front under $300,000, we have about a three-month supply of homes available. In a real estate market, it’s considered a level market when you have between a four-to-six-month supply of homes available. When there are fewer than four months, it’s considered a seller’s market. When there are more than six months, it’s considered a buyer’s market.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=I want you to be able to win no matter what market you're completing in.%20localhost:5000/the-tale-of-2-markets-48.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“I want you to be able to win no matter what market you’re completing in.”&lt;/a&gt;
In any price point less than $300,000, then, it’s absolutely a seller’s market. Here are three quick strategies you can use to help you compete if you’re a buyer in that market:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be the first to know. Your agent should be able to match your specific home buying criteria so you can be the first to know about homes as they become available. This will allow you to weed out the competition and avoid multiple offer scenarios that may cause the price of the home to increase.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get a full approval letter.  This will take you through parts of the underwriting process, and that’s exactly what the seller wants to see. This will turn you into a cash buyer in the eyes of the seller and help you stand out from the competition.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Try using an escalation clause on the offer you write. For example, you could state that you’re willing to offer X amount of dollars higher than the highest net offer the seller receives, provided the cost doesn’t exceed a certain price.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I said, we’re experiencing a tale of two markets. The other market I’m referring to is all the housing types above $500,000, in which there is a 10-month supply of homes. This, obviously, is a buyer’s market. Here are three tips you can use if you’re a seller to ensure your home priced more than $500,000 sells fast and for the most amount of money:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Boost your curb appeal. It’s a fact of life—everyone judges a book by its cover. Make sure the front door’s got a fresh coat of paint on it and the landscaping looks good. Take photos now if you’re planning on listing over the winter.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stage the home. Clear off all the flat surfaces in the property of everything other than decorative items. Clean lines show the property, and it’s the property you’re selling, not the stuff. Flat surfaces run vertically as well as horizontally, so make sure both surfaces are cleared of all clutter.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Price the home right. Be sure to use accurate comparables within your micro-market and view those comparables through the eyes of the buyer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of what tale our market is telling, I want you to win. If you have any questions, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 13:33:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:5000/the-tale-of-2-markets-48.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:5000/the-tale-of-2-markets-48.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How We Sold an Expired Listing in Less Than 2 Weeks </title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/6kIh3UiGab4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We recently sold a property for more than list price in less than two weeks. Prior to working with us, these clients had their home on the market for over six months before the listing expired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During that time, the property had six showings and no offers, so the sellers were understandably frustrated. When they were referred to us, I told them exactly what they needed to do to get the property sold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing you need to understand is curb appeal. If you look at the video above, you will see before and after pictures of the property. I had the clients paint the exterior of this beautiful log home because the photos from the original listing showed that the home had deferred maintenance. Everybody on the Internet judges a book by its cover, so your home needs to look good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine going to an expensive restaurant and paying $50 for a plate of food. That plate of food will come out looking good, and because it looks good, it’s going to taste better. The same principle applies to buying a home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you look at the video above, you will see a couple of interior photos as well. Before, the property had not been staged. I found that the clients were more than happy to stage the home but their prior agent didn’t give them any direction on what to do or how to do it. We went room by room and staged the property correctly. For instance, we referred them to our countertop guy so they could finish updating the kitchen. It cost $1,500 to replace the countertops and they look great.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Always look at comparable properties to see if the property is fairly priced.%20localhost:5000/how-we-sold-expired-listing-in-less-47.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Always look at comparable properties to see if the property is fairly priced.”&lt;/a&gt;
When you look at a listing online, after the exterior photos, the buyer should see a picture of the kitchen, the master bedroom, and the master bathroom in exactly that order. Those three rooms are the most important to buyers and most buyers will only look at your listing for a little bit, so you need to post photos of those rooms up front in order to grab their attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are incredibly grateful to these clients. They did everything that we asked them to do. We launched the property using our grand opening technique and, as a result, we sold this property in fewer than two weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about the home selling process or if you’re having trouble selling your property, give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 15:51:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:5000/how-we-sold-expired-listing-in-less-47.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:5000/how-we-sold-expired-listing-in-less-47.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Do You Want to Buy a Fixer-Upper? </title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2_Wz0A18JT0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I have a few tips for buying a home that needs work. There are different types of fixer-uppers out there and some need more work than others. The way you pursue a purchase offer on the home most likely depends on which fixer-upper category it is in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most sellers realize that a home needs work when they put it up on the market and have already accounted for that when they priced the home. I have yet to find a seller who is willing to subsidize a buyer’s home improvement dreams, yet that doesn’t stop buyers from trying to get a discount on an already discounted price. It is very important to look at comparable properties in order to determine whether a fixer-upper has been priced correctly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, let’s talk about the different types of fixer-upper homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, you have your basic fixer-upper. Fixer-upper homes are generally priced for sale as-is. These homes often have deferred maintenance items or other minor repairs that the sellers either aren’t willing to fix or cannot afford to fix. When you make an offer on these properties, have your buyer’s agent pull comparables for other fixer-upper properties to see how the price stacks up. That way, you are comparing apples to apples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, you may be interested in a mint condition vintage house. Although these properties are not modernized, they can be very desirable. Mid-century modern houses have made a real comeback recently; other vintage houses include Victorians or Craftsman bungalows. Generally, the seller will add a premium price pad due to the area and architectural uniqueness of the property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually, the interior of a vintage property will be in incredible condition. However, they can look very outdated. When you write an offer on this kind of property, be aware that there may be a premium price to pay for the uniqueness of the property. Make sure that you look at other similar homes and compare the listing price to those that have already sold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another kind of fixer-upper is the newer home that may be outdated. Lots of subdivisions have homes that were built in 1995; these sellers know there are newer homes out there, but still price their homes as if they are brand new. That is unfortunate because a lot of the trends from the 90s — like hunter green carpeting — are not popular today. Some of these sellers may be priced above where they should be, so again, make sure to look at comparable properties. When you send your offer in, send along the list of work it would take to modernize the home and include how much it would cost to do all of that work. That way, the seller can see things from your perspective.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Always look at comparable properties to see if the property is fairly priced.%20localhost:5000/do-you-want-to-buy-fixer-upper-46.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Always look at comparable properties to see if the property is fairly priced.”&lt;/a&gt;
A lot of buyers think they will get a good deal when it comes to buying a foreclosure property, but that’s not always the case. Banks will usually not lower the purchase price on a foreclosure property within the first 30 days. Foreclosures normally come with other rules beyond that. For example, after 30 days, the bank may lower the price by 3%. If 60 days go by without an offer, they may lower the price again by another 3%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should also make sure to do a title check on foreclosed properties because the banks have not occupied these properties. The bank should have cleared any hidden liens on the property, but it is still a good idea for you to work with a good title company and pull a complete title report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in a short sale, you need to know that there is nothing short about them. Short sale transactions can take a lot of time to close. Since the seller cannot afford to make the payments on the home, they also cannot afford to do any work on the property, so short sale homes are often sold as-is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should also be aware that the price an agent sets for a short sale property is not always accepted by the bank. The bank will do an independent appraisal on a short sale property to ensure that it will be sold at market value. Don’t be lured in by the price on the MLS system unless it says that the price has been previously approved by a third party. More often than not, that’s the price the bank is willing to accept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, you may want to buy a “packrat” house. If you have ever watched Hoarders, you know that these houses have stuff stacked up to the ceiling and aisles to get from room to room. The challenge with these properties is not that there is a lot of stuff in the house (which makes it hard to visualize what you’re going to do with the property, though), but that there is a monstrous amount of deferred maintenance that needs to be addressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, it helps to look at other distressed properties to see if the packrat house is priced correctly. It is especially important in this case because you won’t know how much work the property really needs until you get a home inspector in there. Keep in mind that if all of that stuff in the home is still in the way, the home inspector won’t be able to do their job thoroughly. Consider extending your due diligence period and require the seller to allow access to all visible parts of the interior of the property before the home inspection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number one thing to keep in mind when purchasing a house that needs some work is to look at comparable sales. You can then deduct the price of the work that’s needed based on estimates from licensed contractors. If that adjusted price lines up with the listing price, you might need to pay the listing price to purchase that fixer-upper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about fixer-upper properties or need to get in touch with a licensed contractor to fix up your property, just give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2016 16:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:5000/do-you-want-to-buy-fixer-upper-46.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:5000/do-you-want-to-buy-fixer-upper-46.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Using Football to Explain Your Home’s Closing</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/m7hJNxrCOlg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How does football relate to the closing of your property? The analogy we’ve come up with makes a lot of sense, and we hope it will help shine some new light on the process for you if you’ve been thinking about selling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this analogy, let’s say we are starting with the ball right on our own one-yard line. There are 99 yards between you and the goal line. Once an offer is accepted, you’ve made it to midfield.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An offer will be contingent on a few things, including due diligence. Due diligence is basically any type of inspection a buyer wants to do. We know that 24% of contracts fail and 80% of those are due to due diligence. The buyer could decide they don’t want to buy at this point for pretty much any reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good news is that once we’ve made it past due diligence, we are in the red zone. Good offense so far, but you’re not quite there yet. Now the offer is contingent upon the financing going through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your buyer should already be pre-approved by a lender; however, that still doesn’t mean they will get the loan. The “defense” in this situation is underwriting. It’s a secret weapon that is going to look for every reason not to lend the buyer money, so certain things can come up.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=%20localhost:5000/using-football-to-explain-your-homes-45.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good agent will be in contact with the lender who issued the pre-approval to ask certain questions to see if they will be able to pay. You want to find out as much as you can up front about their financing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the financing hurdle has been cleared, you are on the 10-yard line. The offer is now contingent upon the appraisal. In the last couple of years we’ve had more and more issues with appraisals because the market is improving. Homes still have to appraise for buyers to be able to purchase. If you get a bad appraisal, you do have options to remedy it without throwing the deal away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you’re through the appraisal, you are at the five-yard line. The final hurdle is the settlement table. This is where we sign all the documents with the title company to be able to transfer the deed into the buyer’s name. It usually happens a week or two after the appraisal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bad things can happen, like a medical emergency or the buyer losing their job, but it’s not likely. Now you are at the one-yard line, and the property must fund in order for the seller to receive the money and the buyer to get the deed. Once that has happened, you are in the end zone! Time for a touchdown dance!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 09:57:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:5000/using-football-to-explain-your-homes-45.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:5000/using-football-to-explain-your-homes-45.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Which Updates Won’t Add Value to Your Home?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/aHpIt47TDzk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When updating or renovating your home, you may be under the impression that making major renovations to your property will net you more money on the appraisal. This may not always be the case. In fact, some improvements may not increase your home’s value at all, leaving you with a sunk cost. In an effort to help you avoid this situation, I’d like to share with you seven home improvements that will not add to the value of your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Extensive professional landscaping. You may not recoup the cost of that koi pond and waterfall in your backyard. Realize that major outdoor features like these are personal aesthetic choices, and that a future buyer may not share your same vision or want to pay for the maintenance of those choices.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Upgraded electrical or plumbing. Odds are, your neighbors have already upgraded to copper plumbing and have probably already updated their electrical systems as well. These improvements are only considered to be ones that bring a property up to modern standards, so they’re not likely to increase the value of your home.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;New roof, gutters, sprinklers or HVAC. These are all major systems of a property since they can last for over 10 years. The reality is that it is unlikely that the appraiser is going to add any value to your property, since these are the kinds of systems that the buyer is going to expect are already in great working order at the time of purchase.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Swimming pool. Here in Utah, swimming pools and other water features like hot tubs are not all that common, and some buyers may have a problem with that. This is called functional obsolescence—something about the property that you will not get back from a value standpoint.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Painting your home is not likely to add value in an appraisal.%20localhost:5000/which-updates-wont-add-value-to-your-44.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Painting your home is not likely to add value in an appraisal.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Making dated improvements. Upgrading to white appliances or white ceramic countertops might seem like a great idea because they are newer to you, but these decisions may deter some potential younger buyers, since they’ll see those as “dated updates.” If you have questions on which improvements to make or not make, ask me!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Painting your home. While painting your home can actually freshen up the property and strengthen its appeal, it is not likely to add value in an appraisal; it may, however, increase the probability of it selling.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Solar panels. Regardless of the Kool-aid that the solar panel salespeople are selling you in regard to resale value, realize that an appraiser is not adding value for solar panels. Worse yet, if you’ve financed solar panels, you’ll probably have to pay them off at the time of sale, which is something that probably was not disclosed to you when you purchased them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about what to do or what not to do in order to get your home sold for the most amount of money possible, please give me a call or shoot me an email and I’d be happy to answer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2016 13:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:5000/which-updates-wont-add-value-to-your-44.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:5000/which-updates-wont-add-value-to-your-44.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Do We Know Our Market Is Strong?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/mz9b_628GTY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are the signs of a strong housing market? We’re here to tell you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all starts with the economy. Right now, there’s really only one portion of our economy that’s firing on all cylinders, and that’s the housing market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New home sales are currently at their highest level since 2008 and home prices are at or above their all-time highest levels in almost all areas on the Wasatch Front.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The economy will eventually see a big boost from strong housing sales. We think it’s a little premature to start worrying about whether a recent housing market rebound could lead to another real estate bubble. Appreciation in the first quarter of 2016 was only up 5.7% from last year. That’s not too bloated a number.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Now is the time to get involved in buyer or selling real estate.%20localhost:5000/how-do-we-know-our-market-is-strong-43.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Now is the time to get involved in buyer or selling real estate.”&lt;/a&gt;
The recession that happened in 2008 was largely a byproduct of the tech bubble. Normal recessions are caused by excess somewhere, but that level of excess doesn’t seem to exist anywhere right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a final thought: If interest rates go up by 1%, the cost of owning a home will go up by 10%. Which is going to happen first - home prices falling by 10% or interest rates going up by 1%?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for us, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We’re always here to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2016 12:12:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:5000/how-do-we-know-our-market-is-strong-43.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:5000/how-do-we-know-our-market-is-strong-43.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>When Should Sellers Respond to Offers?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wrw50fQI4SQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question of when you should respond to an offer as a seller is one we get quite frequently, especially in a market like this. Most agents are advising their clients to hold off on responding to offers until after the first weekend they’ve listed, in which an open house will often be held.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This benefits buyers because many can only go out to look at homes on weekends when they don’t have to work. It gives everyone equal footing to get into the property and enough time to prepare financing. The seller benefits as well because they don’t have to show the property as much and can get all the offers around the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re responding to an offer as a seller, you do have four different options:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Accept the offer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make a counter-offer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reject the offer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No response to the offer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You want to be gracious, not forceful.%20localhost:5000/when-should-sellers-respond-to-offers-42.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You want to be gracious, not forceful.”&lt;/a&gt;
 That being said, a seller really isn’t going to ignore an offer unless it’s blatantly ridiculous. The real key to getting your offer accepted is understanding timing. Maybe the seller is waiting for other offers to come in before deciding because they just listed. However, if the home has been on the market for a month or more, the seller is probably very anxious to get an offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recommend that you call the seller’s agent and ask them what would be enough time for a response. This is a gracious way to make it clear to them that you still want the home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for us, feel free to give us a call or send us an email anytime. We look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2016 11:13:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:5000/when-should-sellers-respond-to-offers-42.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:5000/when-should-sellers-respond-to-offers-42.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Beat the Wasatch Market With These Eight Tricks</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Gu-YaT1IHcg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The law of supply and demand in real estate is irrefutable. It’s important to understand. Generally, if there’s a low supply and a high demand, price will be high, of course. In contrast, the higher the supply and the lower the demand, the lower the price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let’s define inventory and absorption rate in real estate. If you take the amount of available homes and you divide that by the amount of homes sold in the past 30 days, you’re left with what’s called a month’s supply of housing. It’s considered a level market when you have a four to six month supply of homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there’s less than four months of supply, it’s a seller’s market. Likewise, a more than six month of supply of homes gives us a buyer’s market. 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You need a strong Realtor to help you navigate this market.%20localhost:5000/beat-wasatch-market-with-these-eight-40.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You need a strong Realtor to help you navigate this market.”&lt;/a&gt;
So let’s take a look at the Wasatch Front’s supply of single-family homes (excluding townhomes and condos). Right now we have a 4.4 month supply of homes available. Seems like we’d be in a level market, right? Not so fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we look at homes by price range, we only have a 3.4 month supply of homes on the market under $350,000. If we look at homes under $250,000, we have just 2.75 months of supply. This poses a real challenge for first-time homebuyers, as they’re finding they are competing with multiple offers for almost all of the well-priced homes under $350,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For that reason, we’re seeing condos and townhomes really take off as affordable housing for first-time homebuyers. In this market, we only have a 3.78 month supply of such homes along the Wasatch Front. As a result, we’re seeing buyers try to tie up homes to lock out the competition - sometimes without even seeing the inside of the home before writing an offer! This allows people to lock up a property even though they sometimes cancel the offer down the road after finding a better option. We’re seeing a lot of this right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2016 11:02:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:5000/beat-wasatch-market-with-these-eight-40.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:5000/beat-wasatch-market-with-these-eight-40.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Inventory Affects the Wasatch Front Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/cWAQJiC92yE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are eight things that we feel you can do to compete to get the home you want in the Wasatch market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be informed. If there’s a specific neighborhood, community, or builder you’re interested in, start researching and following them on social media and set up Google alerts. The first line of defense is to know what’s going on so you can act fast.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Register your name on the internet list. Most of the communities and builders will reach out to those who have interest on their internet lists. You’ll receive news about model homes, property releases, and other updates. If you want to be the first to know, make sure the community or builder knows about you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Work with a Realtor. We have the inside track and in many cases will be able to alert you to important news before the public is aware of it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make a friend. It doesn’t hurt to make friends with a sales agent in a community because they’re great resources for details that other people might not be aware of.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get pre-approved for a loan. If you’re not pre-approved and you go to buy, you could lose out to someone who is pre-approved.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check for financing options through the builder. Sometimes builders will provide incentives for using their lender, like assistance with closing costs or money towards upgrades at the design center.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Talk to your Realtor about options and upgrades. Model homes will likely be very upgraded and full of options that raise the price beyond the base price of the property. Having an idea of the options and upgrades that you want will be important for you to know upfront to make sure you can qualify for that loan and still be within the payment you’re comfortable with.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Familiarize yourself with the community and the properties. Intense community interest can cloud judgement and create a frenzy. You never know which line you’ll be in for a home. It could be the home you’re dreaming of, and it’s gone by the time you get to the front of the line! Knowing the community well will help you make an informed choice when the time comes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Realtors have the inside track on many new homes.%20localhost:5000/how-inventory-affects-wasatch-front-41.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Realtors have the inside track on many new homes.”&lt;/a&gt;
If you or anyone you know has any real estate questions, email me or give me a call!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2016 10:38:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:5000/how-inventory-affects-wasatch-front-41.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:5000/how-inventory-affects-wasatch-front-41.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
