<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Albany Real Estate Video Blog with Kevin Clancy</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Clancy Real Estate - your professional Albany Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 11:37:52 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 11:37:52 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Its Important to Work With a Relationship-Based Agent</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0jyAE55e9x4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the agents in our industry are transactional instead of relationship-based. Here’s why you should work with one who’s relationship-based.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Buying a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.capitalregionhomesearch.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to perform a full home search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Selling a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.albanynyhomevalues.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Call me at &lt;a href=&quot;tel:518-861-7016&quot;&gt;518-861-7016 for a FREE home buying or selling consultation&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s the difference between being transactional and being relationship-based in the real estate industry? The answer lies in how our team does business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read an alarming article the other day that described Realtors along the same lines as personal injury attorneys and insurance salesman. In other words, it held our profession in a really low regard. This was disheartening to me because I know how hard my team works and how much we love our clients. Overall, it was hard to read this article and think that the public thinks so little of Realtors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the reason for this is &lt;strong&gt;most Realtors are transactional instead of relationship-based.&lt;/strong&gt; My firm is relationship-based.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me tell you a quick story of how a transactional mindset works. I met with a couple last week who listed their home last year with a Realtor who was a friend of theirs. After six months, their home hadn’t sold and they were ready to take it off the market. When they told their Realtor this, their Realtor threatened to sue them for $8,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=I VALUE THE LONG-TERM RELATIONSHIP OUR TEAM HAS WITH EACH OF OUR CLIENTS.%20localhost:4000/transactional-agents-vs-relationship.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“I VALUE THE LONG-TERM RELATIONSHIP OUR TEAM HAS WITH EACH OF OUR CLIENTS.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s not how you build a business, build a career, or build trust with the public. I’ve never, ever told someone that I was going to sue them if they took their home off the market. In fact, we’re one of the few firms that offer an easy-exit listing agreement. If you’re one of our sellers and you want to take your home off the market, just call us up and we’d be happy to do that for you. I value the long-term relationship our team has with each of our clients—not the short-term, transactional gain of $8,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Long story short, we plan on selling this couple’s home. If their previous Realtor would have agreed to take their home off the market last fall, they might have retained the client this spring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We want to earn your business, and we want to do business with you for life.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you ever have any real estate questions or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be glad to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 09:47:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/transactional-agents-vs-relationship.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/transactional-agents-vs-relationship.html</guid>
        
        <category>Expert Advice</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What All Sellers Need to Know About Basement Egress Windows</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/1UbJqJVWkUY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is having a second basement egress actually as important as recent buzz would have you believe? Today, I’ll address this hot topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Buying a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.capitalregionhomesearch.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to perform a full home search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Selling a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.albanynyhomevalues.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Call me at &lt;a href=&quot;tel:518-861-7016&quot;&gt;518-861-7016 for a FREE home buying or selling consultation&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spring is here and we’re seeing great buyer activity out there in our market. Many homes are selling above list price, but there certainly are some that are remaining stagnant on the market. The distinction comes down to things like price point, school systems, and location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, homes I’ve got listed that are priced at or above $900,000 are seeing very little activity, while homes I’ve got listed at or under $350,000 are receiving tremendous activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, this isn’t the main point I want to make today. The message I want to share with you is about basement egress windows. &lt;strong&gt;To elaborate, an egress window is just a separate way to get out of the basement.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Real estate goes through cycles. In the past, there’s been buzz about asbestos, radon, mold, and more. These days, there’s a lot of talk about homes without a basement egress. Homes without a basement egress have been causing a lot of grief for agents lately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=NOT HAVING A SECOND EGRESS WON’T MAKE OR BREAK YOUR ABILITY TO SELL A HOME.%20localhost:4000/the-truth-about-listing-without-second.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“NOT HAVING A SECOND EGRESS WON’T MAKE OR BREAK YOUR ABILITY TO SELL A HOME.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a seller, think about this: You’ve got a finished basement. Most likely, you didn’t pull permits from the town. Still, in most municipalities, you’ve got to have a second egress out of the basement beside the stairs. Nevertheless, 90% of people probably don’t have this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have sold dozens upon dozens of homes that don’t have a second basement egress. I think it all comes down to an agent’s ability to negotiate. An agent who says you can’t sell a home without a second egress is an agent who can’t negotiate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me tell you a story to illustrate what I mean. Two or three years ago, I spoke with a couple who had just met with another agent. They told me, “Don’t worry, we’ve already put a deposit down on a second egress.” I told them to cancel the contract and that I would sell the house without them putting a window in. &lt;strong&gt;They followed my advice, got their home sold, and saved $5,000 in doing so.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what Realtors do: We work through problems. If you’re a seller and you have a finished basement, adding a second egress is something to think about. It is certainly beneficial to have one from a safety perspective, and the presence of this feature is something I will always argue for my buyers. However, &lt;strong&gt;having one won’t make or break your ability to sell a home.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 12:36:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/the-truth-about-listing-without-second.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/the-truth-about-listing-without-second.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Dirty Little Secret in Real Estate</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/BKFK0j_E7uE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s the dirty little secret no one else will tell you about the real estate industry? I’ll share it with you today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Buying a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.capitalregionhomesearch.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to perform a full home search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Selling a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.albanynyhomevalues.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Call me at &lt;a href=&quot;tel:518-861-7016&quot;&gt;518-861-7016 for a FREE home buying or selling consultation&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we head into spring, the weather is starting to warm up a bit. We are seeing great buyer activity, and inventory remains low. Interest rates are starting to move up, so if you’re a buyer, you may want to make your move now before they get even higher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you’ve been briefed on our current market conditions, I want to talk about the dirty little secret in real estate that no one likes to talk about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In my opinion, the real estate industry is broken.&lt;/strong&gt; There are 3,100 brokers in the Capitol region, and 99% of them are set up as independent contractors within a real estate firm. On average, these agents sell seven or eight homes a year. What tends to happen is that these agents do some crazy things in an unethical environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, consumers lose tens of millions of dollars a year because of unscrupulous activities by Realtors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This week alone, I had three Realtors ask me or say things that were an ethical violation.&lt;/strong&gt; Whenever a Realtor says to me, “Hey Kevin, between you, me, and the lamppost . . .” I know the next words out of their mouth are going to be some sort of ethical violation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s really disheartening, but when you think about the way our industry is set up, it’s not surprising. You have these very large commissions and agents that are only doing six or seven transactions a year, which means there is a huge motivation to work unethically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I really want to stress that our firm is different.&lt;/strong&gt; We have the saying “clients first” posted everywhere in our office. We have a fiduciary responsibility to treat your transaction like our own and put your needs before ours. That’s what we always do at our firm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I ever get wind that anyone at my office is doing anything unethical, I will take action. They are not going to work with our firm any longer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=I BELIEVE THAT THE INDUSTRY WILL CHANGE.%20localhost:4000/real-estates-dirty-little-secret.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“I BELIEVE THAT THE INDUSTRY WILL CHANGE.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just to give you an idea of what I mean, I had an agent call me from another firm and we went out for coffee. They told me that they had called up a listing agent and said, “Hey, I have an offer coming in. What’s it going to take to put this transaction together?” That listing agent responded, “Bring me an offer of $340,000.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing is, the buyer was going to offer $360,000, so the listing agent just cost their seller $20,000. The seller doesn’t even know that this conversation happened. They got sold out by their listing agent for $20,000, but they are probably happy because their home sold in two weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s just one of the many atrocities that go on in our business and it drives me nuts. Going forward, I think something needs to change. &lt;strong&gt;I believe the industry will change.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s likely that going forward, Realtors will become employees with most teams. That’s why we work as a team; we do things differently at my firm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about how my team operates or if you need help buying or selling a home, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 13:10:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/real-estates-dirty-little-secret.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/real-estates-dirty-little-secret.html</guid>
        
        <category>Kevin Clancy Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Factors That Can Kill a Sale</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/WxbIv-TQdoI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why hasn’t your home sold? There are usually three reasons why good homes don’t sell on the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Buying a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.capitalregionhomesearch.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to perform a full home search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Selling a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.albanynyhomevalues.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Call me at &lt;a href=&quot;tel:518-861-7016&quot;&gt;518-861-7016 for a FREE home buying or selling consultation&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why didn’t that home sell?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve heard this question and others like it many times in my 25 years in the business. I’ve sold thousands of homes in that time, so my experience and education in marketing have given me three reasons why I think a home won’t sell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=YOU’VE GOT TO BE FLEXIBLE AS A SELLER.%20localhost:4000/why-your-home-doesnt-get-any-offers.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“YOU’VE GOT TO BE FLEXIBLE AS A SELLER.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Pricing.&lt;/strong&gt; As hard as it is for a seller to understand, I can sell a home with mold, radon, bad wells with coliform in the water, and more. When it comes to pricing, it has to reflect those issues. Often agents simply don’t do their homework on pricing correctly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Marketing.&lt;/strong&gt; I hate to see homes that are advertised with pictures taken on a cell phone. We always use professional photographers when we market for sellers. But it’s more than just that; you also need to position the home to reach the target market and promote the price. A lot of Realtors don’t understand the market that they’re trying to reach. 86% of people start their home search on the internet, so if an agent doesn’t understand how to use social media or isn’t spending enough on online marketing, it simply won’t sell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Sellers.&lt;/strong&gt; Sellers can often be their own worst enemies. They might mean really well, but sometimes they hire us and don’t take our advice or they don’t let buyers in. I recently took on a home that had been on the market for over a year with another agent—over the first week, we had five showings and my seller had five showing requests denied! Buyers that are denied showings probably won’t come back. Don’t assume that a buyer isn’t serious enough. You’ve got to be flexible as a seller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about real estate, feel free to email at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:kevin@clancyrealestate.com&quot;&gt;kevin@clancyrealestate.com&lt;/a&gt; or call me directly at any time. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 16:12:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/why-your-home-doesnt-get-any-offers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/why-your-home-doesnt-get-any-offers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Expert Advice</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Answering a Couple of Common Real Estate Questions</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/lX66g5coVvs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I want to answer two common questions I hear from buyers and sellers, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Buying a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.capitalregionhomesearch.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to perform a full home search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Selling a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.albanynyhomevalues.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Call me at &lt;a href=&quot;tel:518-861-7016&quot;&gt;518-861-7016 for a FREE home buying or selling consultation&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I want to talk about two questions people ask me all the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first question is one I often hear from buyers, which is: “Is buying a home the right thing for me?” And the second question, which is something sellers tend to ask me, is: “If I can’t sell my house, is renting a good option?” Let’s start with the first question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;*Contrary to what you might expect me to say as a Realtor, buying a house isn’t right for everyone.&lt;/strong&gt; There are many situations where people are simply better off renting. The first factor you should consider if you aren’t sure whether buying is right for you is your time frame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re planning to be in a home in the Capital region for less than four years, you’re better off renting. Closing costs in New York state are the highest in the country, which means it’s very difficult to make them back in a short time frame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another indicator that you’re better off renting is if you are risk-averse. &lt;strong&gt;If you aren’t sure about your employment stability or don’t have cash reserves saved up, you may want to rethink buying a home.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=BUYING A HOME IS A GREAT OPTION FOR PEOPLE WHO HAVE THE TIME AND MONEY TO MAKE SUCH A COMMITMENT.%20localhost:4000/answering-2-common-questions.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“BUYING A HOME IS A GREAT OPTION FOR PEOPLE WHO HAVE THE TIME AND MONEY TO MAKE SUCH A COMMITMENT.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things happen. Your boiler could blow up a week after you move into the home. If you aren’t prepared for these possibilities, renting might be the way to go. The same can be said if you are someone who travels a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, buying a home is a great option for people who have the time and money to make such a commitment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, let’s move on to the second question. Should you rent a home if you’re having issues selling it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my experience, more people are moving out of the Capital region than are moving in. &lt;strong&gt;Wanting to pay down your mortgage and let the house potentially appreciate is not a good enough reason to rent out your property.&lt;/strong&gt; This is particularly true if you’re moving out of the area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have seen first-hand the devastation tenants can do to a home when their landlord is long-distance. Chaos can befall you when you leave your property in the hands of another person. Renting is just prolonging the pain of the sale. Generally, you are better off just selling your home and moving on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 11:43:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/answering-2-common-questions.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/answering-2-common-questions.html</guid>
        
        <category>Kevin Clancy Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Trust in Our Agents Experience to Help You Get Your Dream Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/PElBNQ3sm4Y?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After thinking about perspective lately, I wanted to share with you the ways that our agents’ experience and perspective can help you navigate real estate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Buying a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.capitalregionhomesearch.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to perform a full home search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Selling a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.albanynyhomevalues.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Call me at &lt;a href=&quot;tel:518-861-7016&quot;&gt;518-861-7016 for a FREE home buying or selling consultation&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I want to talk about perspective and address some questions buyers and sellers frequently ask me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t know that we could volunteer at the Ronald McDonald House. My team was down there this week, and we thought that we were going to be helping the people staying there by cooking them breakfast, among other things. But the reality is they ended up helping us more than we help them. It really puts things into perspective when you worry about making a mortgage or car payment, but there are people out in the world fighting some really big battles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why you hire us when you have questions about real estate — &lt;strong&gt;you hire us for our experience and our perspective.&lt;/strong&gt; I have an amazing team of people with ample experience. Four of our team members have graduate degrees, which is absolutely unheard of in the real estate industry. Between all of us, we probably have hundreds of years of experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drawing on that experience, &lt;strong&gt;I want to answer a few questions I’m regularly asked by our buyers and sellers.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From buyers, I hear, “How many homes do I need to look at? What price should I offer?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And from sellers, I get, “How do I know when I should take the offer?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s begin with the buyer’s side. &lt;strong&gt;The average buyer looks at seven to eight homes,&lt;/strong&gt; though many look at more or fewer. Our goal is to narrow down your search to homes that fit your criteria to save you time and money. We don’t want to waste your time by showing you 30 homes that don’t match what you’re looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=WE’RE HERE TO MAXIMIZE YOUR RETURN AND LESSEN THE INCONVENIENCE FOR YOU, WHETHER YOU’RE BUYING OR SELLING.%20localhost:4000/trust-our-perspective-and-experience.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“WE’RE HERE TO MAXIMIZE YOUR RETURN AND LESSEN THE INCONVENIENCE FOR YOU, WHETHER YOU’RE BUYING OR SELLING.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of what price you should offer, the answer is that it depends. &lt;strong&gt;On average, homes in the Capital Region area sell at 95% to 100% of the list price.&lt;/strong&gt; But not all homes are priced correctly; there are many homes that are overpriced in the MLS, as well as homes that are underpriced and those that are spot on. We can tell you what the home is worth and what kind of offer you should make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an example, if you make an offer in January on a house that has been on the market for six months, we won’t let you offer 95%—that’s probably a motivated seller, so there’s an opportunity for us to get you a good deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For sellers, on the other hand, if your home has been on the market for two days and someone makes a full-price offer, you’ll probably ask if you could get more. That’s where our expertise in valuing homes comes into play. &lt;strong&gt;In my experience, the first offer is the best offer 99% of the time.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We recently had a high-profile investor receive a full-price offer on a property he was selling. This was his first offer, but his natural inclination was to wait for more exposure on the market to see if he could get more. Long story short, that first buyer didn’t want to wait around, and so three months later, he got $15,000 less than what he could have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scenarios like that are why we are here. We’re here to maximize your return and lessen the inconvenience for you, whether you’re buying or selling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about what’s going on in the real estate market, feel free to contact me directly. I’d be glad to use my experience and perspective to guide you through your transaction.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 16:40:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/trust-our-perspective-and-experience.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/trust-our-perspective-and-experience.html</guid>
        
        <category>Kevin Clancy Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Will Your Wheel of Life Look Like in 2018?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_BjXrjBkEnY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new year is a great opportunity for a fresh start, but you have to be willing to work for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Buying a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.capitalregionhomesearch.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to perform a full home search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Selling a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.albanynyhomevalues.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Call me at &lt;a href=&quot;tel:518-861-7016&quot;&gt;518-861-7016 for a FREE home buying or selling consultation&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2018 is upon us and I hope you’re having a fantastic year so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said, January is a time of change. People tend to set goals for themselves when this month rolls around only to abandon them in February. Why does this happen?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something I want you to think about this year is the “Wheel of Life.” The Wheel of Life is basically comprised of every aspect of your life, including your finances, your health, your career, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about this: &lt;strong&gt;If you had to rate each aspect of your life on a scale from one to 10, how well would those ratings turn out?&lt;/strong&gt; Ideally, every aspect of your life should be well-balanced around this wheel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But real life isn’t so simple. Change is not easy, nor is it comfortable. That’s exactly why successful people get comfortable being uncomfortable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=SUCCESSFUL PEOPLE GET COMFORTABLE BEING UNCOMFORTABLE.%20localhost:4000/my-challenge-to-you-in-2018.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“SUCCESSFUL PEOPLE GET COMFORTABLE BEING UNCOMFORTABLE.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pain of changing must be less of the pain of staying stuck in something negative. It really comes down to asking yourself what you’re willing to accept in life. &lt;strong&gt;In 2018, I challenge you to raise your standards.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you decide what you want and expect out of life, you have the power to take control. One way to help yourself take control is by surrounding yourself with people who build you up instead of those who tear you down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What gets me out of bed every day is making a difference in people’s lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there’s anything I can help you with, real estate or otherwise, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 10:36:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/my-challenge-to-you-in-2018.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/my-challenge-to-you-in-2018.html</guid>
        
        <category>Expert Advice</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Should Buyers and Sellers Know About President Trumps Tax Cuts?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/4kDALsFZZXw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever happens with the upcoming tax cuts may have a short-term impact on our real estate market, but it won’t be the end of the world. Here’s why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Buying a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.capitalregionhomesearch.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to perform a full home search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Selling a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.albanynyhomevalues.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Call me at &lt;a href=&quot;tel:518-861-7016&quot;&gt;518-861-7016 for a FREE home buying or selling consultation&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How will President Trump’s new tax cuts affect our real estate market and you as a homebuyer or seller?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I give my thoughts on that question, I want to thank you for coming out to our recent Thanksgiving pie giveaway. We had a great turnout and had a lot of fun giving away so many pies. As you know, we also held a gift card raffle at the giveaway, so today I’ll announce the winners of our grand prizes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, onto the news at hand. Nobody knows exactly what’s going to happen with these tax cuts, but there’s plenty of concern that the mortgage interest deduction is going away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re buying real estate just for the mortgage interest deduction, you’re buying real estate for the wrong reason.&lt;/strong&gt; People buy real estate for many reasons, and the deduction was a great benefit, but it’s not the end of the word if it goes away. People will still buy real estate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=DON’T BUY REAL ESTATE FOR THE TAX DEDUCTIONS.%20localhost:4000/how-will-president-trumps-tax-cuts.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“DON’T BUY REAL ESTATE FOR THE TAX DEDUCTIONS.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many years ago, I was in a situation where I was fortunate enough to be able to pay off my home, and my financial planner told me not to pay off the home for the mortgage interest deduction because then I’d lose that deduction. I just went back and ran some quick numbers regarding what I saved with the deduction and having no mortgage, and I calculated that my savings were vastly greater by paying off the house instead of taking the mortgage interest deduction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I liken this situation to when the state of New York banned smoking in bars. Back then, it was common to wonder if a lot of bars and restaurants would go out of business. 10 years later, the bar and restaurant industry is thriving. Everyone survived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Change is sometimes hard, but change is generally good and positive. &lt;strong&gt;Whatever happens with the mortgage interest deduction may have a short-term impact on the market, but we’ll survive.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 11:24:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-will-president-trumps-tax-cuts.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/how-will-president-trumps-tax-cuts.html</guid>
        
        <category>Expert Advice</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Has My Team Found Success?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/OGVUnvt27VE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How is my team so successful in our industry? Well, it all comes down to the behind-the-scenes work my team members do each day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Buying a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.capitalregionhomesearch.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to perform a full home search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Selling a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.albanynyhomevalues.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Call me at &lt;a href=&quot;tel:518-861-7016&quot;&gt;518-861-7016 for a FREE home buying or selling consultation&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I want to talk a little bit about how we sell so many homes. Most of all, I want to talk about the efforts of my team. The work they do behind the scenes is truly to thank for our success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=THE WORK MY TEAM DOES BEHIND THE SCENES IS TRULY TO THANK FOR OUR SUCCESS.%20localhost:4000/what-my-team-does-behind-scenes.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“THE WORK MY TEAM DOES BEHIND THE SCENES IS TRULY TO THANK FOR OUR SUCCESS.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My team members are averaging 30 sales a piece, when the average agent in our area tends to average just seven or eight homes.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I absolutely appreciate the credit I receive for my team’s success, I want to make it known that each and every one of my team members plays a huge role in what we do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2016, we were named the No. 3 team in the state of New York in terms of sales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our team makes it a priority to take care of buyers and sellers in today’s market. For example, if you are a buyer and are unhappy with your home within your first year of residing there, I will sell that property for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t just take my word for it. You can hear a testimonial from one of our past clients, Nicole Cohen, in the video above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 15:37:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/what-my-team-does-behind-scenes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/what-my-team-does-behind-scenes.html</guid>
        
        <category>Kevin Clancy Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Could There Be Carbon Monoxide in Your Home This Winter?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/iYeCF28JP0s?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our furnaces may keep us warm during the winter months, but did you know they may also be kicking off carbon monoxide? Here’s what you need to know to stay safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Buying a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.capitalregionhomesearch.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to perform a full home search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Selling a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.albanynyhomevalues.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Call me at &lt;a href=&quot;tel:518-861-7016&quot;&gt;518-861-7016 for a FREE home buying or selling consultation&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I delve into today’s topic, I’d like to begin with a special message. Thanksgiving is upon us and I want to take a moment to say thank you. I can’t tell you enough how much I appreciate your support, which has made us the No. 3 real estate team in New York state. Your experience and satisfaction is of the utmost importance to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Thanksgiving, we’ve reached the time of year when people are beginning to turn on their heating systems. Furnaces may keep us warm, but they can also pose a hazard related to today’s subject: carbon monoxide. If a system is malfunctioning, it could be spewing carbon monoxide into your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carbon monoxide is an odorless, colorless gas that can be put off by gas stoves, furnaces,&lt;/strong&gt; or any other appliances in your home that use gas or oil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems like there isn’t a year that goes by that I don’t hear about an injury or death having occurred as a result of just this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if you don’t already have a carbon monoxide detector, get one. They cost just about $29 and you can find them at Home Depot, Walmart, and any other similar stores. This small expense is well worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=IF YOU DON’T ALREADY HAVE A CARBON MONOXIDE DETECTOR, GET ONE.%20localhost:4000/could-common-deadly-gas-be-in-your-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“IF YOU DON’T ALREADY HAVE A CARBON MONOXIDE DETECTOR, GET ONE.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You cannot detect carbon monoxide without a detector, and breathing in high levels can kill you or cause you to become seriously ill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe in the importance of this so strongly that &lt;strong&gt;if you can’t afford a carbon monoxide detector, reach out to me and I will buy one for you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you have a safe and happy holiday season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 09:31:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/could-common-deadly-gas-be-in-your-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/could-common-deadly-gas-be-in-your-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Safety</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
