<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kansas CIty Real Estate Video Blog with Adam Butler</title>
    <description>Our mission at The Adam Butler Team is to be your best resource for Kansas City real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The The Adam Butler Team, your professional Kansas City Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 11:35:11 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 11:35:11 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Have You Cleaned Out Your Gutters Yet?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/dy7pkYCn_mw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When is the best time to clean your gutters? It’s always a good idea to clean them in the spring, but I recommend getting ahead of the problem and cleaning them now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Buying a Kansas City home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://adambutler.kwrealty.com/map/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a full home search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Selling your Kansas City home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://adambutler.kwrealty.com/sell/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free Home Price Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The leaves are falling and filling up your gutters. Most people wait to clean their gutters in the spring when the rain comes, but guess what?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you clean your gutters before winter hits, snow won’t pack those leaves down and clog your gutters.&lt;/strong&gt; It is easier to clean your gutters when the leaves are dry, anyway. If you wait until spring, the leaves will be a soggy mess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only that, if we happen to have a 40° day this winter, it could rain. If your gutters are clogged, that rain will come down the side of your house. If your sump pump does not keep up with it, you’ll wind up with water in your basement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=IT IS EASIER TO CLEAN YOUR GUTTERS BEFORE ALL THE SNOW HITS ANYWAY.%20localhost:4000/have-you-cleaned-out-your-gutters-yet.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“IT IS EASIER TO CLEAN YOUR GUTTERS BEFORE ALL THE SNOW HITS ANYWAY.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, check your gutters now. It’s always good to clean them in the spring, too, but &lt;strong&gt;cleaning the gutters now should help you avoid any major problems in the winter or early spring.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any real estate questions or need to hire someone to clean your gutters, please don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I can certainly refer you to someone. I look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 11:23:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/have-you-cleaned-out-your-gutters-yet.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/have-you-cleaned-out-your-gutters-yet.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Owner Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Do You Need to Cover Your Homes Spigots During the Winter?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/XqWEt1Y_4-s?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Placing an insulated cover over your home’s outside spigots can prevent them from freezing over and possibly causing your basement to flood once you turn them on again in the spring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Buying a Kansas City home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://adambutler.kwrealty.com/map/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a full home search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Selling your Kansas City home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://adambutler.kwrealty.com/sell/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free Home Price Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the easiest, cheapest winter home preparation tips I always recommend is &lt;strong&gt;placing an insulated cover over your home’s outside spigots.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If left uncovered during the winter, they can freeze over, which can cause your basement to flood once you turn them on again in the spring. Repairing that kind of damage can cost you a couple hundred dollars to fix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can buy insulated spigot covers at Lowe’s, Home Depot, or any hardware store for as little as $3. As you can see in the video above, attaching them over your spigot is a simple process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=PUTTING A LITTLE BIT OF MONEY TOWARD YOUR HOME’S PREVENTATIVE MAINTENANCE CAN GO A LONG WAY.%20localhost:4000/why-do-you-need-to-cover-your-homes.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“PUTTING A LITTLE BIT OF MONEY TOWARD YOUR HOME’S PREVENTATIVE MAINTENANCE CAN GO A LONG WAY.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of us are almost done using our spigots anyway, so you might as well do this now. Putting a little bit of money toward your home’s preventative maintenance can go a long way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about preparing your home for winter or you’re curious about what’s going on in our Kansas City market, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 12:28:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/why-do-you-need-to-cover-your-homes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/why-do-you-need-to-cover-your-homes.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Owner Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Quick Tip on Patching Your Walls</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/YVNnp8GaLP4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I have some advice about patching your walls: never use brushes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Buying a Kansas City home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://adambutler.kwrealty.com/map/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a full home search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Selling your Kansas City home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://adambutler.kwrealty.com/sell/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free Home Price Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m at one of my investment properties touching up sheet rock dents in the wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve got a little spackle on it, and I’m about to sand it down. While doing this, I realized that &lt;strong&gt;a lot of my clients don’t realize that if you use a brush to cover a patch, the strokes will show&lt;/strong&gt;; almost all your walls are rolled on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For little spots like this, &lt;strong&gt;I use a mini tray and roller to make the process easier.&lt;/strong&gt; Regular-sized trays and rollers make a mess and would really be overkill for a small patch. When you roll it on, the texture matches the wall around it, and when it dries, it’ll look perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=IF YOU’RE EVER TOUCHING UP YOUR WALLS, USE WHATEVER SIZED ROLLER YOU NEED, JUST DON’T USE A BRUSH.%20localhost:4000/a-quick-tip-on-patching-your-walls.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“IF YOU’RE EVER TOUCHING UP YOUR WALLS, USE WHATEVER SIZED ROLLER YOU NEED, JUST DON’T USE A BRUSH.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re ever touching up your walls, use whatever sized roller you need, just don’t use a brush.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like one of these little roller kits, I’ll be happy to give one to you. Call, email, or text me, and I’ll bring one over to you and say hi. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 11:23:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/a-quick-tip-on-patching-your-walls.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/a-quick-tip-on-patching-your-walls.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Owner Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why I Love Arbor Masters</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/tjKKqw96_xs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arbor Masters is my preferred vendor for all things trees. They’ve done some fantastic work for me in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Buying a Kansas City home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://adambutler.kwrealty.com/map/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a full home search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Selling your Kansas City home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://adambutler.kwrealty.com/sell/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free Home Price Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m coming to you live from my front yard today. As you can see in the background of the video above, one of my favorite vendors is here removing a pretty big tree from my yard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I trust Arbor Masters to do a great job simply because they’ve done a great job for me before.&lt;/strong&gt; Preventative maintenance goes a long way when it comes to tree care. These guys are always willing to come out and take a look to make sure all your trees are healthy and any damage they can cause to your home is minimal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=PREVENTATIVE MAINTENANCE GOES A LONG WAY WITH YOUR TREES.%20localhost:4000/why-i-love-arbor-masters.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“PREVENTATIVE MAINTENANCE GOES A LONG WAY WITH YOUR TREES.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a pesky tree, pesky branches, or just have a question about any of your trees, don’t hesitate to &lt;strong&gt;give Arbor Masters a call at &lt;a href=&quot;tel:1-800-256-4193&quot;&gt;1-800-256-4193&lt;/a&gt; or visit their website &lt;a href=&quot;http://arbormasters.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any real estate needs or questions for us in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 11:43:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/why-i-love-arbor-masters.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/why-i-love-arbor-masters.html</guid>
        
        <category>Arbor Masters</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>An Easy Fix for Loose Screws</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/3HOGHTm5Eko?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a quick, easy, cheap solution for loose screws I want to show you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Buying a Kansas City home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://adambutler.kwrealty.com/map/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a full home search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Selling your Kansas City home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://adambutler.kwrealty.com/sell/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free Home Price Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A long time ago, my dad taught me a quick, cheap, easy fix for loose screws that never fails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All you need to apply this fix are Elmer’s glue and a few toothpicks. Just squirt a little Elmer’s glue into the hole, jam the toothpicks in, and break them off. If you put your screw in after that, it’ll fit just like new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=THIS CHEAP, EASY FIX NEVER FAILS.%20localhost:4000/an-easy-fix-for-loose-screws.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“THIS CHEAP, EASY FIX NEVER FAILS.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The first person who emails me and tells me they tried this tip and it worked will receive a $20 gift card to Lowe’s.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, if you have any questions or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home in the Kansas City market, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be glad to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 11:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/an-easy-fix-for-loose-screws.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/an-easy-fix-for-loose-screws.html</guid>
        
        <category>Common Fixes</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Keep Up With Your Landscaping </title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ca9FRxFlM58?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t let your yard go to the geese—it’s much easier to take care of landscaping projects yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Buying a Kansas City home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://adambutler.kwrealty.com/map/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a full home search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Selling your Kansas City home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://adambutler.kwrealty.com/sell/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free Home Price Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s very important that you keep up with landscaping this time of year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You don’t want to let your yard get out of control.&lt;/strong&gt; Good, clean landscaping adds value to your house. Plus, it just looks nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t let crabgrass take over your yard or garden beds. Your house will benefit so much from your steady upkeep. After all, it’s much harder to track down some geese to do your weeding for you than it is to just take care of it yourself in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=YOUR HOUSE WILL BENEFIT SO MUCH FROM PROPER LANDSCAPING.%20localhost:4000/keep-up-with-your-landscaping.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“YOUR HOUSE WILL BENEFIT SO MUCH FROM PROPER LANDSCAPING.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or need a referral to a landscaping company—I do not recommend these geese—just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2017 11:23:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/keep-up-with-your-landscaping.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/keep-up-with-your-landscaping.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Owner Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>When Is It Time to Fly the Coop?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/hME8gGn24jE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is your family reaching a point where you home has begun to feel smaller and smaller? Today’s advice is for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Buying a Kansas City home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://adambutler.kwrealty.com/map/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a full home search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Selling your Kansas City home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://adambutler.kwrealty.com/sell/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free Home Price Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some birds that nested in a light fixture outside my house got too big to even get out, and it got me thinking about move-up buyers who have outgrown their home. I’ve notice this being a common problem for homeowners here in the Kansas City area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My advice for you today is not to wait so long that your house becomes so small that you can’t even get out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=DON'T WAIT UNTIL YOUR HOME GETS SO SMALL THAT YOU CAN'T GET OUT!%20localhost:4000/when-is-it-time-to-fly-coop.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“DON’T WAIT UNTIL YOUR HOME GETS SO SMALL THAT YOU CAN’T GET OUT!”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking to move to your next home, &lt;strong&gt;check out all homes available on the Kansas City MLS &lt;a href=&quot;http://adambutler.kwrealty.com/map/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; on our home search tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or just need some helping flying the coop into a new home, give me call or send me an email. I’d love to help you out!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 12:34:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/when-is-it-time-to-fly-coop.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/when-is-it-time-to-fly-coop.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Taking a Page on Teamwork From Kansas Speedway</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/9Hv2QMjgFx4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was recently a guest out at Kansas Speedway and I thought it was a good opportunity to talk about the importance of every player when it comes to teamwork.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Buying a Kansas City home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://adambutler.kwrealty.com/map/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a full home search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Selling your Kansas City home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://adambutler.kwrealty.com/sell/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free Home Price Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was recently a guest at Kansas Speedway of Jamie McMurray, the No. 1 car for Cessna McDonald’s. I wanted to give them a shout out today because they really put on a show of teamwork during the race.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My team focuses on getting you the best results thanks to years of experience and honing our negotiating skills. &lt;strong&gt;We’re like this racing team in that so many people need to do their job just right to get the best results.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=JUST LIKE THIS RACING TEAM, SO MANY PEOPLE NEED TO DO THEIR JOB JUST RIGHT TO GET THE BEST RESULTS.%20localhost:4000/taking-page-on-teamwork-from-kansas.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“JUST LIKE THIS RACING TEAM, SO MANY PEOPLE NEED TO DO THEIR JOB JUST RIGHT TO GET THE BEST RESULTS.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s always something we focus on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about how our team works to get you the best deal possible when buying or selling a home here in the Kansas City market, give me a call or send me an email soon. I’d love to speak with you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 14:44:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/taking-page-on-teamwork-from-kansas.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/taking-page-on-teamwork-from-kansas.html</guid>
        
        <category>Lesson on Teamwork</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Prepare for storm season in Kansas City </title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/5auscFEMt1g?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We recently had a pretty nasty storm here in Kansas City. With storm season on its way, there’s one thing you need to make sure you do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Buying a Kansas City home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://adambutler.kwrealty.com/map/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a full home search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Selling your Kansas City home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://adambutler.kwrealty.com/sell/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free Home Price Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the storm season fast approaching, it’s essential to take a look at the trees around your home. What condition are they in? Are you worried a storm could potentially knock down a tree and cause damage to your property?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now is the time to have a certified arborist come take a look.&lt;/strong&gt; Power lines are also a huge concern when it comes to trees and storm season. Kansas City Power and Light will trim back foliage around the main power pole, but the lines running to your house are your responsibility as the homeowner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=BEING PROACTIVE ABOUT YOUR TREES NOW COULD SAVE YOU TIME, MONEY, AND A LARGE AMOUNT OF STRESS.%20localhost:4000/prepare-for-storm-season-in-kansas-city.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“BEING PROACTIVE ABOUT YOUR TREES NOW COULD SAVE YOU TIME, MONEY, AND A LARGE AMOUNT OF STRESS.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An arborist will come out to give you a free evaluation and provide you with an estimate for trimming. Being proactive about your trees now could save you time, money, and a large amount of stress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about getting ahold of an arborist, or if you have any real estate questions, please feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I’m always happy to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 12:01:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/prepare-for-storm-season-in-kansas-city.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/prepare-for-storm-season-in-kansas-city.html</guid>
        
        <category>Prepping for Storm Season</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Keeping Groundwater From Intruding on Your Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/z7N8NAgG0xQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Water is a home’s worst enemy. Today, I wanted to show you how to keep groundwater out of your home using my house as a live example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Buying a Kansas City home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://adambutler.kwrealty.com/map/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a full home search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Selling your Kansas City home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://adambutler.kwrealty.com/sell/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free Home Price Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Groundwater in your basement is an issue that nobody wants to deal with, so today I have some preventative maintenance tips that I wanted to share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Water is a home’s worst enemy and it can get in three ways: your roof, plumbing leaks, or groundwater.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To get water to shed when there’s heavy rain, you need one inch of drop per foot.&lt;/strong&gt; As you can see in the video above, there’s a spot near my home’s downspout where water will pool and try to get into my basement when it rains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve started by adding some dirt to divert water. I’ve brought in a dump truck’s worth of dirt, but $1.33 per bag at a hardware store will take care of it too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=WATER IS A HOME’S WORST ENEMY.%20localhost:4000/how-to-keep-your-homes-worst-enemy-out.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“WATER IS A HOME’S WORST ENEMY.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created a nice slope that will keep water from pooling when it rains. Some people would say that this is what a sump pump is for, but the best sump pumps to have are the ones that never have to run!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about preventing groundwater from getting into your house or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home here in the Kansas City area, give me a call or send me an email. I’m always here to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 12:18:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-to-keep-your-homes-worst-enemy-out.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/how-to-keep-your-homes-worst-enemy-out.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Owner Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
