<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Northern Nevada Real Estate Video Blog with Rick Canale</title>
    <description>Our mission at  is to be your best resource for Northern Nevada real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The , your professional Northern Nevada Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://rickcanaleblog.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://rickcanaleblog.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 11:38:38 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 11:38:38 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Should You Work With an Agent?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/C6oK8NSP0GA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why should you resolve to work with a real estate professional in your transactions? Today, I’ll be discussing five of the benefits you’ll gain from partnering with an agent when you go to buy or sell a home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Experience.&lt;/strong&gt; A well-educated real estate agent understands the entire sales process and will help you navigate through it, all while brokering a deal and working with other professionals to streamline the transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Negotiations.&lt;/strong&gt; Real estate professionals represent you and act as a buffer, negotiating with all the parties throughout the entire transaction to a successful close.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Pricing.&lt;/strong&gt; We can help you understand today’s real estate values when setting the price of the home you want to list or making an offer on a home you want to purchase. Don’t rely on third-party applications, which we know are way off the mark when it comes to pricing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Understanding the market conditions.&lt;/strong&gt; We can simply and effectively explain today’s real estate headlines and decipher what they mean to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Paperwork&lt;/strong&gt;. We’ll help explain and navigate all the disclosures and paperwork necessary in today’s heavily regulated environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A well-educated real estate agent understands and will help you navigate the entire sales process.%20http://rickcanaleblog.com/why-should-you-work-with-an-agent.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A well-educated real estate agent understands and will help you navigate the entire sales process.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this topic or if you’re thinking of buying or selling a home, feel free to give me a call or send an email. We can provide you a free consultation so that you can have a competitive advantage.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 05:59:31 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://rickcanaleblog.com/why-should-you-work-with-an-agent.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rickcanaleblog.com/why-should-you-work-with-an-agent.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
