<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Brian Canady &amp; Tim Chase Video Blog</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Campbell &amp; Keller Team - your professional Baltimore &amp; Carroll Counties Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>localhost:5000/</link>
    <atom:link href="localhost:5000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 14:48:14 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 14:48:14 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>What’s Happening in the Carroll County Real Estate Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2p4b-MgKJdQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People ask me all the time whether we’re in a buyer’s or seller’s market. In our industry, the answer usually depends on the season.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the spring, we typically see more of a seller’s market, and that was the case this year. Right around the beginning of July it started to slip, and we started to see the days on market creep up. Houses were sitting on the market a little longer and they weren’t selling for the same prices that we saw in the spring. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That trend has continued into the fall. How do we know this? We use what’s called the ‘absorption rate.’ The absorption rate measures the sales pace versus the current active inventory. An absorption rate of four to six months is considered a balanced market. Anything less than four months is considered a seller’s market. Anything longer than six months is considered a buyer’s market. Right now, we’re seeing things push a little bit closer to that six-month mark. That would currently make our area a buyer’s market. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How does that impact property values? The longer things stay on the market, the less they stand to make. As far as the current inventory goes, there aren’t a lot of new homes coming on the market, but there isn’t a whole lot of activity on what’s being listed. I’ve also discovered that here in Baltimore and Carroll County, there’s typically a 5% correction in the price from the spring market (2nd quarter) to the fall market (3rd quarter). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Inventory is down, and interest rates are extraordinarily low.%20localhost:5000/what-s-happening-in-the-carroll-county-real-estate-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Inventory is down, and interest rates are extraordinarily low.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interest rates are extraordinary right now, and this has created huge buying opportunities for anyone looking to purchase a home. The Fed has left them untouched, but they’re rumored to be hiking them up in the 4th quarter. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does all this mean for buyers and sellers? It depends on your particular situation and what your goals are. If you’re a seller, there aren’t a lot of new homes coming on the market. There are opportunities out there, you just have to be more strategic about pursuing them. If you’re a buyer, now is a great opportunity to act due to the combination of low interest rates and the seasonal decline in prices.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any more questions about the current market, please don’t hesitate to reach out to us. Just give us a call or send us an email, and we’d be happy to help you! &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:5000/what-s-happening-in-the-carroll-county-real-estate-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:5000/what-s-happening-in-the-carroll-county-real-estate-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Introducing the Campbell &amp; Kellar Team YouTube Channel</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0-YjJzolcaM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the new YouTube channel for the Campbell &amp;amp; Kellar Team! We will update this channel regularly with great seller tips, buyer tips, and real estate market updates for our area. Take a look around, discover topics that interest you, and if there are topics that you’d like to learn more about, reach out to us and we just might answer your question with a video. To learn more about our new channel, watch this short video. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:5000/introducing-the-campbell-kellar-team-youtube-channel.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:5000/introducing-the-campbell-kellar-team-youtube-channel.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
