<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Heidi Phong Real Estate Team - your professional Sacramento Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://heidiphong.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://heidiphong.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 11:05:30 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 11:05:30 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Who Pays Your Agent’s Commission as a Buyer?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/AxQi4-G9oM4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you work with a buyer’s agent, do you have to pay them commission?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Believe it or not, the answer is no.&lt;/strong&gt; The buyer’s agent’s commission has already been figured out and agreed upon by the seller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of first-time homebuyers may worry that their Realtor’s commission will cut into their savings for the down payment. Some homebuyers even skip hiring a buyer’s agent for that reason. However, that’s the beauty of hiring a buyer’s agent: when it’s all said and done, the seller pays for your agent’s commission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The seller pays the commission for the buyer’s agent.%20http://heidiphong.com/who-pays-your-agents-commission-as-a-buyer.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The seller pays the commission for the buyer’s agent.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re not already working with a professional to help you find homes, &lt;strong&gt;we recommend hiring a Realtor at no cost to you to find the best home.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about beginning your home search or if you would like to learn more about real estate in general, just give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 06:40:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://heidiphong.com/who-pays-your-agents-commission-as-a-buyer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://heidiphong.com/who-pays-your-agents-commission-as-a-buyer.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Are the Main Advantages of  Veteran Financing?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/kRVSVLdWlUQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an agent, I get asked about VA loans all the time. Today I’m going to talk about what they are, what their benefits are, and how you can apply for one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First off, it’s important to note that in order to qualify for a VA loan, you will need to be active-duty military or an active-duty veteran. &lt;strong&gt;The biggest benefit to VA loans is that there is no down payment required.&lt;/strong&gt; That’s an awesome benefit considering you’d need around $10,000 to get into a $300,000 home at 3.5% down with a conventional loan, not including closing costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to apply for a VA loan, the first thing you should do is find a good lender. You want to find someone you can trust. &lt;strong&gt;They’ll be able to make sure you are eligible for a VA loan and can help out if there are any hiccups.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Hire a good lender to see if you qualify.%20http://heidiphong.com/what-are-the-main-advantages-of-veteran-financing.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Hire a good lender to see if you qualify.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you find a good lender, find a good real estate agent who is also familiar with VA loans. They will be able to avoid the pitfalls that other people come across when looking for a house. Since a VA loan is federally backed, they have much higher standards for homes they’re willing to approve. If there are any problems, it won’t qualify for the VA loan and the seller would have to either make all the necessary repairs or find another buyer instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We are always happy to answer them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 06:16:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://heidiphong.com/what-are-the-main-advantages-of-veteran-financing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://heidiphong.com/what-are-the-main-advantages-of-veteran-financing.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Buyer Advice From Lending Expert Nick Street</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_EDc2KmcW-o?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’re back with Nick Street, the branch manager at Mountain West Financial, to go over some important advice for homebuyers. You can check out the first part of our conversation &lt;a href=&quot;http://heidiphong.com/part-1-of-our-sit-down-with-nick-street.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;There is a large percentage of first-time buyers in our current market. Nick says that there are many loan programs available for first-time buyers, but some are shrinking and some are changing. What’s available today might not be available tomorrow.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The best thing you can do is meet with a loan officer&lt;/strong&gt; to go over your specific situation so that you can find the program that is best for you. You still need to have good credit, a job, and verifiable income. Some programs even give you a low down payment option, but keep in mind that it’s always best to have access to some funds when buying a home, as there are definitely costs that come with the transaction.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;It’s incredibly important that you find a lender you are comfortable with before you start looking at homes. You need to know what your options are and what your buying power is. Some people start looking at homes in a certain price range only to discover that they cannot afford to buy those homes. That can make the home search process frustrating, as you are constantly comparing the homes you can afford to the homes you want in that other, higher price bracket. Knowing your buying power helps you set realistic expectations for your home search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Make sure you talk to a lender before you start looking at homes.%20http://heidiphong.com/buyer-advice-from-lending-expert-nick-street.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Make sure you talk to a lender before you start looking at homes.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, some buyers may get approved at that higher number but they don’t want to buy in that price range. If you look at your own budget and set a more comfortable number, that is perfectly fine. No one understands your financing better than you do, so it’s really important that you &lt;strong&gt;talk to your lender and develop a plan that is based on your wants, needs, and goals.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;If you have any other lending questions for Nick, you can reach him at 916-262-7631 or email him at Nick.Street@MWFInc.com. As always, if you have any real estate questions, please don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://heidiphong.com/buyer-advice-from-lending-expert-nick-street.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://heidiphong.com/buyer-advice-from-lending-expert-nick-street.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Part 1 of Our Sit Down With Nick Street</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/nkKouVLrbto?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently sat down with Nick Street, a branch manager with Mountain West Financial. We had a great conversation about mortgages, interest rates, and more. For part one of our conversation, we talked about the current state of interest rates and what the future holds for them.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Nick has been in the mortgage industry since 2004, so he has a wealth of knowledge to share. &lt;strong&gt;One of the things he has taken notice of in the last few years is that many people aren’t aware that interest rates are affected by how our economy is doing.&lt;/strong&gt; When the economy is suffering, rates are going to be pushed down. When our economy is doing well, like it is right now, you will start to see rates increase.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Interest rates greatly affect buying power in this market. If you’re approved for a $300,000 home right now with current interest rates, you would only be able to afford a $270,000 home if rates went up by just 1%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Interest rates have a big impact on buying power.%20http://heidiphong.com/part-1-of-our-sit-down-with-nick-street.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Interest rates have a big impact on buying power.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Right now is actually a great time to buy for a number of reasons.&lt;/strong&gt; For one, interest rates remain historically low. While it’s true they aren’t as low as they were last summer, when you look at historical data it’s clear that rates are still just about as low as they ever have been. Our market specifically gives buyers a lot of advantages that renters don’t have. Sacramento is a fairly affordable market as well.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;In part two, we’ll talk more with Nick about all things mortgage. If you have any questions for Nick, you can reach him at 916.262.7631 or at Nick.Street@MWFInc.com. If you have any questions for us in the meantime, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://heidiphong.com/part-1-of-our-sit-down-with-nick-street.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://heidiphong.com/part-1-of-our-sit-down-with-nick-street.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Benefits of Hiring a Buyer’s Agent</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/cNY2ZTxJIw0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why do you need to hire an agent when buying a home? There are actually a few reasons you’ll want representation when making that big of a purchase.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;First, &lt;strong&gt;the agent won’t cost you anything.&lt;/strong&gt; Your agent’s commission actually comes from the seller as payment for bringing the buyer to the property. The bottom line is that you don’t pay a dime to have a buyer’s agent on your side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=An agent will show you all the homes you want to see.%20http://heidiphong.com/the-benefits-of-hiring-a-buyers-agent.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“An agent will show you all the homes you want to see.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, &lt;strong&gt;a buyer’s agent knows exactly how to negotiate the transaction.&lt;/strong&gt; Things might come up that need to be negotiated such as repairs you want to be done before closing or complications with the appraisal. You’ll want someone on your side who you are confident can handle those situations for you.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;An agent can also show you all the homes you want to see. This means you won’t have to rely on open houses and drive-bys.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Lastly, you want the transaction to be smooth, exciting, and fun. &lt;strong&gt;An agent will do all the heavy lifting for you so you can enjoy the process of buying your first home!&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;If you have any other questions or if you are looking to buy or sell a home, please feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 10:31:01 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://heidiphong.com/the-benefits-of-hiring-a-buyers-agent.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://heidiphong.com/the-benefits-of-hiring-a-buyers-agent.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thuc’s Record Making Sale with Heidi Phong Real Estate</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe frameborder=&quot;no&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/310194824&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Well the results were extremely surprising. I knew the market was hot but I didn’t expect to get what I got and I think it’s due in large part to the agents I picked, Heidi and Billy. They really negotiated and marketed the house well. For my floor plan and model I got the highest selling price ever, so that was awesome. Their responsiveness is top notch, first of all. They answered all of my questions, they responded to every email and text I sent them. As far as going above and beyond that, I know they marketed the property in every place imaginable, they conducted the open house very well from what I saw. Yeah, a just overall great experience.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 13:33:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://heidiphong.com/thucs-record-making-sale-with-heidi.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://heidiphong.com/thucs-record-making-sale-with-heidi.html</guid>
        
        <category>Testimonial</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The 10 Steps of Buying a Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/748hRx_eXqQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Do your due diligence.%20http://heidiphong.com/the-10-steps-of-buying-a-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Do your due diligence.”&lt;/a&gt;If you’re thinking about buying a home, you should know the transaction will be a little bit more complicated than your average purchase. Today I’ll give you the steps of buying a home so you can be better prepared to jump into the market:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Consult a real estate agent. Make sure the agent you hire knows your wants, needs, and time frame.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Apply for a loan. By doing this, you’ll see how much you can get approved for and what sort of rate you’ll get. You want to make sure the monthly payment will be comfortable for your family.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Look at the available homes that match your criteria. This step is when you’ll determine exactly what sort of home and neighborhood you want to be in.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Submit an offer. Once you have found your dream home, your agent will submit an offer and negotiate your terms.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do your due diligence. Once your offer is accepted, you’ll need to do a variety of home inspections. An appraiser will also come out during this step to make sure the home is selling at fair market value.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Send your loan package into the underwriters to get approved for your loan.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do a final walkthrough. You’ll want to make sure all the repairs have been done that the seller agreed to do. It’s your last chance to verify the condition of the property.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sign the documents.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pay the down payment and closing costs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get the keys!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about buying a home, please feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 11:44:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://heidiphong.com/the-10-steps-of-buying-a-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://heidiphong.com/the-10-steps-of-buying-a-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How HP Real Estate Helped Jennifer Through the Home Buying Process</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe frameborder=&quot;no&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/307584281&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It was really good working with them. Our real estate agent Chia Vang, he was really good, very professional. Whenever we had a question, he was always there to answer them. He was really quick with his response. And for us, because we work during the day until 5, Chia knew that we were getting nervous during the house search and so he worked with our schedule. When we would email him he would respond right away, call he would always answer, text message he would reply back very soon. We were fairly young, it’s our first time purchasing a home, we didn’t know the process to it and so, like example, when we really liked a house, and we told him we were interested in it he helped us through the process and he explained to us exactly what was going to happen. And then when we saw a few things wrong with the house that needed to be fixed he made sure to tell us, don’t worry I’ll make sure that the seller will address it and I’ll make sure to address it with the seller’s agent. We were very happy because we got a new roof. They didn’t just fix the roof, the shingles were replaced three times so they put in a brand new roof. Things around the house that we saw were fixed right away. When we did notice [something] after the final walk-through Chia was able to push for the seller to give us money towards our closing costs so I was very happy with that. Chia, our Realtor, is actually my cousin. He’s like my older brother. One thing that’s really special about him is that he never let family come into it. He didn’t push me to do things just because he was my cousin. I remember asking him about, I think the house inspection, I was like should we do all of it or what do you think? And he was just like, this is what I suggest, but I would never tell what to do exactly. This is the outcome if you do it this way or if you don’t. That was one thing I really appreciated from him was when I didn’t know something he would explain it to me from both perspectives and I was like, alright, that gives we a better understanding of what we need to do for the house.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 16:19:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://heidiphong.com/how-hp-real-estate-helped-jennifer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://heidiphong.com/how-hp-real-estate-helped-jennifer.html</guid>
        
        <category>Testimonial</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Do Pre-Approvals Determine Your Purchasing Power?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Im8iiT6E-Yc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is a pre-approval so important? What all goes into the pre-approval process?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First off, you need to get pre-approved so you know what kind of home you are able to buy. Your pre-approval number is generally referred to as your purchasing power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How does your lender calculate this amount? By going through your credit, looking at your income, and determining your debt-to-income ratio, your lender will help you determine what mortgage payment you’re comfortable making.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interest rate you qualify for is a big factor in determining your purchasing power. For example, if you qualified for an interest rate of 3.25%, your mortgage payment for a $250,000 home would be roughly $1,088 per month. If you don’t qualify for that 3.25% rate and instead qualify for a rate as high as 4.75%, your mortgage payment for that same $250,000 home would increase to $1,300 per month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The interest rate you qualify for plays a big role in your purchasing power.%20http://heidiphong.com/how-do-pre-approvals-determine-your-purchasing-power.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The interest rate you qualify for plays a big role in your purchasing power.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See why it’s so important to know what interest rate you’re able to qualify for and lock in? That extra $212 could mean a lot. By saying yes to that increased payment, you’re saying no to eating out more often with your family. A higher mortgage rate means more sacrifices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many times, I have to explain this process to my clients in more detail, so if you want to dive further into this subject matter, don’t hesitate to ask your own loan officer. They’ll be able to give you the answers you need before buying your first home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or are looking to buy or sell a home, feel free to reach out to us. We’d be happy to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 09:46:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://heidiphong.com/how-do-pre-approvals-determine-your-purchasing-power.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://heidiphong.com/how-do-pre-approvals-determine-your-purchasing-power.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How the MLS and Lockboxes Help You Buy and Sell a Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/g20qkWLNcYU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately, I’ve had a lot of buyers wondering how I’m able to show them homes that I don’t personally have listed. If my picture isn’t on the ‘for sale’ sign, how can I show the home?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a homeowner decides to sell their home with the help of an agent, they’re working with a listing agent. The listing agent puts the home on a service called the MLS (multiple listing service), which basically advertises that home to every agent who has access to the MLS. Why would you want your home advertised to these agents, though? When a home is put on the market, there’s a certain commission that’s agreed upon by the seller to pay the listing agent and the agent who brings them a willing buyer. The agent who brings a buyer is known as a buyer’s agent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Lockboxes let any agent show a home to their buyer, no matter who the listing agent is.%20http://heidiphong.com/how-the-mls-and-lockboxes-help-you-buy-and-sell-a-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Lockboxes let any agent show a home to their buyer, no matter who the listing agent is.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Realtor who shows the home represents the buyer’s side of the transaction, whereas the listing agent represents the seller’s side of the transaction. Every agent who has access to the MLS also has access to a lockbox, which they can log into for access to the keys to the home. Every time a buyer’s agent logs into a lockbox, their ID and license verification get sent to the seller to notify them who is looking at their home and how much traffic is coming in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will give sellers an idea of whether their home is priced right and attractive to buyers. So that’s how we’re able to show homes to our clients that aren’t our listings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this helps you understand the MLS and how showings work, no matter who the listing agent is. If you have any other questions or you’re looking to buy or sell a Sacramento home, give us a call or send us an email. We’d love to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2017 15:15:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://heidiphong.com/how-the-mls-and-lockboxes-help-you-buy-and-sell-a-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://heidiphong.com/how-the-mls-and-lockboxes-help-you-buy-and-sell-a-home.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
