<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pinellas Real Estate Video Blog with Jason Duraj</title>
    <description>Our mission at Future Home Realty is to be your best resource for Pinellas real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Future Home Realty, your professional Pinellas Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://floridasbestrealtorblog.net/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://floridasbestrealtorblog.net/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 10:51:51 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 10:51:51 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Is Happening in Our Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Bf0GMahkwjo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s the latest news from our market?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The snowbirds are down here in record numbers, and traffic is starting to pick up on the local roadways. If you’re looking to purchase a home, though, the good news is these snowbirds aren’t purchasing yet because they’re still focusing on the holidays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This makes December a great time to buy&lt;/strong&gt; because activity typically slows down during this time. Once January hits, these snowbirds will re-shift their focus to buying homes and that slowdown will end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year, our market experienced a considerable amount of growth, and our economy remains strong and vibrant. Things are looking like they were back in 2006. In fact, the third quarter GDP numbers just came out and reported that our economy had grown another 3.3%, which is the largest increase since 2007.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the end of the year nears, there will be some tax reform taking place, and this will ultimately spur and add more money to the economy. The Federal Reserve is expected to raise policy rates this month, but because the shift happening with banks and mortgage brokers has already been accounted for, &lt;strong&gt;we shouldn’t see too much of a spike in interest rates&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you’re looking to purchase a home, now is the month to do it.%20http://floridasbestrealtorblog.net/what-is-happening-in-our-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you’re looking to purchase a home, now is the month to do it.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New homes sales in October unexpectedly rose to the highest levels we’d seen in a decade. Single-family home sales rose about 6.2%, which is absolutely incredible. Pending homes sales also rose 3.5% in October, and that growth has more than doubled here locally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot of movement taking place in our market, so if you have any more questions about it or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home soon, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you, and I wish you a very healthy, happy holiday season.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 06:33:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://floridasbestrealtorblog.net/what-is-happening-in-our-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://floridasbestrealtorblog.net/what-is-happening-in-our-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
