<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>Our mission at RE/MAX Results is to be your best resource for St. Louis Metro Area real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The RE/MAX Results, your professional St. Louis Metro Area Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 16:02:15 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 16:02:15 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>These 3 Inspections Could Save You a Lot of Trouble Later On</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/za84fMM39qs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m back talking about more home inspections I recommend you get before purchasing a property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buying a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stlouispropertysearch.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to perform a full home search&lt;/a&gt;
Selling a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stlouishomevalues.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’re back with part two of our coverage on home inspections. Like last time, I’ll be going over a few inspections I think are the most important if you’re buying a new home. Whenever you are about to make a home purchase, you need to know exactly what you’re getting into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, don’t underestimate the importance of a termite inspection. Termites can do a great deal of damage. You certainly wouldn’t want to purchase a home only to find out that you’ll be dealing with these pests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Termites are also something homeowners should check for on an annual basis.&lt;/strong&gt; For about $65, a termite inspection is well worth the cost. Mud tunnels or damage to the wood are two strong indicators that a home may have termites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, I recommend a radon inspection. Radon is an odorless, colorless gas that seeps out from the Earth’s surface. This gas can come up through cracks in the basement or foundation, as well as through any holes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=YOU NEED TO KNOW EXACTLY WHAT YOU’RE GETTING INTO WHEN YOU PURCHASE A HOME.%20localhost:4000/these-3-inspections-could-save-you-lot.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“YOU NEED TO KNOW EXACTLY WHAT YOU’RE GETTING INTO WHEN YOU PURCHASE A HOME.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the EPA, a radon level higher than 4.0 picocuries per liter is a hazard. At this point the levels will need to be mitigated, since &lt;strong&gt;radon is the second leading cause of lung cancer in the United States.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, there are ways to test for it. Certified radon inspectors can come out and set up a test that will monitor your home for two-and-a-half days. This test costs about $150 and will determine whether the radon level needs to be lowered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third inspection I recommend is to have an environmental inspection done. This is especially important if your family has allergies. Having a test for mold is one of the more common environmental inspections out there. &lt;strong&gt;Mold can be present anywhere in a home, and is especially likely if the property has taken on any water.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 10:37:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/these-3-inspections-could-save-you-lot.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/these-3-inspections-could-save-you-lot.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Common Real Estate Contract Contingencies</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0JBkrLDEyLA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which contingencies should you know about? Here are five of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buying a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stlouispropertysearch.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to perform a full home search&lt;/a&gt;
Selling a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stlouishomevalues.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is a real estate contingency? By definition, it’s a future event or circumstance that is possible but can not be predicted with certainty. There can be quite a few of them included within a real estate contract, as far as buyers are concerned. Here are five of the most common contingencies buyers include in a contract and what they mean:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Financing.&lt;/strong&gt; This kind of contingency means they will buy the house if the lender gives them the mortgage at the interest rate and terms they first agreed on and which are written into the sales contract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Appraisal.&lt;/strong&gt; This contingency means they will buy the house if the appraiser says the house is worth at least what the contract price is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Inspection.&lt;/strong&gt; In this case, the contingency states that will buy the house if they are happy with the inspections or negotiated repairs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=THESE CONTINGENCIES ARE STANDARD.%20localhost:4000/5-common-real-estate-contract.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“THESE CONTINGENCIES ARE STANDARD.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Survey.&lt;/strong&gt; A contingency based on a survey means buyers will buy the house if they are happy with the way the improvements fall within the boundaries of that property, as determined by a boundary survey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Title exam.&lt;/strong&gt; This contingency means they will buy the house if the title company determines that there are no liens or encumbrances against the seller on the title of that house and it comes out clear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Real estate transactions are complicated. Leave them in the hands of a professional. If you have any questions for me or any real estate needs I can assist with, I’d love to help you navigate the real estate jungle. Just give me a call or send me an email today. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 10:08:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/5-common-real-estate-contract.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/5-common-real-estate-contract.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Which Home Inspections Should You Order?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ekWMkvKCU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What inspections should you have done on the home you’re buying? Here’s a few to get you started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buying a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stlouispropertysearch.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to perform a full home search&lt;/a&gt;
Selling a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stlouishomevalues.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why should you have a home inspection when buying a home? Which inspections should you order? The first answer is obvious, but the second is not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home inspections protect your investment as a buyer.&lt;/strong&gt; If your home has a plumbing issue that may cost you thousands of dollars to repair down the line, wouldn’t you want to know about it before committing to purchase it? That’s the idea of home inspections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there are many different kinds of home inspections, so which is right for you? I’m going to go through a few of them today and explain how the process works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For starters, every homebuyer should have a building inspection that is completed by a certified home inspector. They will give you an overview of any problems in the house you are buying. They aren’t plumbers or electricians, but they are very knowledgable and will be able to spot a problem when they find it.The inspector will take note of any and all problems. &lt;strong&gt;They can then refer you to a professional who can better estimate the repairs.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inspector will spend at least a few hours in the home (around four hours for a 2,500 sq ft. house) and it’s important that you are with them every step of the way. It will help you better understand their findings and what you can do resolve any issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=EVERY BUYER SHOULD HAVE A BUILDING INSPECTION.%20localhost:4000/which-home-inspections-should-you-order.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“EVERY BUYER SHOULD HAVE A BUILDING INSPECTION.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside from the building inspection, a gas inspection is another important one to consider. In the past, they were done by the local utility company. Now you can hire your own HVAC contractor to perform tests and make sure that any gas powered appliances are following the proper code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last inspection I wanted to mention today is the sewer lateral inspection. &lt;strong&gt;If you’re not buying a brand new home, there is a possibility that the plumbing underneath your home is made of old, clay pipes.&lt;/strong&gt; A sewer lateral inspection will alert you to any creaks, leaks, or invasive roots blocking your sewage lines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are just a few of the many inspections you can choose to have done on a home. Stay tuned for part two, where we’ll cover even more ground. In the meantime, if you have any questions for me at all don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email at your convenience. I look forward to hearing from you&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 14:22:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/which-home-inspections-should-you-order.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/which-home-inspections-should-you-order.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How To Ensure a Successful Home Sale</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/pRfB_Er3ttE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you know if you’re hiring the right agent to sell your home? I’ve got a few things you should consider when choosing your Realtor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buying a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stlouispropertysearch.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to perform a full home search&lt;/a&gt;
Selling a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stlouishomevalues.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I’ve mentioned in previous videos, there are a lot of things that they don’t teach in real estate school. Interviewing two or three Realtors for the job of selling your house is critical to the success of the sale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even in a market as hot as this one, not all houses sell or sell at their asking price. Hiring a competent agent is your best strategy. When interviewing agents, there are a few things you should look out for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure the sure the agent doesn’t just come prepared with information from your neighborhood, but &lt;strong&gt;also has a wider understanding the market in your area.&lt;/strong&gt; Do they have knowledge of the macro- and micro-markets and see the trends that are happening? Do they know the absorption rate? Anyone can compile information on listings and what’s sold and what hasn’t. Make sure that they can interpret that data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=BEING A LISTING AGENT IS DIFFERENT FROM BEING A BUYER’S AGENT.%20localhost:4000/how-to-make-sure-youre-hiring-right.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“BEING A LISTING AGENT IS DIFFERENT FROM BEING A BUYER’S AGENT.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make sure the agent that you choose is marketing and tech-savvy.&lt;/strong&gt; You want them to be able to understand how to market your home across social media platforms and get it in front of the right buyers and demographics. They should be utilizing every resource that they have available to them both on and offline in order to market your house to worldwide prospective buyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is their track record?&lt;/strong&gt; What have they sold in the last three, six, and nine months? You need to make sure that the agents you interview can show you the statistics of the homes they’ve listed, not just the buyers they’ve worked with. What is the number of days that those homes spent on market? What was their list-to-sales price ratio?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being a listing agent is different from being a buyer’s agent. &lt;strong&gt;The skills required for each role are different, and be sure to ask the tough questions of the Realtors you’re interviewing&lt;/strong&gt; to determine that they have the knowledge and experience to sell your home quickly and for top dollar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or you’re thinking of selling, please give me a call. I would consider it a privilege to be interviewed by you to sell your home. I look forward to speaking with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 11:31:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-to-make-sure-youre-hiring-right.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/how-to-make-sure-youre-hiring-right.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Do You Know the Answers to These Common Appraisal Questions?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jfqFFUdm1Ew?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m covering some of the most commonly asked questions I hear about the appraisal process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buying a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stlouispropertysearch.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to perform a full home search&lt;/a&gt;
Selling a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stlouishomevalues.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Appraisals are a subject about which people often have many questions. Today, I’ll be discussing three of these common questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, what does the appraiser look for? The appraiser first and foremost will be looking for capital improvements to the home. Additionally, &lt;strong&gt;the appraiser will consider how a given house compares to other comparable properties of similar size, age, and location.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The radius within which the appraiser will look is usually about a quarter of a mile to a mile, but can vary depending on the average distance between homes in your area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Granite countertops, upgraded appliances, upgraded bathrooms, improved additions, and finished lower levels are all things that an appraiser will look for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there are a few things that don’t truly matter to an appraiser. &lt;strong&gt;Things like window treatments, a new furnace, or a new roof won’t make a difference.&lt;/strong&gt; These things will be more important to buyers than they will be to an appraiser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=AN APPRAISAL IS NEVER PUBLIC KNOWLEDGE.%20localhost:4000/do-you-know-answers-to-these-common.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“AN APPRAISAL IS NEVER PUBLIC KNOWLEDGE.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second question is: “What happens if my home doesn’t appraise?” Well if the buyer has an appraisal rider in the contract, they have the right to negotiate with you on the price. Finding a happy medium will be key here. But, if an agreeable solution cannot be reached, the deal will be terminated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In that case, we get to our third question: “Who gets to see that appraisal?” An appraisal is never public knowledge. &lt;strong&gt;The only people who will get to see it will be the buyer and their lender.&lt;/strong&gt; Technically, you could put your home back on the market without anyone else knowing that it didn’t appraise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 09:56:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/do-you-know-answers-to-these-common.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/do-you-know-answers-to-these-common.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Tips for Winning a Bidding War</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/inqsdzwTAgY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Winning a bidding war isn’t as hard as you think when you’ve got strategies like these.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buying a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stlouispropertysearch.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to perform a full home search&lt;/a&gt;
Selling a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stlouishomevalues.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would you like to win a bidding war in this hot market? I’m going to tell you exactly how to do it today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going to real estate school doesn’t teach you how to write a contract, as I’ve mentioned before. You need to hire an agent like you’d hire a lawyer, based on their track record of wins. This indicates that they can write quality offers. That’s one of the best tools an agent can have.&lt;strong&gt;Here are three things an agent can do with an offer to help you get the home of your dreams:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Remove all contingencies.&lt;/strong&gt; Or, at least remove as many as you can. This includes financing contingencies, inspection contingencies, and home warranties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Remove as many contingencies as you can.%20localhost:4000/3-ways-to-win-bidding-war.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Remove as many contingencies as you can.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Write an escalation clause.&lt;/strong&gt; This says that you’ll beat any other offer by &lt;strong&gt;X&lt;/strong&gt; number of dollars up to a certain max price. It’s very complicated, but can work like a charm in the right situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Writing a full-price offer prior to the house’s first available showing date.&lt;/strong&gt; This would be contingent upon you being able to preview the house within 24 hours. An agent is obligated to present every written offer to their client, and one like this would certainly catch their eye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There you have it—my top three tips. If you have any questions about them or any questions about real estate in general, give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 13:03:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/3-ways-to-win-bidding-war.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/3-ways-to-win-bidding-war.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What to Look for When Buying a Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/11gszBsEs4w?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I wanted to spend some time on what to look for when buying a home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buying a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stlouispropertysearch.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to perform a full home search&lt;/a&gt;
Selling a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stlouishomevalues.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of rehabs, also known as flips, in our market and although everything looks beautiful, you have to be careful about what you see on the outside of the house. I think it’s really important that you look at not just how beautiful a home is, but also at the critical components of the house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You want to know how old the HVAC and the roof are because you don’t want to empty your pocketbook the first year that you live there. Knowing the life expectancy of those items and how old they are is important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walk around the exterior of the home and look for damage, cracks, offset bricks, or rotted columns on the front porch. These are all signs of neglect, so even if the house looks beautiful on the inside, a poorly-maintained exterior is a red flag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Not maintaining the outside of the home is a red flag.%20localhost:4000/what-to-look-for-in-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Not maintaining the outside of the home is a red flag.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open windows and doors to make sure they do so smoothly and check for tight seals on the windows. If any of the doors don’t close properly, check the top of the frame. If the doors are rubbing there, it could mean that the house is settling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are lots of ways to protect yourself before you spend money on inspections, like by looking for red flags that should be obvious to you and your agent. Work with an agent who has the experience of many sales and knows what to look for, because they don’t teach us that in real estate class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or you’re looking to buy or sell a home, please give me a call. I’d be happy to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2017 14:08:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/what-to-look-for-in-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/what-to-look-for-in-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>6 Month Market Recap for the St. Louis Area</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/VyLG3TDL1jM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I wanted to give you an update on how our market has been doing
over the last six months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buying a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stlouispropertysearch.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to perform a full home search&lt;/a&gt;
Selling a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stlouishomevalues.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I wanted to give you an update on how the St. Louis area market has been doing for the last six months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may have been hearing that we are in a very critical time with inventory on the market. What does that mean, exactly? This means that fewer and fewer sellers are putting their homes on the market each month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Fewer sellers are putting their homes on the market each month.%20localhost:4000/st-louis-metro-area-real-estate-st.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Fewer sellers are putting their homes on the market each month.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For March 2017, &lt;strong&gt;we were down 13.3% in number of listings versus March 2016.&lt;/strong&gt; In February, it was down 22% from the prior year, so you can see that it’s been coming back up as the months go by, but it’s been difficult to find people who are ready to move, even though we have families forming who are ready to move out and buy a new house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In March 2017, &lt;strong&gt;the average days a home stayed on the market was 52&lt;/strong&gt;, which is down 7% from March 2016. In February 2017, that number was 63, which is down 13% from the previous February. So we’re looking good for this year. The number of days on market is very low, which means houses are selling very quickly and for top dollar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the median sales price for homes has been up every month for the last six months. So now is a great time to list your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or you’re ready to buy or sell a home, please give me a call. I’d be happy to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 10:37:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/st-louis-metro-area-real-estate-st.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/st-louis-metro-area-real-estate-st.html</guid>
        
        <category>St. Louis Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>BUYING A HOME? Step #1 is ...</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8F2ju7t6EUw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step of the home buying process isn’t looking at homes. It’s figuring out which homes you can actually afford.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buying a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stlouispropertysearch.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to perform a full home search&lt;/a&gt;
Selling a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stlouishomevalues.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that there are many people who think you should start the home buying process by taking a look at homes online. However, that’s not what your first step should be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step when buying a home should be to speak with a mortgage professional. They will look at your credit score, let you know if there is anything you need to fix, and issue that all-important pre-approval letter once they have gone through all of your financial information. &lt;strong&gt;You need that pre-approval letter when you make an offer on a home. Sellers likely won’t entertain an offer without one.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Meet with a mortgage professional first.%20localhost:4000/this-should-be-your-first-step-when.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Meet with a mortgage professional first.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give me a call or send me an email today and &lt;strong&gt;I can connect you with my preferred lenders to get you started.&lt;/strong&gt; These are professionals you can count on with competitive rates and fees. I would be happy to help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about the real estate market, don’t hesitate to reach out by phone or email. I would love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 11:22:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/this-should-be-your-first-step-when.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/this-should-be-your-first-step-when.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>This Tip May Save Your Life</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/szmFCbkQzIk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve got some important information to share today from the American Society of Home Inspectors. It regards your smoke detectors and what you should do if they are old or outdated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buying a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stlouispropertysearch.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to perform a full home search&lt;/a&gt;
Selling a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stlouishomevalues.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve got a very important message to share with you today about smoke detectors. When is the last time you switched yours out? I’m not talking about the batteries; I’m talking about the device itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently went to a very important meeting where the American Society of Home Inspectors (ASHI) was there to give us some lesser-known facts about smoke detectors that I think you should be aware of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They recommend you throw out the detector that utilizes ionization versus photoelectric sensor.  In addition, a smoke detector older than 10 years is ineffective.&lt;/strong&gt; Another thing they mentioned about older detectors is that they utilize ionization as opposed to photoelectric sensors. Ionization detectors are less responsive by 30 to 60 minutes, which could mean the difference between you getting your entire family out of a burning house. Those detectors are also less susceptible to go off if you just burn a roast or a pizza in the oven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You should change your unit every 10 years.%20localhost:4000/st-louis-metro-area-real-estate.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You should change your unit every 10 years.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look on the front, back or inside of the unit. &lt;strong&gt;Check for the word “Photoelectric” (or the symbol “P”) or the word “Ionization” (or the symbol “I”). Also if there’s any mention of radioactive material, like Americium 241 or Illerium 231&lt;/strong&gt;, it’s an ionization model and should be switched out for a new photoelectric one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this or any other topic relating to your home or real estate, give us a call or send us an email. We would love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 12:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/st-louis-metro-area-real-estate.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/st-louis-metro-area-real-estate.html</guid>
        
        <category>Expert Advice</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
