<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Betz Team | NMLS # 280613 - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://winningwithwade.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://winningwithwade.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 10:12:01 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 10:12:01 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>4 Reasons Why Your Lender Matters</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2COKY9-dYdI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today’s topic is about why your lender matters in a competitive market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I talk to a lot of Realtors in my profession, and frankly, they tell me there are about four key things that make a difference in the likelihood of an offer getting accepted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.) Local lenders. &lt;strong&gt;Listing agents routinely look for local lenders&lt;/strong&gt;; they prefer not to work with large national banks or internet lenders. They want to be able to contact someone local if there’s an issue and someone who has local appraisers on their panel. Choose who you work with carefully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2.) Pre-approval letters. In the state of Texas, pre-approval letters are required to list what documents have and have not been verified, so if the letter that you’re looking at doesn’t have those items on there, I’d encourage you to ask your lender why, or find a different lender. &lt;strong&gt;Make sure the lender has actually looked at some documents.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3.) Have the underwriter sign off. Have the lender take the process a step further and have the underwriter sign off on the pre-approval letter. Even though it takes a little bit more time for the lender, it’s a much more thorough way to go about it. &lt;strong&gt;It gives the listing agent certainty that you can actually close on the financing that you’re applying for&lt;/strong&gt; because the underwriters actually sign off on it. As long as you don’t lose a job or blow your down payment money in Las Vegas, you’ll be able to close on the transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4.) &lt;strong&gt;Have your loan officer contact the listing agent to talk up your offer.&lt;/strong&gt; Frankly, that type of call goes over very, very well with the listing agent. This can be the thing that pushes you over the edge in a multiple offer situation. I had a client just last week who was one of 22 offers on a property, and the seller took our offer because I called them—even though it was $8,000 less than the highest offer. We’re a local lender with a good reputation, and they knew we were communicative about having the underwrite on the file.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Frankly, that type of call goes over very, very well with the listing agent. This can be the thing that pushes you over the edge in a multiple offer situation. I had a client just last week who was one of 22 offers on a property, and the seller took our offer because I called them—even though it was $8,000 less than the highest offer. We’re a local lender with a good reputation, and they knew we were communicative about having the underwrite on the file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=When you find your dream home, you need to be working with a lender that will do whatever it takes to get you into that home.%20http://winningwithwade.com/4-reasons-why-your-lender-matters.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“When you find your dream home, you need to be working with a lender that will do whatever it takes to get you into that home.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These measures can really put you in the driver’s seat with your offers, because let’s face it, you’re not in the market to just make offer after offer and not get a property under contract. When you find your dream home, you need to be working with a lender that will do whatever it takes to get you into that home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you or someone you know is looking for that type of service, please contact us. We’d be honored to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 08:24:47 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://winningwithwade.com/4-reasons-why-your-lender-matters.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://winningwithwade.com/4-reasons-why-your-lender-matters.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Can You Protect Your Credit After the Equifax Hack?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZSUwqqnyzvQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you’ve probably heard by now, the personal information of 145 million Americans was compromised by hackers who breached data from Equifax, one of the three major credit bureaus in the U.S. This is a big deal, and could be a significant issue for years if not decades to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Once your information is out there, it’s always out there. &lt;/strong&gt;We took certain steps to protect ourselves in light of this situation, and we wanted to make sure we shared with you what those steps were in case you wanted to take them as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The very first thing I did was head over to &lt;a href=&quot;www.trustedidpremier.com/eligibility&quot;&gt;www.trustedidpremier.com/eligibility&lt;/a&gt;. This is the website that Equifax set up for people to check and see if their information was compromised. Unfortunately, myself, my wife, and my two sons were all affected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Unfortunately, my entire family was affected by the hack.%20http://winningwithwade.com/how-can-you-protect-your-credit-after-the-equifax-hack.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Unfortunately, my entire family was affected by the hack.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of that, we decided to sign up with &lt;a href=&quot;http://lifelock.com&quot;&gt;http://lifelock.com&lt;/a&gt;. There are a number of different credit protection companies out there that can help you out. We decided that LifeLock gave us the best peace of mind. If thieves were to get ahold of my kids’ info, they can have years or even decades of ruined credit on their hands without ever knowing about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We actually decided to take it one step further and freeze our credit reports.&lt;/strong&gt; This may or may not make sense to you depending on your situation. A credit freeze means nobody can open or access lines of credit in your name, even you. If you don’t use credit very often, it’s something to consider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me about any of this or you need any advice in order to make the best long-term decision for your family’s future, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://winningwithwade.com/how-can-you-protect-your-credit-after-the-equifax-hack.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://winningwithwade.com/how-can-you-protect-your-credit-after-the-equifax-hack.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Things to Know About Flood Insurance</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/9PsW2QGAVHQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the devastating hurricanes, we have a unique situation out there in the insurance world. I wanted to take just a minute to talk about flood insurance here in Texas and how it relates to your mortgage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When you take out a home loan, your lender is required to pull a flood certification to see if your property is in a flood zone.&lt;/strong&gt; If you are, you’ll be required to take out a flood insurance policy. These can get quite pricey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have to pay for them in full prior to closing, and you have to have them escrowed in your account regardless of whether you’re escrowed for taxes or insurance. It’s very important that if you are in a flood zone or looking at a home in a flood zone, you learn about it early on in the process so you can have time to make an educated decision on how to proceed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Many of them don’t protect against water damage at all.%20http://winningwithwade.com/things-to-know-about-flood-insurance.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Many of them don’t protect against water damage at all.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being from New Orleans and having to go through Hurricane Katrina, I have deep sympathy for all of our friends in Houston and Florida. &lt;strong&gt;I’ve learned from first-hand experience that the biggest floods tend to happen in non-flood zones.&lt;/strong&gt; Even if your home isn’t in one, I encourage you to at least have a conversation with your insurance professional about what exactly your policy covers. Many of them don’t protect against water damage at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions in the meantime or if you know anyone looking to buy a home in the near future, don’t hesitate to reach out and give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 09:37:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://winningwithwade.com/things-to-know-about-flood-insurance.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://winningwithwade.com/things-to-know-about-flood-insurance.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why You Shouldn’t Be Scared of ARMs</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Cyug6rA_5Pw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people associate an adjustable-rate mortgage, or ARM, with the market crash of 2008. In reality, ARMs were misrepresented to the public during that time and people have been slow to come back to them. However, they have a purpose. An ARM could be the perfect thing for you, depending on what your goals are as a homeowner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=There is some risk involved, but it can be a very useful tool.%20http://winningwithwade.com/why-you-shouldnt-be-scared-of-arms.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“There is some risk involved, but it can be a very useful tool.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re going to be in a home for a set period of time, let’s say four or five years, it behooves you to look at an ARM mortgage&lt;/strong&gt; because it could actually save you a lot of money. While ARMs are known for adjusted rates, they usually have a fixed period at the beginning of the loan. This means for a certain time, the interest rate is lower on that mortgage than it would have been on a traditional 15 or 30-year loan. After the “fixed period,” the rate will adjust up or down depending on what you agreed to on the front end. There are caps in place to protect you from large swings, however. That’s what happened to a lot of people during the recession.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those who benefit from ARMs have a defined holding period and know exactly how long they want to own a property. You can also benefit from an ARM by rapidly paying down your loan at the beginning of the term while the rate is low. &lt;strong&gt;By the time the rate adjusts, your payment will have lowered, even with a higher rate.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An ARM definitely has a place in the lender’s toolbox, but there is some risk involved. If you have any questions for us about ARMs or any other type of loan, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We would love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2017 04:24:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://winningwithwade.com/why-you-shouldnt-be-scared-of-arms.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://winningwithwade.com/why-you-shouldnt-be-scared-of-arms.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are You Ready to Get Rid of Your Mortgage Insurance?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/zR6wgPYdlrM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Removing mortgage insurance is different for conventional and FHA loans. However, most people may not realize that the removal of mortgage insurance, regardless of loan type, is actually dictated by the federal government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you take out an FHA loan, your ability to remove mortgage insurance is predicated on the down payment amount. If you put more than 10% down, you are only required to pay mortgage insurance for 11 years. If you put less than 10% down, &lt;strong&gt;then you have to pay mortgage insurance for the entire life of the loan.&lt;/strong&gt; So, keep that in mind if you are considering an FHA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conventional loans carry private mortgage insurance, or PMI. Most people think that once they get to 80% loan to value, the mortgage insurance falls off. That’s not exactly true. The rule states that if you pay mortgage insurance, it automatically falls off at 78% loan to value—but you can request to remove it at 80% LTV. Contact your loan servicer once you reach 80% and ask to get that PMI removed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Appreciation in value adds a bit of a wrinkle to this process.%20http://winningwithwade.com/are-you-ready-to-get-rid-of-your-mortgage-insurance.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Appreciation in value adds a bit of a wrinkle to this process.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Appreciation in value does add another wrinkle to this process.&lt;/strong&gt; A lot of customers say, “My home appreciated in value since I bought it. Now I have the 20% equity and would like to remove my mortgage insurance.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is fine, but the rules for using appreciation as justification are different than the rules based on the original purchase price. You are ineligible to use appreciation as justification years zero through two of owning the home. Between the two and five-year mark, you need 25% equity for justification; after five years, that number goes back down to 20%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your loan servicer will require an updated appraisal at that time to make sure that you have subsequent equity levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about removing mortgage insurance, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 10:54:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://winningwithwade.com/are-you-ready-to-get-rid-of-your-mortgage-insurance.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://winningwithwade.com/are-you-ready-to-get-rid-of-your-mortgage-insurance.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Texas-Specific Equity Loan Rules</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/adaXpZFGsus?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may not realize it, but we actually have some of the most conservative equity laws in the country down here in Texas. They limit the maximum loan-to-value of your financing to 80% of the home’s value. &lt;strong&gt;Regardless of the financing you are doing, the state requires an appraisal to be conducted to determine its value to make sure it doesn’t exceed the 80% threshold.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few different types of equity loans out there. Here’s a little bit of information about each.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Equity lines of credit are variable and can be used for practically anything. Standalone second liens are typically taken out for home improvements. Cash-out refinances are when you refinance your entire loan balance in excess of what you want to borrow to get cash out of the property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You can only have one equity loan at a time.%20http://winningwithwade.com/texas-specific-equity-loan-rules.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You can only have one equity loan at a time.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are advantages and disadvantages to each, but one thing about these loans is universal in Texas. &lt;strong&gt;Whenever you take one out, there is a 12-month cooling off period until you can touch it.&lt;/strong&gt; If you did a cash-out refinance and rates cratered immediately after, you are prevented from refinancing again until after the period has passed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, keep in mind that in Texas, you are only allowed one equity loan on a property at a time. If you did a cash-out refinance, for example, you are not allowed to take a home equity LOC out after the fact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me or would like to discuss your specific scenario, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 11:02:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://winningwithwade.com/texas-specific-equity-loan-rules.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://winningwithwade.com/texas-specific-equity-loan-rules.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Can You Buy a Home for Your Parents?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/gsGxSsduAb0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people would like to buy a home for their parents, but don’t know the best way how. The answer largely depends on the circumstances of the parents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fannie Mae guidelines allow a child to buy a property for their parents, &lt;strong&gt;and if the parents don’t qualify, the child can purchase it as a primary residence.&lt;/strong&gt;The advantage of this is the lower interest rates and lower down payment requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=How you buy a house for your parents depends on their unique circumstances.%20http://winningwithwade.com/can-you-buy-a-home-for-your-parents.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“How you buy a house for your parents depends on their unique circumstances.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the parents qualify for a mortgage, the child can still purchase the property, but it has to be structured as an investment property purchase, which will have more restrictive down payment requirements and higher interest rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you or anyone you know are thinking about buying a home for your parents, we’d love to sit down with you and talk about the intricacies of this kind of transaction and how to put you in the best possible position. We’d be honored to serve you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2017 11:29:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://winningwithwade.com/can-you-buy-a-home-for-your-parents.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://winningwithwade.com/can-you-buy-a-home-for-your-parents.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Handle a Mortgage During a Divorce</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/RpzletUHTGQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a marriage ends, what happens to the house and the mortgage?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to know the plans for the home. You can refinance to remove one person from the loan or sell the house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Texas is a community property state. A refinance may not be necessary if you dictate in the divorce decree who will be obligated to make the payments. However, the downside is that the departing spouse’s credit is still tied to the home. If the occupying spouse misses a payment, it would still negatively affect the other’s credit. That’s why I recommend refinancing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=It's important to know the plans for the home.%20http://winningwithwade.com/how-to-handle-mortgage-during-divorce.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“It’s important to know the plans for the home.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The timing will dictate whether an owelty lien is used. In Texas, if you’re trying to refinance to remove one spouse, many times you need to take cash out to pay them their share of the equity. Texas has limits for the maximum loan-to-value you can have on a cash-out refinance of 80%. Depending on what the home appraises at or the agreed payment, it may or may not be enough equity to take out. The alternative is the owelty lien, which gets put on the property for the agreed-upon amount and prevents the occupying spouse from refinancing or selling the property without guaranteeing payment to the departing spouse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the most secure way to get equity out of the home. However, it needs to be agreed upon before the divorce is finalized. Sadly, I many people come to me after the divorce is already finalized, so this option is off the table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Selling the property releases both parties from the obligation of the mortgage, but they both still need to move somewhere. That’s why it’s still important to speak with a mortgage lender to get the situation resolved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information on this sensitive topic, click here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you or anyone you know is in this situation and needs guidance, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. It would be my honor to help you through this process.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 16:16:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://winningwithwade.com/how-to-handle-mortgage-during-divorce.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://winningwithwade.com/how-to-handle-mortgage-during-divorce.html</guid>
        
        <category>Mortgage Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Different Types of Mortgage Insurance and How They Function</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/s2cDOcklKKI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To many people, the topic of mortgage insurance carries a negative connotation, but it shouldn’t. It has its place in the mortgage process and can benefit you as a consumer. There are three main types of mortgage insurance you need to be aware of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Know the goals of your property before picking a mortgage insurance.%20http://winningwithwade.com/the-different-types-of-mortgage.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Know the goals of your property before picking a mortgage insurance.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most common type is borrower-paid monthly mortgage insurance. This is where the monthly amount gets added to the principal and interest portion of your payment. You would then make that payment each month until you get to a 78% loan-to-value ratio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other type is single-premium financed mortgage insurance. This is where the lifetime costs of the mortgage insurance get financed into the loan amount. It keeps your interest rate the same, but it adds to the loan amount. This actually results in a lower monthly payment because you don’t have the interest rate at that higher amount each month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last type is lender-paid mortgage insurance. This is where the lender pays the lifetime cost of the mortgage insurance in exchange for you agreeing to a higher interest rate. A higher interest rate has a negative connotation with most consumers, but the reality is that it results in the lowest possible monthly payment, and it’s even lower once you consider the after-tax mortgage interest deduction. This is a good way to structure your loan, but not if you’re going to keep the loan for a very long time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The benefit of the monthly mortgage insurance is that it can fall off once you get to the 78% loan-to-value ratio. If you finance it in as a lump sum into the loan amount or roll it into the interest rate, there’s nothing to fall off because it has already been factored in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rules to remove monthly insurance are pretty complicated, and which structure makes the most sense for you is largely dependent on your goals for your property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My staff and I would be honored to help walk you through this, so if you have any more questions or know anyone looking to purchase a home in the next six months, please don’t hesitate to give us a call. we‘d love to speak with you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 14:56:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://winningwithwade.com/the-different-types-of-mortgage.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://winningwithwade.com/the-different-types-of-mortgage.html</guid>
        
        <category>Mortgage Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Can You Get the Effect of Bi-Weekly Payments Without the Middleman?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/U4p8l27fX68?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We often get questions from clients asking about bi-weekly payment options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact is, once you close on a transaction, you’re going to get inundated with junk mail, much of which will be requests for you to sign up for a bi-weekly payment option. This means that instead of paying your mortgage once a month, you’d pay twice a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=With this plan, you get the same effect as bi-weekly payments without the middle man and their fee.%20http://winningwithwade.com/how-can-you-get-effect-of-bi-weekly.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“With this plan, you get the same effect as bi-weekly payments without the middle man and their fee.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reality of working with these companies, though, is that you’ll pay them a month in advance. Then, you’ll pay every two weeks, and in turn, they will pay your lender once a month. This will continue until they’ve built up enough reserves in the escrow account they’ve set up for you to make that 13th payment a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I advise my clients to take that monthly payment you’re paying to your lender each month, divide it by 12, and add that amount to what you pay every single month. This results in a 13th payment being made every year. It’s exactly the same as the bi-weekly payment plan, with the only difference being that by doing it yourself, you cut out the middleman—and their fee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this payment plan, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I’d be honored to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 14:40:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://winningwithwade.com/how-can-you-get-effect-of-bi-weekly.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://winningwithwade.com/how-can-you-get-effect-of-bi-weekly.html</guid>
        
        <category>Mortgage Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
