<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The VA Loan Guy</title>
    <description>Patrick Fitzgerald, the VA Loan Guy, is located in San Antonio, Texas and is a true “One Stop Lender”. We originate, underwrite, and close all types of loans. We offer Texas Vet, Veterans, FHA, Conventional, Jumbo, Adjustable Rate, and Investment products.</description>
    <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.thevaloanguy.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 15:12:57 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 15:12:57 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Is Your Future Property Located in a Flood Zone?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/62imiwsSbog?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is it crucial when buying a property that you check if it’s located in a flood zone? Let me tell you a quick story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m doing a loan for a couple who bought a 12-acre property awhile back but didn’t know that part of the property was in a flood zone. Since they only recently learned about this and we’ve pulled a flood certificate, they now have to pay between $100 and $200 a month extra for the entire life of their loan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you use a Realtor to buy a property, make sure they work hard to check for this kind of information. &lt;strong&gt;Most of the time, if a property is located within a flood zone, that fact will be listed in the seller’s disclosure.&lt;/strong&gt;Some sellers themselves don’t even know if their property is located in a flood zone, though. This could be because they inherited the property, bought it at an auction, or the land was split off from another parcel. Sometimes, unfortunately, they can also be dishonest and just not tell you about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You should always research if a property is located within a flood zone before you buy it.%20http://www.thevaloanguy.com/is-your-future-property-located-in-a-flood-zone.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You should always research if a property is located within a flood zone before you buy it.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why, again, you should always research if a property is located within a flood zone before you buy it. If you’re using a mortgage to finance the purchase, ask your lender to run what’s called a “flood cert” (or flood certificate), where they reach out to FEMA and FEMA reports back to them whether the property is located either partially or wholly within a flood zone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have that flood certificate, it will put your home into a certain category. You can then give this information to your insurance agent and they can tell you to what extent your flood insurance will cost you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the property is only located partially within a flood zone, &lt;strong&gt;you can ask a surveyor to provide an elevation certificate,&lt;/strong&gt; which may show that the home site where you plan on building is not in a flood zone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about flood insurance or there’s anything else I can help you with, don’t hesitate to give me a call. As always, it doesn’t cost a penny to talk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 14:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/is-your-future-property-located-in-a-flood-zone.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thevaloanguy.com/is-your-future-property-located-in-a-flood-zone.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Should You Work With My Own Realtor</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/UsF-etNFkTw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, we’re going to talk about why you need your own Realtor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When driving around looking for a home, you might come across a house you like with a yard sign featuring a phone number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people are tempted to pick up the phone and call, but you need to know that the number on the sign is for a Realtor who represents the seller. They have a signed contract with that homeowner, &lt;strong&gt;meaning that they’re not financially obligated to represent your interests, and don’t have to inform you about any known issues in the house.&lt;/strong&gt; They have no fiduciary responsibility to you as a buyer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A buyer’s agent will represent you and only you.%20http://www.thevaloanguy.com/why-should-you-work-with-my-own-realtor.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A buyer’s agent will represent you and only you.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why it’s important for you to have your own Realtor. When you have your own representation, &lt;strong&gt;it doesn’t cost you anything because the selling fees are paid for by the seller of the property.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A buyer’s agent will represent you and only you. They’re obligated to protect your interests. Your Realtor will work in conjunction with the seller’s agent to negotiate the best deal for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, feel free to reach out to me. Remember, it doesn’t cost a penny to talk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2018 13:57:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/why-should-you-work-with-my-own-realtor.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thevaloanguy.com/why-should-you-work-with-my-own-realtor.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What’s the Difference Between an Inspection and an Appraisal?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/G283RfQsw2o?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the difference between an inspection and an appraisal? Today, I’d like to clear up some key differences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many veterans call me believing that the VA is going to do an inspection on their home, when in fact, that’s not really the case. &lt;strong&gt;The VA will appraise a home, not inspect it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An appraiser is there to view the property, measure it for square footage, take pictures of the home, and study the property as a whole to determine its value.&lt;/strong&gt; This is done by comparing it to other properties with similar square footage and amenities that have sold in the area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The VA does not require a veteran to get an inspection of the home they’re buying.%20http://www.thevaloanguy.com/whats-the-difference-between-an-inspection-and-an-appraisal.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The VA does not require a veteran to get an inspection of the home they’re buying.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An inspector, on the other hand, couldn’t care less about the value of the property. &lt;strong&gt;Inspectors are there to measure the home’s functionality. &lt;/strong&gt;In other words, the inspector’s goal is to make sure that the air conditioning and heating system is working, any appliances are fully functional, the electrical framework is up to scratch, and that there are no safety issues in the house. The inspector will generate a 35- to 40-page document with pictures of anything of interest found that needs to be addressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be clear, the VA does not require a veteran to get an inspection of the home they’re buying. Personally, I would never buy a house without an inspection, but under the terms of the VA loan, they’re not necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, it doesn’t cost a penny to talk to me. Feel free to give me a call and I’d be happy to answer all of your questions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 09:46:59 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/whats-the-difference-between-an-inspection-and-an-appraisal.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thevaloanguy.com/whats-the-difference-between-an-inspection-and-an-appraisal.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mortgage Loan Rules for Moving a Manufactured Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/OdZutuonvBc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I wanted to clarify the rules on moving a manufactured home. A lot of people don’t know this, but there are some very, very specific rules regarding this topic and there’s a lot of confusion about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why is this so important?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lender may not be able to do one of the top three loans—FHA, conventional, or VA loan—on a manufactured home if it’s been moved. FHA and conventional loans don’t allow a home to be moved or reinstalled once it has been in installed in its original location. Only VA loans, the loan option for veterans, allow the option to move a home once after its initial installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Does the trip from the manufacturer to the location count as a move?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;No, it doesn’t count as a move. But here’s what you need to know: If the owner sells the home or has been foreclosed upon, if the home is moved from where it was installed to another location after having been sold, then that is considered a move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Only VA loans, the loan option for veterans, allow the option to move a home once after its initial installation.%20http://www.thevaloanguy.com/mortgage-loan-rules-for-moving-a-manufactured-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Only VA loans, the loan option for veterans, allow the option to move a home once after its initial installation.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where do we get all this information?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can visit the Texas Department of Housing website at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.TDHCA.state.tx.us&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.TDHCA.state.tx.us&lt;/a&gt; for records on every installation of manufactured homes. A manufactured home installer is licensed and by law they must log on to that site, enter their license number, then tag numbers of the manufactured home and the serial numbers and declare that they installed a specific home with both the date and location of that installation. This site is how lenders find out if a home has been moved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is critical information no matter if you’re on the buyer’s or seller’s side because some lenders don’t even know how to do this. You should want to know in advance if you’re wasting your time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this, feel free to give me a call or send an email. I’ll answer all of your questions, and after all, it doesn’t cost a penny to talk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/mortgage-loan-rules-for-moving-a-manufactured-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thevaloanguy.com/mortgage-loan-rules-for-moving-a-manufactured-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Where Can Veterans Get a Home Improvement Loan?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/QcJ98XHnu54?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a veteran looking for a home improvement loan to make some upgrades to your home, I have good news and bad news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bad news is the VA doesn’t offer any loans for this purpose. &lt;strong&gt;The good news is the Texas Veterans Land Board does,&lt;/strong&gt; and they recently doubled the amount they’re willing to loan to a veteran—$50,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a couple very favorable terms to this loan. Not only will they go up to 20 years on the loan at below market rate, but you don’t have to provide a down payment either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You don’t even need a down payment with this loan.%20http://www.thevaloanguy.com/where-can-veterans-get-a-home-improvement-loan.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You don’t even need a down payment with this loan.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To apply for this loan, just go online at &lt;a href=&quot;www.texasveterans.com&quot;&gt;www.texasveterans.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; From there, they’ll contact you to get the ball rolling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the requirements for this loan is you need to gather two bids for the work you want to be done—they won’t allow you to do it yourself. After they underwrite and approve the loan, the work will begin. Typically, they’ll send the money to a local title company in your area. As soon as the work is done, they’ll send an inspector to your home to ensure the work has been done satisfactorily and you’re happy with it. After that, they’ll fund the work and make sure the suppliers get paid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are home improvement loans available for non-veterans too. They’re typically done by most banks or federal credit unions, and most of them are underwritten by HUD. If you’d like to know more about these, ask your local bank or credit union.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any more questions about home improvement loans, don’t hesitate to give me a call. As always, it doesn’t cost a penny to talk, and I’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 07:10:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/where-can-veterans-get-a-home-improvement-loan.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thevaloanguy.com/where-can-veterans-get-a-home-improvement-loan.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Unique Opportunity for Veteran Homebuyers</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/VPX_b-Kyumg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you know that you can not only use VA financing to buy a home with 0% down, but you can also use VA financing to buy a multi-family property? If you set things up right, the home will essentially pay for itself. Here’s what I mean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You are allowed to use a VA loan to purchase a multi-family property, but there are a few caveats.&lt;/strong&gt; First, you must occupy the property as a primary residence within 60 days of closing on the property. That’s a very important rule to remember.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=This is a smart investment strategy.%20http://www.thevaloanguy.com/a-unique-opportunity-for-veteran-homebuyers.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“This is a smart investment strategy.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to multi-family properties, you can actually use the projected rent from the other units in the home to count towards your qualifying number. Because of this, you will be able to qualify for a home with a much higher price. You’ll also have the opportunity to make passive income through rent as you own the home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have VA disability, you will also have a reduction in your property taxes. If you are 100% service-connected disabled, there are no property taxes whatsoever on the entire complex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are a lot of ways we can make this work, even if you don’t have any prior experience as a landlord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this program or about anything else, give me a call or send me an email today. It doesn’t cost a penny to talk. I look forward to hearing from you soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 07:04:36 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/a-unique-opportunity-for-veteran-homebuyers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thevaloanguy.com/a-unique-opportunity-for-veteran-homebuyers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What You Need to Know About Property Surveys</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/W5CGD7ddiEI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A property survey is a very important document in a real estate transaction. What is a property survey, though? What do you need to know about them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When a mortgage company finances the property in question of a real estate transaction, they’ll require a property survey.&lt;/strong&gt;This survey shows several key things. Most importantly, it shows where the house will sit on that property. It also shows the legal description of the property— which is important for recording ownership—and where the exact property lines are and where the fences are. If the property doesn’t have a fence and you’re thinking of putting one in, that will show the fence contractors where to put it on the property line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The property survey will also note the locations of any pools, outbuildings, or driveways, and where those are in reference to any legal setbacks. Legal setbacks are the dimensions that the city or county requires you not to encroach upon when building your house. There is no set amount of space in this regard, but if you’re thinking about building a swimming pool in the backyard, you don’t want to build it within the utility easement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Property surveys show several important things.%20http://www.thevaloanguy.com/what-you-need-to-know-about-property-surveys.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Property surveys show several important things.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This information is important not only if you’re building a home, but if you’re buying an existing home as well.&lt;/strong&gt; If your property is encroaching on your neighbor’s, for example, you need to know that up front so it can be remedied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the state of Texas, a property survey can be reused. A lot of people don’t recommend that, but our position is as long as it’s legible and the engineer’s stamp can be read, there’s no reason you can’t reuse it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reusing a survey, however, means that it may not show any changes that have been made in utility easements. This doesn’t happen very often, but it’s why some real estate companies require the prospective buyer to always get a new survey. That’s a decision you and your Realtor can make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, it doesn’t cost a penny to talk, so if you have any more questions about property surveys, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 06:50:42 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/what-you-need-to-know-about-property-surveys.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thevaloanguy.com/what-you-need-to-know-about-property-surveys.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Is Using an IRRL a Smart Move for You?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/xm4bU0aRWD0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Pat, I just closed my VA loan with you. Within two weeks, I’m starting to get letters every week offering me to refinance my home loan. How do they even know I did a loan with you? Why am I getting these offers right off the bat?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a question I get asked a lot and a scenario I encounter quite often. We didn’t sell your loan or your information to anybody, but in the state of Texas, whenever someone buys a home, it’s public information if there’s a loan put on it at the courthouse. No other information is recorded—it just denotes that the person bought a home and used a VA loan to do so&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are people who sell that information and there are certain mortgage companies who focus solely on an interest rate reduction refinance, or IRRL.&lt;/strong&gt; This is a product that the VA allows that, in my opinion, got completely out of hand. The VA’s position on it, however, is if the veteran can benefit from a reduced house payment, they see no issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=In my opinion, these fast and low refinance offers very rarely make sense to pursue.%20http://www.thevaloanguy.com/is-using-an-irrl-a-smart-move-for-you.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“In my opinion, these fast and low refinance offers very rarely make sense to pursue.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How does this product work?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some nice things about it. It greatly reduces paperwork, and in most cases, it doesn’t require another appraisal, any paycheck stubs, or even bank statements. The VA also allows the closing costs to be put into the new loan. We do have to verify in the credit report that the payments have been made on time and for at least the last 12 months. In most cases, you can come to closing with nothing but a pen in hand and can get a lower house payment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, the payment is lowered, and there are other advantages, but at what cost? &lt;strong&gt;In order to get that lower rate, these mortgage companies force you to buy points.&lt;/strong&gt; This means that once you do the closing, the balance on the rate begins to grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me give you an example of a situation like this I dealt with a few months ago. One of these mortgage companies came to one of my clients that had closed on a home two months prior and offered him a 2.99% rate to refinance a loan that had a $200,000 balance. When I asked him to give me a copy of the good faith estimate, I found that they had $17,000 worth of points and other associated fees to buy that loan down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did they give him a lower house payment? Yes—it was about $137 per month. The problem, though, was when he came away from closing, he owed $217,000 on the home instead of $200,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This kind of situation can spell trouble for you if and when you sell your home.&lt;/strong&gt; In many cases, you have to come to closing with money in order to get out from under the loan. Let’s not forget, in most cases when you sell a home, you’ll also have about 6% in real estate fees. If you tack that onto the extra $17,000, you’ve got a really difficult situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do these fast and low refinance offers make sense to pursue? In my opinion, very rarely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about IRRLs, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 08:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/is-using-an-irrl-a-smart-move-for-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thevaloanguy.com/is-using-an-irrl-a-smart-move-for-you.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>If a Storm Hits, Do You Have Coverage?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/j9NPVY4yQUo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The terrible situations that have unfolded in Texas, Florida, and elsewhere are still fresh in our minds, and for good reason. People have been flooded out of their homes, and it has been absolutely heartbreaking to watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So today, I wanted to talk about what flood insurance is and why it can be helpful in situations like these.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important thing I want you to know is that &lt;strong&gt;homeowners insurance does not cover rising water.&lt;/strong&gt; If water happens to come in from the roof, it will be covered under homeowners insurance. If it comes from beneath and rises into your home, however, it is simply not covered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of the approximately 185,000 homes that were flooded in Houston, 80% of them did not have flood insurance. Flood insurance is its own separate policy, meaning that you will need to call and request this specific type of coverage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Don’t wait until you see the hurricane coming before you think about your coverage.%20http://www.thevaloanguy.com/if-a-storm-hits-do-you-have-coverage.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Don’t wait until you see the hurricane coming before you think about your coverage.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s important to be aware that flooding can still occur in non-flood zones.&lt;/strong&gt; If you do happen to live in a non-flood zone, the government caps the price of coverage at $410. Here’s something else you need to know: Because flood insurance is a separate policy, it covers just $250,000 on the dwelling regardless of the value of the home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There is also an additional $100,000 worth of coverage for the contents of your home, such as furniture and other personal effects.&lt;/strong&gt; Keep in mind that both of these figures are the maximum amount of coverage provided and may not always be what is given in the event of a flood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should also realize that flood insurance does not go into effect for 30 days after purchase. For this reason, you don’t want to wait until you see the hurricane coming before you think about your coverage. For $30 or so a month, I find the coverage to be well worth it. After everything that happened, I’ve definitely purchased flood insurance, myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/if-a-storm-hits-do-you-have-coverage.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thevaloanguy.com/if-a-storm-hits-do-you-have-coverage.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Can You Build With the VA Loan?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wzOuuHovmuw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you use a VA loan to build on land you own? Of course you can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t cost a penny to talk….&lt;a href=&quot;http://texas-vet-loans.com/contact/&quot;&gt;so call me right now and I will answer your questions!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://preapp1003.com/id/Patrick-Fitzgerald/&quot;&gt;Apply Now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve got land, can you use your VA loan to build on it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer is: of course you can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you know this is a possibility, there are a few things you need to consider before you can make it happen. The first step is to have your home designed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you’ve met with an architect to do this, you’ll need to generate the blueprints and specifications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step is to determine what costs will be associated with this process. That cost includes the &lt;strong&gt;price of building the home itself, site preparation, and other factors as well.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of this information that you’ve gathered until this point will then need to be presented to an appraiser. Requesting a VA construction appraisal is different from the normal appraisal process because in this case, the appraiser has no house to look at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=THE FUNDS FROM THIS 30-YEAR VA LOAN WILL PAY OFF THE CONSTRUCTION LOAN.%20http://www.thevaloanguy.com/can-you-build-with-the-va-loan.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“THE FUNDS FROM THIS 30-YEAR VA LOAN WILL PAY OFF THE CONSTRUCTION LOAN.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, the appraiser will visit and photograph the site, look at the plans for your home, and find comparable properties in the area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within a couple of weeks, the appraiser will determine an approximation of the home’s value upon completion. Having this value from the start is a great way to prevent any unsavory surprises down the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this, you’re finally ready to get a construction loan. If you happen to owe money on the land, &lt;strong&gt;the first draw of the construction loan will pay that cost off,&lt;/strong&gt; as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At various points throughout the process, the builder will take draws—with the final draw coming once the house is completed. It is at this point, during the final phase of construction, that your VA loan will be put together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The funds from this 30-year VA loan will pay off the construction loan. It’s really that simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, remember that it costs nothing to talk. Feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 13:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/can-you-build-with-the-va-loan.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thevaloanguy.com/can-you-build-with-the-va-loan.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
