<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Dave Friedman Team - your professional Charleston Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://davefriedmancoaching.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://davefriedmancoaching.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 14:17:13 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 14:17:13 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Check Out My Full Appearance on Real Estate Uncensored</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently had the pleasure of being a guest on the Real Estate Uncensored podcast with Greg McDaniel and Matt Johnson. We had a wide-ranging discussion that touched on a number of topics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://realestateuncensored.libsyn.com/podcast/dave-friedman&quot;&gt;Click here to listen to the full podcast.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main area of focus was how I went from being a solo agent doing 40 deals a year to being a team leader who was doing 400 deals a year in a short time. I also had some time to answer questions, both from the viewers and from Matt and Greg about my business. &lt;strong&gt;Here’s a summary of our discussions with timestamps so you can skip ahead if any part particularly interests you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3:30- How I like to handle hesitant clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;12:00- How I developed my method for getting more referrals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;19:00- How I’m continuing to grow my database even today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;25:30- How my 71-touch program is getting me a 55x ROI and making up a third of my business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;33:00- Why discipline and culture are the two keys to our dramatic growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Discipline and culture are the two biggest keys to our growth.%20http://davefriedmancoaching.com/check-out-my-full-appearance-on-real-estate-uncensored.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Discipline and culture are the two biggest keys to our growth.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;36:00- How we discovered our team members’ motivations and how that has impacted the culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;43:00- What motivates me today?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;47:00- How letting my system take over improved my business and my life in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;52:00- Hungry and humble is the name of the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I’m here for you anytime.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://davefriedmancoaching.com/check-out-my-full-appearance-on-real-estate-uncensored.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://davefriedmancoaching.com/check-out-my-full-appearance-on-real-estate-uncensored.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Our Comprehensive Open House Marketing Plan</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wStGDEGEQKo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many sellers have recently asked me how we have such great turnout at our open houses, so I wanted to share some quick advice. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We have a 15-page marketing page that explains our whole open house process&lt;/strong&gt; that I’d be happy to send to you, but for now, I wanted to give you the main points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start by keeping the home clean and maximizing the curb appeal. The home should be completely decluttered and the curb appeal should be 10/10 because it means everything. People will drive up to the house, take a look, and keep on driving if the curb appeal isn’t up to par. If it needs to be painted, get it painted. If it needs pine straw or mulch, get some. To get people inside the home, the outside has to be beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It takes about 90 minutes to prepare for our open houses because we put up more than 100 signs.&lt;/strong&gt; We’ll put one sign per turn in the neighborhood, and once we get to the major arteries outside the neighborhood, we’ll put 10 directional signs pointing to your neighborhood from one direction and 10 more from the other direction. That way, traffic on both sides of the street can see the signage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=To get people inside the home, the outside has to be beautiful.%20http://davefriedmancoaching.com/our-comprehensive-open-house-marketing-plan.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“To get people inside the home, the outside has to be beautiful.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, we generate a lot of interest with our digital marketing. We have a database of more 800 active buyers looking to buy a home, so we’ll not only market to them, but target people on social media who are likely to make a move. We run marketing campaigns for about a week in advance to drum up interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Publications also work great, so I publish a 15-page real estate-related newspaper that goes to 28,000 homes with an open house section where we feature homes. Finally, we try to get everyone to register once they come in so we can follow up with them and ask questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, if you’d like our full 15-page document, I’d be happy to share it with you. If you have any questions about open houses or anything in your real estate career, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I hope to hear from you soon!
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://davefriedmancoaching.com/our-comprehensive-open-house-marketing-plan.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://davefriedmancoaching.com/our-comprehensive-open-house-marketing-plan.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How I Increased My Business by Working My Database</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/b5QjNvxxaoE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Above, you’ll find a replay of my full discussion with Frank Klesitz of Vyral Marketing. &lt;strong&gt;Here is what we covered with timestamps so you can jump to the section that most interests you:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(0:50) My professional story. How I got into real estate and built my company from the ground up.
&lt;br /&gt;(5:00) How I took the next step in my business by implementing different systems.
&lt;br /&gt;(8:05) How many people I talk to a week and how I went from three to 30 sales a year from my database.
&lt;br /&gt;(10:25) How many opt-ins I get every week.
&lt;br /&gt;(15:20) What caused my recent increase in production? The conversion of previous leads we already had or the increased attention to my database?
&lt;br /&gt;(20:00) How to avoid spam when marketing online.
&lt;br /&gt;(21: 50) My take on traditional real estate farming.
&lt;br /&gt;(26:45) What do I recommend for you to feed your database?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://davefriedmancoaching.com/how-i-increased-my-business-by-working-my-database.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://davefriedmancoaching.com/how-i-increased-my-business-by-working-my-database.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Our Team Finds Success With This Unique Tool</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8pdA2eQPuu4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of people want to know how our team is able to be so productive. Our agents’ 40 transactions per year, do over $10 million in volume, and take home big paychecks. How are they able to do this? A lot of their success is due to one simple tool that will change the way you approach your career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a simple form called “Dominate your day, win your week!” and it’s something our team members fill out each day. It helps you plan out your day to make it as productive as possible. &lt;strong&gt;There are six steps to personal productivity mastery:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Focus, do not multi-task, and eliminate distractions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make lists based on dollar-producing activities. 20% of your activities will produce 80% of the results.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prioritize everything you do based on your goals.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Protect your time blocks. Plan your day in 30-minute increments and don’t let anything interfere.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eliminate clutter.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Plan your week on Sunday and plan each day in advance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you figure out what your top money making activities are, put those on your list first. Then, you can fill out the different time slots, noting when you plan to start and stop. As we move down the form, you have sections for determining how much each activity is worth to you so you can wrap your head around what it will cost you to neglect those activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s also a section on there for you to write down your “10 wins for the day” to give yourself a more positive focus. &lt;strong&gt;Sometimes a win is setting an appointment. Sometimes it’s having lunch with your spouse.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s important to keep things in perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, there’s a section on the form for you to write down notes. Anything that comes to mind during the day can be written, including notes for the day and things you might need to add to your dollar-producing activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this form or would like to get a copy of your own, just give me a call or send me an email and I’d be happy to get you one. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Send me an email and I’d be happy to get you one. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 11:46:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://davefriedmancoaching.com/how-our-team-finds-success-with-this.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://davefriedmancoaching.com/how-our-team-finds-success-with-this.html</guid>
        
        <category>Increase Business</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What’s Sexy About Consistency?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I had the pleasure of being a guest on Patrick Lilly’s Real Estate Success Rocks podcast. Patrick puts on phenomenal masterminds with a select group of top-producing real estate agents across North America; his podcasts are a great way to get a sneak peek into those masterminds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was on his show, Patrick and I discussed the importance of consistency in your business. Here are a few things we went over:When I was on his show, Patrick and I discussed the importance of consistency in your business. Here are a few things we went over:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-daily-routine&quot;&gt;My Daily Routine&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Miracle Morning&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tell Me Something Good call&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dominate your day&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Daily prospecting using Mojo&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Daily follow up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;weekly-routine&quot;&gt;Weekly Routine&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pipeline report&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;List of opportunities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hopper system&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Weekly one-on-one meetings&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Weekly team meetings&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Our 70-touch system for our database&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Using quarterly lookbacks and a business grading score card.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Patrick likes to say, there is nothing sexier than consistency. You can listen to the full episode &lt;a href=&quot;http://repodcast.rocks/096-consistency-is-sexy-with-dave-friedman/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in any of the resources Patrick and I discuss on the show, check out this list:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.SoldWithDave.com&quot;&gt;www.SoldWithDave.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/realestaterants&quot;&gt;twitter.com/realestaterants&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I highly recommend that you listen to all of the Real Estate Success Rocks podcast episodes. You will learn a lot from Patrick and other agents across the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any questions about how to improve your business, just give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 16:12:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://davefriedmancoaching.com/whats-sexy-about-consistency.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://davefriedmancoaching.com/whats-sexy-about-consistency.html</guid>
        
        <category>Increase Business</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Do You Build a Winning Real Estate Team? </title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently had the pleasure of appearing on Pat Hiban’s Real Estate Rockstars Radio, where Pat interviews the top voices in the real estate industry. On this episode, you’ll learn:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A bit of my business background.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why I decided to build a real estate team instead of becoming an individual agent.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How I close a deal per open house.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How long it took me to build a team.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How my ISA helps drive my business.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How many appointments I get thanks to the systems I set up within my team.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The biggest part of my business.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to break through your goals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is just a sample of the great conversation I had with Pat HIban. You can listen to the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://hibandigital.com/davefriedman/&quot;&gt;full episode here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in any of the resources we mention on the show, here is a complete list:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://davefriedmantv.com/&quot;&gt;Dave Friedman Real Estate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://draft.blogger.com/&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://clickcharlestonsc.com/&quot;&gt;clickcharlestonsc.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter/&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vulcan7.com/&quot;&gt;Vulcan 7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mojosells.com/&quot;&gt;Mojo Dialer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kunversion.com/corporate/archer/&quot;&gt;Kunversion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theredx.com/&quot;&gt;REDX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I highly recommend listening to the rest of Pat Hiban’s Real Estate Rockstars episodes to learn more from the top producing agents, coaches, and brokers in the industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, if you have any questions for me, please don’t hesitate to reach out. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 10:56:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://davefriedmancoaching.com/how-do-you-build-winning-real-estate.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://davefriedmancoaching.com/how-do-you-build-winning-real-estate.html</guid>
        
        <category>Build a Real Estate Team</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Join Us and Make 2017 the Best Year of Your Life</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/S34OOxUbcw0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you reach all of your personal and professional goals in 2016? Do you want to do better in 2017?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re looking for motivated, energetic, talented people to join our team, and today I wanted to you tell about** a great tool we started using to hold ourselves accountable so we can hit all of our personal and professional goals and make 2017 the best year of our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On average each agent produces $10M in volume and sells 40 homes per year. In comparison to the average agent who sells 4 homes a year, its obvious our team has created a proven and repeatable system for Realtors to become extremely successful. If you didn’t achieve what you set out to do in 2016, this tool will help you immensely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=This tool will help you reach all of your personal and professional goals.%20http://davefriedmancoaching.com/join-us-and-make-2017-best-year-of-your.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“This tool will help you reach all of your personal and professional goals.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have many job openings listed on this blog, so if you’re interested in achieving all the goals that you didn’t in 2016, reach out to me so I can share this tool with you and discuss the opportunities we have to offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I look forward to hearing from you! , reach out to me so I can share this tool with you and discuss the opportunities we have to offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 15:03:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://davefriedmancoaching.com/join-us-and-make-2017-best-year-of-your.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://davefriedmancoaching.com/join-us-and-make-2017-best-year-of-your.html</guid>
        
        <category>Increase Business</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How I Doubled My Dealings In One Year</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/luT2ErUTYcM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an overview of what we covered with time-stamps so you can jump to the section that most interests you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2:00&lt;/strong&gt;- How I dealt with the problems and challenges of closing so many buyer sides in one year and how I supercharged my business by adding the right systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3:30&lt;/strong&gt;- All the pillars I’ve implemented in my business, and how that helped me get to where I am today.  ** 6:30**- How I implemented and executed an expired system to increase my listing business and get a 6x ROI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8:30&lt;/strong&gt;- How I got 30 deals and a 70x ROI  from my database marketing in one year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11:00&lt;/strong&gt;- An overview of our business dashboard and how it helps us stay organized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;13:00&lt;/strong&gt;- How we use our goal tracker to keep our agents on the path to success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15:00&lt;/strong&gt;- Other systems that help us dial in what my business is looking like.  If you have any questions on what we talked about, reach out to me through a call or email. I’d love to chat and see what I can do to help you! ut, reach out to me through a call or email. I’d love to chat and see what I can do to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2016 14:28:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://davefriedmancoaching.com/how-i-doubled-my-dealings-in-one-year.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://davefriedmancoaching.com/how-i-doubled-my-dealings-in-one-year.html</guid>
        
        <category>Increase Business</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
