<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Heidi Phong Real Estate Team - your professional Sacramento Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://heidiphong.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://heidiphong.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 11:35:47 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 11:35:47 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>4 Things Homebuyers Should Never Say to Sellers</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/TuTySxG2dEs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a buyer, there are four things that you should never say during a showing or to the seller:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Never say that this is your dream home.&lt;/strong&gt; It doesn’t matter how gorgeous the house is or how ugly the house is; you never want to say that you love the home, especially if the seller or seller’s agent is present. You might think that making this kind of comment would make the seller want you to get the home. However, once they know you are in love with the home, they will want to mark up the price. They will use your love for the home as leverage and maybe even make you overpay for the property, so make sure that you leave your feedback and comments with your Realtor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Never tell a seller that you can afford their home. &lt;/strong&gt;Once they know you can afford it, they will try to make you go higher. Now, there’s no room for negotiation for your buyer’s agent. The negotiation process will be more challenging, and you may end up paying more for the home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Don’t tell the seller how much you love the home unless you want to pay extra for it.%20http://heidiphong.com/4-things-homebuyers-should-never-say-to-sellers.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Don’t tell the seller how much you love the home unless you want to pay extra for it.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Don’t ask the seller why they are selling.&lt;/strong&gt; When you ask this question, sellers immediately put their guards up. They don’t have to share this information with you, and they could be moving for very personal reasons. Maybe somebody passed away, or they have to relocate because of a job situation. Don’t get really personal when it comes to buying your home, especially if the seller is right there in front of you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Never submit a lowball offer,&lt;/strong&gt; especially in a seller’s market where inventory is low and demand for houses is high. A lowball offer could be offensive to the seller. They know their home is worth a certain amount, and submitting an offer way below market value would definitely offend them. They would put their guard up and they may not entertain your offer. You will most likely lose out on a chance to get a home that you really like if you make a lowball offer. The seller will want nothing to do with you. When deciding what price to offer, talk to your professional real estate agent to come up with a fair value that will work for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, do not attempt to say any of the four things we mentioned today at your next home showing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions in the meantime, just give us a call or send us an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://heidiphong.com/4-things-homebuyers-should-never-say-to-sellers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://heidiphong.com/4-things-homebuyers-should-never-say-to-sellers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>4 Reasons Why You Should Work With a Real Estate Professional</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ko4-ivaBdd4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I have four tips for sellers who are looking to list their homes in today’s market. These tips will help you sell your home quickly, smoothly, and for more money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A real estate professional will take care of the costs of marketing your home.%20http://heidiphong.com/4-reasons-why-you-should-work-with-a-real-estate-professional.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A real estate professional will take care of the costs of marketing your home.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t list your home inaccurately.&lt;/strong&gt;This will affect how long it will take for your home to sell, how long you’ll end up staying on the market, and how much money you’ll be leaving on the table. Hire a local professional to help you determine the right price for your home.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hire an agent.&lt;/strong&gt; If you plan on listing by yourself, how will you handle negotiations and determine which offer is best for you and your family? The knowledge and expertise that Realtors have will help you negotiate terms and understand the contract, and they’ll help you eliminate stress from the process.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A real estate professional can help reduce marketing expenses.&lt;/strong&gt; By yourself, you could advertise your home on free websites, but you’d actually be missing out on the true potential of buyers on the market. A real estate professional will take care of the costs of marketing your home and will have access to even more avenues through which your home can be exposed to potential buyers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A professional will lend you time and freedom.&lt;/strong&gt; Imagine if you listed your home on your own and you tried to go on a family vacation. Your phone would blow up because everyone would want to see your home and ask questions about it. Hiring an agent would take the stress off your shoulders by managing the listing, answering calls, and making sure that you don’t miss out on opportunities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are looking to buy or sell a home in today’s market, feel free to reach out to us. We’d love to be your real estate professionals.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 11:17:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://heidiphong.com/4-reasons-why-you-should-work-with-a-real-estate-professional.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://heidiphong.com/4-reasons-why-you-should-work-with-a-real-estate-professional.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>4 Tips to Help You Get Into a Home Fast</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/HmgwJECkPGg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to get pre-approved to buy a home quickly, here are four tips which can help:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Have at least two years’ worth of work history. &lt;/strong&gt;This doesn’t mean you have to have been at the same job for two years—it just means you have to have been working for at least the last two years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Have credit.&lt;/strong&gt; Make sure you’ve been building up your credit so you can qualify for the best interest rates. If you haven’t started building your credit, apply for some credit cards from your local bank and use them wisely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=These four tips will help you get pre-approved for a loan quickly.%20http://heidiphong.com/4-tips-to-help-you-get-into-a-home-fast.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“These four tips will help you get pre-approved for a loan quickly.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Save money. &lt;/strong&gt;Nowadays, there are a lot of down payment assistance programs out there that could help you, but you’ll still have to pay for things like closing costs once you purchase your home. That money will have to come out of your pocket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Have all your documents in place. &lt;/strong&gt;This means your pay stubs, bank statements, W-2s, and all forms of identification are in place and ready to go when your lender asks for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about how to get pre-approved quickly or you have any other real estate needs, don’t hesitate to call us or send us an email. We’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 04:25:25 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://heidiphong.com/4-tips-to-help-you-get-into-a-home-fast.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://heidiphong.com/4-tips-to-help-you-get-into-a-home-fast.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Does Your Home Insurance Policy Cover Everything It Needs to?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/uzvjGvlS8tc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of commercial advertisements for different home insurance companies out there, and these advertisements can get repetitive to the point where you might assume that when they promise you “peace of mind,” they mean they will cover everything. Is that true?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are just advertisements, so &lt;strong&gt;not everything they say is true.&lt;/strong&gt; The best way to know for sure is to dive into your policy. One of the reasons I wanted to address this topic today is because of the recent wildfires Southern California’s been experiencing. So many insurance claims have been racked up due to these wildfires, and they can get expensive, especially with recent supply and demand and home values increasing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If your policy doesn’t cover certain natural disasters, it may be time to switch companies.%20http://heidiphong.com/does-your-home-insurance-policy-cover-everything-it-needs-to.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If your policy doesn’t cover certain natural disasters, it may be time to switch companies.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why you need to &lt;strong&gt;make sure your policy is up to date.&lt;/strong&gt; A couple years ago, your home may have been covered up to a certain dollar amount, but that may have changed without you even knowing about it. Make sure any damage that can be caused to your home is covered. If your neighbor’s home burned down but yours didn’t, your home can still be affected by the ash blowing onto your property. Is that cleanup covered? If you don’t understand your policy, odds are that it isn’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When an insurance company promises peace of mind, you need to make sure you understand the ins and outs of your policy. If it doesn’t cover certain natural disasters that can happen in your area, it may be time to switch companies. &lt;strong&gt;Sit down with your agent and double-check if everything is up to date.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this topic or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home in the near future, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 04:29:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://heidiphong.com/does-your-home-insurance-policy-cover-everything-it-needs-to.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://heidiphong.com/does-your-home-insurance-policy-cover-everything-it-needs-to.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>4 Ways to Make the Home Selling Process Faster and Easier</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/6vuAEbu4Ssc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you plan on selling your home, follow these four tips to make the whole process quicker and easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Take photos of your home early.&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t wait until the grass turns yellow and the leaves are off the trees. Prepare in advance by taking pictures of the inside and outside of your home while the landscaping still looks really good and green.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Have floor mats ready.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s wintertime in California, which means the weather will be rainy. Have floor mats going in and out of your home so that people don’t track water onto your wood or laminate flooring. The last thing you want is for buyers to come in and leave a mess all over your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Make sure that everything works properly.%20http://heidiphong.com/4-ways-to-make-the-home-selling-process-faster-and-easier.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Make sure that everything works properly.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Make sure everything is working properly.&lt;/strong&gt; You don’t want a buyer to come to your home and find that two out of three lights aren’t working. Make sure the HVAC system works as well. Buyers always test everything to make sure it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Listen to your Realtor when it comes to home pricing.&lt;/strong&gt; You don’t want your home to be on the market longer than it should. Pricing too high will cause your home to linger on the market, which causes buyers to wonder what’s wrong with it. Make sure that you work with your Realtor to make sure that your home is priced correctly for the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These four tips will help make the selling process faster and less stressful. If you have any other questions about selling your home, give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 06:37:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://heidiphong.com/4-ways-to-make-the-home-selling-process-faster-and-easier.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://heidiphong.com/4-ways-to-make-the-home-selling-process-faster-and-easier.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Do You Need to Know About Closing Costs?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/djQpHVdjOk8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are closing costs? How do you know what you’ll have to pay for them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Closing costs consist of escrow fees, title fees, lender fees, taxes, and the first mortgage on the home that needs to be paid off. Taking all that into consideration, the majority of buyers end up surprised by what they have to pay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We always like to educate our buyers about what to expect in a home sale, and that usually means giving them an estimate on what they will have to pay for closing costs up front.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Closing costs are usually 2% to 5% of the home’s purchase price.%20http://heidiphong.com/what-do-you-need-to-know-about-closing-costs.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Closing costs are usually 2% to 5% of the home’s purchase price.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most accurate way to estimate what you’ll have to pay in closing costs before actually closing on the house is to &lt;strong&gt;speak with a local Realtor or lender so they can review the numbers with you.&lt;/strong&gt; If you’re submitting an offer for a home, they can let you know how much you’ll need for a down payment and all your closing costs so you’re not surprised or caught unprepared at the last minute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a rule of thumb, &lt;strong&gt;closing costs are usually 2% to 5% of the home’s purchase price.&lt;/strong&gt; Again, though, always consult with a professional to find out for sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about closing costs or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home in the Sacramento area, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 06:04:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://heidiphong.com/what-do-you-need-to-know-about-closing-costs.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://heidiphong.com/what-do-you-need-to-know-about-closing-costs.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Buyers and Sellers Need to Know About Today's Sacramento Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/LfjcUIyP88Q?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been looking to buy or sell in today’s real estate market, there is some important information you’ll need to know before moving forward. Today, I’m bringing you a market update.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, sales have dropped dramatically. This isn’t because people aren’t buying—it’s because, currently, &lt;strong&gt;the supply is far too low for the high demand in our area.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There simply isn’t enough for people to choose from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, this is a great opportunity for sellers. Competition is low from a selling perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, listing your home right now could mean getting more bang for your buck. This is a strong seller’s market, so you should absolutely take advantage if you’ve been thinking of doing so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Today’s market has a lot to offer for buyers and sellers alike.%20http://heidiphong.com/what-buyers-and-sellers-need-to-know-about-todays-sacramento-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Today’s market has a lot to offer for buyers and sellers alike.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there’s still some great news for buyers in today’s market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interest rates are very low—they’ve been hovering around 4% since the beginning of 2017.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite this being a seller’s market, buyers have a lot of opportunities to take advantage of in our market today, as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have been thinking of buying or selling, now is a great time to do so. Today’s market has a lot to offer for buyers and sellers alike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, do consider your personal situation before making any move. Questions about your individual circumstances should all be taken care of with the help of your local real estate professionals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 08:31:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://heidiphong.com/what-buyers-and-sellers-need-to-know-about-todays-sacramento-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://heidiphong.com/what-buyers-and-sellers-need-to-know-about-todays-sacramento-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are You Unsure If You Want to Buy a New Home?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ATXSBCje3VY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I have three questions for buyers who think they might want to wait until next year to list their home:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Why do you need to buy?&lt;/strong&gt; Are expecting a new addition to the family? Have you just outgrown the place that you’re currently at? Is rent too high? Does buying make sense?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. What are home prices currently like&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;,&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;and where is the price headed?&lt;/strong&gt; Are they going up? If you look at home prices this year compared to last year, they’ve increased between 5% to 10%. The prices are projected to increase for another year, so if you’re waiting until next year to start looking a few home, the property you’ve had your eye on might be more expensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Home prices have increased 5% to 10% since this time last year.%20http://heidiphong.com/are-you-unsure-if-you-want-to-buy-a-new-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Home prices have increased 5% to 10% since this time last year.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. How are the mortgage rates right now?&lt;/strong&gt;These rates are projected to continue to rise, and if you wait until next year to lock in that rate, you might find you have less buying power than if you started looking now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re indecisive and you’re still sitting on the fence about whether to buy or wait, hopefully considering these questions will help you made a better decision for you and your family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any additional questions or you’re looking to buy or sell a home, please give us a call. We’d be happy to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 06:10:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://heidiphong.com/are-you-unsure-if-you-want-to-buy-a-new-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://heidiphong.com/are-you-unsure-if-you-want-to-buy-a-new-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Is Sacramento Headed for Another Bubble?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZJnFK5jEFSs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With home prices continuing to rise and new developments popping up, are we approaching another bubble in the Sacramento market like we saw in 2007?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back 10 years ago, mortgage lending standards were very lenient. With so many unqualified buyers coming into the market, the market tanked and many of them lost their homes. Fast forward 10 years and we see that &lt;strong&gt;lenders have learned from that mistake.&lt;/strong&gt; To get a home loan now, you have to verify your job and income, and your credit score and debt have to meet certain standards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what about all those new homes and developments? What happens when the supply explodes and nobody is able to buy them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=New lending standards keep unqualified homebuyers from entering the market like 2007.%20http://heidiphong.com/is-sacramento-headed-for-another-bubble.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“New lending standards keep unqualified homebuyers from entering the market like 2007.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you spoke with a lender or builder today, you’d see that &lt;strong&gt;all of these new homes have actually already been bought&lt;/strong&gt; and simply need to be completed. In fact, if you went to an office of a new developer to buy a home, you’d most likely have to go on a waiting list. You might have to wait a number of months for a new home, or to even get a chance to buy a lot and then start the building process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Builders have even been held back  by a limited number of permits given for things like building roads for homes to go by. Everything is being watched and managed carefully so we don’t end up in another bubble like 2007.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope that gives you a better perspective about how the market today differs from what it looked like during the bubble 10 years ago. If you want to learn more or you’re interested in buying or building a home, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email soon. I’d love to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2017 08:22:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://heidiphong.com/is-sacramento-headed-for-another-bubble.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://heidiphong.com/is-sacramento-headed-for-another-bubble.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Ways Working With a Team Beats Working With a Solo Agent</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/lJYvb7JAsek?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to buying and selling properties, there are three main benefits of working with an agent who’s a part of a team instead of a solo agent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The No. 1 benefit is if you’re the type of client who has a busy schedule and you’re prone to making last-minute changes, &lt;strong&gt;they can accommodate you.&lt;/strong&gt; For example, let’s say you schedule a showing with your Realtor at 2 p.m. but work kept you late and you can’t get to the house until 3 p.m. If your Realtor works with a team and they have another appointment at 3 p.m., they can simply send one of their teammates to meet you. A solo agent usually isn’t that flexible, and you would probably have to reschedule for another day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Your needs are always the top priority when you work with a team.%20http://heidiphong.com/3-ways-working-with-a-team-beats-working-with-a-solo-agent.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Your needs are always the top priority when you work with a team.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second benefit is &lt;strong&gt;that agent’s team will hold them accountable.&lt;/strong&gt; The last thing you want to do as a client is forget to schedule an inspection and then schedule one on the day it’s due. A team will keep your agent accountable to prevent that situation from happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third benefit is &lt;strong&gt;the team will be able to help that agent answer all of your questions&lt;/strong&gt; and concerns. A team is full of experts in various fields within our industry, whereas a solo agent is a one-stop shop who might not have all the answers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about working with a team or you’re looking to buy or sell a home, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d be happy to assist you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 11:18:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://heidiphong.com/3-ways-working-with-a-team-beats-working-with-a-solo-agent.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://heidiphong.com/3-ways-working-with-a-team-beats-working-with-a-solo-agent.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
