<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Brainerd Lakes Real Estate Video Blog with Chad Schwendeman</title>
    <description>Our mission at Exit Lakes Realty Premier is to be your best resource for Brainerd Lakes real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Exit Lakes Realty Premier, your professional Brainerd Lakes Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 13:47:29 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 13:47:29 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Interest Rates Will Be Rising Soon</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qUSWFWLqM90?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interest rates are creeping up. Here’s how people are taking advantage of the market now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Selling a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.findbrainerdareahomes.com/sell/default&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a free home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Buying a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.findbrainerdareahomes.com/search/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to search the MLS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re in for a very competitive stretch in the real estate market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First off, mortgage rates have started increasing. For the first time since last summer, &lt;strong&gt;the 30-year average mortgage rate is now over 4%.&lt;/strong&gt; This follows a long period when mortgage rates were near record lows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This latest increase might be &lt;strong&gt;more than just a temporary bump.&lt;/strong&gt; Some experts predict that we’ve seen the last of sub-4% mortgage rates, thanks to strengthening inflation and broad-based economic growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, &lt;strong&gt;mortgage applications are also increasing.&lt;/strong&gt; Applications were up in January by 4.1% compared to last year. This has been led by people looking to refinance their homes, while mortgage applications by homebuyers remained at steadier levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=HOMEBUYERS ARE LOOKING TO LOCK IN THE CURRENT, LOW RATES.%20localhost:4000/4-ways-tax-reform-will-impact-our-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“HOMEBUYERS ARE LOOKING TO LOCK IN THE CURRENT, LOW RATES.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third, housing supply continues to be increasingly tight, with &lt;strong&gt;10% fewer homes on the market than a year ago.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do all of these numbers mean for you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The growth in mortgage rates shouldn’t affect the number of eager homebuyers very much because there is so much more demand than supply right now. However, &lt;strong&gt;this rise in mortgage rates might actually reduce the number of homes for sale&lt;/strong&gt; even further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Homebuyers should be looking to lock in the current, still fairly low mortgage rates. When mortgage rates increase further, &lt;strong&gt;homeowners will have less of an incentive to sell their current home and buy a new home,&lt;/strong&gt; which will require a mortgage at a new, higher rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about where the current rates are at or you have any real estate needs we can assist with, please don’t hesitate to reach out and give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 13:08:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/4-ways-tax-reform-will-impact-our-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/4-ways-tax-reform-will-impact-our-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Tax Reform</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Happy Holidays From the Chad Schwendeman Real Estate Group at Exit Lakes Realty Premier</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/alRi1zN9y-Y?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy holidays to you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Selling a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.findbrainerdareahomes.com/sell/default&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a free home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Buying a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.findbrainerdareahomes.com/search/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to search the MLS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The holiday season has officially arrived. We hope you enjoy this wonderful time of year and make some fantastic memories with your family and friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We just wanted to take a moment to thank you for your continued support. We love helping people make their real estate dreams come true, so thank you for working with us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may be a busy time of year, but we are always here to help you and answer any questions you may have. Just give us a call or reply to this email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in case we don’t hear from you, have a happy new year!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 14:40:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/happy-holidays-from-exit-lakes-realty.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/happy-holidays-from-exit-lakes-realty.html</guid>
        
        <category>Happy Holidays!</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Questions to Ask Before Hiring a Realtor</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/zPto0nU1ZNs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What questions should you be asking a Realtor before you hire them? Start with these three.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Selling a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.findbrainerdareahomes.com/sell/default&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a free home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Buying a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.findbrainerdareahomes.com/search/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to search the MLS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When hiring a Realtor to list your home, you shouldn’t make an impulse decision. In fact, you should interview a few different Realtors for the job and ask them specific questions about their business. Here are three examples of smart questions to ask any Realtor before you hire them:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. What’s your track record?&lt;/strong&gt; Ask them how long they’ve been in the business, how many homes they’ve sold, how big their team is, and more. You don’t want to hire somebody that doesn’t have any experience. You want a Realtor with the experience and knowledge necessary to get your home sold for top dollar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. What are you going to do to market my home?&lt;/strong&gt; The days of putting a sign in the yard and waiting for a buyer are long over. Your Realtor needs an aggressive marketing plan and an aggressive marketing budget in order to have a successful sale. It takes a strategy to sell a home for the price you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. What are your reviews like?&lt;/strong&gt; You don’t even have to necessarily ask this question. You can find the answer for yourself online. If the Realtor doesn’t have very many online reviews or has poor reviews, you should avoid them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=YOU CAN INVESTIGATE CUSTOMER FEEDBACK ONLINE.%20localhost:4000/3-questions-to-ask-before-hiring-realtor.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“YOU CAN INVESTIGATE CUSTOMER FEEDBACK ONLINE.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choosing a Realtor is about more than just picking a friend or a face on a sign. &lt;strong&gt;It’s about knowing who has the track record and the motivation to get your home sold for the most money possible.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for us or you’d like to interview us for the job of selling your home, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 11:05:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/3-questions-to-ask-before-hiring-realtor.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/3-questions-to-ask-before-hiring-realtor.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Could Refinancing Hurt Your Credit?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/g3JGinwZQRk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can refinancing your mortgage actually hurt your credit? The short answer is yes, but whether or not it will is much more complicated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Selling a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.findbrainerdareahomes.com/sell/default&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a free home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Buying a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.findbrainerdareahomes.com/search/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to search the MLS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can refinancing your mortgage actually hurt your credit?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, mortgage rates are at historic lows. For many people, this is a reason for them to refinance their current mortgage, since refinancing allows you to pay off your current mortgage with a new one at a lower rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, refinancing means you can lower your monthly payment and put more money in your pocket. &lt;strong&gt;But an important factor that many people don’t understand is that refinancing can negatively affect your credit score.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you refinance your mortgage, the new creditor will do a hard inquiry about your credit history, and this hard inquiry can lower your credit score. This is because looking into new credit lines, like a new mortgage, equates to a greater risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How much will this actually lower your credit score? It depends on several factors. In some cases, a hard inquiry may not lower your score at all. In other cases, your score may be lowered by five or more points. &lt;strong&gt;It depends on the number of inquiries you’ve had over a certain time frame.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your score may also be more dramatically impacted if you have a short credit history. If you shop around for the best rate for 45 days or more, you might accrue multiple hard inquiries. This could translate into a negative impact on your credit score.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=REFINANCING MEANS YOU CAN LOWER YOUR MONTHLY PAYMENT AND PUT MORE MONEY IN YOUR POCKET.%20localhost:4000/could-refinancing-hurt-your-credit.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“REFINANCING MEANS YOU CAN LOWER YOUR MONTHLY PAYMENT AND PUT MORE MONEY IN YOUR POCKET.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does all of this mean for you as a homeowner? Is this a reason for you not to refinance? This isn’t an easy question to answer. &lt;strong&gt;It’s best to meet with a mortgage professional who will help you determine what’s best for your specific circumstances.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My team and I would be happy to refer you to one of the many great professionals we’re connected with in this area. If you are thinking of refinancing, the first step is to call us and get a market analysis. The more equity you have in your home, the lower your interest rates could be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 12:20:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/could-refinancing-hurt-your-credit.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/could-refinancing-hurt-your-credit.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Owner Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>7 Reasons to Buy a Home During Fall</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/h2OKCM2k9Xc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why should you consider buying a home this fall? Here are seven reasons to start off with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Selling a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.findbrainerdareahomes.com/sell/default&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a free home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Buying a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.findbrainerdareahomes.com/search/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to search the MLS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why should you consider selling your home during the fall instead of waiting for spring or summer? &lt;strong&gt;Here are seven good reasons:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Competition drops off in the fall.&lt;/strong&gt; Many people consider the fall to be the “offseason” for buying homes, but there is still quite a bit of inventory left on the market. Some of it’s new, some of its inventory that’s being re-positioned and re-priced to sell before the holidays. Either way, it gives you much more negotiating power than you’ll see during the spring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Sellers are worn out.&lt;/strong&gt; Many times when sellers overprice their homes, they sit on the market for months without offers. If their homes are still on the market during this time of year, they will realize that they need to be aggressive with their pricing in order to get the home sold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Sellers are serious about selling.&lt;/strong&gt; In many cases, sellers need to close by the end of the year. Whether it’s for tax reasons, a job transfer, or something else, many sellers are motivated to make a quick deal. That’s always good news for buyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. You can take advantage of tax breaks for the whole year.&lt;/strong&gt; Even if you close on your home in December, you’ll still be able to take advantage of the mortgage interest and property tax deductions for the income you’ve earned in 2017. Even though you would only have owned the home for one month of the year, you would still be able to take deductions for the whole year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Fall is a safer time to purchase.&lt;/strong&gt; Although crime and burglary rates in this area aren’t high by any means, they do drop off significantly in the fall. Most break-ins occur during the summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. You will stand out.&lt;/strong&gt; During the fall, there tends to be a slowdown within the industry. As a buyer, that means you’ll receive more attention from the sellers who do have their home listed. This will help the transaction move along much more quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. You can take advantage of year-end deals for your new home.&lt;/strong&gt; The end of the year is the time to buy if you’re looking to furnish your home with new appliances and furniture. You’ll need to get them anyway, so you might as well buy during a time of year where you can get a great deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for us or you’re thinking about buying or selling a home in the Brainerd Lakes area, give me a call or send me an email. I would love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 12:35:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/7-reasons-to-buy-home-during-fall.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/7-reasons-to-buy-home-during-fall.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>These 3 Seller Mistakes Are More Common Than You Think</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/fc_QSQP6XM0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The days of putting a sign in your yard and expecting your home to sell itself are gone. Today, I’ve got three selling sins to avoid if you want to achieve listing success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Selling a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.findbrainerdareahomes.com/sell/default&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a free home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Buying a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.findbrainerdareahomes.com/search/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to search the MLS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of ways to succeed when selling your home, but there are just as many ways to fail. When it comes to selling your home this season, it’s important that you avoid these three home selling sins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Asking too much.&lt;/strong&gt; Of course you don’t want to sell your home for less than it’s worth, but overpricing your home can cause it to sit on the market for months and either sell for a low price or not sell at all. Buyers can see how long your home has been on the market and how many times the price has been reduced. This causes a lot of doubt. Even if a buyer likes a home, they’ll wonder what’s wrong with it if it’s taking a long time to move off the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Not advertising enough.&lt;/strong&gt; Your home isn’t going to sell itself. These days, it takes an aggressive marketing plan and budget to get your home off the market. The days of simply putting a sign in the yard and waiting for buyers are long gone. Today, you need to advertise to get your home sold for top dollar. You can advertise online, on TV, on the radio, in print, or in a number of other ways. My team and I spend over $60,000 a month advertising our listings. As we like to say, it isn’t the market that gets homes sold, it’s the marketing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Not making your home presentable for showings.&lt;/strong&gt; Buyers expect a meticulous home. They expect nothing less than something that looks like a model home. Be sure to clean, declutter, and stage your property accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=YOUR HOME ISN’T GOING TO SELL ITSELF.%20localhost:4000/these-3-seller-mistakes-are-more-common.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“YOUR HOME ISN’T GOING TO SELL ITSELF.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions, would like more information, or want to talk about how my team and I could market your home, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 15:47:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/these-3-seller-mistakes-are-more-common.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/these-3-seller-mistakes-are-more-common.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Has the Home-Flipping Craze Done to Our Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/U3T5d-8oY-8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is home flipping and how has it had an effect on our market? Here’s what you should know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Selling a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.findbrainerdareahomes.com/sell/default&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a free home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Buying a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.findbrainerdareahomes.com/search/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to search the MLS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you heard about the home-flipping craze? Home-flipping is the process of buying a home, making improvements to it, and then turning it around to sell for a profit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A decade ago, home-flipping was a huge trend. The real estate market was on fire at the time. Unfortunately, though, it was the extreme lengths to which the home-flipping craze was taken that caused the real estate crash we saw between 2008 and 2009.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, with the recent popularity of television shows like “Flip or Flop” and “Flipping the Block,” the home-flipping craze has come back in full swing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re considering going into home flipping, there are a few things to consider before doing so. First of all, know that home flipping is now more profitable than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Waco, Texas home that was recently featured on HGTV’s “Fixer Upper,” for instance, was originally bought for $28,000. After several renovations, however, &lt;strong&gt;that same home is being listed at over $950,000—that’s over 30 times its original purchase price.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this big of a profit isn’t the norm, the flipping game is becoming more and more profitable all the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=THE HOME FLIPPING-CRAZE HAS COME BACK IN FULL SWING.%20localhost:4000/what-has-home-flipping-craze-done-to.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“THE HOME FLIPPING-CRAZE HAS COME BACK IN FULL SWING.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The median household in 2016 sold for $189,000—over $62,000 above the average sales price. At a 49.2% return, this is the most profitable return we’ve seen since 2000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But these high returns aren’t the only thing driving the current home-flipping craze. Years ago, most home-flipping was a result of speculation. Investors would buy and fix homes, then wait for the market to go up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the strength of our market combined with a lack of inventory, this is no longer the case. Today, &lt;strong&gt;flippers need to bring added value to their flips.&lt;/strong&gt; Home-flipping today is much more profitable than it was in past years. This is largely thanks to low inventory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though it isn’t just sellers who benefit from this flipping craze. Because flipped homes are done well and are available in all price points, &lt;strong&gt;home-flipping has brought a lot of opportunity into the market for buyers, as well.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 14:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/what-has-home-flipping-craze-done-to.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/what-has-home-flipping-craze-done-to.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Do Fannie Maes 3 New Rule Changes Affect You?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/eJuiN56t22Q?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have student loans or you’re a cosigner for someone who does, Fannie Mae has implemented three new rules changes that will affect you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Selling a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.findbrainerdareahomes.com/sell/default&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a free home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Buying a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.findbrainerdareahomes.com/search/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to search the MLS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fannie Mae—the nation’s largest underwriter for mortgages—has introduced three new rules that affect those who have or have cosigned for student loans. These rule changes can make it easier for you to get a mortgage and pay off your student loans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The first change applies to how they calculate your debt-to-income ratio.&lt;/strong&gt; If you’re on an income-based repayment plan, you might know that the No. 1 reason why they don’t get approved is a high debt-to-income ratio. Previously, Fannie Mae calculated this debt by taking 1% of the outstanding balance. If you have a huge student loan, that’s pretty substantial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, they’ll use your monthly payment instead of the principle to calculate your debt. This will hopefully decrease your debt-to-income ratio and enable you to meet the criteria to secure a mortgage to purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The second change relates to third-party payments.&lt;/strong&gt; Some folks are lucky enough to have their parents or employers pay off their student loans. The trouble in the past, though, has been that Fannie Mae still counted that as debt against your debt-to-income ratio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, if you can prove your parents or your employer has paid your student debt for the last 12 months, it will no longer be calculated in your debt-to-income ratio. This will make it easier for you to get approved for a mortgage, and with today’s low interest rates, the timing could not be better to buy. The market is very robust and we’re seeing inventory fly off the shelves. In many cases, it’s much cheaper to buy than it is to rent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=THESE NEW RULES CAN BE A BIG MONEY SAVER FOR THE RIGHT PERSON.%20localhost:4000/how-do-fannie-maes-3-new-rule-changes.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“THESE NEW RULES CAN BE A BIG MONEY SAVER FOR THE RIGHT PERSON.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The third change is they’re eliminating the 0.25% fee they normally charge if you choose to refinance your current home and use that cash to pay off your student loan.&lt;/strong&gt; This applies whether the loan is yours or you’re a cosigner. There are often benefits to education loans that you won’t get with a mortgage, such as deferment or income-driven repayment plans. However, the mortgage rate is significantly lower than the student loan rate, so it makes sense to refinance this way if you want to save up to three percentage points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These new rules can be a big money saver for the right person. If you need help understanding these guidelines to see whether they’re right for you or you have any questions about putting them in place, don’t hesitate to call me or shoot me an email. I’d be happy to assist you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 12:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-do-fannie-maes-3-new-rule-changes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/how-do-fannie-maes-3-new-rule-changes.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Tips for First-Time Homebuyers</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qXwhMamLAXU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buying a home for the first time can be intimidating. I’ve listed a few tips to make the process less overwhelming below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Selling a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.findbrainerdareahomes.com/sell/default&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a free home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Buying a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.findbrainerdareahomes.com/search/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to search the MLS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’re going to talk about buying your first home. This can be a very exciting process, but it’s also a huge commitment and investment. It can have huge repercussions in your life for years to come. That’s why I want to share with you three tips that can protect you as a first-time homebuyer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Know what you can afford.&lt;/strong&gt; A mortgage is only part of what you’re going to have to pay each month. This does not include taxes, utilities, repairs, and the upkeep that is required when owning your home. Once you have a clear idea how much everything will cost, you can compare your income to what those expenses will be each month and make sure you feel comfortable moving forward with your purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Choose your lender wisely.&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t just go with a lender that will offer you the cheapest interest rate. You want a lender that is confident and trustworthy and will offer you advice on how to improve your credit. The right lender will also lead you in the direction of taking advantage of the special loan programs that are out there, including ones where you can be pre-approved with 0% down. Make sure you go through the whole underwriting process before putting a purchase agreement on the home you want to buy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Don’t overlook the details.&lt;/strong&gt; There are many details you need to pay attention to during this process. An example is getting an inspection for the home you want to buy. This is different from an appraisal as a home inspector spends more time in the home tearing the place apart, looking for anything that might be wrong with it. Inspections generally cost $400, but it’s worth the money in the long run. Another example is understanding the fine print of the contracts. If anything is unclear to you, talk to your real estate agent. There are no dumb questions when it comes to the purchase agreement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The process of buying a home for the first time can be very intimidating, which is why it’s important that you hire a real estate agent that can walk you through every step of the process. If you have any questions about this topic or you’re looking to buy or sell a home, please give us a call. We’d be happy to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 16:03:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/3-tips-for-first-time-homebuyers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/3-tips-for-first-time-homebuyers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>10 Reasons Why Selling on Your Own Is a Mistake </title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/OREXHHfCwRw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should you sell your home on your own? We’ll go over 10 reasons why For Sale By Owner properties can actually cost you more time, money, and headaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Selling a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.findbrainerdareahomes.com/sell/default&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a free home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Buying a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.findbrainerdareahomes.com/search/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to search the MLS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many homeowners think they can sell their own home. However, there are 10 reasons why you should avoid listing your home as “For Sale By Owner.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. There are common scams that target FSBO properties.&lt;/strong&gt; The scammer sends you fraudulent papers from an attorney requesting your private information and, before you know it, your identity has been stolen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. You will have all of the liability.&lt;/strong&gt; We all make mistakes, but if you make a mistake selling your home, it’s more likely that the buyer will sue you personally. When you work with a real estate agent, we have insurance that covers up to $1 million for each incident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. The paperwork is daunting.&lt;/strong&gt; The current purchase agreement is more than 50 pages. Filling out the wrong information or checking the wrong box could cost you thousands of dollars or land you in court.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. You could end up in a bad deal.&lt;/strong&gt; If the buyer makes a low offer, you’re stuck with it once you sign on the dotted line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. You will sell your home for a lot less money.&lt;/strong&gt; FSBO properties sell for about 16% less than properties represented by real estate agents. The median sales price for a For Sale By Owner home is $210,000, while homes represented by an agent sell for an average of $249,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Your home will not attract as many buyers.&lt;/strong&gt; A lot of buyers do not want to deal with FSBO properties because they don’t want to deal with the lack of representation, liability, or headaches that arise without a professional Realtor involved. As a result, you will be selling your home to a smaller buyer pool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Inspections can be problematic.&lt;/strong&gt; Sellers who don’t know the rules can get stuck with unnecessary costs for repairs. For example, when Sue sold her 10-year-old home, the inspector said she needed to change a variety of things because the code had changed. The inspector did not understand that since the home was built before the code changed, Sue did not have to make those repairs. So, because Sue and the inspector did not understand the code and the current law, Sue wound up paying thousands of dollars for unnecessary repairs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. Your marketing is limited.&lt;/strong&gt; The National Association of Realtors did a study to figure out where FSBO home sellers found their buyers. 42% of those sales came from the yard sign, 32% came from family and friends, and 15% came from social media. No disrespect to any For Sale By Owner sellers out there, but if all you have is a yard sign and your uncle Bob to promote your house, you can see how that impacts your bottom line. We spend over $45,000 a month to advertise our listings, so we will get your home in front of every potential buyer in your price point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. The little costs add up.&lt;/strong&gt; The main reason most people want to sell their own homes is to avoid paying the Realtor commission. However, there are so many hidden fees involved in selling a home that not hiring a Realtor may cost you more money. Whether it’s photography, fliers, or listing your home on the MLS, you will get nickel and dimed through the whole process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10. Selling your own home will cost you a lot of time.&lt;/strong&gt; It takes time to take the pictures, study the contracts, find an attorney, find a title company, and research whether or not a buyer can obtain a mortgage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, we recommend that you work with a real estate agent to help sell your home. We can help you sell your biggest investment; after all, we are the No. 1 real estate team in Minnesota.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for us, just give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 16:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/10-reasons-to-avoid-listing-your-own.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/10-reasons-to-avoid-listing-your-own.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
