<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>Our mission at Hatch Homes Group is to be your best resource for Portland real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Hatch Homes Group, your professional Portland Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://hatchhomesgroup.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://hatchhomesgroup.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 09:07:51 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 09:07:51 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>A One-of-a-Kind Northwest Home We’d Like to Show You</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/5Ow9ih6S-5Q?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to 3245 Northwest Thurman Street.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you follow along in the guided video tour above, you can see a first-hand look at all the amenities and features that make this newly listed property special.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a remodeled modern home with old-world historic details. By entering through the romantic iron gates, you’ll find yourself inside a private courtyard with 100-year-old brick walls. This home is truly one of a kind, with a floor plan centered around an outdoor courtyard which brings the outdoors in while maintaining privacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It has three bedrooms, three full bathrooms, and occupies just under 4,000 square feet. &lt;/strong&gt;Rich with history, in the 1970s the structure was in disrepair and said to once be a Willamette Heights horse stable, then a trolly car garage, and then an auto barn. It was then repurposed during that time by homeowners truly dedicated to preserving the history while modernizing and honoring the historic neighborhood of Willamette Heights. You can still see the huge old-growth beams supporting the 12-foot ceilings of the kitchen, and you will notice many architectural details salvaged from other northwest mansions of the past, like the solid oak doors, the beautiful fireplace, and the antique door hardware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=This home is truly one of a kind.%20http://hatchhomesgroup.com/a-one-of-a-kind-northwest-home-wed-like-to-show-you.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“This home is truly one of a kind.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, it’s had over $50,000 worth of updates just in the last six months, in addition to the beautiful remodeled kitchen and bathrooms. The master suite and a second bedroom can be found on the main level, which showcases those beautiful floor-to-ceiling brick walls. The daylight lower level below that offers wine room storage, a dumbwaiter, wood storage, a huge family room with a separate entrance, and a second master suite or separate apartment that could function as an additional dwelling unit or a possible nanny suite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you fall in love with this amazing home, you can step outside and find yourself surrounded by one of Portland’s best neighborhoods. It sits in close proximity to fabulous cafes, restaurants, walking trails, and shops—not to mention some of the top-rated schools in Portland. This home does not disappoint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information about this home, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d be happy to speak with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 05:05:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://hatchhomesgroup.com/a-one-of-a-kind-northwest-home-wed-like-to-show-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hatchhomesgroup.com/a-one-of-a-kind-northwest-home-wed-like-to-show-you.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Did the Hurricanes Impact the Caribbean Real Estate Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/NGCUSNPwRL8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week, we’re on the lovely island of Santa Lucia in the Caribbean. We’ve been looking at properties ranging from $300,000 to $3 million with other international Realtors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were interested in the effect that the recent hurricanes had on the real estate market. Puerto Rico has had a lot of business failures and employment problems, which resulted in over 4,000 foreclosures and a 50% decrease in prices in some areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The recent hurricanes resulted in over 4,000 foreclosures and a 50% decrease in prices in some areas.%20http://hatchhomesgroup.com/how-did-the-hurricanes-impact-the-caribbean-real-estate-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The recent hurricanes resulted in over 4,000 foreclosures and a 50% decrease in prices in some areas.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of this, there are some great buying opportunities in the short term. Places like St. Croix are still facing a lot of turmoil, so it might be better to wait in those cases. Santa Lucia, however, is completely unaffected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you know anyone who’s interested in learning more about investing and purchasing in the Caribbean, I have contacts and information for you that will help. Feel free to reach out to me. I’d love to talk with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 08:54:36 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://hatchhomesgroup.com/how-did-the-hurricanes-impact-the-caribbean-real-estate-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hatchhomesgroup.com/how-did-the-hurricanes-impact-the-caribbean-real-estate-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Should You Put Your Home on the Market This Winter?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_0b6Rl-Fw6U?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Should you put your home on the market this winter or wait until spring? We have a few statistics to help you make this decision today.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should you list your home for sale in the winter, or should you wait until spring?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;December is actually the biggest month for us out of the whole year. We sell more houses in December than any other time of year. There are a few other reasons why you may not want to wait until spring to put your home on the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For one, homes tend to show better this time of year. Tasteful holiday decor makes your home appear warm and cozy to potential buyers. Also, winter makes for an even playing field when it comes to curb appeal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Redfin, 9% of winter listings are more likely to sell. On average, winter listings sell a week faster and for 1.2% more money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=People don’t window shop for homes during a snowstorm.%20http://hatchhomesgroup.com/should-you-put-your-home-on-the-market-this-winter.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“People don’t window shop for homes during a snowstorm.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the peak season of the market, there are 45% more listings but only 23.5% more sales. More listings in January and February means more competition for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have about 2,000 sales each month at any given time of year. There might be an extra push of sales in the peak of the market, but you will have more competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By selling in the winter, you will have less competition and more serious buyers. People don’t window shop for homes during a snowstorm. Even last year, when it was snowing for weeks and we had an ice storm, the real estate market kept going. It was amazing to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about selling your home this winter, or if you are interested in buying a home before competition heats up this spring, just give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://hatchhomesgroup.com/should-you-put-your-home-on-the-market-this-winter.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hatchhomesgroup.com/should-you-put-your-home-on-the-market-this-winter.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Happy Thanksgiving From Hatch Homes Group</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/DSHTWkR8-y8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Hatch Homes Group is coming to you today from our annual retreat. We are busy planning for next year and brainstorming ways to improve our service. &lt;strong&gt;We’ve got some exciting things coming next year, including enhanced marketing and better client service.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you or anyone you know is looking for professional representation in a real estate transaction, let us know. We’re always happy to help out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We’ll see you on November 21!%20http://hatchhomesgroup.com/happy-thanksgiving-from-hatch-homes-group.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We’ll see you on November 21!”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One more thing:&lt;/strong&gt; You should have already received your e-vite, but our annual pie party is coming up on Tuesday, November 21. You can pick up your pie either at our office or at Angela’s house: 1934 SE Umatilla Street&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions for us, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 08:27:10 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://hatchhomesgroup.com/happy-thanksgiving-from-hatch-homes-group.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hatchhomesgroup.com/happy-thanksgiving-from-hatch-homes-group.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Does Portland’s New Home Energy Score Requirement Affect You?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ICXLhxfMY4U?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of January 1st, 2018, the City of Portland’s Home Energy Score Program will officially take effect. Portland has a goal to reduce their carbon footprint, and this new energy score is a big step toward that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Under this program, home sellers will be required to hire an assessor to come to their home, assess its energy efficiency, and have them award a score based on the home’s efficiency.&lt;/strong&gt; Studies show that 79% of buyers want to know this information, so disclosure is key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The report will give your home a rating of one to 10. We like to think of this rating as a “miles per gallon” for your house—a lot of nice cars with low miles per gallon are selling for great prices. This program is beneficial to homeowners in that these reports can notify them of money-saving home improvements and give them the opportunity to recoup the investments they make in any energy efficiency upgrades at the time of sale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Think of this rating as a ‘miles per gallon’ for your home.%20http://hatchhomesgroup.com/how-does-portlands-new-home-energy-score-requirement-affect-you.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Think of this rating as a ‘miles per gallon’ for your home.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This program offers a few benefits to buyers, as well, including:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Better insight into the full costs of owning or renting a home.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The ability to compare energy costs and performance between homes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The knowledge of potential home improvements in advance of purchase.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Access to additional mortgage products.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a seller and you want to get your home’s official energy score, there are three steps you must take:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hire a professional assessor and get your rating.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provide the official report to your agent/buyer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Confirm all listings of your house show that number.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a seller and you want to bypass this program, you still have time to sell, so don’t wait to get in touch with us so we can help you with that. If you have any other questions, just give us a call or send us an email. We’d be glad to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 06:18:32 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://hatchhomesgroup.com/how-does-portlands-new-home-energy-score-requirement-affect-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hatchhomesgroup.com/how-does-portlands-new-home-energy-score-requirement-affect-you.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Join Our Class and Become a Homebuyer Expert</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/CS-zrZp0ezw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;On October 21st, Michele Descombes will be teaching a class instructing homebuyers about the home buying process and discussing what they need to know about our market.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking to buy a Portland home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hatchhomes.com/results-gallery/?sort=popularity&amp;amp;status=A&quot;&gt;Search all homes for sale here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking to sell your Portland home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hatchhomes.com/Sell/&quot;&gt;Use our free home evaluation tool here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On October 21st at the Umpqua Bank in the Pearl, Michele DesCombes will be teaching another home buying class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This class is intended for anyone who is interested in buying a home, whether you’ve owned one before, it’s been awhile since your last purchase, or this is your first home purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this session, Michele will be covering a lot of great information about our market. As you might’ve noticed, it’s has shifted a little bit in favor of buyers, even though inventory is still a little low. She’ll also discuss what your options are in the home buying process as well as which loan programs are available for first-time homebuyers or low-income buyers who can qualify for a grant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=All types of homebuyers are welcome to join us.%20http://hatchhomesgroup.com/join-our-class-and-become-a-homebuyer-expert.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“All types of homebuyers are welcome to join us.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re renting right now, you’re probably paying at least 30% of your income on your rent. If you were to purchase a home using a grant program or any of the fantastic loan programs available out there, you could pay as little as 15% of your income.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Michele will be teaching with Mac Dengsot of Umpqua bank, a home loan specialist. They both can answer your questions about anything regarding the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To find out how, all you have to do is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/first-time-home-buyer-tickets-38257036827&quot;&gt;sign up and register here&lt;/a&gt;. We hope to see you there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to speak with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 06:59:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://hatchhomesgroup.com/join-our-class-and-become-a-homebuyer-expert.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hatchhomesgroup.com/join-our-class-and-become-a-homebuyer-expert.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Few Important Numbers From the Portland Real Estate Market </title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0XAJeuX11OY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What is happening in the Portland real estate market? We have six important statistics to share with you today.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking to buy a Portland home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hatchhomes.com/results-gallery/?sort=popularity&amp;amp;status=A&quot;&gt;Search all homes for sale here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Looking to sell your Portland home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hatchhomes.com/Sell/&quot;&gt;Use our free home evaluation tool here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s time for your Portland real estate market update. There are a few important market statistics that we want to share with you today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First of all, there are 98 bumpable listings on the market right now.&lt;/strong&gt; That means that these listings are contingent on something happening on the buyer’s or seller’s side of the transaction in order for the sale to go through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is really important. In the past, sellers have been cautious about contingent home offers. Most of the time, sellers would wait to find their next home before putting their current home on the market. It’s very promising that there are 98 bumpable listings. With all of those contingent offers, we’ll likely see 98 new homes hit the market soon, which is good news for buyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, there are 197 expired homes. That means these homes failed to sell in the last few months. As your agents, we look at why those listings failed to sell so that you don’t end up in the same situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Another important thing to know is that 612 homes are back on the market.&lt;/strong&gt; Buyers these days are more particular on what they want from a home. They expect the home to be in good condition for a certain price. On the other side, sellers are not willing to negotiate repairs, so these deals are falling apart and those homes are coming back on the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is great news for buyers. Those 612 homes increase inventory. Plus, you may even get a second chance at a home that you liked earlier but didn’t get a chance to make an offer on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=There is a disparity between buyer’s expectations and how sellers view the current market.%20http://hatchhomesgroup.com/a-few-important-numbers-from-portland.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“There is a disparity between buyer’s expectations and how sellers view the current market.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sellers should take note that in the last week alone, we had 783 price changes. Although Portland is still in a strong seller’s market, it’s not as strong as some people may think. You can’t overprice your home in this market, and those 783 price changes prove that. We’re here to guide you. We can help you avoid that price adjustment by pricing your home correctly from the start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the number of closed sales in July dropped by 12%, while the number of pending sales dropped 7.9%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, these numbers indicate that our market is shifting into a more balanced, healthy market. &lt;strong&gt;We are not in the housing bubble that everyone feared.&lt;/strong&gt; Prices are still very healthy, and inventory is still fairly low, which makes it a good time to sell your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, these numbers do show a disparity between buyer expectations and what sellers believe they can get out of the current market. Don’t forget those 612 homes that went back on the market after their deal fell apart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we mentioned earlier, there is slightly more inventory for buyers to choose from these days. Make sure you take advantage of the updated inventory and low mortgage rates now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about buying or selling in our current market, just give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 16:22:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://hatchhomesgroup.com/a-few-important-numbers-from-portland.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hatchhomesgroup.com/a-few-important-numbers-from-portland.html</guid>
        
        <category>Portland Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How I Use Real Estate Conventions to Better Myself for My Clients</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/FensfJR-eoU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How do real estate conventions help my team and I perform better for our clients? Today I’m bringing you those answers from one I recently attended in Las Vegas.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking to buy a Portland home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hatchhomes.com/results-gallery/?sort=popularity&amp;amp;status=A&quot;&gt;Search all homes for sale here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Looking to sell your Portland home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hatchhomes.com/Sell/&quot;&gt;Use our free home evaluation tool here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m in Las Vegas at the Tom Ferry Success Summit—a real estate convention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Real estate conventions are something we engage in frequently because doing so helps us maintain our constant commitment to being on the cutting edge of real estate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technology is a large portion of this. &lt;strong&gt;In fact, Zillow, Google, and others are here at this same convention, where I have been for the past week.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=My team and I have a constant commitment to being on the cutting edge of real estate.%20http://hatchhomesgroup.com/how-i-use-real-estate-conventions-to.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“My team and I have a constant commitment to being on the cutting edge of real estate.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s incredibly important for us to make our buyer and seller transactions even smoother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the ways we achieve this is by networking with other Realtors. Recently, for example, I sat down for a drink and conversation with an HGTV star who actually works in Portland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Being face to face with these fellow professionals really helps me to build a larger database.&lt;/strong&gt; This means that whether our clients are looking to move to another state or even another country, I can help refer them to the right agent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 15:02:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://hatchhomesgroup.com/how-i-use-real-estate-conventions-to.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hatchhomesgroup.com/how-i-use-real-estate-conventions-to.html</guid>
        
        <category>Portland Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We're Hosting a Warehouse Sale</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/umRwaNc1Bqk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You won’t want to miss this warehouse sale event.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking to buy a Portland home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hatchhomes.com/results-gallery/?sort=popularity&amp;amp;status=A&quot;&gt;Search all homes for sale here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Looking to sell your Portland home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hatchhomes.com/Sell/&quot;&gt;Use our free home evaluation tool here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m excited to announce that I’m partnering up with my client Adrienne to host an event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this event, we’ll be featuring items from Adrienne’s online eco-fashion store, Faerie’s Dance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will also be a doTERRA essential oils representative and a doctor specializing in whole life wellness plans. Many other female entrepreneurs are expected to attend, as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will also be coffee and cakes provided for your enjoyment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, there will be a raffle drawing for various prizes every half hour throughout the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You won’t want to miss this warehouse sale event.%20http://hatchhomesgroup.com/were-hosting-warehouse-sale.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You won’t want to miss this warehouse sale event.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One prize we’ll be raffling off early in the day will be two tickets to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.streetofdreamspdx.com/&quot;&gt;Street of Dreams.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You won’t want to miss this warehouse sale event, &lt;strong&gt;which will take place Saturday, August 26th from 11 a.m. to 5 p.m..&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sale will actually be located at an urban farm I sold about five years ago at &lt;strong&gt;12400 SE Crest Drive, Happy Valley, Oregon.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you see you there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 09:59:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://hatchhomesgroup.com/were-hosting-warehouse-sale.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hatchhomesgroup.com/were-hosting-warehouse-sale.html</guid>
        
        <category>Event Announcement</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Is Happening in the Portland Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/WrX8yS6MImo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Now that we’re halfway through the year, I sat down with my daughter, Angela, to give you a look at what’s happening in our market.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking to buy a Portland home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hatchhomes.com/results-gallery/?sort=popularity&amp;amp;status=A&quot;&gt;Search all homes for sale here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Looking to sell your Portland home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hatchhomes.com/Sell/&quot;&gt;Use our free home evaluation tool here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we’re over halfway through the year, it’s time for us to take a look at what’s going on in our market. Recently, I was joined by my daughter Angela, the team leader for Hatch Homes Group, to talk about &lt;strong&gt;why it is that Realtors are feeling a little bit uneasy about certain aspects of the market.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number of days homes are spending on the market has risen a little bit, more listings have come on the market, and there have been more price reductions, as well. So why is all of this happening?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Angela explained, it’s likely caused by an uptick in inventory. She also mentioned, though, that homes that aren’t priced correctly are the only ones really having a problem getting off the market. Homes that are priced right are moving as quickly as ever and with record-low inventory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buyers are more discerning, as well. Right now, buyers are less willing to settle for a property with problems. So, poorly-prepared homes are really struggling when it comes time for them to undergo inspections. For this reason, we’re experiencing a lot more terminations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Homes that are priced right are moving as quickly as ever.%20http://hatchhomesgroup.com/what-is-happening-in-portland-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Homes that are priced right are moving as quickly as ever.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what makes it so important for sellers to meet with realtors; &lt;strong&gt;doing so can help them avoid termination.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all of this considered, many people are wondering if we’re in a bubble. Well, we actually saw this same thing happen last year. According to Angela, there is cause to be optimistic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sellers who were trying to buy and sell at the same time are now finding themselves in a good position, as there is a little more inventory for them to choose from. The same can be said for buyers, as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, &lt;strong&gt;this is a better opportunity than we’ve seen for buyers in a long time.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s also a good opportunity for sellers to get the most out of the market. And, because so many people are attracted to the lifestyle, we’re continuing to see an influx of population here in Portland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 15:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://hatchhomesgroup.com/what-is-happening-in-portland-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hatchhomesgroup.com/what-is-happening-in-portland-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Portland Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
