<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bigfork Real Estate Video Blog with Scott Hollinger</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Hollinger Team - your professional Bigfork Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://blog.flatheadrealestate.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.flatheadrealestate.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 11:29:43 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 11:29:43 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Prevent and Deal With Ice Dams</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/xlaPCxEqeBI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’d like to talk about a common winter problem homeowners in our area have to face from time to time: ice dams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An ice dam occurs when you’ve got a lot of snow on your roof and your attic is just warm enough to melt some snow, causing it to run down the roof until it gets to the colder parts and freezes. That water backs up the shingles and will eventually start coming in underneath through the roof.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The vent on our roof is snowed over, so the heat isn’t escaping out the top. One of the ways to prevent that is installing heat tape in the summer so it’s ready for the winter. Shoveling the roof off is also an option, but it is dangerous. A roofing company would be able to do it for you without damaging the roof. Also, if you google “roof rake” or “roof snow rake,” there are a lot of products out there that will help get the snow off your roof.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Roofing companies aren’t as busy this time a year, so they could safely shovel your roof off for you.%20http://blog.flatheadrealestate.com/how-to-prevent-and-deal-with-ice-dams.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Roofing companies aren’t as busy this time a year, so they could safely shovel your roof off for you.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not too late to get that taken care of, and you’ll want to make sure another snow storm doesn’t add to the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any further questions about this topic or if you have any other real estate questions, feel free to shoot me a text, give me a call, or send me an email. I’m always happy to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.flatheadrealestate.com/how-to-prevent-and-deal-with-ice-dams.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.flatheadrealestate.com/how-to-prevent-and-deal-with-ice-dams.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Valuable New Resource For You</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/coOQEEu6T5w?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like to welcome you to my new video blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my blog, you’ll find tips for both buyers and sellers in the real estate market, as well as updates on what’s happening in our local market. The real estate market affects all of us!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We want to be your local real estate resource.%20http://blog.flatheadrealestate.com/a-valuable-new-resource-for-you.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We want to be your local real estate resource.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really want this page to be a valuable resource for you. If you have any questions about our market or about real estate in general, send me an email. Odds are good that if you have a question about a topic, someone else does as well, so send your questions my way and we’ll make an educational video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a look around. I look forward to hearing from you soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.flatheadrealestate.com/a-valuable-new-resource-for-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.flatheadrealestate.com/a-valuable-new-resource-for-you.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
