<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Orlando Real Estate Careers and Training Video Blog with Tom Nickley</title>
    <description>A Video Blog about Orlando Real Estate; It's industry, and the people working in it. Whether you're just starting out, aspiring to begin, or been working in the field for a few years, tune in to get updates, tips, tricks and more!</description>
    <link>http://tngrealestatetraining.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://tngrealestatetraining.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 14:03:59 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 14:03:59 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Build and Maintain a Database</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/KD855k3Cv6s?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As real estate professionals, our databases and spheres of influence are a gold mine for future business, but only if you are working them correctly. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re first getting started, it can be difficult to know how to compile this database. However, your database and sphere of influence is especially important during the first few years of your career as a real estate professional. Earning the business of people who already know and trust you will provide a critical starting point for your career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Earning the business of people who already know and trust you will provide a critical starting point for your career.%20http://tngrealestatetraining.com/how-to-build-and-maintain-a-database.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Earning the business of people who already know and trust you will provide a critical starting point for your career.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As agents, we have to get over the fear of talking to your sphere. Today, I’d like to go over a three-step process for building and communicating with a database. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create a spreadsheet of everyone who knows, likes, and trusts you.&lt;/strong&gt; The best place to start is by extracting the names, phone numbers, and addresses of everyone in your cell phone. Plug in this information into a spreadsheet.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start calling that list.&lt;/strong&gt;Use a simple script that you can use every time to let them know how excited you are to be in the industry. Let them know you would love the opportunity to talk to them or anyone they know about their real estate needs. Most people you speak to will be happy to have this conversation. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Put forth a follow-up process.&lt;/strong&gt; People may not have referrals or an interest in doing business right away, so you need to stay consistently in front of your database to make sure you’re able to capture their business once they’re ready. On our team, we have a rule that agents must communicate with their sphere of influence every 30 days at a minimum. You can alternate between methods of communication, which is what we do on our team. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here at the Nickley Group, we’re proud to say that 40% of our business comes from referrals and our sphere of influence. It all comes down to consistently communicating with and building your database. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 14:47:07 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://tngrealestatetraining.com/how-to-build-and-maintain-a-database.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tngrealestatetraining.com/how-to-build-and-maintain-a-database.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Should You Become a Buyer’s Agent or Listing Agent?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/iLdm7MvW5mI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to take a moment today to answer a question that I’m asked frequently by new agents: “Should I become a buyer’s agent or a listing agent?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t think there’s a specific, correct answer to that question. As a new agent, I think it’s important that you learn the buying and the listing side of the business so you can become more of a well-rounded professional. &lt;strong&gt;The psychology behind a seller is much different than the psychology behind a buyer.&lt;/strong&gt; I also think that the easiest way to see scale and see early success in your business is through focusing on both sides of the transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=After you’ve learned both sides, then you can decide what you want your business to be.%20http://tngrealestatetraining.com/should-you-become-a-buyers-agent-or-listing-agent.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“After you’ve learned both sides, then you can decide what you want your business to be.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that when you get into the industry, everybody’s always talking about listings. Listings, listings, listings. You’ve got to list to last, etc. While I don’t disagree with that, I will say that focusing on buyers and sellers allows you to learn both sides of the business. &lt;strong&gt;That’s really important as a new agent.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you’ve learned both sides, you can decide for yourself what you want your business to be about. &lt;strong&gt;I actually find that the top agents on our team end up working a 50/50 split between buyer and seller transactions each year.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are thinking about making a change in your career or want to advance your real estate career further, I would love to sit down and have coffee sometime and discuss your career and where you want it to be. Just give me a call or send me an email. I would love to hear from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 05:59:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://tngrealestatetraining.com/should-you-become-a-buyers-agent-or-listing-agent.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tngrealestatetraining.com/should-you-become-a-buyers-agent-or-listing-agent.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Get More Business From Your Database</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/HrcpfrvPGag?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste present-before-paste&quot;&gt;As you’re probably aware already, there are a ton of different opinions out there regarding how often you should stay in contact with the people in your database. &lt;strong&gt;No matter what method you choose, you need to have a plan, you need to be consistent, and you need to stay in front of them. &lt;/strong&gt;The people in your database should already know, like, and trust you, so they should be a huge source of business for you. It’s low-hanging fruit, you just need to have a plan. Here are a few of the bare minimum things you should do:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Making phone calls at least once per quarter.&lt;/strong&gt; This is the easiest and cheapest way to stay top-of-mind with your database. Just have a conversation, remind them that you’re thinking about them, and let them know that you’re here to serve them or anyone else that they know. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;A good old-fashioned note.&lt;/strong&gt; All this will cost you is a few dollars in postage, but it will go a long way in staying top-of-mind with your clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Our team is very passionate about our past clients.%20http://tngrealestatetraining.com/how-to-get-more-business-from-your-database.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Our team is very passionate about our past clients.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Client appreciation events.&lt;/strong&gt; This is a great way to add value to your relationships. It also gives you another opportunity to reach out to your database and invite them. If you don’t have the budget for an event just yet, inviting your clients out for a drink or a cup of coffee is always a good idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Send something in the mail&lt;/strong&gt; at least once a month (or a monthly e-newsletter).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our team is very passionate about our past clients &lt;/strong&gt;and the results speak for themselves. 40% of our business this year is coming from repeat or referral clients. We actually utilize a 100-touch program for each person in our database. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;We do direct mail once a month, email market snapshots once a month, educational videos twice per month, three client appreciation events each year, four VIP Raving Fan Club events each year, as well as monthly calls and handwritten notes. &lt;strong&gt;We’ve been reaping the benefits of this strategy as a team and if you don’t have a similar strategy in your business you’re just missing out.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;If you have any questions for us about getting or keeping referral and repeat business, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We’d be glad to help.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 08:09:55 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://tngrealestatetraining.com/how-to-get-more-business-from-your-database.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tngrealestatetraining.com/how-to-get-more-business-from-your-database.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Is the Easiest Way to Organize and Manage Leads?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Zb9Uzy_rlCE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As real estate professionals and business professionals, it’s imperative that we have one central place where we can manage and keep records of our business relationships over time. This will allow us to create even more business in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s where the term “CRM” comes from. CRM stands for “customer relationship management,” and that’s exactly what these systems do. They allow you to manage and follow up with your clients over the course of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many different CRMs out there, but they all share a basic premise. &lt;strong&gt;CRMs give you a centralized place to manage communications, future follow-ups, and records and notes.&lt;/strong&gt; Using this kind of system will allow you to grow a bigger and more abundant business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there is a lot of confusion out there about how to segment one’s database. Ultimately, the most important thing when it comes to database management is to develop a plan and stick to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The most important thing when it comes to database management is to develop a plan and stick to it.%20http://tngrealestatetraining.com/what-is-the-easiest-way-to-organize-and-manage-leads.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The most important thing when it comes to database management is to develop a plan and stick to it.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the very least, I recommend that you take every single lead that you have and segment them in your database by label or grade. &lt;strong&gt;The easiest way to do this is by dividing leads into A, B, and C opportunities.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The A list should be made up of people you have worked with and referred you to others. Your B clients are people you may or may not have worked with. These people may not have yet referred business to you but are good prospects for future referrals. C clients are people who you don’t think will likely refer you business in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should be dividing your database into these A, B, and C categories at the very minimum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Once you’ve segmented your clients, it’s key to have a follow-up plan.&lt;/strong&gt;One of the great things about CRMs is that they not only help you manage past relationships, they are also set up to give you reminders for when you need to follow up with clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here at the Nickley Group, we utilize two different CRMs. Our entire back-end business is run out of Top Producer and our sales team uses Commissions Inc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2018 07:45:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://tngrealestatetraining.com/what-is-the-easiest-way-to-organize-and-manage-leads.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tngrealestatetraining.com/what-is-the-easiest-way-to-organize-and-manage-leads.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>4 Strategies to Take Your Open House to the Next Level</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/DwOqg89RlLU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I see many agents out there who try to do open houses by putting up a few signs, neglect to follow-up on any leads they get, and then claim that open houses don’t work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reality is, &lt;strong&gt;open houses are a great opportunity to attract business from people who are out and about looking for homes.&lt;/strong&gt; The quality of your open house and the results you get from it are a direct result of what you put into it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, many people assume open houses are only a good source for buyer business. The truth is that they’re also a great source to attract seller business. If you market that open house, talk to the neighbors, and put out a lot of signs, those same neighbors will think about you when it’s time for them to sell their home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are four strategies you can use to take your open house to the next level and reap the all the benefits from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First, use signs, signs, and more signs.&lt;/strong&gt;Way too often I see agents only putting out only two, three, or four signs. On our team, we encourage our agents to put up anywhere from 25 to 50 signs. Every single time we do an open house, the No. 1 source of all the attendees is our signs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Second, advertise the open house on social media.&lt;/strong&gt;Social media, particularly Facebook, allows you to target certain audiences so you can take that open house and create an audience within one mile of it for a cheap price. In addition to that, there are some really cool tools like Mojo Dialer and Cole Realty Resource that allow you to pull the phone numbers of all the neighbors in the area. We encourage our agents to create a list of 200 to 300 of the closest neighbors and invite them or leave them a voicemail 24 to 48 hours before the open house. Again, this shows them that you’re willing to put in the time, energy, and focus to market that open house at the highest level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The quality of your open house and the results you get from it are a direct result of what you put into them.%20http://tngrealestatetraining.com/4-strategies-to-take-your-open-house-to-the-next-level.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The quality of your open house and the results you get from it are a direct result of what you put into them.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;While people are coming to your open house, make sure you’re offering a tremendous amount of value.&lt;/strong&gt; One of the things we see the most success from is finding out exactly what the people coming into the house are looking for in a home—the schools, price points, neighborhoods, etc. Offer to set them up on a custom search either on your website, your company’s provided website, or the MLS for the exact types of properties they’re looking for that will update every single day, keep properties in front of them, and keep them engaged. This is a goldmine if you do it correctly because consumers don’t always realize we have the ability to do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lastly, make sure you have a follow-up plan in place&lt;/strong&gt; and start following up with those leads consistently and systematically the Monday after the open house. Keep following up until you know there’s no more opportunity there. Our team has a 21-day follow-up process we use with every open house lead that starts the Monday after with texts, emails, phone calls, and videos. This process enables us to reach out and convert those leads after the open house. The open house doesn’t stop that day—most of the conversion happens after it’s over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any more questions about how to market open houses or you’d like to talk about taking your career to the next level, give us a call or shoot us an email. I’d love to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 04:38:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://tngrealestatetraining.com/4-strategies-to-take-your-open-house-to-the-next-level.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tngrealestatetraining.com/4-strategies-to-take-your-open-house-to-the-next-level.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are Expensive Internet Leads Worth It?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/bLw4v4RXu64?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can get some great leads by purchasing them from Zillow and Realtor.com. But are they worth the money? From our experience, it depends on a few things. Chief among these are your conversion and follow-up processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case you don’t know already, both of these websites are very expensive lead sources. &lt;strong&gt;On average, you’re paying $100 per lead for a zip code that’s in a $300,000 price point.&lt;/strong&gt; I’ve heard that less than 5% of agents who purchase these leads are actually turning a profit on them. The rest are losing money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With both of these lead sources, consumers come to you. On Zillow, when one visits the site to look at a specific home and wants to get more information or request a showing, your name will appear on the right-hand side with two other agents. Your Zillow profile and recent sales will be listed underneath. In order to increase your chances of being chosen, you need to have a lot of positive reviews and a good sales record. Typically, the agent with the most reviews and the most sales is the one that gets chosen. On Realtor.com, it’s a similar process. However, they actually sell each lead to multiple agents at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Our team follows a very strict 21-day follow-up process.%20http://tngrealestatetraining.com/are-expensive-internet-leads-worth-it.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Our team follows a very strict 21-day follow-up process.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not only are these leads expensive, but there is also a lot of direct competition for them.&lt;/strong&gt;Whether or not you find success with this type of lead depends entirely on how you handle the lead after you receive it. Our team follows a very strict 21-day follow-up process. We send 15 different texts, videos, and emails over those 21 days in order to convert your leads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These lead sources can be lucrative, but they aren’t for the faint of heart. If you think it’s going to be easy to make a quick buck on these leads, you shouldn’t even consider purchasing them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me about these leads or want any tips to help convert them, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 07:24:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://tngrealestatetraining.com/are-expensive-internet-leads-worth-it.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tngrealestatetraining.com/are-expensive-internet-leads-worth-it.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>4 Tips That Will Help You Maximize Your Productivity as an Agent</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/a5ENoJcrPhg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a real estate professional and a business owner, I’m a firm believer that we have to make sure our time, energy, and focus are directly related to dollar-producing activities and we’re focusing daily on maximizing our effort and productivity to become the best professionals we can be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To ensure that you’re achieving your maximum productivity every day, here are four tips you can follow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First and foremost, &lt;strong&gt;focus on new business development consistently every single day.&lt;/strong&gt;Whether that means prospecting calls, knocking on doors, hosting open houses, or contacting your SOI, make sure you focus time and energy on new business development on a daily basis. We’re in the sales business, and without developing new business, you won’t have any business. Make sure you’re setting, tracking, and hitting goals on a daily basis in terms of the number of calls, conversations, or people you’re adding to your database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Become a student of this industry to become the best in this industry.%20http://tngrealestatetraining.com/4-tips-that-will-help-you-maximize-your-productivity-as-an-agent.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Become a student of this industry to become the best in this industry.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, &lt;strong&gt;make sure you time block for your most important duties of the day.&lt;/strong&gt;New business development, database management, emails, and follow-ups should all happen within a specific time block every day to make sure they’re not lost, forgotten, or sacrificed, and to make sure you’re not making excuses not to do those things. Unless we’re time blocking during the day, the most important things don’t get done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third, &lt;strong&gt;don’t spend your time on non dollar-producing activities until you’ve done your dollar-producing activities.&lt;/strong&gt;Again, these activities include talking to people about real estate and adding them to your database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, &lt;strong&gt;become a student.&lt;/strong&gt;Read, watch webinars, attend classes, and do whatever else you need to do to learn the skills and knowledge you need to become the best professional you can be in this industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here at the Nickley Group, our whole business model is built upon these exact points. We have daily role-playing and prospecting blocks that are required from our team. Every single day, we’re time blocking and coaching and training our agents because we’re not just interested in teaching them how to be real estate agents—we’re interested in teaching them how to build a business that will grow and become their own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking about making a change in your career and entering the real estate industry or you’re already in the industry and want to step up your game, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to speak with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 04:17:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://tngrealestatetraining.com/4-tips-that-will-help-you-maximize-your-productivity-as-an-agent.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tngrealestatetraining.com/4-tips-that-will-help-you-maximize-your-productivity-as-an-agent.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>4 Questions to Ask Yourself About Your Work Environment</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/CjWjqSeWFzc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As real estate agent and, more specifically, as a business owner, you are the boss. You make all of the rules and call all of the shots. As a business owner, you have to constantly analyze the things that will make you the most successful or stop you from being successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That means you constantly have to analyze your work habits, mindset, and focus. One of the most important things to pay attention to is the environment you choose to work in every single day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is your work environment conducive to achieving your goals?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of people get into real estate because they like the idea of being their own boss. People like the flexibility, being able to set your own hours, and working from home. It all sounds very appealing, but working from home only works for a small percentage of people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re like me, it’s impossible for you to get into the right mindset and develop the right habits when working from home. There are just so many distractions at home: laundry, dishes in the sink, dogs barking, television—there are a million and one things that will get in the way. You won’t be as productive as you could be and you won’t be able to achieve your goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Does your work environment offer the training and resources you need?%20http://tngrealestatetraining.com/4-questions-to-ask-yourself-about-your-work-environment.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Does your work environment offer the training and resources you need?”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can you choose the right work environment that will set you up to smash your goals? I have a few questions you should ask yourself to make sure that you are putting yourself in the right situation every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Does your work environment allow you to surround yourself with like-minded and goal-driven individuals?&lt;/strong&gt; It’s no secret that the people you surround yourself with are a direct reflection of your own mindsets, habits, and focus. By surrounding yourself with like-minded, hard-working people, you will elevate your own game because of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Is your environment supportive?&lt;/strong&gt; Does your environment allow you to focus on new business development each and every day? It’s especially important for newer agents in the industry to develop new business. We have to make calls and prospect. Does your work environment support that or is prospecting a dirty word around your office?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Does your work environment offer the opportunity to have coaches, mentors, books, and other training resources?&lt;/strong&gt;That’s what it will take for you to be successful. When you first get into this industry, it can be very overwhelming. There are so many things you have to do. After all, you are a business owner. Are you surrounded by people who will help you take your career to the next level? Or is your office a ghost town, with no one there to help you? You need to be surrounded by people who will help you get to where you want to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Does the work environment allow you to be accountable for what you do on a daily basis?&lt;/strong&gt; If you have big goals and you are driven, you have to have people hold you accountable to that. Does your work environment offer that kind of support?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the Nickley Group, we are very proud of our work environment. We do everything we can to help our agents be as productive as possible and put it all on the line every day so that they can smash past their goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each day, we are role-playing together, prospecting together, and we have unlimited resources for training together. I am here every day to help train our agents. We also have a dedicated sales manager who works one-on-one with our agents. We offer accountability, new business development, coaching, and training to help our agents be successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about making your work environment more conducive to your success or are interested in a change, just give me a call or send me an email. I would love to sit down and talk with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 06:47:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://tngrealestatetraining.com/4-questions-to-ask-yourself-about-your-work-environment.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tngrealestatetraining.com/4-questions-to-ask-yourself-about-your-work-environment.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
