<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Career Advancement Video Blog</title>
    <description>Govig &amp; Associates is one of the largest privately held firms in the Executive Search industry. With more than three decades in staffing and recruiting, we have the knowledge, the network and the speed to provide unparalleled service to our clients.</description>
    <link>http://govigblog.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://govigblog.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2017 11:02:23 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2017 11:02:23 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>These 3 Traits Make a Great Team Player</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/KpGLfMjYqxA&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does the ideal team player look like?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently read a book by Patrick Lencioni called “The Ideal Team Player,” and the premise of this book is that when the author hires for his team or assesses his team, he hones in on three main traits: &lt;strong&gt;humble, hungry, and smart&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Humble” is pretty self-explanatory because you don’t want a team member who is arrogant or egocentric. Someone who is humble and plays well with others will put the team before themselves. Herb Brooks said it best in “Miracle,” the name on the front of the jersey should always be more important than the name on the back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone who is hungry will want more responsibility, will want to learn more, and be self-motivated. They won’t need to be micromanaged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Someone who is hungry will want more responsibility, to learn more, and be self-motivated.%20http://govigblog.com/these-3-traits-make-a-great-team-player.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Someone who is hungry will want more responsibility, to learn more, and be self-motivated.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, when he says someone is “smart,” it’s not the first thing you think of when it comes to intelligence. In this context, it refers more to being socially smart. A smart team member knows how to read people, knows how they’re perceived, and is aware of their social presence in a conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With these traits, there are also three extremes to be aware of as well.&lt;/strong&gt; Someone who is too humble could be afraid to contribute or speak up when it could benefit their team. Someone who is too hungry can be a steamroller, rolling over anyone at any cost to succeed. Someone who is too socially smart might be considered a schmoozer who tells you everything you want to hear, even when it might not be the truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to talk further about how these traits affect a team dynamic or you’d like to talk more about your career, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I’d love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/these-3-traits-make-a-great-team-player.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://govigblog.com/these-3-traits-make-a-great-team-player.html</guid>
        
        <category>Health Care</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Conflict Resolution in the Workplace</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7yglxiGlEo8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are the top leadership skills? There are really quite a few skills we’d like to cover, so this video is the first of a bimonthly series on this topic. The first skill I wanted to focus on is how to navigate relationships in the workplace, or conflict resolution.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Conflict resolution is not a topic that most people are eager to discuss. However, fundamentally, &lt;strong&gt;it is one of the most important things you can learn how to do and learn how to be effective at&lt;/strong&gt;. This is because everything is team-oriented today. We rarely see business environments that don’t have people somehow involved in a team. Plus, it’s a management skill; how do you create teams that are effective, efficient, and that have good communication?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Everything is team-oriented today.%20http://govigblog.com/conflict-resolution-in-the-workplace.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Everything is team-oriented today.”&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Patrick Lencioni’s book “The Five Dysfunctions of a Team” helped me significantly in learning and mastering this particular leadership skill and I recommend it highly for anyone who is interested. The process of conflict resolution is:
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;1. Identify the problem and decide what the end goal will be and why that outcome will be beneficial.
&lt;br /&gt;2. Craft your language with an objective third party.
&lt;br /&gt;3. Have a meeting with the person you have a concern with. Be straightforward with the issue right away.
&lt;br /&gt;4. Compliment the person on their good aspects to diffuse any kind of defensiveness they may have as you discuss the issue.
&lt;br /&gt;5. Move on to what your concern is, what your end goal is, and why that would be beneficial to both that person and the team as a whole.
&lt;br /&gt;6. Ask for feedback.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;It sounds simple, but you need to practice this tactic. It is fundamental to not only leadership within a group, but also how effectively you can manage and navigate relationships as you progress to management.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;In our next video, we’ll talk more about leadership skills. If you have any questions about this or any other topic we’ve covered, please don’t hesitate to reach out. We’d be happy to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/conflict-resolution-in-the-workplace.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://govigblog.com/conflict-resolution-in-the-workplace.html</guid>
        
        <category>Bio Pharma</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Must Companies Constantly Reinvent Themselves?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/fT_36L3-8OY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To keep pace with constant changes in the market and in the world at large, businesses must learn how to adapt and continually reinvent themselves in order to secure a future. Why do companies need to do this, though? It reminds me of the Winchester Mansion project. Let me tell you why.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Sarah Winchester was an heir to the Winchester Rifle fortune. Unfortunately, after her husband died she became convinced that she was cursed by all the victims that had lost their lives to Winchester rifles.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;She decided to build a sprawling mansion and she never stopped. She built stairways to ceilings, doorways in floors, and all sorts of hidden passageways and secret rooms. What appeared to be beautiful from the outside was actually very chaotic and confusing on the inside&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Many factors can lead to chaos.%20http://govigblog.com/why-must-companies-constantly-reinvent-themselves.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Many factors can lead to chaos.”&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;An evolving business can be like that. &lt;strong&gt;When you think about the technology advancement, market shorts, organic growth, and new leadership all playing a part in a company’s future, what can appear to be calm on the outside is often chaotic from the inside.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;When you’re living in a business day in and day out, you don’t necessarily see what’s going on. So take a step back and be objective when looking at your organization and how it needs to adapt in order to continue its success in the future. &lt;strong&gt;What was relevant yesterday just might not be relevant today.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;If you’d like to talk more about your business or how you can ensure it’s as efficient and effective as possible, give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/why-must-companies-constantly-reinvent-themselves.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://govigblog.com/why-must-companies-constantly-reinvent-themselves.html</guid>
        
        <category>Futurity</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Telephone and Virtual Interview Tips</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/NEcRwQgQX5c&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We recently had a question about how to better handle telephone interviews or virtual (Skype) interviews. I am going to elaborate a little bit on this topic today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In both of these instances, you want to make sure you’re prepared and know your skills, your accomplishments, and how those things benefit the person you’re interviewing with. Secondly, you want to make sure you’ve done your research on the hiring authority, their background, and their accomplishments. Finally, you’ve got to do your research on the company. &lt;strong&gt;The more prepared you are, the more confident you will be.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=In either instance, you want to be prepared.%20http://govigblog.com/telephone-and-virtual-interview-tips.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“In either instance, you want to be prepared.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For telephone interviews, the best tip I have for you is to stand up. By standing up, you will have more energy in your voice and in terms of how you bring across the information that is relevant in the interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re doing a Skype interview, it’s not as simple. You typically have to sit down in that situation, so standing up can be difficult. &lt;strong&gt;The big thing to remember is to keep distractions at a minimum.&lt;/strong&gt; That means making sure everything shown on camera is neat and anyone else in the house with you knows to keep loud noises at a minimum for the duration of your interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this topic or want to learn more interview tips, give me a call or send me an email. I would be glad to discuss this topic further with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/telephone-and-virtual-interview-tips.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://govigblog.com/telephone-and-virtual-interview-tips.html</guid>
        
        <category>Bio Pharma</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Few Outside the Box Hiring Tips</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/r4oz30UsuGg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do companies in this industry grow faster than the industry average? &lt;strong&gt;The common denominator is that they think outside the box when bringing new people on board.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you think about it, every company is basically looking to fill their roles by looking at the same criteria. You want someone with product experience, selling experience, and a proven track record. The only thing that separates the top companies from the average ones is the culture of the organization. In fact, a recent USA Today study concluded that &lt;strong&gt;85% of the people that were hired only had 65% of the actual criteria they were looking for.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Companies are hiring people who fit their culture as opposed to people who have the exact skill sets they are looking for. They are thinking outside the box about what skills could be transferrable from a similar industry just by teaching the product. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We’ve had success recruiting pharmaceutical reps%20http://govigblog.com/a-few-outside-the-box-hiring-tips.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We’ve had success recruiting pharmaceutical reps”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we look for A&amp;amp;D reps, we certainly would love to find someone with that experience, but we also have had a tremendous amount of success actually recruiting pharmaceutical reps. A&amp;amp;D reps update libraries, work with a designer to influence them to specify their product on a particular project, and they do lunch and learns. Pharmaceutical reps have a very similar transactions with their doctors. They influence the doctor to write the scripts, work with the office in updating samples, and do lunch and learns. &lt;strong&gt;As you can see, those skills are very transferrable and this strategy has been very successful for the companies we have worked with.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re thinking about hiring, thinking outside the box is important. Don’t go down that normal track because you have the same people always cycling through the industry, just with a different business card. Be different and be bold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/a-few-outside-the-box-hiring-tips.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://govigblog.com/a-few-outside-the-box-hiring-tips.html</guid>
        
        <category>Building Products</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Questions That Lead to the Perfect Hire</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/iIMyBCLaua0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making a better hiring decision boils down to three questions you should ask yourself when interviewing any candidate for your organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, &lt;strong&gt;can do they do the job? &lt;/strong&gt;Do they have the mental ability, skill set, and personality to do the job well? If they don’t have the skill set to do the job well, do you have the ability to train them and teach them the required skills to get them up to speed quickly to give you a return on investment for that hire?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The best candidate is not always the right candidate.%20http://govigblog.com/3-questions-that-lead-to-the-perfect-hire.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The best candidate is not always the right candidate.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, &lt;strong&gt;can they do the job long term?&lt;/strong&gt; Do they have the aspirations to be at the job long term? If they don’t, do you have a timeline that aligns with theirs or can you give them additional responsibilities or a promotion to keep them engaged in your organization in the long term?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, &lt;strong&gt;are they the right fit for the team?&lt;/strong&gt; The best candidate is not always the right candidate. The team culture is very important, so they need to fit the mold and fit to the culture while also performing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this topic, please feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/3-questions-that-lead-to-the-perfect-hire.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://govigblog.com/3-questions-that-lead-to-the-perfect-hire.html</guid>
        
        <category>Health Care</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Jumpstart Your Post-College Career</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/6mGZ-B_KWCg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you just finished college but you aren’t sure what you want to do or how to enter the business world, then you’re not alone. If you want a successful career, there are two things that you need to understand. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, you need to be aware of the latest demographic trends and how they will affect your career. Baby boomers are retiring at a rate of 10,000 people a day. There simply aren’t enough experienced people to replace the baby boomers, which creates an opportunity for up and comers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, I recommend that you read &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Outliers-Story-Success-Malcolm-Gladwell/dp/0316017930/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1488484320&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=book+the+outliers&quot;&gt;“Outliers” by Malcolm Gladwell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. This is a great book and its fundamental thesis is that it takes 10,000 hours for you to become really good at any skill set. From athletics to music to software programming, you need 10,000 hours of experience to fully understand the skills needed for the job. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Choose a job that you can develop a passion for and stick with it.%20http://govigblog.com/how-to-jumpstart-your-post-college-career.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Choose a job that you can develop a passion for and stick with it.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As a recent college graduate, you need to figure out how you can combine the demographic trends with the 10,000 hour rule.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than following what appears to be the millennial career path of having 16 different jobs with 20 different companies in three years, find something that you can develop a passion for over time. The problem with frequently changing jobs is that you are never in one place long enough to get really good at one particular job. If you spend 10,000 hours—which roughly equals five years—in one career, then you will be extremely knowledgeable about that particular area.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It takes awhile to understand the common knowledge of the domain, and it takes even longer to know the uncommon knowledge that gives the top 1% their competitive edge. That uncommon knowledge is not a secret; you just don’t have enough knowledge to really execute the job properly until you have been there long enough to know the common knowledge. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, you need to go into an area where you can develop some passion for the job and learn all about it. Since baby boomers are retiring in droves, there will be plenty of opportunities for you down the line. By spending all your time on one career path, you will have a leg up on other millennials who have had a few different jobs and aren’t especially good at any one thing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Companies are dying to hire people who know their space and can bring value to the table.&lt;/strong&gt; To be successful in your career, you need to become that person. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about entering the real world of business, give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/how-to-jumpstart-your-post-college-career.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://govigblog.com/how-to-jumpstart-your-post-college-career.html</guid>
        
        <category>Careers</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Leading a Hockey Team Is Like Leading a Business</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7uzZOUO5ntA&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What can business leaders learn from hockey? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In hockey, players are taught to skate not to where the puck is, but where it’s going next. &lt;strong&gt;To win the game, you have to be able to effectively anticipate your next move.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In N. Dean Meyer’s book, “Structural Cybernetics,” he actually talks about five different organizational systems. The first is culture, which is how we treat one another. The second is structure, which is work charts and workflows. Then, there is the internal economy, which is how money moves throughout the organization. The fourth is methods and tools, and the last is metrics and reward, which is incentives and accountability. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a really good example of how anticipation works in business. In a company, you could have a people problem, which ultimately could be a structural problem or a culture problem. Or, simply put, it could simply be that you need to change out an existing tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For companies, not knowing how to anticipate the difference or the end result of your actions can mean fixing one problem only to cause two more. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Companies need to think like hockey players so they can effectively anticipate their next move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Winning is all about the ability to anticipate the next move.%20http://govigblog.com/how-leading-a-hockey-team-is-like-leading-a-business.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Winning is all about the ability to anticipate the next move.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the movie &lt;em&gt;Miracle on Ice&lt;/em&gt;, there’s a saying that comes up over and over, ‘the legs feed the wolf.’ &lt;strong&gt;The coach anticipated that in order for this team to go all the way to the Olympics, they would need one thing,&lt;/strong&gt; and that was to be able to have the strongest legs on the ice. So he trained his players to not only have the strongest legs but also have the greatest amount of endurance. His ability to anticipate what his team needed from beginning to end was why they won the gold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any further questions about the power of anticipation in business, we’d be happy to answer them. We hope to hear from you soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/how-leading-a-hockey-team-is-like-leading-a-business.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://govigblog.com/how-leading-a-hockey-team-is-like-leading-a-business.html</guid>
        
        <category>Futurity</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How the Affordable Care Act Affects the Nursing Home Industry</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7ZfWZlBruQ8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Affordable Care Act was designed to provide health care coverage for those who didn’t have insurance, so how is it affecting the nursing home industry?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within the nursing home industry, most residents do have some form of coverage whether it’s Medicare, Medicaid, or an HMO, so the thought was that the impact the Affordable Care Act would have on the nursing home industry would be small, if any.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The unforeseen consequence is that it really exacerbates the shortage and the demand for physicians. &lt;strong&gt;It adds strain on the number of medical professionals available.&lt;/strong&gt; In fact, by the year 2025, there will be a shortage of 52,000 primary care physicians for a few reasons. The first is that very few study nursing home care while in medical school. Second, regulations are often very high, and third, the pay is often lower for that type of role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=By the year 2025, there will be a shortage of 52,000 primary care physicians.%20http://govigblog.com/how-the-affordable-care-act-affects-the-nursing-home-industry.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“By the year 2025, there will be a shortage of 52,000 primary care physicians.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are, however, a few things that management of nursing home facilities can do to make sure they are aligned strongly with a physician for their community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, take an executive approach to make sure your administrator and the director of nursing build a good rapport with physicians in your marketplace. If the medical community hires a new physician, your administrator should &lt;strong&gt;invite them out to get a feel for your community and introduce them to the care you provide.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, physicians want to have a rapport built with key executives, like the administrator and director of nursing. &lt;strong&gt;Ensuring that rapport is built will have you on your way to having a physician in your corner.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, please feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/how-the-affordable-care-act-affects-the-nursing-home-industry.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://govigblog.com/how-the-affordable-care-act-affects-the-nursing-home-industry.html</guid>
        
        <category>Health Care</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Best Ways to Differentiate Your Company in Today’s Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8gYAsTVjt0Y&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What really differentiates companies in today’s marketplace? The two biggest ways companies can set themselves apart are through &lt;strong&gt;thought leadership and online presence. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, 2017 is going to be a big year for manufacturers in the building products industry. As a whole, the industry is projected to grow, but that also means there will be a lot of competition. The manufacturers who stay ahead of the curve with their sales and marketing efforts will continue to create competitive advantages as the industry continues to rebound. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In many ways, though, the building and design industry is still old school. Jobs are won and lost through relationships and connections, and products are chosen for similar reasons. Even though manufacturers understand that their online presence is important, they haven’t gone the extra step to truly differentiate themselves from the competition. The “follow the leader” mentality is still a prevailing force in the industry, and even the companies who invest in their online presence tend to have similar online profiles. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Use articles, blogs, and videos to produce thought leadership.%20http://govigblog.com/the-best-ways-to-differentiate-your-company-in-todays-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Use articles, blogs, and videos to produce thought leadership.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As online usage continues to grow, your online presence needs to measure up. &lt;/strong&gt;Consumers want the manufacturers to solve their problems, so manufacturers are realizing that just pushing their product isn’t enough to get their audience’s attention anymore. You really have to produce thought leadership through articles, blogs, videos, and other online content that really helps solve that everyday business problem. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, great marketing helps the audience solve the issues that matter to them. Remember, people are not buying products; they are buying solutions. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, please don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/the-best-ways-to-differentiate-your-company-in-todays-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://govigblog.com/the-best-ways-to-differentiate-your-company-in-todays-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Building Products</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
