<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- MARKET -- Real Estate Video Blog with -- CLIENT NAME --</title>
    <description>Our mission at Keller Williams Realty | Alaska Group is to be your best resource for Anchorage real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Keller Williams Realty | Alaska Group, your professional Anchorage Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://darwaldenteamblog.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://darwaldenteamblog.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 12:00:45 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 12:00:45 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>2018 Home Seller's Seminar Reminder</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/W4yakmWutp4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SAVE THE DATE TO ATTEND THE 2018 SELLERS SEMINAR!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Want to sell your home? &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a FREE home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Want to buy a home? &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all homes for sale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On March 3, our team of local real estate experts will reveal the essential home selling secrets you’ll need to get a jumpstart on preparing your home for the 2018 market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dar Walden only holds the &lt;strong&gt;SELLER SEMINAR ONCE A YEAR!!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn from the #1 Real Estate Team in the state of Alaska!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seats are limited, so &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alaskatopagent.com/Pages/Seminar.aspx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;register now!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 14:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://darwaldenteamblog.com/2018-home-sellers-seminar.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://darwaldenteamblog.com/2018-home-sellers-seminar.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Seminar</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Home Seller's Seminar Reminder</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/FTlP_D92c4E?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SAVE THE DATE TO ATTEND THE 2018 SELLERS SEMINAR!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Want to sell your home? &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a FREE home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Want to buy a home? &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all homes for sale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On March 3, our team of local real estate experts will reveal the &lt;strong&gt;essential home selling secrets&lt;/strong&gt; you’ll need to get a jumpstart on preparing your home for the 2018 market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dar Walden only holds the &lt;strong&gt;SELLER SEMINAR ONCE A YEAR!!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn from the #1 Real Estate Team in the state of Alaska!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seats are limited, so &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alaskatopagent.com/Pages/Seminar.aspx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;register now!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 09:13:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://darwaldenteamblog.com/home-sellers-seminar-reminder.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://darwaldenteamblog.com/home-sellers-seminar-reminder.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Seminar</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Are the Dos and Don'ts of Home Renovation?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/VYc0slZmErg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re planning on renovating your house before selling it, there are certain things you should do and certain things you shouldn’t do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Want to sell your home? &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a FREE home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Want to buy a home? &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all homes for sale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a rundown of some of the do’s and don’ts of home renovation if you’re getting ready to sell your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t:&lt;/strong&gt; Wait until you’re ready to sell to start renovating. This is one of the biggest mistakes sellers can make. Do yourself a favor and do your renovations while you live in the property so you can enjoy them. You’ll never be able to get a dollar-for-dollar return for them, so the best way to compensate for that is to use those renovations for your own personal enjoyment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do:&lt;/strong&gt; Work on curb appeal. People tend to overlook this here in Alaska because it’s hard to manage curb appeal in February, but curb appeal is the No. 1 thing that draws people into a home. If they don’t like what they see when they drive up, you’ll probably lose them before they ever step foot into the home. Just make sure to use common sense and avoid doing something like building a $10,000 decorative retaining wall because you definitely won’t get your money back. Just clean everything up and make your exterior look nice and neat and it will carry you further than you can imagine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=DO YOUR RENOVATIONS WHILE YOU LIVE IN THE PROPERTY SO YOU CAN ENJOY THEM.%20http://darwaldenteamblog.com/the-dos-and-donts-of-home-renovation.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“DO YOUR RENOVATIONS WHILE YOU LIVE IN THE PROPERTY SO YOU CAN ENJOY THEM.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t:&lt;/strong&gt; Expect to get a dollar-for-dollar return on invisible repairs. Repairing or improving things like heaters, septic tanks, and roofs is necessary for your sale, but buyers will already expect them to be done, so you won’t be able to raise your list price $15,000 just because you put $15,000 into repairing your septic tank. That’s not how the market works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do:&lt;/strong&gt; Make sure the upgrades you make are appropriate for your home. You don’t want to tear apart a kitchen in a million-dollar home and replace it with $10,000 worth of upgraded kitchen cabinets. The reverse is also true—you don’t want to put $150,000 into a kitchen in a home that’s only worth $250,000. It’s OK to go high on a renovation, just make sure you’ll be living in that home for the next three to 10 years. The longer, the better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t:&lt;/strong&gt; Overspend on a deck upgrade. Everybody loves decks, and in the lower 48 the return on investment is very good for an upgraded deck, but that’s not the case in Alaska. We typically don’t spend a lot of time on our decks—our winters are too harsh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do:&lt;/strong&gt; Make sure your upgrades are appropriate for the subdivision. If you put $150,000 into a home that’s worth $250,000 and you wanted to get $400,000 out of the home, you should know that the subdivision would never support that $400,000 pricing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about home renovation or you’re thinking about buying or selling a home in our market, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 14:37:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://darwaldenteamblog.com/the-dos-and-donts-of-home-renovation.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://darwaldenteamblog.com/the-dos-and-donts-of-home-renovation.html</guid>
        
        <category>Expert Advice</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Home Seller's Seminar</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/RgqZLUhYKUI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SAVE THE DATE TO ATTEND THE 2018 SELLERS SEMINAR!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Want to sell your home? &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a FREE home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Want to buy a home? &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all homes for sale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On March 3, our team of local real estate experts will reveal the essential home selling secrets you’ll need to get a jumpstart on preparing your home for the 2018 market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dar Walden only holds the &lt;strong&gt;SELLER SEMINAR ONCE A YEAR!!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn from the #1 Real Estate Team in the state of Alaska!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seats are limited, so &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alaskatopagent.com/Pages/Seminar.aspx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;register now!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2018 09:19:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://darwaldenteamblog.com/home-sellers-seminar.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://darwaldenteamblog.com/home-sellers-seminar.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Seminar</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Must You Avoid These 3 Mistakes?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/K5_OfzzdOJg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re selling a home, there are many mistakes that you can make. Just be sure you don’t make any of these three.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Want to sell your home? &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a FREE home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Want to buy a home? &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all homes for sale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking about selling your home, you need to make sure that you avoid these three major mistakes before you officially list your home for sale:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Overpricing.&lt;/strong&gt; Often, the agent will give the homeowner a range in value of where they think the home should be priced. Many homeowners want to go above that because they think the property is worth more. However, overpricing your home will gain nothing. It will end up costing you months on the market, lead to multiple price reductions, more negotiations, and less money overall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Marketing.&lt;/strong&gt; Not all agents are created equally when it comes to marketing. Homes don’t sell themselves, contrary to popular belief. The best way to ensure a quick and profitable sale is by getting the property out there and in front of potential buyers. Last year, we sold more homes than any other agent or team in the state of Alaska. Our 574 total sales in 2017 is a much higher figure than the nine homes per year the average agent sells.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=YOUR HOME NEEDS TO BE SHOW-READY AT ALL TIMES.%20http://darwaldenteamblog.com/3-deal-killing-mistakes.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“YOUR HOME NEEDS TO BE SHOW-READY AT ALL TIMES.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Not making the home presentable.&lt;/strong&gt; If your home is on the market for sale, it needs to be in show-ready condition at all times. It should smell good, but not too good. What I mean here is that you want to get rid of any unpleasant or odd odors, but you don’t want to overdo it on the air freshener or candles because then the buyers will think you’re trying to hide something. You want to find a nice, happy, and fresh medium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about selling a home or anything else about real estate in general, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 16:08:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://darwaldenteamblog.com/3-deal-killing-mistakes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://darwaldenteamblog.com/3-deal-killing-mistakes.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Are We Seeing in the Anchorage Area Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/XObRS_foTnc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully you had a great holiday season! Now that it’s 2018, it’s time for a market update.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Want to sell your home? &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a FREE home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Want to buy a home? &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all homes for sale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to 2018! I hope you and your family had a great holiday season and were able to spend some time with your loved ones. I apologize for being gone from my video blog for longer than normal; I had surgery and I’m hobbling around on crutches, so I’ve been out of the office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, we’re going to talk a little bit about what our local market is doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Right now, we have 637 active listings, which is about 3.3 months of inventory.&lt;/strong&gt; We have 200 pending properties at the moment, and that’s about a third of what’s out there. Pending properties mean that they’re under contract and haven’t been sold yet but are on the way to being sold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We’ve had 160 expired properties over the last six months.&lt;/strong&gt; There are really only three reasons why a property doesn’t sell and the listing expires: the condition, the pricing, and the location. Typically, location is the smaller percentage, with 98% of the reason being price and condition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=98% OF THE REASON WHY A LISTING EXPIRES IS PRICE AND CONDITION.%20http://darwaldenteamblog.com/anchorage-market-update.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“98% OF THE REASON WHY A LISTING EXPIRES IS PRICE AND CONDITION.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The average sales price is a little bit higher than it was in 2016, at just under $270,000. The &lt;strong&gt;sellers are still getting about 99% of their last list price&lt;/strong&gt;, as long as they’re priced appropriately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The average days on market to be sold is 54 days, but right now in the Anchorage/Eagle River/Girdwood area, the average days on market is 123 days. Why the difference? The properties that sold in 54 days were priced appropriately and were in good condition, so buyers swept them up quickly. It’s a red flag when properties have been on the market for 123 days, usually meaning that the price and/or condition aren’t attractive to buyers. &lt;strong&gt;As a seller, you really control how long it takes to sell your home through those factors.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are thinking of selling your home this year, now is the time to get started on it. If you’re thinking about buying, we’re going to start seeing inventory increase in February and it will be rolling pretty well by April.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For any questions or real estate needs, feel free to give us a call. We’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 10:24:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://darwaldenteamblog.com/anchorage-market-update.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://darwaldenteamblog.com/anchorage-market-update.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dont Be Afraid of Selling in the Winter</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/iKKzvGKMZ7A?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t believe the hype; winter is a perfectly viable time to sell your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Want to sell your home? &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a FREE home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Want to buy a home? &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all homes for sale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week we’re going to talk about selling your home in the winter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people think that homes don’t sell in the winter. Surprisingly enough, you’d be amazed at the number of sales that we have in the winter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s face it—when you have to sell your home, you have to sell your home, whether it’s winter or summer. However, if you have the convenience of waiting, many people prefer to do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Waiting can often be a mistake.&lt;/strong&gt; Inventories in the fall tend to drop down, and buyers have fewer choices to pick from, which can often drive the pricing up on your home that is for sale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other thing is that in the summertime, you typically have more showings than in the winter, but &lt;strong&gt;often you get a lot of what we call “looky-loos”&lt;/strong&gt; out there shopping and half-heartedly looking around. A lot of people like to go to open houses and look at homes for remodeling purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the wintertime, you have fewer showings. However, those buyers are typically more serious.&lt;/strong&gt; They’re not out dragging themselves through the snow because it’s fun, but because they need a home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do not be afraid to put your property on the market in the winter. Yes, it is slower, but property still sells.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=DO NOT BE AFRAID TO PUT YOUR PROPERTY ON THE MARKET IN THE WINTER.%20http://darwaldenteamblog.com/selling-in-winter.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“DO NOT BE AFRAID TO PUT YOUR PROPERTY ON THE MARKET IN THE WINTER.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I can be of any help, please feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I’m happy to do a cursory walk around your property and give you some marketing tips. After all, now is the time to amp up your curb appeal to avoid having to do so with snow on the ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a great week!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 11:50:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://darwaldenteamblog.com/selling-in-winter.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://darwaldenteamblog.com/selling-in-winter.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Avoid Major Expenses With These Home Maintenance Tips</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/NRh_LiqXR8Q?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Winter is here, which means it’s time to take care of some basic home maintenance items in order to avoid major damages and expenses down the line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Want to sell your home? &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a FREE home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Want to buy a home? &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all homes for sale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Winter is here, and we’ve had our first official snowfall. As a homeowner, there are a few things you need to do to protect your home from damage and avoid major expenses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, you need to remove your hoses from the hose bib. If you have the older kind of hose bib, you’ll need to put a cover on it. Newer hose bibs do not require a cover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Secondly, although icicles may look really cool, they are not good for your roof at all.&lt;/strong&gt; Find out why those icicles are forming and get someone out there to remove them. Do not try to remove them yourself. Hire a professional. Icicles can cause roof damage and cost you thousands and thousands of dollars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, caulk your windows and make sure that your doors are sealed. Caulk the baseboards and walk around the outside of your house to check for any other gaps. Get everything caulked and sealed up. If you were to add all of the cracks and crevices together, &lt;strong&gt;the average house has a 3x3 foot window of air coming into the home.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or need referrals to any professionals to help you with these maintenance items, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 15:34:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://darwaldenteamblog.com/winter-is-officially-here_17.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://darwaldenteamblog.com/winter-is-officially-here_17.html</guid>
        
        <category>Expert Advice</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>7 Reasons Why Fall Is a Great Time to Buy a Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/glfY6ECpEQ0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are more than a couple reasons why fall is a great time to buy a home in our market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Want to sell your home? &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a FREE home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Want to buy a home? &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all homes for sale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are seven reasons what fall is a great time to purchase a home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. There is less competition.&lt;/strong&gt; If you’re a buyer out there looking in the fall, chances are you face less competition from other buyers and steer clear of any multiple offer situations like you’d see in the spring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Sellers are tired of marketing.&lt;/strong&gt; They want to be done with things. They’ve probably been on the market since summer, and that tends to wear them down. This makes them a little more motivated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Sellers are more serious.&lt;/strong&gt; Oftentimes, they’re trying to move before winter hits, so that works in your favor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. You can also take advantage of the tax breaks you’ll get during this time of year.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Pricing tends to be more reasonable.&lt;/strong&gt; Again, sellers have been on the market for a while and they’re tired of marketing their property. As we all know, the longer a seller’s home is on the market, the less they’ll typically take for their property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. There are fewer buyers out there.&lt;/strong&gt; This is somewhat related to the first point, but fewer buyers means sellers are happy when they get active showings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Interest rates are still great!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=IF YOU’RE THINKING OF PURCHASING A HOME, NOW IS THE TIME TO DO IT.%20http://darwaldenteamblog.com/why-fall-is-great-time-to-purchase-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“IF YOU’RE THINKING OF PURCHASING A HOME, NOW IS THE TIME TO DO IT.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking of purchasing a home, now is the time to do it. If you want to start the home buying process or you have any questions about what’s happening in our Anchorage market, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 15:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://darwaldenteamblog.com/why-fall-is-great-time-to-purchase-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://darwaldenteamblog.com/why-fall-is-great-time-to-purchase-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Educational Tips and Tricks</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Make Your Home More Energy-Efficient Over the Winter</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/SsYuF-kKQM0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to stay warm during the winter and lower your energy costs, there are a few things you must do around the house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Want to sell your home? &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a FREE home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Want to buy a home? &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all homes for sale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can you make your home more energy-efficient now that winter is here? There are several things you can do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things I often see with sellers is them not having serviced their heating systems for sometimes as long as two, three, or even five years. By servicing your heating system, you can almost double the life of your heater. If you haven’t done that, &lt;strong&gt;now is the time to call a heating company to service and clean your heating system and make any necessary repairs to it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people wait until the heater breaks, and that’s usually during the first winter freeze-up. Heating companies can sometimes be backed up three or four days during this time, though, so you want to stay ahead of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing you can do is make sure all of your windows are caulked on the outside and inside. If you’ve got older windows that naturally leak air, you can also insulate them by putting plastic shields over them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, &lt;strong&gt;consider installing a programmable thermostat.&lt;/strong&gt; Turning your thermostat down 10 to 15 degrees at night or while you’re not at home can save you about 10% on your heating bill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, &lt;strong&gt;don’t heat unused spaces.&lt;/strong&gt; If you have rooms you don’t use, shut the heater down in them. That will filter the heat to other places in the house. If the heater works less, it will cost you less money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=THE LESS YOUR HEATER WORKS, THE LESS IT WILL COST YOU.%20http://darwaldenteamblog.com/energy-efficiencies-in-your-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“THE LESS YOUR HEATER WORKS, THE LESS IT WILL COST YOU.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, if you have large windows that let a lot of sun in during the day, make sure those windows are open so that sunlight can heat your home naturally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about energy efficiencies in your home or you have any other real estate questions, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send us an email. I’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 16:11:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://darwaldenteamblog.com/energy-efficiencies-in-your-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://darwaldenteamblog.com/energy-efficiencies-in-your-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Expert Advice</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
