<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Brad Korb Real Estate Group - your professional Burbank Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>lasells.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="lasells.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 11:40:49 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 11:40:49 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>You Don’t Need as Much for a Down Payment as You Think</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/leOfMKAFd5U?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve talked to a lot of first-time homebuyers recently that are under the impression that they need to save up a lot of money for their down payment. You should know that there are plenty of down payment options out there for different loans.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;You don’t need 10% or 20% to purchase a home. In fact, &lt;strong&gt;you can get into a home with FHA financing for just 3.5% down.&lt;/strong&gt; Rather than saving for years to get to that level, let’s talk about getting you into a home now so you can start looking sooner rather than later and lock in a low rate with a low down payment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You don’t need 20%; you only need 3.5%.%20lasells.com/you-dont-need-as-much-for-a-down-payment-as-you-think.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You don’t need 20%; you only need 3.5%.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me or want to hear more about the different financing options out there, give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 08:48:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>lasells.com/you-dont-need-as-much-for-a-down-payment-as-you-think.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">lasells.com/you-dont-need-as-much-for-a-down-payment-as-you-think.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Rising Rates Impact Our Market</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;What’s going on in the market now that interest rates have gone up?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the election ended, rates have jumped up. The Fed is talking about raising rates three more times throughout 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buyers are pouring into the market now in order to lock in a low interest rate. If they wait to buy, they will likely get stuck with a higher interest rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is light inventory right now, which is beneficial to home sellers. If you’ve been thinking about selling your home, I recommend getting on the market as soon as possible. Buyers are ready to make a purchase now and you won’t face as much competition from other sellers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about our current market, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 13:11:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>lasells.com/how-rising-rates-impact-our-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">lasells.com/how-rising-rates-impact-our-market.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Help Us Donate to Toys for Tots This Winter</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/KhkFwJ-szog?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just wanted to drop by and send you a quick reminder today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to help keep a child happy this holiday season, I’ve got some good news to share with you. This year, our office will be accepting donations for Toys for Tots!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stop by our office before December 16th and drop off any new, unwrapped toys that you’d like to donate. Your donation could mean the world to a child this holiday season, so come by our office, say hello, and donate anything that you can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, if you have any questions related to real estate in our area, give me a call or send me an email anytime. I look forward to hearing from you soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 16:23:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>lasells.com/help-us-donate-to-toys-for-tots-this-winter.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">lasells.com/help-us-donate-to-toys-for-tots-this-winter.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Join Us and Give Back This Thanksgiving and Holiday Season</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Idm6wtZS6Ik?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We just wanted to reach out to you today to wish you and your family a very happy Thanksgiving. Today we have a short video to share with you of our time helping out the Burbank Temporary Aid Center.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They have been serving the Burbank community for 40 years and we figured we should give them some extra help this holiday season. That is why we loaded up a van full of turkeys and took them over!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We help The Burbank Temporary Aid Center out year round, and you can too. They always need food, but those aren’t the only services they offer for the less fortunate. They offer programs for many of the other basic necessities of life, including: Groceries, Lunches, assistance with utility bills, transportation services, limited medical assistance, shower facilities, and laundry facilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here at the Brad Korb Real Estate Group we are so thankful for the support from our friends and family. We invite you to join us in giving thanks and give back this year. For more information about the Burbank Temporary Aid Center and how to donate today, check out their website here. If you have any other questions, please feel free to give us a call or send us an email. Thanks, and have a happy Thanksgiving!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 15:52:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>lasells.com/join-us-and-give-back-this-thanksgiving-and-holiday-season.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">lasells.com/join-us-and-give-back-this-thanksgiving-and-holiday-season.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Accurate Are Zillow’s Zestimates?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/r0cczgna0cg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How accurate are Zestimates? Most of the time, not very. They’re basically a computer program designed to give you a ballpark figure of what the property is worth in today’s market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How does Zillow determine my home’s value? It gives you a broad range of what’s been sold in the neighborhood, but it doesn’t go into specifics about your exact home. It doesn’t know about what kind of features you’ve got; maybe the kitchen you’ve upgraded, or that big back yard behind the deck, or the fantastic view over the neighborhood. Since Zillow’s Zestimate is a computerized program, it doesn’t know about these things, and that can result in quite a bit of fluctuation between what the real value is and what Zillow says it is. Zillow also can’t measure how market trends function, meaning it can give you a wide estimation of what’s selling in the area, but not in specific niche markets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How off is Zillow on pricing? If you check their website, you’ll see that they themselves say their Zestimates can be off by as much as 8% to 10%. When you’re talking about the California market, that can result in an extreme difference between Zillow’s price and the real price. The founder of Zillow himself recently sold his home for far less than it should have been because the Zestimate was 10% off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What goes into pricing your home and why is it important to be accurate? To sell your home for top dollar in today’s market and get the most we can for you, it’s important to examine market trends to know how to compete against the other homes out there. How do we do this? We come to your home and check things like what kind of landscaping you’ve done and what updates you’ve made. From there we make sure these kinds of things are showcased to maximize value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click on the link above if you would like a free market analysis. If you have any questions about Zillow or anything regarding real estate, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2016 14:21:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>lasells.com/how-accurate-are-zillows-zestimates.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">lasells.com/how-accurate-are-zillows-zestimates.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How We Helped Chris with Real Estate Investments</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/euPXPkh8Q14?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have worked with so many wonderful clients over the years, including Chris Cannon. Today, I wanted to share Chris’s story with you all:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We first met Brad in 2002, when he helped us buy a duplex. That’s the property we now live in, after it paid its own mortgage. We also inherited a triplex in Glendale. We sold our portion and, after five years, Brad moved us into an eight-unit complex, which also pays for itself.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We’ve been very happy with Brad and his team. They seem to work very diligently. They also hooked us up with a management company, so we have no worries. They take care of the late night calls, advertising, and any repairs that might be needed.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about real estate or are interested in working with us, please give us a call or send us an email. My team and I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 12:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>lasells.com/how-we-helped-chris-with-real-estate-investments.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">lasells.com/how-we-helped-chris-with-real-estate-investments.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What’s the Best Way to Renovate Your LA Home Before Listing?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/waOhgUNepjI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, I’ve had a couple of clients working on their property and doing things that I didn’t think were important in order to get top dollar in the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This got me thinking about how I could help others. Before you go and spend any time and money working on things around the house to get it fixed up and ready for sale, talk to an experienced real estate professional who knows about the buyers in your market. They can help you determine the best ways to spend your time and money when updating your home for sale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clients often invest money in their house before listing, which is nice for them, but they’re the seller - not the buyer. Whatever they invest in might not be what buyers are looking for in today’s market. This is why we want our sellers to be laser-focused on the best way to spend the least amount of money to get the top dollar in today’s market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have more questions how to spend money wisely when improving your home, give me a call or send me an email. I’d be happy to give you advice about preparing your home for the market.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2016 16:16:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>lasells.com/whats-the-best-way-to-renovate-your-la-home-before-listing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">lasells.com/whats-the-best-way-to-renovate-your-la-home-before-listing.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Handle Multiple Offers in LA</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/FdHi0yakLNo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our current market, many properties are getting multiple offers. So how do you handle multiple offers as a buyer or seller?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a seller, it is very important to get multiple offers in order to drive up the price. With our pricing strategies, we can get you a great offer and promote it to other agents so they have the opportunity to bring other bids in. Drawing multiple offers is a great way to get top dollar for your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a buyer, consider writing a personal letter to the seller. Warm, fuzzy letters about your family, kids, pets, and how you connected with the house or neighborhood can really appeal to sellers. It also helps if you introduce yourself to the seller and talk about how much you love the house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, one of my buyer’s agents created a fantastic letter that really won the seller’s heart. The property had 10 offers on it, but we were able to help them get their dream home!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about how to navigate a multiple offer situation, just give us a call or send us an email. My team and I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 16:34:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>lasells.com/how-to-handle-multiple-offers-in-la.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">lasells.com/how-to-handle-multiple-offers-in-la.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Is LA Real Estate Faring in 2016?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/CqAsOFoSTts?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of people have been asking me about the real estate market in Los Angeles, and so today I’ll update you with statistics that will tell us more about the health and wealth of this market. We’re currently in a seller’s market in almost all price ranges. Inventory is very low, so multiple offers are common and sale prices remain high.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Home values in LA are still rising, and appreciation is still on the rise. We aren’t seeing home values rise as sharply as they used to, but it’s still a great time to sell a home and cash in on that appreciation. The average days on market is currently fewer than 30 days, so the market is moving very quickly right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where are we seeing the hottest real estate markets? I would recommend looking at homes in Glendale, Burbank, the NoHo District, Toluca Lake, Lake Balboa, all of the areas in the Valley, and East LA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any further questions, please don’t hesitate to contact me. I would love to share some more information with you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 16:09:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>lasells.com/how-is-la-real-estate-faring-in-2016.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">lasells.com/how-is-la-real-estate-faring-in-2016.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Spend Wisely on Upgrades When Listing in LA</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8KEdQxY6IuU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re considering selling your home, when is the right time to call your Realtor to get your home ready to go on the market?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I had some clients spending time and money on things that I actually thought weren’t important to get top dollar in their market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you spend that time and money, just give me a call! I’ll come out and give you a free market overview and point out some things that as a Realtor, I think are important to fix up in order to sell for top dollar. Too many times sellers invest in upgrades that are nice in their eyes, rather than thinking about what will appeal to buyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want sellers laser-focused on the best ways to spend the least amount of money to get top dollar in today’s market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reach out to me and let’s do a walkthrough. I look forward to seeing you soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 16:16:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>lasells.com/how-to-spend-wisely-on-upgrades-when-listing-in-la.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">lasells.com/how-to-spend-wisely-on-upgrades-when-listing-in-la.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
