<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from  - your professional Strong Tower Associates Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://ashtoumayants.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://ashtoumayants.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 16:25:20 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 16:25:20 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>A New Tool to Better Your Investing</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/WrBJaw0i1K8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I want to talk to you about a new tool we have to help our friends and clients. It’s called &lt;strong&gt;Riskalyze&lt;/strong&gt; and it’s the leading tool to help you find out what your risk number is when investing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The old-fashioned way to find out your risk number was to use a long, drawn-out questionnaire. Riskalyze actually modernized that questionnaire to help you more easily figure out how much you’re willing to risk and how much gain you’re willing to expose your assets to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It not only helps you find out what you’re comfortable with in terms of investing, but also if your investments are ultimately matching up with your end goals.&lt;/strong&gt; Some people have portfolios that are way too risky for their comfort levels, and some people have portfolios that are way too conservative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Knowing your risk number is the first step&lt;/strong&gt;, and the second step is finding out if your investments mesh well with that number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our goal is to help investors better their finances by helping them understand their choices and explaining how taxes, insurance, and financial planning can play a big role in their portfolios.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, please feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to helping you in any way we can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Riskalyze is the modern, efficient way to figure out what your risk number is.%20http://ashtoumayants.com/a-new-tool-to-better-your-investing.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Riskalyze is the modern, efficient way to figure out what your risk number is.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://ashtoumayants.com/a-new-tool-to-better-your-investing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ashtoumayants.com/a-new-tool-to-better-your-investing.html</guid>
        
        <category>401K Advisors</category>
        
        <category>Financial Planning</category>
        
        <category>Retirement Planning</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
