<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Southern California Real Estate Video Blog with Barbara Radke</title>
    <description>Our mission at Radke Agency &amp; Associates is to be your best resource for Southern California real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Radke Agency &amp; Associates, your professional Southern California Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://blog.radkeagency.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.radkeagency.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 16:41:50 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 16:41:50 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Should You Know About Title Insurance?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/auf6ARnZEQg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Today, Malay Wadhwa is here to talk about title insurance.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I have a special guest with me, Malay Wadhwa from Pacific Coast Title, to give us some insight about the role of title insurance in the real estate process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the role of title insurance?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Title insurance is very insignificant, but at the same time, a very significant part of our transaction. We make sure that the homeowner that is coming onto the property is free of any unforeseen challenges and that they have a free and clear title.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are the most important things that a client should be looking for when they’re reviewing their title policy?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They should definitely be looking at the legal listings, the liens, and the statement of information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two types of liens that are commonly attached: unsecured liens and secured liens. Secured liens are attached with to property and are available through the public records. Examples include child support liens, mechanic liens, or deeds of trust. Unsecured liens can be any liens that are attached to the individual that owns the house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Sometimes it’s best to put the property in a living trust.%20http://blog.radkeagency.com/what-should-you-know-about-title-insurance.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Sometimes it’s best to put the property in a living trust.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When clients are buying a home, how should they hold their vesting?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If, for example, a husband and wife are buying a property, they can buy it as a joint community property with the right of survivorship. Two individuals can also buy a property together, each with 50% interest on it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason that we specify the interest is so that, if need be, one can assign their interest to their spouse and children. It is important to do this because if, say, they just acquired a property without specifying the interest, then they have to go to the court to analyze who owns what percentage of the property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, sometimes it’s best to put the property in a living trust. A living trust allows the homeowner to assign a beneficiary without going into the court. It adds an extra layer of protection for their property from any online frauds that people sometimes try to commit on free and clear properties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any additional questions, please feel free to reach out to me. I’d be glad to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 09:23:19 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.radkeagency.com/what-should-you-know-about-title-insurance.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.radkeagency.com/what-should-you-know-about-title-insurance.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thank You for Your Support in 2017</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_d99-OuRa_g?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;I want to thank you all for your support in 2017! You helped us exceed our goals and win four awards.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to give a big shoutout and thank you to all of our past clients, family, and friends who helped us exceed our goals in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were the recipients this week of four special awards based on closings and productions, and &lt;strong&gt;we couldn’t have done it without you!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We couldn’t have done it without you!%20http://blog.radkeagency.com/thank-you-for-your-support-in-2017.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We couldn’t have done it without you!”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keller Williams World Class has over 350 associates in our market center here in Westlake Village, and we are honored to have received the following awards for 2017:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;First Place Team Associate by Closed Volume—Heather Case&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;First Place Team by Closed Volume&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;First Place Listing Team by Units Closed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Third Place Team by Units Closed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would like to thank everyone for helping us get there. As always, feel free to reach out if you have any real estate questions. We look forward to helping you all in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 07:57:45 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.radkeagency.com/thank-you-for-your-support-in-2017.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.radkeagency.com/thank-you-for-your-support-in-2017.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Can You Help Manna Food Bank Make a Difference?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jKYyOqTTUkY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Manna Food Bank is a great addition to our community. Let’s take a look inside at what they do.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Want to sell your home?&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.propertyhomevalue.com/&quot;&gt;Get a FREE home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Want to buy a home?&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.radkeagency.com/homes-for-sale&quot;&gt;Search all homes for sale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, we’re going to be talking about the Manna Food Bank, which is a 45-year-old independent organization that helps feed people in need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The week before Thanksgiving, we worked with them on a food drive. &lt;strong&gt;The drive was a success, and we are so thankful for the work Manna is doing for our community.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, they’re actually in the process of moving to a new facility, which will be 4.5 times larger than the current facility. There, they’ll host classes in nutrition, cooking, and more. These classes will focus on helping people with health problems learn more about their nutritional needs and how to meet them. Additionally, &lt;strong&gt;Manna will provide education on financial literacy and household management.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The more food Manna gets from the community, the more they are able to give.%20http://blog.radkeagency.com/can-you-help-manna-food-bank-make-a-difference.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The more food Manna gets from the community, the more they are able to give.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When people hear about hunger, they often think of a fairly narrow demographic. But the people who benefit from Manna’s services actually come from all walks of life. This is especially true following the recession years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, over 85% of Manna’s clients are employed families. The remaining 15% is made up of senior citizens and disabled people on fixed incomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, community support plays a massive role in what Manna does. The more food they get from the community, the more they are able to give. &lt;strong&gt;While all donations are welcome, they do have a list of preferred items on the front page of their website: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mannafoodbank.org&quot;&gt;mannafoodbank.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Manna is classified as a choice-based pantry, meaning their clients can choose their food as opposed to being limited to pre-bagged selections. Clients can visit three times a week with no appointment necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.radkeagency.com/can-you-help-manna-food-bank-make-a-difference.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.radkeagency.com/can-you-help-manna-food-bank-make-a-difference.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What’s With the Low Inventory We’ve Been Seeing?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Nq7aOYyCop0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to a recent study, 47% of sellers are worried about selling their homes for fear of not being able to find a new one that meets their needs. The trick is to find creative ways to find sellers the homes they need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to sell your home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.propertyhomevalue.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get a FREE home value report&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to buy a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.radkeagency.com/homes-for-sale&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Search all homes for sale&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today’s topic of discussion will be the question, “Why are there so few homes for sale here in the Conejo Valley?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First American did a study to find out why we have such a low amount of inventory. They found that the No. 1 reason had to do with the sellers. &lt;strong&gt;47% of sellers are very uncomfortable about the inventory level,&lt;/strong&gt; and they don’t want to put their home on the market until they find the home of their choice. They’re ready to move, they’re just holding back. This has an effect on the inventory level all across the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We’re seeing now that we have to become creative in how we get sellers to put their homes on the market.&lt;/strong&gt; We did just that with two clients of ours, David and Tessa. They, too, wanted to move, but had not found a home that had met their needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We knew where they wanted to live, so we worked with the title company, and we had them put together a report that showed homes that were on the view-side of the street, had a pool, and had a certain number of bedrooms and bathrooms. &lt;strong&gt;We sent out a targeted letter to the specific homes that met this criteria,&lt;/strong&gt; and lo and behold, we heard back from one family who agreed to meet with us. We took our buyers there, and we’re proud to say they’re now in escrow and will be closing in three weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you know of anyone who has that same concern and are struggling to find the home that they’re looking for, give us a call. We can sit down and put together a game plan of how we can go find that house for them, even if it’s not on the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a topic you’d like us to discuss on our blog, feel free to reach out to us directly. We look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.radkeagency.com/whats-with-the-low-inventory-weve-been-seeing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.radkeagency.com/whats-with-the-low-inventory-weve-been-seeing.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Your Neighbors Can Help You Sell Your Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/kA0xQGBPnJk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to sell your home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.propertyhomevalue.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get a FREE home value report&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to buy a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.radkeagency.com/homes-for-sale&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Search all homes for sale&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking of selling your home, you need to immediately start preparing your neighbors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what I mean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home appraisals are 5% to 10% lower if you have a so-called “bad” neighbor,&lt;/strong&gt; with an unkempt yard or poorly maintained exterior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That shouldn’t be surprising when you consider that 63% of homebuyers drive by a home before coming for a showing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make no mistake — those potential buyers won’t just be impacted by the exterior of your home, but by the state of your neighborhood as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, &lt;strong&gt;neighbors can also be your best friend in selling your home.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They can provide you with free advertising, they can promote the neighborhood to inquiring buyers, and they might even actively work with you to help you achieve a higher price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are three tips on working with your neighbors to achieve a faster, more profitable sale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First, set up a special open house just for your neighbors.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many neighbors will be curious for a peek inside your home. You can make the deal even more enticing by providing some free snacks and drinks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use this open house as an opportunity to show off your home, as well as to build better relations with your neighbors so they’ll be more disposed to help you during the sale process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One way to do this is to &lt;strong&gt;be forthcoming with information,&lt;/strong&gt; including the price you’re aiming for, renovations you’re planning, or showings that might eat up local parking for an afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get your neighbors involved, ask them for suggestions, and ask them how you can make the process easier for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, don’t forget to mention that if you are successful in selling your home, this will positively impact the values of all homes in the neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Second, organize a neighborhood cleanup party.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an opportunity to boost the image and value of your entire neighborhood, as well as to further cement good relations with your neighbors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also use this as a discreet way to suggest small home improvement projects to your neighbors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which leads me to the third and final tip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also &lt;strong&gt;offer to help with — or even pay for — any upgrades you’d like to see&lt;/strong&gt; on your neighbors’ homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if you’re having a landscaping crew come as part of your sale preparations, ask your neighbors with the overgrown lawn if they’d be ok with the landscapers also taking care of their yard for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These kinds of &lt;strong&gt;small investments can be worth thousands of dollars in terms of your final sale price.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to get an estimate of what your home is currently worth without any of these upgrades, check out this home value calculator on my site:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.propertyhomevalue.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enter your street address here to find out what your home is worth&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you need more advice on dealing with your neighbors in preparation for a home sale, just give me a call at &lt;a href=&quot;tel:800-405-1433&quot;&gt;800-405-1433&lt;/a&gt;. I’ve got several other tips I can share with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.radkeagency.com/how-your-neighbors-can-help-you-sell-your-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.radkeagency.com/how-your-neighbors-can-help-you-sell-your-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thank You for Making Us the Team We Are</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/741WNKclgNQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our team just won a very important award, and I have some people to thank for it. It all starts with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to sell your home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.propertyhomevalue.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get a FREE home value report&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to buy a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.radkeagency.com/homes-for-sale&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Search all homes for sale&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I just want to let you know how grateful I am for our team receiving the number one listing award for 2016. Our team in 2016 also received the following awards:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1st Place Listing Team&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2nd Place Selling Team&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2nd Place Total Volume Team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With close to 400 agents in our office we feel honored and grateful to have received these awards. Of course, none of this would be possible without the support of our amazing team and clients! It really means a lot to us and we couldn’t have done it without you. &lt;strong&gt;Thank you from the bottom of my heart&lt;/strong&gt;—not only to my team but also to you for your support. We look forward to working with your friends and family in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or are thinking of buying or selling a home, please don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 06:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.radkeagency.com/thank-you-for-making-us-the-team-we-are.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.radkeagency.com/thank-you-for-making-us-the-team-we-are.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We Can Help Find Trusted Contractors</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/lvSJBU3ICRg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to hire a contractor, how can you find one you can trust? Let us help you with that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to sell your home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.propertyhomevalue.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get a FREE home value report&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to buy a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.radkeagency.com/homes-for-sale&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Search all homes for sale&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking to hire a contractor, how can you find one that you trust?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to tell my clients that in order to really trust a contractor, you need to know that they’ve been in business for an extended period of time. You also want to be sure that they are licensed, insured, and bonded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I have a list of trusted contractors and vendors that I’ve amassed during my experience in real estate.&lt;/strong&gt; If you need a contractor of any kind, I can definitely help you. Our network includes electricians, plumbers, roofers, general contractors, handymen, and many more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you need a contractor of any kind, I can definitely help you.%20http://blog.radkeagency.com/we-can-help-find-trusted-contractors.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you need a contractor of any kind, I can definitely help you.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just give us a call or send an email and we’d be happy to send you our network of preferred contractors and vendors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or you know a great contractor that should be added to our list, call me! I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2017 09:19:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.radkeagency.com/we-can-help-find-trusted-contractors.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.radkeagency.com/we-can-help-find-trusted-contractors.html</guid>
        
        <category>Radke Agency and Associates</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A New Resource for You</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/L3-IngqS2Ho?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like to welcome you to my new YouTube Channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my channel, you’ll find tips for both buyers and sellers in the real estate market, as well as updates on what’s happening in our local market. The real estate market affects all of us!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I really want this page to be a valuable resource for you.&lt;/strong&gt; If you have any questions about our market or about real estate in general, send me an email. Odds are good that if you have a question about a topic, someone else does as well, so send your questions my way and we’ll make an educational video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a look around the channel and subscribe. I look forward to hearing from you soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 06:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.radkeagency.com/a-new-resource-for-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.radkeagency.com/a-new-resource-for-you.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
