<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hoboken Real Estate Podcast with Brian Riolo</title>
    <link>localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Riolo Residential Group - your professional Hoboken Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Brian Riolo</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2017-07-25 17:15:11 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Brian Riolo</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Hoboken, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Brian@RioloResidentialGroup.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Brian Riolo</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Brian Riolo</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Hoboken, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Hoboken Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Riolo Residential Group - your professional Hoboken Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>What’s Happening in the Hoboken Real Estate Market?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/whats-happening-in-the-hoboken-real-estate-market.html</link>
        
        <author>Brian Riolo</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-24 10:33:26 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brian+Riolo+/Riolo+July+1+What%E2%80%99s+Happening+in+the+Hoboken+Real+Estate+Market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Lately, a lot of people are asking, “Are we approaching another real estate bubble?”

Here in Hoboken, the market trends are not pointing to another bubble. Right now, there is enough equity built into homes that we should be able to sustain any interruption in the market or any decrease in pricing.

Historically, real estate trends on a seven-year scale. Since we are reaching the latter end of the scale, it makes sense that we’re starting to see a bit of a slowdown in the market, as well as an increase in the absorption rate this year as opposed to last year.

In the higher end of the market, specifically above the $1.25 million price point, properties are staying on the market longer and the list to sales price ratio has gone down over the last year and a half. We are starting to see a similar trend in the higher hundred-thousand dollar price range, too.

“In the higher end of the market, we are seeing a bit of a slowdown.”

Interest rates will also play a major part in our market for the next six months to a year. The Fed is expected to raise rates again in the third quarter. However, positive job numbers should ease off some of the bond buying in our market.

There has been a slight uptick in inventory. Due to a huge build up in rental properties along River Road and in downtown Jersey City, investors and landlords have seen a negative impact on their bottom line, as some of these investors have had to lower their rental prices.

That said, every situation is different. If you have any questions about buying, selling, or investing in our market, just give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brian+Riolo+/Riolo+July+1+What%E2%80%99s+Happening+in+the+Hoboken+Real+Estate+Market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brian+Riolo+/Riolo+July+1+What%E2%80%99s+Happening+in+the+Hoboken+Real+Estate+Market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>How is the Hoboken real estate market doing? Although there is concern about another real estate bubble, it doesn’t look like there’s anything to worry about.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brian Riolo</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>How is the Hoboken real estate market doing? Although there is concern about another real estate bubble, it doesn’t look like there’s anything to worry about.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Hoboken, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Brian Riolo</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Brian Riolo</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Riolo Residential Group - your professional Hoboken Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
