<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title> Real Estate Podcast with Patrick Fitzgerald</title>
    <link>localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The VA Loan Guy - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Patrick Fitzgerald</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2017-09-05 13:20:09 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Patrick Fitzgerald</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>PFitzgerald@GuildMortgage.net</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the  Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The VA Loan Guy - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>Can You Build With the VA Loan?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/can-you-build-with-va-loan.html</link>
        
          <category>VA Loans</category>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-24 13:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/Videos/2017/August/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Can+You+Build+With+the+VA+Loan%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Can you use a VA loan to build on land you own? Of course you can.

It doesn’t cost a penny to talk….so call me right now and I will answer your questions!

Apply Now

If you’ve got land, can you use your VA loan to build on it?

The answer is: of course you can.

Now that you know this is a possibility, there are a few things you need to consider before you can make it happen. The first step is to have your home designed.

After you’ve met with an architect to do this, you’ll need to generate the blueprints and specifications.

The next step is to determine what costs will be associated with this process. That cost includes the price of building the home itself, site preparation, and other factors as well.

All of this information that you’ve gathered until this point will then need to be presented to an appraiser. Requesting a VA construction appraisal is different from the normal appraisal process because in this case, the appraiser has no house to look at.

“THE FUNDS FROM THIS 30-YEAR VA LOAN WILL PAY OFF THE CONSTRUCTION LOAN.”

Instead, the appraiser will visit and photograph the site, look at the plans for your home, and find comparable properties in the area.

Within a couple of weeks, the appraiser will determine an approximation of the home’s value upon completion. Having this value from the start is a great way to prevent any unsavory surprises down the road.

After this, you’re finally ready to get a construction loan. If you happen to owe money on the land, the first draw of the construction loan will pay that cost off, as well.

At various points throughout the process, the builder will take draws—with the final draw coming once the house is completed. It is at this point, during the final phase of construction, that your VA loan will be put together.

The funds from this 30-year VA loan will pay off the construction loan. It’s really that simple.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, remember that it costs nothing to talk. Feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/Videos/2017/August/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Can+You+Build+With+the+VA+Loan%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/Videos/2017/August/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Can+You+Build+With+the+VA+Loan%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Can you use a VA loan to build on land you own? Of course you can.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Can you use a VA loan to build on land you own? Of course you can.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Are VA Appraisals Any Different from Conventional Ones? </title>
        <link>localhost:4000/are-va-appraisals-any-different-from.html</link>
        
          <category>VA Loans</category>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-11 15:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today I wanted to talk about VA appraisals and how they differ from conventional appraisals.

It doesn’t cost a penny to talk….so call me right now and I will answer your questions!

Apply Now

I get a lot of calls about this with lots of questions about the VA appraisal and how it’s different from conventional appraisals. An appraisal is an estimated value of a property done by a licensed appraiser. One thing to remember is that VA appraisals are not that much different from a conventional appraisal.

The appraiser will first visit the property and measure the square footage of the home, take photos of all sides of the home’s exterior, and then photograph of each room inside the home. The appraiser will then take note of any amenities in the home that might affect the value—such as updated kitchens or bathrooms.

If the home has any damage, then it will be noted as a repair on the appraisal. They will take note of any damage to the interior or exterior that can decrease the value of the home—like rotting wood and cracked or peeling paint. If there are any serious matters that need to be addressed, the appraiser will put it in the report given to you and your Realtor.

You need to write up any needed repairs the appraiser sees. This is a VA requirement. The VA doesn’t necessarily need a brand new home, but they want to make sure that the home is in sound condition and that the veteran is not buying a problematic home.

“THE VA DOESN’T NECESSARILY NEED A BRAND NEW HOME, BUT THEY WANT TO MAKE SURE THAT THE HOME IS IN SOUND CONDITION FOR THE VETERAN.”

Once the appraiser finishes the inspection, they will then take pictures of other comparable homes in the neighborhood and with that information, head back to the office to calculate the value of the home. Once the value is determined, it is forwarded to the mortgage company and we have a dollar value for the house that we can work with.

If there are any repairs that were noted on the appraisal, both Realtors are notified that those repairs need to be made in order to close on a VA loan.

If there’s a problem with the value, under the VA loan process we have an opportunity to appeal the value and bring additional comparables to the attention of the appraiser in order to get the value changed.

If you have any additional questions about VA appraisals or any other VA loan-related topic, please give me a call. I’d be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today I wanted to talk about VA appraisals and how they differ from conventional appraisals.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today I wanted to talk about VA appraisals and how they differ from conventional appraisals.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Taxes and Insurance Figure into VA Loans</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-taxes-and-insurance-figure-into-va.html</link>
        
          <category>VA Loans</category>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-28 10:37:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/Videos/2017/July/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Taxes%252C+VA+loans%252C+Insurance+July+1.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I wanted to talk a bit more in-depth about how property taxes and homeowners insurance figure into the VA loan process.

It doesn’t cost a penny to talk….so call me right now and I will answer your questions!

Apply Now

Today I wanted to talk about taxes and insurance and how they figure into a VA loan. I get this question from both veterans and real estate agents alike.

In most areas, real estate taxes are comprised of state, local, city, and school taxes. They are all figured in by the local appraisal district, who then sets the value of the home. Then those taxes are set based on a percentage

The monthly house payments figures into an escrow account that not only includes principal and interest, but also 1/12th of the property taxes that will be due at the end of the year as well as 1/12th of the insurance. In the state of Texas, veterans who are 100% disabled pay absolutely no property taxes whatsoever. The doesn’t happen automatically, however. They have to fill out the appropriate form and send a copy of that to the lender that is holding the loan in order to stop collection of the taxes.

Now I wanted to talk a little bit about homeowners insurance. Homeowners insurance has nothing to do with life insurance or private mortgage insurance. Homeowners insurance covers fire, liability, weather-related issues, but does not cover the home from a flood. Rising water is not covered by regular homeowner’s insurance.

“RISING WATER IS NOT COVERED BY REGULAR HOMEOWNERS INSURANCE.”

Recently I’ve been asked why insurance rates are all over the board, so I did a little digging and contacted three separate insurance agents that I do business with to get an answer. The general consensus is that homeowner’s insurance is based on the size and age of the property. The older a home is, the more claims there can be on it, which will affect your rates.

Insurance rates are also affected by claim history on the home if it’s pre-owned, and the insurance claim history of the buyer themself. Insurance companies also factor in your credit score to determine rates. Generally, there are more claims on insurance policies owned by individuals with lower credit scores. Additionally, the location of the home can affect rates as well.

Something interesting to note is that insurance agents won’t insure individuals who own dogs that are pit bulls or dobermans or similar dog breeds. This is because they have seen a spike in claims related to dog bites, and don’t want to undertake that liability.

I would advise you to bundle your insurance if you can. If you combine your homeowners insurance with your car insurance, you could get up to a 20% reduction in the overall rate.

Like I always say, it doesn’t cost a penny to talk, so if you have any questions at all, give me a call. I’d be happy to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/Videos/2017/July/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Taxes%252C+VA+loans%252C+Insurance+July+1.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/Videos/2017/July/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Taxes%252C+VA+loans%252C+Insurance+July+1.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today I wanted to talk a bit more in-depth about how property taxes and homeowners insurance figure into the VA loan process.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today I wanted to talk a bit more in-depth about how property taxes and homeowners insurance figure into the VA loan process.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Manufactured Homes Made Simple</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/manufactured-homes-made-simple.html</link>
        
          <category>VA Loans</category>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-03 13:49:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/Videos/2017/July/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Manufactured+Homes+Made+Simple.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There are a few key rules you should know about in order to get a VA loan under a manufactured home.

It doesn’t cost a penny to talk….so call me right now and I will answer your questions!

Apply Now

If you’re considering using a VA Loan on a manufactured home, I have some information that you’ll need to know.

To begin, you should know that you are, in fact, allowed to have a VA loan under a manufactured home. However, this can be difficult in certain cases. Though VA loans are technically allowed on both double-wide as well as single-wide homes, you will experience a great deal of difficulty in finding a lender who will do a VA loan for you on a single-wide home.

Along with this, there are some other rules. For example, a manufactured home needs to be compliant with any foundation requirements—the home must have a foundation that is attached to the ground, called a HUD-style foundation. Luckily, an engineer can inspect and retrofit this style of foundation on homes that don’t already have one.

Additionally, any wheels or axles must be removed from the home. This is because, from a title standpoint, the home must be considered permanently one with the land.

Speaking of mobility, in order to get a VA loan under a manufactured home, the home must have been moved one or fewer times since its original installment.

“THE VA WANTS BUYERS TO BE SAFE AND HEALTHY WITHIN THEIR HOMES.”

To ensure that these requisites have been met, the home must go through a number of inspections, including a septic inspection, termite inspection, and, if there is one present on the property, a well inspection and water quality test.

While they are negotiable between the buyer and seller, the seller is no longer required to provide funds for these inspections so the impetus falls largely on the buyer to ensure that these inspections are carried out and paid for.

A final rule to keep in mind is that the home must be a 1976 or newer model.

This may seem like a lot, but all of the inspections and regulations required are for the benefit of the veteran—as the VA wants buyers to be safe and healthy within their homes.

Also, while many may say that acreages are not allowed under a VA loan with a manufactured home, this is not the case.

If you want more information on VA loans and manufactured homes, or if I can answer any other questions for you, feel free to get in touch by giving me a call or sending me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/Videos/2017/July/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Manufactured+Homes+Made+Simple.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/Videos/2017/July/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Manufactured+Homes+Made+Simple.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

There are a few key rules you should know about in order to get a VA loan under a manufactured home.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

There are a few key rules you should know about in order to get a VA loan under a manufactured home.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Is the Anatomy of a VA Loan?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/what-is-anatomy-of-va-loan.html</link>
        
          <category>VA Loans</category>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-12 11:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+How+veterans+financing+works.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’re thinking of applying for a VA loan, here’s what you should know about them.

It doesn’t cost a penny to talk….so call me right now and I will answer your questions!

Apply Now

The anatomy of a VA loan features four components: principal, interest, property taxes, and homeowners insurance.

In January 2017, the U.S. Department of Veteran Affairs increased the loan amount on a VA loan to $424,100. That’s called the “conforming limit,”  and it means in most states around the country, a veteran can borrow up to $424,100 with no down payment. In other areas of the country where housing is dramatically more expensive (Alaska, Hawaii, California, New York, etc.), the conforming limit is much higher than that.

VA loans don’t require any PMI (private mortgage insurance), but property taxes and insurance must be included with it. The Department of Veteran Affairs has compensated for the rise in home prices by offering jumbo loans or high-balance loans that go above the $424,100 limit. However, that’s also where the no down payment portion ends.

“A VA LOAN ALLOWS YOU TO BORROW UP TO $424,000 WITH NO DOWN PAYMENT.”

If the purchase price of the home is above $424,100, you would have to pay 25% of the overage. For example, if a home is priced at $524,000—which is $100,000 over the limit—that means you’d pay $25,000. There is no limit as to how high you can purchase as you pay 25% of the overage

If you have any questions about the anatomy of a VA loan, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. As I always say, it doesn’t cost a penny to talk. Just give me a call and I’d be happy to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+How+veterans+financing+works.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+How+veterans+financing+works.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you’re thinking of applying for a VA loan, here’s what you should know about them.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you’re thinking of applying for a VA loan, here’s what you should know about them.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Types of Property You Can Buy With VA Financing</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/types-of-property-you-can-buy-with-va.html</link>
        
          <category>Military Loans</category>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-22 11:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+The+kinds+of+properties+you+can+purchase.mp4</guid>
        <description>

VA loans allow you to buy a wide variety of properties.

It doesn’t cost a penny to talk….so call me right now and I will answer your questions!

Apply Now

If you plan to use a VA loan, you might be wondering what types of properties you can use your VA loan for.

The most popular use is for a single-family residence, but you can also use a VA loan on a multi-family property like a duplex or triplex, but you can’t go higher than four units in one building. To use it on a multi-family home, the cardinal rule is that the veteran must occupy one of the units as their primary residence. You can also use a VA loan for a condo if it’s on the list of VA-approved condo associations, which I can send you.

You can use a VA loan for a townhouse, and it doesn’t have to be on any list. You can also use it on manufactured homes that are 1976 or newer. It’s allowed for single-wide or double-wide manufactured homes, but it’s almost impossible to find a lender who will offer a loan on a single-wide. Manufactured homes must also be properly attached to the ground with a HUD-style foundation—it can’t just be tied down sitting on concrete blocks.

“YOU CAN BUY MULTI-FAMILY PROPERTIES UP TO FOUR UNITS WITH A VA LOAN.”

You can also use VA loans for modular homes, which are growing in popularity.

I get a lot of questions about using VA loans on acreages as well. Many lenders will tell you that you can’t use it on a property with 20 or 30 acres, but that’s simply not true. VA loans do not have a limit on acreage; it just has to make sense. More importantly, they want to know the use of the land because they don’t want to finance a home if the veteran is going to use it for a for-profit use.

Finally, you can, in fact, use a VA loan for a home with an agricultural tax exemption. You can’t use it to buy raw land, however.

If you have any other questions about the types of property you can buy with a VA loan, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. Like I always say, it doesn’t cost a penny to talk.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+The+kinds+of+properties+you+can+purchase.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+The+kinds+of+properties+you+can+purchase.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

VA loans allow you to buy a wide variety of properties.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

VA loans allow you to buy a wide variety of properties.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Can You Still Get a VA Loan Post-Bankruptcy?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/can-you-still-get-va-loan-post.html</link>
        
          <category>VA Loans</category>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-05 15:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Veterans+financing+post-bankruptcy.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you had a bankruptcy in the past and it involved a home that you used a VA loan to purchase, you haven’t lost your eligibility. Here’s the situation you’ll face instead.

It doesn’t cost a penny to talk….so call me right now and I will answer your questions!

Apply Now

If you’ve had a bankruptcy in the past and it involved a home you used a VA loan to finance—have you lost your eligibility?

No, you haven’t. The Department of Veterans Affairs has a heart. They’ll always note that they lost money in that situation, but they have a non-collection policy.

“YOU ARE STILL ELIGIBLE FOR A VA LOAN, BUT ONLY AFTER A CERTAIN AMOUNT OF TIME HAS PASSED.”

Instead, they will send you a new certificate of eligibility request, note how much they lost on the home, and deduct that amount from your eligibility. You still have eligibility and you can still get another VA loan just as long as at least two years have passed since the bankruptcy.

Remember, if you have any questions about this or any other subject, feel free to give me a call. I’d be happy to talk to you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Veterans+financing+post-bankruptcy.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Veterans+financing+post-bankruptcy.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you had a bankruptcy in the past and it involved a home that you used a VA loan to purchase, you haven’t lost your eligibility. Here’s the situation you’ll face instead.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you had a bankruptcy in the past and it involved a home that you used a VA loan to purchase, you haven’t lost your eligibility. Here’s the situation you’ll face instead.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Who Qualifies for VA Loans?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/who-qualifies-for-va-loans.html</link>
        
          <category>VA Loans</category>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-24 14:54:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Who+Qualifies+for+a+VA+Loan%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Who can qualify for a VA loan? Do you have to have military benefits? I’ll go over the answers to those questions today.

It doesn’t cost a penny to talk….so call me right now and I will answer your questions!

Apply Now

Who qualifies for a VA loan? I get asked this question quite often, and I’ll go over the details behind qualifying today.

It’s true that in order to qualify for a VA loan, you have to be a veteran. However, a lot of veterans have spouses that are not associated with the military. Can they both qualify if that’s the case? The answer is yes.

Fiances are another story. If you are not married, your fiance would also have to have military benefits in order for you to both qualify. If the fiance of a spouse does not have military benefits, they would not qualify for the loan.

“THE SPOUSE OF A VETERAN CAN QUALIFY FOR A VA LOAN.”

The main thing that the VA wants to achieve is making sure the people taking advantage of VA loans are actually living in the home purchased with one. Gone are the days when people could co-sign for a VA loan. Again, a spouse can certainly co-sign and qualify for a VA loan but don’t plan on having a fiance do that unless they qualify on their own.

If you have any other questions please feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Who+Qualifies+for+a+VA+Loan%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Who+Qualifies+for+a+VA+Loan%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Who can qualify for a VA loan? Do you have to have military benefits? I’ll go over the answers to those questions today.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Who can qualify for a VA loan? Do you have to have military benefits? I’ll go over the answers to those questions today.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Answering Some Common VA Loan Questions</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/answering-some-common-va-loan-questions.html</link>
        
          <category>VA Loans</category>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-06 14:49:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Can+You+Have+Two+VA+Loans+at+Once%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I get a lot of questions about VA loans and the eligibility restrictions. Can you use a second VA loan? Can you rent a home purchased with a VA loan? Find out here.

It doesn’t cost a penny to talk….so call me right now and I will answer your questions!

Apply Now

I’ve been getting a lot of questions lately from people, which is great. I wanted to answer a few of them today. One of the most common questions I get asked about VA loans goes like this: “Pat, I have used my VA loan to buy a home in the past, can I use it again?”

The simple answer is absolutely yes. All veterans and active military have the benefit of using VA eligibility to buy a home. When someone uses it the first time, all they have to do is pay off the house or sell their current home, and it will free up their eligibility.

“THE SIMPLE ANSWER IS ABSOLUTELY YES.”

The other question I often get goes like this: “I already have a home with a VA loan on it, and I have been renting that home out. Can I buy another house with a VA loan as well?”

Yes, you can have two VA loans at once, but there are some restrictions. You will have to fill out a form for us, and then we can insert those numbers and tell you how much more you can borrow on another VA loan in addition to your first.

If you have any questions about this topic or any mortgage needs, give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to helping you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Can+You+Have+Two+VA+Loans+at+Once%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Can+You+Have+Two+VA+Loans+at+Once%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

I get a lot of questions about VA loans and the eligibility restrictions. Can you use a second VA loan? Can you rent a home purchased with a VA loan? Find out here.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

I get a lot of questions about VA loans and the eligibility restrictions. Can you use a second VA loan? Can you rent a home purchased with a VA loan? Find out here.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>I Specialize in Working with Military Clients</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/i-specialize-in-working-with-military0.html</link>
        
          <category>Military Loans</category>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-16 13:31:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+My+specialty+is+military+loans.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I offer all types of mortgages, but my specialty is making sure military personnel can buy their dream homes.

It doesn’t cost a penny to talk….so call me right now and I will answer your questions!

Apply Now

I’m a loan officer here at Guild Mortgage in San Antonio and a mortgage expert. Although I do offer conventional, FHA, and all other different types of loans, my specialty is helping military personnel with their home loan needs. I’ve been doing this for the past 15 years.

One of the unique things I do is meet with my clients in person. A lot of our competition doesn’t do this anymore, but I think it’s important to be able to talk to someone in person when going through the home buying process. There are a lot of options to choose from and a lot of paperwork needed to determine what you qualify for.

“IT DOESN’T COST A THING TO TALK TO ME ON THE PHONE.”

If you have any questions for me, I would be glad to answer them. I’m here six days a week in my office and when you dial me, you will talk to me. I don’t have a receptionist or assistant answering my calls for me. I’m here for you, so don’t hesitate to give me a call. It doesn’t cost a thing to talk to me on the phone. I look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+My+specialty+is+military+loans.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+My+specialty+is+military+loans.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

I offer all types of mortgages, but my specialty is making sure military personnel can buy their dream homes.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

I offer all types of mortgages, but my specialty is making sure military personnel can buy their dream homes.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>I Specialize in Working with Military Clients</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/i-specialize-in-working-with-military.html</link>
        
          <category>Military Loans</category>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-16 13:31:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+My+specialty+is+military+loans.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I offer all types of mortgages, but my specialty is making sure military personnel can buy their dream homes.

It doesn’t cost a penny to talk….so call me right now and I will answer your questions!

Apply Now

I’m a loan officer here at Guild Mortgage in San Antonio and a mortgage expert. Although I do offer conventional, FHA, and all other different types of loans, my specialty is helping military personnel with their home loan needs. I’ve been doing this for the past 15 years.

One of the unique things I do is meet with my clients in person. A lot of our competition doesn’t do this anymore, but I think it’s important to be able to talk to someone in person when going through the home buying process. There are a lot of options to choose from and a lot of paperwork needed to determine what you qualify for.

“IT DOESN’T COST A THING TO TALK TO ME ON THE PHONE.”

If you have any questions for me, I would be glad to answer them. I’m here six days a week in my office and when you dial me, you will talk to me. I don’t have a receptionist or assistant answering my calls for me. I’m here for you, so don’t hesitate to give me a call. It doesn’t cost a thing to talk to me on the phone. I look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+My+specialty+is+military+loans.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+My+specialty+is+military+loans.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

I offer all types of mortgages, but my specialty is making sure military personnel can buy their dream homes.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

I offer all types of mortgages, but my specialty is making sure military personnel can buy their dream homes.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Patrick Fitzgerald</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Patrick Fitzgerald</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The VA Loan Guy - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
