<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Portland Real Estate Podcast with Steve Schwab</title>
    <link>localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Portland Lifestyle Team - your professional Portland Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Steve Schwab</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2017-04-13 14:36:24 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Steve Schwab</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Portland, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">News &amp; Politics</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Steve@PortlandLifestyleTeam.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Steve Schwab</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Steve Schwab</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Portland, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Portland Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Portland Lifestyle Team - your professional Portland Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="News &amp; Politics"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>Make Sure Youre Protected This Tax Season</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/make-sure-youre-protected-this-tax.html</link>
        
          <category>Tax Season</category>
        
        <author>Steve Schwab</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-30 14:21:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

It’s tax season! To make sure your refund dream doesn’t turn into a tax fraud nightmare, Peter Wease, our preferred lender from Fairway Independent Mortgage, has three tips for you.

First, file your taxes early. File your taxes before anyone has a chance to steal your information to file for you and collect your refund.

Second, get a free copy of your credit report. Go online to TransUnion, Experian, or Equifax and they will send you a free copy of your credit report. If you see anything odd going on, make sure you report it immediately.

“IF YOU SEE ANYTHING WEIRD ON YOUR CREDIT REPORT, MAKE SURE YOU REPORT IT IMMEDIATELY.”

Finally, get a security freeze put on your credit account. This way, whenever something unusual happens with your credit, the account will freeze until you can review the information and unfreeze it.

If you have any further questions for Peter about protecting yourself this tax season, you can reach him at petew@fairwaymc.com or 503-765-1173.

As always, if you have any questions for me, please feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

It’s tax season! To make sure your refund dream doesn’t turn into a tax fraud nightmare, Peter Wease, our preferred lender from Fairway Independent Mortgage, has three tips for you.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Steve Schwab</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

It’s tax season! To make sure your refund dream doesn’t turn into a tax fraud nightmare, Peter Wease, our preferred lender from Fairway Independent Mortgage, has three tips for you.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Portland, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4 Tips to Crafting the Best Possible Offer on a Home</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/4-tips-to-crafting-best-possible-offer.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Steve Schwab</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-02 16:37:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

If you’ve found the perfect home and you’re ready to make an offer, here are four tips to make your offer stand out and ensure that you get that perfect home.

First, understand what you can afford. Work with a well-known lender who’s highly qualified so they can make you look as solid as possible on paper. You also want to know from them what your big-picture financial situation looks like so you can know what loan programs are available and you can prepare for any future updates or repairs on the home.

Secondly, act fast. A balanced market is considered to have six months’ worth of inventory. In Portland, we have 1.3 months’ worth of inventory. Our market is very competitive, so once you find a home, you must move forward under the guidance of your agent as quickly as possible.

“Our market is very competitive, so you must move quickly.”

Third, make sure your offer is solid. Don’t make a lowball offer. Instead, have your agent look through a list of comparable properties in the area and what they have sold for so you can make a good offer. Another thing you could do is write a letter to the seller telling them all about you, your family, what you plan to do with the home, and any other information of that type that might ingratiate yourself to them. You could also have your agent dig further into the motivations of the seller to find out if there is some need of theirs that you can satisfy.

Finally, be prepared to negotiate. After you submit an offer, you will probably receive a counter offer, and you need to be prepared to respond. This is another instance where being pre-approved up front is crucial—you know that if you have to raise your price a little bit, you can.

If you have any questions about this topic or there’s anything else we can help you with, please don’t hesitate to give us a call or send me an email. In the meantime, make it a great day!

If you have any other questions, please feel free to call me or send me a quick email. I’m here to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you’ve found the perfect home and you’re ready to make an offer, here are four tips to make your offer stand out and ensure that you get that perfect home.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Steve Schwab</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you’ve found the perfect home and you’re ready to make an offer, here are four tips to make your offer stand out and ensure that you get that perfect home.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Portland, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Does Your Credit Score Impact Buying Power?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-does-your-credit-score-impact.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Steve Schwab</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-16 11:43:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Some people aren’t aware of how important their credit score is when it comes to purchasing a home. A credit score needs to be high enough to qualify for the loan program they are trying to get approved for.

So can you buy a home in Portland with a low credit score? The answer is yes.

From about 2000 to 2007, basically all you would need to do to get a stated income loan was tell your lender what you made without having to prove it and they wouldn’t do a credit check. Luckily, those are no longer available. People now have to be qualified for a home, and credit scores are key in getting that done.

“Your credit score plays a hugh role in if and how you qualify for loan programs.”

We want to get you started by connecting you to the right people. We work very closely with Fairway Independent Mortgage, specifically Pete Wease, and we would love to refer him to you. Pete will sit down with you and discuss the many programs available and take a look at your score. If your score is low, he will help you figure out a strategy to bring it up and in turn get you a better interest rate. To reach Pete, you can call (503-267-6391) or email him at petew@fairwaymc.com.

There are so many different loan programs that you can take advantage of as well. There are low money down programs, some grant programs with no money down, and conventional loans with still historically low interest rates.

Your credit score plays a huge role in if and how you qualify for those loan programs, and Pete and I want to make sure we can get you prepared to take action in the spring market.

If you have any other questions please feel free to call me or send me a quick email. I’m here to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Some people aren’t aware of how important their credit score is when it comes to purchasing a home. A credit score needs to be high enough to qualify for the loan program they are trying to get approved for.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Steve Schwab</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Some people aren’t aware of how important their credit score is when it comes to purchasing a home. A credit score needs to be high enough to qualify for the loan program they are trying to get approved for.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Portland, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Do You Need a Real Estate Professional?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/portland-real-estate-agent-5-reasons-to.html</link>
        
          <category>Portland Real Estate Tips</category>
        
        <author>Steve Schwab</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-31 14:49:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Whether you are looking to buy or sell a home, you don’t want to try to tackle the market alone. I’ve put together a list of five reasons why hiring a real estate professional is always better than trying to go it alone.


  
    Paperwork. There is much more paperwork that goes into buying or selling a home than there used to be. A transaction of this size requires more than a single sheet of paper. There is a lot of information contained in the paperwork that you should be aware of, and a real estate professional will help you navigate that.
  
  
    Experience. Having someone who is educated and highly experienced is key.
  
  
    Negotiations. Having someone help you negotiate who isn’t swayed by emotion will make sure you get the best deal whether you are buying or selling.
  


“Having someone who is educated and highly experienced is key.”


  
    Pricing. Pricing is an art. There are a lot of tools that can help you determine pricing. However, to make sure your home is priced correctly and in order to sell in a brief amount of time, you need to make sure a professional is pricing your home.
  
  
    Understanding of current market conditions. We shift in and out of buyer’s and seller’s markets, and hiring someone who understands those shifts will provide you with a solid foundation to either look for a home on the market or sell a home on the market.
  


If you have any questions please feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Whether you are looking to buy or sell a home, you don’t want to try to tackle the market alone. I’ve put together a list of five reasons why hiring a real estate professional is always better than trying to go it alone.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Steve Schwab</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Whether you are looking to buy or sell a home, you don’t want to try to tackle the market alone. I’ve put together a list of five reasons why hiring a real estate professional is always better than trying to go it alone.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Portland, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Things for Millennial Home Buyers to Consider</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/portland-real-estate-agent-new-segment.html</link>
        
          <category>Portland Real Estate Tips</category>
        
        <author>Steve Schwab</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-09 18:40:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>There is one specific segment of buyers that is making our market extra exciting. These buyers are part of the millennial generation (ages 18-34) and they are an integral part of our market. They will continue to be an integral part for the foreseeable future.

As you can see in the video above, the age groups with the highest percentage of people who associate homeownership with the American Dream are those in the 65+ generation and millennials. Business Insider, who did this study, also did a study that examined when these buyers plan to purchase. Over the next five years, over 60% of millennials plan to enter the market. They are going to continue fueling our market going forward.

We don’t see a slowdown coming at all. If you are looking for a larger home or to get out of your rental situation, now is a smart time to do that. We expect significant appreciation to continue for the next few years.

As for first-time home buyers, many are misinformed about how much it actually costs to buy a home. In fact, 73% of millennials are unaware of the fact that there are many down payment assistance programs available that will allow them to get into a house for just 3% to 5% down. That number can be even lower by taking advantage of certain grant programs that are available.

“More and more millennials are choosing to buy.”

Buying a home can be very cost-effective in the long term, and millennials are realizing this.

If you’re looking to buy and want to begin the process, a study by the National Association of Realtors showed that 89% of millennial real estate participants used a Realtor. As a buyer, it costs you nothing for competent, professional representation in a real estate transaction.

If you are thinking about buying or selling, give us a call or send us an email. We would love to speak to you about your specific situation and answer any questions you may have. We look forward to hearing from you soon!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There is one specific segment of buyers that is making our market extra exciting. These buyers are part of the millennial generation (ages 18-34) and they are an integral part of our market. They will continue to be an integral part for the foreseeable future.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Steve Schwab</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There is one specific segment of buyers that is making our market extra exciting. These buyers are part of the millennial generation (ages 18-34) and they are an integral part of our market. They will continue to be an integral part for the foreseeable future.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Portland, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>We Owe All Our Success to You</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/portland-real-estate-agent-thanks-for.html</link>
        
          <category>Portland Real Estate Tips</category>
        
        <author>Steve Schwab</author>
        <pubDate>2016-12-19 10:21:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

We wanted to take a moment to reflect back on 2016 and how you helped us make it great.

We really appreciate all of our new and repeat clients that helped our business this year. I also want to thank everyone who sent us referrals—I can’t even begin to tell you how important they are to us!

“Thanks for helping us make this year a great one.”

This year was an amazing one for the Portland real estate market. We saw some of the most extensive price appreciation that our country has seen in some time. In fact, we led the nation for most of the year in percentage-based appreciation. We expect 2017 to be a very similar year, even though I think the appreciation rate will slow a little bit.

If you or anyone you know is interested in buying or selling a home in the Portland area as we head into 2017, send them our way and we’ll treat them well. We appreciate you thinking of us.

Happy Holidays!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

We wanted to take a moment to reflect back on 2016 and how you helped us make it great.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Steve Schwab</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

We wanted to take a moment to reflect back on 2016 and how you helped us make it great.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Portland, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Can a Lender Help You?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/portland-real-estate-agent-how-lenders.html</link>
        
          <category>Portland Real Estate Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Steve Schwab</author>
        <pubDate>2016-12-08 10:21:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today I’m here with Pete Wease, our preferred lender, to discuss job satisfaction on the lending side of things.

One of the best parts of Pete’s job is when a client gets to the closing table and signs the dotted line. “They’re smiling ear to ear,” Pete says. “That is the biggest sign of job satisfaction for me.” He knows that his clients are feeling a sense of pride and ownership when they close on their home.

Unfortunately, there are situations where a transaction shows signs of trouble. When it looks like a deal might fall apart, Pete just takes a step back, reflects, and communicates with the client to find a solution. “Any time we close a transaction, that’s a home run,” Pete says. “The bottom line is, I am here to help you close on your loan.”

“Communication and proper preparation will get you to the closing table.”

There are times when a transaction may not be able to close. Pete says, “If I can’t help you now, I will help you in the future.” Pete believes that preparation and communication are crucial to making it to the closing table.

If you have any questions for Pete, you can give him a call at 503-267-6391 or email him at PeteW@FairwayMC.com. We have been working with Pete for four years now and it’s been a fantastic experience. We have nothing but good reviews for Pete here, so we highly recommend that you reach out to him if you are thinking of buying a home.

If you have any other real estate questions, just give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today I’m here with Pete Wease, our preferred lender, to discuss job satisfaction on the lending side of things.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Steve Schwab</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today I’m here with Pete Wease, our preferred lender, to discuss job satisfaction on the lending side of things.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Portland, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Don't Kill Your Home Deal With This Mistake</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/dont-kill-your-home-deal-with-this.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Steve Schwab</author>
        <pubDate>2016-11-07 11:27:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

There are some surprises that can seemingly come out of nowhere in a real estate transaction that can take the wind out of your sails or even completely kill a deal. To help me break these surprises down in order to help you avoid them, I’ve brought in mortgage expert Peter Wease with Fairway Independent Mortgage.

According to Peter, the number one killer is opening up new credit. Some home buyers want to buy a new car or new things for their new home like furniture, curtains, paint, etc. Even worse–many buyers open credit without telling their lender. You should avoid opening any new credit at all when buying a house. The house should be the only thing you’re focusing your finances on.

“Opening new credit is the best way to ruin your mortgage qualification.”

After you close, then you can think about those new purchases. In the early steps of the process, your lender will run a credit check, and your mortgage qualification is based on your credit at that time. If that changes midstream, your credit score or debt-to-income ratio could change, and your lender might not be able to get you approved in the end.

If you need help with a home loan or a refinance or you have any questions for him, give him a call at 503-267-6391.

If you have any questions for me or you’re thinking about buying or selling a home in Portland, give me a call or send me an email. I’d love to help you in any way I can!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

There are some surprises that can seemingly come out of nowhere in a real estate transaction that can take the wind out of your sails or even completely kill a deal. To help me break these surprises down in order to help you avoid them, I’ve brought in mortgage expert Peter Wease with Fairway Independent Mortgage.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Steve Schwab</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

There are some surprises that can seemingly come out of nowhere in a real estate transaction that can take the wind out of your sails or even completely kill a deal. To help me break these surprises down in order to help you avoid them, I’ve brought in mortgage expert Peter Wease with Fairway Independent Mortgage.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Portland, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Current Health of the Portland Market</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/the-current-health-of-portland-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Portland Real Estate Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Steve Schwab</author>
        <pubDate>2016-10-26 13:03:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

To examine the market on a monthly basis, one tool we like is the Case-Shiller S&amp;P Index that you can get online. It continues to show us appreciation across the country at a healthy 5%. The report is broken down into 10 and 20-city composites, with Portland in the 20-city composite.

Portland is leading the way in this report. The 20-city composite was actually down slightly in this last report from 5.1% to 5%, but Portland is at 12.4% appreciation. Before you overreact to that, understand that we were even higher than that at one point. We’re starting to see it trend downward, but that’s a good thing.

The report also notes that most analysts are expecting the Fed to raise interest rates this December. Even if they do, though, the impact on mortgage rates and the mortgage industry are going to be so minimal that we’ll still see these historically low rates, so there’s nothing to get too worried about.

“Portland is leading the way.”

We also get questions all the time about whether we’re in a bubble that’s going to pop soon. We’re so programmed with bubbles these days that I believe we just overreact. We know we’re not in a bubble by looking at outstanding mortgage debt and seeing that we’re about 12.6% lower than what it was at its peak in the 1st quarter of 2008, and we’re not seeing much growth there.

In the video above, you can see a table that demonstrates how healthy the indexes are compared to the peak of the market in 2006 and the trough of 2012. We’re starting to see the market shift, and we need to see the market shift. We’re not seeing up to 10 offers on almost everything, and that’s a good thing.

If you have any questions at all about where our market is going and what it means to you as a buyer, seller, or homeowner, give me a call or send me an email. I’d love to hear from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

To examine the market on a monthly basis, one tool we like is the Case-Shiller S&amp;P Index that you can get online. It continues to show us appreciation across the country at a healthy 5%. The report is broken down into 10 and 20-city composites, with Portland in the 20-city composite.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Steve Schwab</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

To examine the market on a monthly basis, one tool we like is the Case-Shiller S&amp;P Index that you can get online. It continues to show us appreciation across the country at a healthy 5%. The report is broken down into 10 and 20-city composites, with Portland in the 20-city composite.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Portland, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Are Transaction Timelines Longer in the Portland Area?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/why-are-transaction-timelines-longer-in.html</link>
        
          <category>Portland Real Estate Tips</category>
        
        <author>Steve Schwab</author>
        <pubDate>2016-10-14 14:05:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Our office recently had a transaction that was supposed to close at the end of September but got postponed by half of a month purely because the appraisal took so long to come in. Why?

Today we’ve invited Peter Wease, our preferred lender from Fairway Independent Mortgage, to talk about turn times for appraisals in the Portland area and how they’re affecting transaction timelines. According to Peter, this type of delay isn’t uncommon. His company has been tracking this type of occurrence for the past year, and they see weekly updates based on different counties.

As you can see in the video above, on September 18th, Clackamas County’s average business day turn time was almost 21 days. On October 3rd, it increased to 23 days. This is in contrast, however, to Washington County, whose average business day turn time dropped from 28 days on September 18th to 16.5 days on October 23rd.

“The appraisers need help.”

The primary factor in this kind of drastic variance from county to county is the fact that roughly 111 people are moving to Portland every single day, and there just aren’t enough appraisers to keep up. The best way to change this turn time, then, is to get more help to the appraisers.

Another consequence of this situation is that appraisal fees have soared. Appraisers are getting inundated by other appraisal management companies, so they’re demanding higher fees and being more selective in which appraisals they choose to undertake. Who pays for that increase? The customer. It’s unfortunate, but it’s the truth.

The moral of the story is that, for the time being, it’s going to be hard to close a transaction in just 30 days in the Portland area. You’d be well-advised to prepare for it to take as long as 45 or even 50 days. In addition, let your clients know about what’s going on with these turn times so they can prepare as well.

If you have any other questions for Pete about current mortgage rates, you can call him at 503-267-6391.

As always, if there’s anything else you’d like us to address relative to the mortgage finance aspect of real estate transactions, give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to talking with you soon!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Our office recently had a transaction that was supposed to close at the end of September but got postponed by half of a month purely because the appraisal took so long to come in. Why?

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Steve Schwab</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Our office recently had a transaction that was supposed to close at the end of September but got postponed by half of a month purely because the appraisal took so long to come in. Why?

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Portland, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What If the First Home You See Is the One?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/what-if-first-home-you-see-is-one.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Steve Schwab</author>
        <pubDate>2016-09-07 11:06:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

If you fall in love with the first property you see, should you buy it or keep looking at other homes?

Some Realtors will say that if you fall in love with the first home you see, you have entered buyer nirvana. You can write an offer, move into the home, and they can move on to the next deal. I think that is a big mistake.

You may still wind up buying the first home you see, but I think it is still very important to compare that first home to other homes. In my 16 years as a Realtor, I have seen many people fall in love with the first home they see and I always encourage them to continue looking at other homes.

You need to compare that property to the others to see what you will get in terms of amenities, size, and finishes. You also need to pay attention to the location. Many buyers tend to overlook these factors, especially when they are buying a new construction home. There is something appealing about the fact that no one else has lived in the property, which makes it easy for buyers to fall in love with new homes.

“You need to compare the first home you see to other properties.”

When that happens, you may not notice that the backyard is not conducive to your family’s needs. You may also overlook the fact that the property backs up onto a busy street, which will be a hindrance when it comes time for you to sell the home. New construction buyers don’t look at properties this way, and they should.

Even if you are buying an older home, you still need to compare the first property you see to other homes available on the market. You may really like the first home only to discover that, for $10,000 more, you can get the perfect home for you and your family.

That said, you can take things too far by looking at too many homes and getting confused about what you want. I’m not saying to go out and look at dozens of homes; just look at a few others. This is probably the biggest investment you will make in your lifetime, so you want to make sure you choose the right property and avoid buyer’s remorse.

If you have any questions about finding the right home or about real estate in general, give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you fall in love with the first property you see, should you buy it or keep looking at other homes?

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Steve Schwab</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you fall in love with the first property you see, should you buy it or keep looking at other homes?

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Portland, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Knowing What You Want vs. What You Need in a Home</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/knowing-what-you-want-vs-what-you-need.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Steve Schwab</author>
        <pubDate>2016-08-22 10:58:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

I believe homeownership is the American Dream. When you buy a home, though, it is important to understand the difference between what you want in a home and what you need. How can you tell the difference?

The first thing I’d advise is pulling out a pen and a piece of paper and writing down two columns. In the left-hand column, list all of the things that you have today. In the right-hand column, list all the things you want. From left to right, your list should expand. This will be the criteria you will use to shop for a new home.

“Make lists detailing what you want and what you need in a home.”

Whatever amenities you end up listing in the right-hand column, it’s important to keep in mind that you may not get all of them in this next purchase. If your new home doesn’t have all the amenities that you want, I would strongly encourage that you start looking for ways to save money so that somewhere down the line you can procure them.

I often see people make upgrades to their home solely as part of their strategy for selling it. This is a mistake — you’re spending money that you don’t get a dollar-for-dollar return on. If you’re making upgrades, do it for yourself first. Reap the benefits of how it contributes to the home’s sale later.

If you have any questions you’d like answered, just shoot me an email or give me a call. I’d love to help in any way I can!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

I believe homeownership is the American Dream. When you buy a home, though, it is important to understand the difference between what you want in a home and what you need. How can you tell the difference?

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Steve Schwab</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

I believe homeownership is the American Dream. When you buy a home, though, it is important to understand the difference between what you want in a home and what you need. How can you tell the difference?

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Portland, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Is Your Portland HVAC System Properly Maintained?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/is-your-portland-hvac-system-properly.html</link>
        
          <category>Other</category>
        
        <author>Steve Schwab</author>
        <pubDate>2016-05-20 10:40:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Sam Murzea, from MP Heating and Air Conditioning in Portland, is our go-to vendor when our clients have issues with HVAC systems. When Sam checks on these units, he often finds they aren’t maintained properly. Typically, people forget about their HVAC units and don’t know anything is wrong until they’re hot in the summer or cold in the winter. This is exactly why Sam suggests an annual checkup.

In an annual checkup, Sam’s team will check out all the electrical components, mechanical components, filters, coils, and everything else. This inspection will eliminate your stresses and worries about your HVAC system, all year long. If you have an AC unit, they can clean it in addition to checking the condenser and other components. Their goal is to prevent breakdowns and future repairs.

“An annual checkup can eliminate issues down the road.”

In between these annual checkups, Sam recommends changing air filters regularly. Different systems require different change intervals. He also recommends changing filters every 30 days in order to ensure the best performance.

If you ignore all of these things, you may end up with no heat on the coldest day of the year or no air conditioning on the hottest day of the year! Additionally, carbon monoxide can leak. To keep your family comfortable and safe, perform regular maintenance on your HVAC units. Pay attention to it, and definitely don’t forget about it!

If you have any further questions, please don’t hesitate to contact Sam or myself. We look forward to working with you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Sam Murzea, from MP Heating and Air Conditioning in Portland, is our go-to vendor when our clients have issues with HVAC systems. When Sam checks on these units, he often finds they aren’t maintained properly. Typically, people forget about their HVAC units and don’t know anything is wrong until they’re hot in the summer or cold in the winter. This is exactly why Sam suggests an annual checkup.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Steve Schwab</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Sam Murzea, from MP Heating and Air Conditioning in Portland, is our go-to vendor when our clients have issues with HVAC systems. When Sam checks on these units, he often finds they aren’t maintained properly. Typically, people forget about their HVAC units and don’t know anything is wrong until they’re hot in the summer or cold in the winter. This is exactly why Sam suggests an annual checkup.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Portland, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Is the Portland Market Heading Towards a Bubble?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/is-portland-market-heading-towards.html</link>
        
          <category>Portland Real Estate Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Steve Schwab</author>
        <pubDate>2016-05-17 12:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Portland is continuing to see an explosive real estate market. I’ve mentioned this before, but we are part of a 20-city composite for a Case Shiller S&amp;P index that looks at national housing trends. The data that just came out last week shows the overall index leveling off a little bit. In January, we saw a 5.7% appreciation average across the 20 cities and that’s dipped down a bit to 5.4%.

However, in Portland we are still continuing to lead the pack with a 11.9% appreciation rate. We attribute our continued growth to a strong job market, strong housing demand, and the high quality of living we have here in the Pacific Northwest.

What’s also interesting is that mortgage defaults continue to be low, much lower than they have been in the past. We are at about a .75% default rate, which is a good place to be. Year-over-year price changes within that 20-city composite have remained very stable, right around the 5-6% range.

“A middle income family doesn’t need to stretch their wallet in order to buy a home.”

I get asked if we’re headed toward a housing bubble quite often, and my answer continues to be no. There are so many other factors that are propping up the real estate market. Our appreciation rate may not continue to be 11%, and it shouldn’t, because it’s not healthy. However, there is a huge upside to our market, and homes are still as affordable as ever.

For someone making a 20% down payment, their mortgage payments would only take about 15% of their income. Just 10 years ago, that figure was near 25%. A middle income family doesn’t need to stretch their wallet in order to buy a home, a statement that has been echoed by the National Association of Realtors’ Chief Economist, Lawrence Yun.

If you have any questions for me about the Portland market, don’t hesitate to reach out by phone or email. I would love to hear from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Portland is continuing to see an explosive real estate market. I’ve mentioned this before, but we are part of a 20-city composite for a Case Shiller S&amp;P index that looks at national housing trends. The data that just came out last week shows the overall index leveling off a little bit. In January, we saw a 5.7% appreciation average across the 20 cities and that’s dipped down a bit to 5.4%.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Steve Schwab</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Portland is continuing to see an explosive real estate market. I’ve mentioned this before, but we are part of a 20-city composite for a Case Shiller S&amp;P index that looks at national housing trends. The data that just came out last week shows the overall index leveling off a little bit. In January, we saw a 5.7% appreciation average across the 20 cities and that’s dipped down a bit to 5.4%.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Portland, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Are There Loans that Dont Require a Down Payment?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-can-you-pay-0-down-for-portland.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Steve Schwab</author>
        <pubDate>2016-03-14 11:42:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Have you been wondering what’s going on in the world of low down payment loans? Today, we are going to discuss a great mortgage loan down payment option that you have right here in Portland. We are here to discuss things with Peter Wease of Fairway Independent Mortgage, our preferred lender. Many people think $0 down home loans are a myth, but we can assure you they are not. They are here, and you could get one today.

“USDA loans are intended for rural housing.”

USDA loans are loans from the department of agriculture and are intended for rural housing, which expands beyond the urban growth boundary. You can get a USDA loan with 100% financing, meaning you will pay $0 down. There are a couple caveats with this loan, including that the home has to be past the urban growth boundary, which is detailed in the video above in the non-shaded areas. Your household income also may not exceed 115% of the median income.

This is a fantastic opportunity for someone to get in the market and own a home with no money down. Rents are going up, and this is a great option for telecommuters who would be working from home anyways without the need to commute.

If you have any questions for us or are interested in using a loan like this to purchase a home, give us a call or send us an email. We would love to talk to you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Have you been wondering what’s going on in the world of low down payment loans? Today, we are going to discuss a great mortgage loan down payment option that you have right here in Portland. We are here to discuss things with Peter Wease of Fairway Independent Mortgage, our preferred lender. Many people think $0 down home loans are a myth, but we can assure you they are not. They are here, and you could get one today.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Steve Schwab</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Have you been wondering what’s going on in the world of low down payment loans? Today, we are going to discuss a great mortgage loan down payment option that you have right here in Portland. We are here to discuss things with Peter Wease of Fairway Independent Mortgage, our preferred lender. Many people think $0 down home loans are a myth, but we can assure you they are not. They are here, and you could get one today.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Portland, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Dont Miss these Expert Portland Home Finance Tips</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/selling-your-portland-home-check-out.html</link>
        
          <category>Portland Real Estate Tips</category>
        
        <author>Steve Schwab</author>
        <pubDate>2016-03-09 16:01:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today I have Peter Wease with me and he will be helping us to discuss some changes that have happened with mortgage financing in Portland. Some of my viewers from last episode were concerned that Portland real estate may be entering a bubble, but I think those concerns are unfounded.

What has changed with mortgage financing in Portland is the creation of the CFPB, the Consumer Finance Protection Bureau. This is supposed to promote fairness and transparency for the consumer. TRID (TILA-RESPA Integrated Disclosure) was also designed to give the consumer time to look at the numbers during the closing process in a real estate transaction. It simply gives the consumer more time during the closing of a sale. Basically, everything in the transaction must be disclosed in paper.

“Consumers are much more protected now than they were in the past.”

This prevents erroneous fees and charges from being issued to the consumer. Furthermore, this prevents bad loans from being made, and this will ultimately prevent another bubble from forming. People borrowing money today are much more protected now than they were in the past.

If you have any questions about these changes, please don’t hesitate to contact me!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today I have Peter Wease with me and he will be helping us to discuss some changes that have happened with mortgage financing in Portland. Some of my viewers from last episode were concerned that Portland real estate may be entering a bubble, but I think those concerns are unfounded.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Steve Schwab</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today I have Peter Wease with me and he will be helping us to discuss some changes that have happened with mortgage financing in Portland. Some of my viewers from last episode were concerned that Portland real estate may be entering a bubble, but I think those concerns are unfounded.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Portland, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Inventory Levels Are Incredibly Low in Portland </title>
        <link>localhost:4000/inventory-levels-are-incredibly-low-in.html</link>
        
          <category>Portland Real Estate Market Update</category>
        
          <category>Market Statistics</category>
        
        <author>Steve Schwab</author>
        <pubDate>2016-02-25 10:26:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today, we’ll talk about the dynamics of the Portland real estate market. We’ll also examine why our inventory levels are causing relative appreciation in our area.

Portland continues to experience a brisk, fast-paced real estate market. Part of that is due to healthy job growth, and Portland has also been ranked as one of the best places to live in several publications. There aren’t many homes for sale, but demand is skyrocketing.

If a real estate market has less than 6 months of inventory, it’s considered a seller’s market. In a seller’s market, home prices go up. A neutral market has 6 to 7 months of inventory, and home prices will only appreciate due to inflation. A buyer’s market has more than 7 months of inventory, and prices will depreciate.

“Portland’s real estate market is highly competitive right now.”

Portland is in a firm seller’s market. Beaverton has less than a month of inventory. Northwest Portland has a month-and-a-half of inventory. Northeast Portland has about a month’s worth of inventory, and North Portland has 6/10ths of a month of inventory. This is what we’re seeing across Portland, especially in entry level price ranges.

Since homes are in such high demand, if you’re a buyer, you will probably face multiple offer situations. We recently helped a client make an offer on a property. He’s in escrow right now, but he had made 7 other offers on different properties before this one was accepted. It’s very competitive right now.

If you have any questions, give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today, we’ll talk about the dynamics of the Portland real estate market. We’ll also examine why our inventory levels are causing relative appreciation in our area.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Steve Schwab</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today, we’ll talk about the dynamics of the Portland real estate market. We’ll also examine why our inventory levels are causing relative appreciation in our area.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Portland, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why 2016 Is the Year to Buy in Portland </title>
        <link>localhost:4000/why-2016-is-year-to-buy-in-portland.html</link>
        
          <category>Portland Real Estate Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Steve Schwab</author>
        <pubDate>2016-02-08 12:04:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Is 2016 the right year for you to buy a home? The short answer is yes.

Here’s why: the S&amp;P Shiller numbers show that in October of 2015, Portland saw an annualized appreciation rate of 10.9%. Along with Denver and San Francisco, Portland is leading the nation in home appreciation. From an investment standpoint, this is a fantastic time to buy.

If you buy now instead of waiting for a year, you will save a lot of money. Today, you can get a $250,000 home with a 4.01% interest rate. Your monthly payment would be $1,195. If rates go up as they’re projected to, that same home will cost $263,250 with a 4.8% interest rate. Your monthly payment will go up to $1,381 if you wait a year to buy a home.

“Right now is a fantastic time to buy!”

If you get in the market today, you will save a lot of money. Don’t wait for next year. If you look at it from a monthly standpoint, you can go out to dinner or make a dent in that car payment with the money you saved. Annually, that money can go towards a vacation or pay off a couple credit cards. Over 30 years, if you buy now, you will save $67,032.

As you can see, it’s a great time to be in the market. If you have any questions, give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Is 2016 the right year for you to buy a home? The short answer is yes.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Steve Schwab</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Is 2016 the right year for you to buy a home? The short answer is yes.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Portland, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Three Reasons to Buy in Portland</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/portland-real-estate-purchasing-power.html</link>
        
          <category>Purchasing Power</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Steve Schwab</author>
        <pubDate>2015-12-01 14:47:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

The National Association of Realtors published a national study on what motivates buyers to purchase a home in today’s economy. Their conclusions included three specific reasons.
1. People want the opportunity to build equity. They’re using a home to augment or enhance their net worth, in addition to any other investments they have. Data reveals the average family wealth among homeowners has gradually increased since 2010. Conversely, renters continue to maintain the same amount of wealth with a slight drop. Indefinitely, owning a home has a dramatic impact on your family’s net worth in the economy.


  
    People want a safe and stable environment to live in. This year’s Rent.com market report orients around property managers. The study results show 88% of property managers increased rent over the past twelve months without intention of stopping; 68% predict rents will continue to rise next year by an average of 8%; and 53% were more likely to bring in a new tenant at a higher rate rather than negotiate and renew a lease with a current tenant.
  
  
    People want to choose the environment they live in. We conduct business with clients we admire. Likewise, we want to foster a neighborhood community with people who share similar values. We often run into clients who are focused on school districts, who else lives in the neighborhood, what other kids are living in the area, etc. That’s why it’s important to us.
  


“People want a safe and stable environment to live in.”

If you have any questions at all about buying or selling a home, feel free to reach out today. Give me a call or email!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

The National Association of Realtors published a national study on what motivates buyers to purchase a home in today’s economy. Their conclusions included three specific reasons.
1. People want the opportunity to build equity. They’re using a home to augment or enhance their net worth, in addition to any other investments they have. Data reveals the average family wealth among homeowners has gradually increased since 2010. Conversely, renters continue to maintain the same amount of wealth with a slight drop. Indefinitely, owning a home has a dramatic impact on your family’s net worth in the economy.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Steve Schwab</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

The National Association of Realtors published a national study on what motivates buyers to purchase a home in today’s economy. Their conclusions included three specific reasons.
1. People want the opportunity to build equity. They’re using a home to augment or enhance their net worth, in addition to any other investments they have. Data reveals the average family wealth among homeowners has gradually increased since 2010. Conversely, renters continue to maintain the same amount of wealth with a slight drop. Indefinitely, owning a home has a dramatic impact on your family’s net worth in the economy.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Portland, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Do You Know if Someone Died in a Portland Home?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/portland-real-estate-seller-disclosure.html</link>
        
          <category>Disclosures</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Disclosures</category>
        
        <author>Steve Schwab</author>
        <pubDate>2015-11-03 15:17:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Since Halloween has recently passed, let’s discuss a question buyers occasionally ask: “Has someone died in the home I want to purchase?”

There are some superstitious people out there who worry about that kind of event in a home. There are other adventurous people who seek out these properties.

“Stignatized homes tend to be unpopular when they come on the market.”

Disclosure law in Oregon does not require the seller to disclose a death in the home. Many states in our country have similar laws.

However, if you want to find out, you can visit a website called DiedInHouse.com. This site searches public and private records to provide you a report on any deaths, fires, or drug activity on a property. Homes that are stigmatized can be less popular and sit on the market for a while. Some homes are even torn down, depending on what happened.

If you have any questions about today’s video, give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Since Halloween has recently passed, let’s discuss a question buyers occasionally ask: “Has someone died in the home I want to purchase?”

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Steve Schwab</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Since Halloween has recently passed, let’s discuss a question buyers occasionally ask: “Has someone died in the home I want to purchase?”

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Portland, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Market Yourself as a More Desirable Buyer in Portland</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/portland-real-estate-importance-of-pre.html</link>
        
          <category>Portland Real Estate Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Pre-approval advice</category>
        
        <author>Steve Schwab</author>
        <pubDate>2015-10-23 09:39:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

The Portland real estate market continues to be brisk and fast paced. Because of the competitive climate, it’s important to make yourself stand out from the rest of the crowd. Today, you will learn creative ways to make yourself stand out as a buyer, despite the rigorous competition.

Get pre-approved! Instead of only getting pre-qualified, it’s useful to get pre-approved by a reputable lender in the area. Allow a well known, reliable lender to help you through the entire process in a timely fashion. They will help you look as strong as possible on paper when it comes time to negotiate.

Have at least a 20% down payment. Even if you can’t afford a 20% down payment, look for innovative ways or creative terms to make yourself stand out. For instance, suppose the seller needs a quick close in order to return to their job in another city. You then have the advantage to market your ability to close quickly. Your flexibility to accommodate the seller’s needs could be a great selling point.

“Make yourself stand out as a buyer.”

Have all your paperwork in order. Organization always works in your favor. Avoid any incomplete paperwork to save everyone’s time. Check for any missing signatures, unanswered questions, and any other blank fields. Remind your agent to make sure everything is complete.

Forget lowball offers. Lowball offers simply don’t work in the current climate. One day, they will work in the future, but not today.

Keep your contingencies reasonable. It’s difficult to get a contingent offer accepted today, even on a good house. Get your home in escrow in order to move forward and enter the market. Other contingencies include shrinking your inspection period from the standard seven to ten days. Again, look for ways to make yourself look good. Remove any barriers that may get in a client’s way.

Feel free to reach out to us if you have any questions. We look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

The Portland real estate market continues to be brisk and fast paced. Because of the competitive climate, it’s important to make yourself stand out from the rest of the crowd. Today, you will learn creative ways to make yourself stand out as a buyer, despite the rigorous competition.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Steve Schwab</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

The Portland real estate market continues to be brisk and fast paced. Because of the competitive climate, it’s important to make yourself stand out from the rest of the crowd. Today, you will learn creative ways to make yourself stand out as a buyer, despite the rigorous competition.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Portland, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Owning a Home in Portland Is Easier Than You Think!</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/portland-real-estate-making-down-payment.html</link>
        
          <category>Portland Real Estate Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Steve Schwab</author>
        <pubDate>2015-09-14 14:21:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

If you can’t afford a large down payment, should you wait to buy? We get this question all the time, so we thought we might address it here today, and explain how private mortgage insurance might help you buy sooner than you thought you could.

It seems we run into people every day who think they need to wait to move in order to save a large down payment. They think that without a 20% down payment, they won’t be able to qualify for a mortgage in today’s market.That is a mistaken belief, as there are many available programs out there that require anywhere from 3.5-10%! There are even some programs that require no money down, but those are a bit harder to qualify for.

Putting 5% down is a whole lot more affordable for many people than putting 20% down, at least in the short term. For instance, if you put 5% down ($10,000) on a $200,000 home, as opposed to 20% ($40,000), your monthly payment would only be $232.75 more expensive. Many people think that saving for a 20% down payment will save them money, but is that really true?

“Putting 5% down is a whole lot more affordable for many people than putting 20% down.”

Core Logic recently published a report that tells us to expect a residential appreciation rate of about 4.3% and I think here in Portland that number is going to be even higher (it’s currently in the 7% range!). If you were to purchase private mortgage insurance, the difference in payments over the next 12 months would be $2,793, whereas the expected appreciation over the next 12 months is $8,600. When you take those numbers together, it shows that you are missing out on $5,807 a month by not owning.

If you would like to sit down and talk about your options, please don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We would love to help in any way we can!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you can’t afford a large down payment, should you wait to buy? We get this question all the time, so we thought we might address it here today, and explain how private mortgage insurance might help you buy sooner than you thought you could.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Steve Schwab</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you can’t afford a large down payment, should you wait to buy? We get this question all the time, so we thought we might address it here today, and explain how private mortgage insurance might help you buy sooner than you thought you could.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Portland, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Stand Out as a Home Buyer in Portland with One Simple Document</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/portland-real-estate-how-to-stand-out.html</link>
        
          <category>Portland Real Estate Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Steve Schwab</author>
        <pubDate>2015-09-09 13:32:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today we’ll be discussing an important distinction among home buyers in Portland. I’m talking about a pre-approval versus a pre-qualification. It’s an important difference that you may not know about, but home sellers will surely be scrutinizing you about it.

A pre-qualification and a pre-approval are two entirely different documents. A pre-qualification is a much more basic certification, and it can be obtained in a few hours. You only need a few pieces of information, none of which is really double-checked, and you can then get your pre-qualification letter once a lender has looked over your numbers. This is a very informal meeting between you and the lender, and it doesn’t mean a whole lot in the eyes of the seller.

“You want a pre-approval letter as a buyer.”

A pre-approval letter is much more desirable, and I highly recommend it to all of my home buyers. This is more time-consuming, but it will designate you as a serious buyer if you can acquire it. You will submit tax returns, pay stubs, insurance information, and more. Once the lender has an opportunity to review these items, you will then be issued an approval letter.

Both buyers and sellers like to see letters of pre-approval, and this is especially true when the real estate market is as hot as it is in Portland.

If you would like to be put in contact with a great local lender, please don’t hesitate to contact me!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today we’ll be discussing an important distinction among home buyers in Portland. I’m talking about a pre-approval versus a pre-qualification. It’s an important difference that you may not know about, but home sellers will surely be scrutinizing you about it.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Steve Schwab</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today we’ll be discussing an important distinction among home buyers in Portland. I’m talking about a pre-approval versus a pre-qualification. It’s an important difference that you may not know about, but home sellers will surely be scrutinizing you about it.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Portland, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Can You Expect from the Portland Market?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/portland-real-estate-end-of-summer.html</link>
        
          <category>Portland Real Estate Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Steve Schwab</author>
        <pubDate>2015-08-24 12:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Portland’s market is still going strong as we wrap up the summer season. Today, we take a quick look at what current conditions mean for you and the future of our market.

Right now, it’s still very common to see multiple offers on any given properties. In fact, some buyers are even willing to waive appraisals and look for ways to leverage themselves against the buyers they are competing with. It’s very competitive these days, and it can be difficult to get into a home unless you get creative.

When multiple offers are as common as they are now, I like to look at the S&amp;P/Case-Schiller Home Price Indices. This is a national report that we get every month and the one we got at the end of July showed that, nationally, single-family homes were at a 4-5% appreciation rate. That’s a much better rate than we saw in 2013. Over the next two years, we’re expecting home prices to slow a bit, as they’ve been rising rapidly over the last few years.

“It can be difficult to get into a home unless you get creative.”

Portland has seen an appreciation level of about 7.4% over the last year or so. Because home prices keep rising, many people in our area have asked if this is a bubble. Frankly, I don’t think so; there’s a difference between the makeup of the buyer today and the buyer leading up to the crash. Back then, you didn’t need much of a down payment or any at all, and generally people weren’t as qualified. Today, the buyers are highly qualified and ready to go!

If you have any questions about where our market is heading, don’t hesitate to give me a call or shoot me and email. I would love to hear from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Portland’s market is still going strong as we wrap up the summer season. Today, we take a quick look at what current conditions mean for you and the future of our market.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Steve Schwab</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Portland’s market is still going strong as we wrap up the summer season. Today, we take a quick look at what current conditions mean for you and the future of our market.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Portland, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Should You Consider Investing in Portland?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/portland-real-estate-investment-tips.html</link>
        
          <category>Investment Tips</category>
        
        <author>Steve Schwab</author>
        <pubDate>2015-08-05 12:32:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

While commodities and stocks can be volatile and dangerous investments, real estate is a relatively safe one. It’s actually quite easy to get involved in investment real estate here in Portland, and it can have huge benefits if done correctly.

Why would someone want to invest in Portland? There is a company out there called Protech Valuation Services, which goes around measuring the best and worst markets to invest in. Believe it or not, Portland is #1 on their list.

“Rent is increasing at a shocking rate.”

In addition to this, Money Magazine recently discussed how rent has been steadily increasing at a much higher rate than mortgage rates. Rent increased by 8.6% last year, and is currently growing at twice the rate of property values. Portland is an expensive market to rent in, but can be lucrative if you are a landlord.

It takes about a 20% down payment to invest in a property today. Now you can have a property that you can rent out to give you positive cash flow, where someone is paying your principle down for you. On top of that, the home will appreciate in value and the tax benefits are substantial.

Another thing that comes into play is the 1031 exchange, where you can take your equity to invest in even more properties. Hopefully this has been of some help to you. If you want to dive deeper, give us a call or send us an email and we’d be happy to talk to you soon!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

While commodities and stocks can be volatile and dangerous investments, real estate is a relatively safe one. It’s actually quite easy to get involved in investment real estate here in Portland, and it can have huge benefits if done correctly.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Steve Schwab</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

While commodities and stocks can be volatile and dangerous investments, real estate is a relatively safe one. It’s actually quite easy to get involved in investment real estate here in Portland, and it can have huge benefits if done correctly.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Portland, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Can You Do About High Levels of Radon in Your Portland Home?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/portland-real-estate-home-safety-tips.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Safety Tips</category>
        
        <author>Steve Schwab</author>
        <pubDate>2015-07-14 16:14:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Not many homeowners are aware of the potential dangers of radon gas. Today, we want to give you some basic information so you can keep your home and your family safe from this toxic gas!

Many home inspections that are done today test for radon gas. It’s an odorless, invisible, radioactive gas that’s produced from the natural decay of uranium and is found in most soil. Exposure to radon is responsible for up to 20,000 deaths in the United States each year and is the number one cause of lung cancer in nonsmokers.

“There are many resources on the web to find out more about radon.”

It’s estimated that one in every four homes in Portland accumulates levels of radon gas that are above what’s acceptable according to the EPA. It’s mostly found in homes with basements, but is sometimes found in homes above ground. A good way to determine whether your area is susceptible to high levels of radon is to get on Google and search your part of town. There are many resources on the web to find more information about radon.

What happens if you learn that your home has high levels of radon? Luckily, it’s not the end of the world if radon is discovered in your home. We’ll install a radon reduction system that can reduce radon levels upwards of 99%. A soil suction system is used to draw radon from below your home and vented through pipes that release it into the atmosphere outside of your house. These systems typically cost anywhere from $1,800-$4,000 depending on how serious the problem is.

If you have any questions about this topic, or if you would like to test your home, give us a call or shoot us a quick email. We’re always here to help you with all of your real estate needs!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Not many homeowners are aware of the potential dangers of radon gas. Today, we want to give you some basic information so you can keep your home and your family safe from this toxic gas!

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Steve Schwab</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Not many homeowners are aware of the potential dangers of radon gas. Today, we want to give you some basic information so you can keep your home and your family safe from this toxic gas!

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Portland, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Changes Are Coming to the CFPB?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/portland-real-estate-tips-and-tricks.html</link>
        
          <category>Portland Real Estate Tips</category>
        
        <author>Steve Schwab</author>
        <pubDate>2015-07-07 11:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Welcome back, everyone. Today we are excited to be joined by Peter Weiss, from our preferred mortgage lender, Fareway Independent Mortgage. Today we are going to talk about the CFPB, or Consumer Financial Protection Bureau, and what changes are coming to it that could affect your next real estate transaction.

The CFPB is a governmental agency that was created out of the mortgage crisis in 2007-2008. The idea of the CFPB is to create a protection for the consumer, and they are making changes soon that will affect both buyers and sellers.

The idea behind the current change is to condense some of the disclosures that are currently sent out to the consumer. Instead of having to fill out all kinds of different disclosure forms, they are pulling all the disclosures together into one form.

With this new disclosure, once we get final approval, we send the disclosure out to the customer well before the closing date, so they have time to review it. We want to hit every closing right on time.

“These changes are coming October 3rd, so mark your calendars.”

Additional changes are coming that could impact the timeline of a real estate transaction. These changes are coming October 3rd, so mark your calendars.

If you have any questions about the mortgage or finance world, let us know. We would love to answer them with Peter in an upcoming video. We look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Welcome back, everyone. Today we are excited to be joined by Peter Weiss, from our preferred mortgage lender, Fareway Independent Mortgage. Today we are going to talk about the CFPB, or Consumer Financial Protection Bureau, and what changes are coming to it that could affect your next real estate transaction.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Steve Schwab</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Welcome back, everyone. Today we are excited to be joined by Peter Weiss, from our preferred mortgage lender, Fareway Independent Mortgage. Today we are going to talk about the CFPB, or Consumer Financial Protection Bureau, and what changes are coming to it that could affect your next real estate transaction.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Portland, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Avoid These 8 Mistakes to Sell for Top Dollar in Portland</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/portland-real-estate-home-seller-tips_19.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Steve Schwab</author>
        <pubDate>2015-05-19 13:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Welcome back to part two of my home-staging video. I’m going to be discussing some common mistakes that buyers make when they stage their home. If you play your cards right in the process, you can see a nice return when you sell your home. Hopefully these tips can help you sell your Portland property for a little extra this spring!

Numbers one through four were discussed last week:


  
    Being too personal. You don’t want people to walk into a room and be able to identify the type of person living in it.
  
  
    Pack away your personal items. You don’t want your potential buyers distracted by photos and other belongings of yours. Your home should stand out to them, not your collection of sports memorabilia.
  


“Bright houses always sell.”


  
    Don’t paint with dark colors. Darker colors make rooms feel smaller, and we always suggest colors that are light and bright. Earth tones seem to be popular right now, and they tend to be more inviting colors for buyers.
  
  
    Not taking advantage of natural light. You want every window of your house open and light shining in. Buyers like to see homes that are well-lit, and opening up your windows and letting the light come inside is a very simple and easy way to improve the look and feel of your home. A lot of buyers want nice natural lighting in their home.
  
  
    Thinking more is better. Remove any large furniture that you have in your home. It will make the room feel smaller and it can clog up traffic in your home when buyers are viewing it.
  
  
    Forgetting the fixtures. Make sure every fixture in your home works and that every light has a fresh bulb. This is also a small pet-peeve that can really irritate some buyers during a viewing. Bright houses always sell.
  
  
    Having pets at home. I love animals, but not when I’m trying to sell a home. They bring along odors and can cause unsightly stains. Remove any litter boxes from your home or kennels that are left out. Try to make it appear as if no pets are in your home.
  
  
    Neglecting the exterior: Buyers are beginning to care more and more about outdoor spaces of properties. Buyers are drawn into your home by what it looks from the outside, so paint your front door, mow your lawn, plant some flowers, and make sure that it looks as inviting as possible. I might even recommend power washing the sides of your home as well as your driveway.
  


Hopefully, these eight tips can help you sell for top dollar this summer in Portland! If you have any questions about these topics, please don’t hesitate to contact me!

Thanks for watching, and stay tuned!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Welcome back to part two of my home-staging video. I’m going to be discussing some common mistakes that buyers make when they stage their home. If you play your cards right in the process, you can see a nice return when you sell your home. Hopefully these tips can help you sell your Portland property for a little extra this spring!

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Steve Schwab</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Welcome back to part two of my home-staging video. I’m going to be discussing some common mistakes that buyers make when they stage their home. If you play your cards right in the process, you can see a nice return when you sell your home. Hopefully these tips can help you sell your Portland property for a little extra this spring!

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Portland, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Avoid These Mistakes to Sell for Top Dollar in Portland</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/portland-real-estate-home-seller-tips.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Steve Schwab</author>
        <pubDate>2015-05-19 12:46:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Now is the time to list your home for sale in Portland, so I wanted to speak about some common mistakes that people make when staging their homes. I’ll discuss four mistakes in this video, and then there will be another follow-up video where I will discuss four more mistakes being made.


  
    Being too personal. You don’t want people to walk into a room and be able to identify the type of person living in it.
  
  
    Pack away your personal items. You don’t want your potential buyers distracted by photos and other belongings of yours. Your home should stand out to them, not your collection of sports memorabilia.
  


“Darket colors make rooms feel smaller.”


  
    Don’t paint with dark colors. Darker colors make rooms feel smaller, and we always suggest colors that are light and bright. Earth tones seem to be popular right now, and they tend to be more inviting colors for buyers.
  
  
    Not taking advantage of natural light. You want every window of your house open and light shining in. Buyers like to see homes that are well-lit, and opening up your windows and letting the light come inside is a very simple and easy way to improve the look and feel of your home. A lot of buyers want nice natural lighting in their home.
  


Hopefully, these tips have been helpful if you plan on buying or selling this summer. We’ll be coming back in a few weeks with tips 5-8.

Thanks for watching, and stay tuned!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Now is the time to list your home for sale in Portland, so I wanted to speak about some common mistakes that people make when staging their homes. I’ll discuss four mistakes in this video, and then there will be another follow-up video where I will discuss four more mistakes being made.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Steve Schwab</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Now is the time to list your home for sale in Portland, so I wanted to speak about some common mistakes that people make when staging their homes. I’ll discuss four mistakes in this video, and then there will be another follow-up video where I will discuss four more mistakes being made.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Portland, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Avoid These Six Buyer Mistakes for a Smooth Transaction</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/portland-real-estate-home-buyer-tips.html</link>
        
          <category>Portland Real Estate Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Steve Schwab</author>
        <pubDate>2015-05-19 10:53:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

As we head into the buying and selling season, I thought I’d give my home buyers some tips for when they set out on the market. Now is a great time to buy a home, but it’s important to make sure you’re avoiding these mistakes.

“You need to set a realistic budget because there are a lot of hidden fees when you purchase a home.”


  Borrowing the maximum amount: You need to set a realistic budget because there are a lot of hidden fees when you purchase a home. You need to be able to afford the costs of maintenance, insurance, HOA fees, and a fund for when something absolutely catastrophic happens. Hopefully, you will never need this, but you never know. You want to be able to comfortably afford a home, not live paycheck to paycheck.


“You need to set a realistic budget because there are a lot of hidden fees when you purchase a home.”


  
    Not Planning Ahead: You need to take into consideration what your home will be worth when you go to sell it in a few years. Are you next to a busy street? Do you need new carpet or a new roof? You want to sell your home for more than you bought it for, and that will take some planning.
  
  
    Get Pre-approved for a loan: You need to get approved for a loan even before you go out and start looking for a home. Sellers probably won’t even consider you as a buyer if you can’t prove that you can buy the home. Getting approved will also allow you to figure out what you can afford to buy, so you won’t be wasting time looking at homes that you cannot afford.
  
  
    Indecision: Our market is moving very quickly, so you need to be able to make decisions quickly if you find a home that you really like. Don’t let someone else buy your dream home!
  
  
    Checking only online sources for mortgage programs: We believe that it’s best to have a face-to-face relationship with your lender. This ensures proper communication between you and your lender, and that is really important during the closing period.
  
  
    Debt to income ratio: You really need to pay attention to this. Don’t think about going out and buying a new car or new furniture that could ruin your debt to income ratio and disqualify you for a loan. I’ve seen people spoil their ability to close by doing this, so please budget wisely during your closing period.
  


We would love to talk to you further about these items. If you have any questions about this, please don’t hesitate to contact us.

As always, consider us your #1 resource for real estate in Portland!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

As we head into the buying and selling season, I thought I’d give my home buyers some tips for when they set out on the market. Now is a great time to buy a home, but it’s important to make sure you’re avoiding these mistakes.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Steve Schwab</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

As we head into the buying and selling season, I thought I’d give my home buyers some tips for when they set out on the market. Now is a great time to buy a home, but it’s important to make sure you’re avoiding these mistakes.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Portland, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Four Easy Ways to Add Value to Your Portland Home</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/portland-real-estate-home-seller-tips.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Steve Schwab</author>
        <pubDate>2015-03-26 12:51:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

With the spring selling season in full swing here in Portland, I wanted to share four inexpensive ways to add some value to your home. These things can easily be done right before a sale, and they can put some extra cash in your pocket at closing.


  
    Appliances: Many of our homes have older appliances within them, and you might be surprised at how inexpensive it is to get new appliances. A company I know of called ABT is able to swap out all of your appliances to get you the stainless steel that buyers like to see these days.
  
  
    Painting: This may be one of the easiest ways to add value to your property. Fresh paint is an extremely cost-effective way to add value to your home, and can go a long way to make buyers believe that your home is brand new. Just make sure that colors throughout your home are uniform, and buyers typically prefer lighter earth tones.
  
  
    Staging: We provide a free stager when you work with us, and she will come out to arrange your home in an enticing way. Homes that are dolled up and staged often sell for more money than homes that have not been altered prior to selling. This is a fantastic way to put some extra cash in your pocket at closing.
  
  
    Depersonalize and declutter: Buyers don’t like to see messy homes, and they also need to imagine themselves living within the space of your home. Cleaning up and organizing your home can go a long way towards making potential buyers feel more comfortable within your home. Remove any collections of photos, art, or other personal items. You don’t need your home to be empty, but don’t let your particular lifestyle be readily apparent to everyone who walks inside your home.
  


“Often times the repairs that you think might net you more money are not the ones you need to be making.”

As you prepare to sell your home this spring, I hope that these tips will be able to put some more money in your pocket. Often times the repairs that you think might net you more money are not the ones that you need to be making. Be sure to speak with us before your home sale so you don’t waste your money on unnecessary repairs.

As always, consider me your #1 resource for real estate in Portland!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

With the spring selling season in full swing here in Portland, I wanted to share four inexpensive ways to add some value to your home. These things can easily be done right before a sale, and they can put some extra cash in your pocket at closing.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Steve Schwab</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

With the spring selling season in full swing here in Portland, I wanted to share four inexpensive ways to add some value to your home. These things can easily be done right before a sale, and they can put some extra cash in your pocket at closing.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Portland, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Does Portland Real Estate Compare to the Rest of the Country?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/portland-real-estate-update-march-2015.html</link>
        
          <category>Portland Real Estate Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Steve Schwab</author>
        <pubDate>2015-03-20 11:17:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Selling your Portland home? Check out our free home value report
Buying a Portland home? Search all homes for sale

Today I will be discussing something a little different than what I usually cover. Today I’ll be discussing the S&amp;P Case-Shiller Home Price Index Report. This report covers the entire US, so we can compare our Portland market to the rest of the country. This report is made up of 2 composites, a 20-city composite and a 10-city composite. Portland was part of the 20-city composite, which makes it pretty fascinating to me.

“In 2015 I think we could expect appreciation right around 5% in the Portland Area.”

Some of the highlights of the report were:

• On average, the cities in the study appreciated by an average of 4.5%
• The report also shows how the housing recovery is slowing down, but this should not be alarming because the recovery has been swift as of late
• In the last twelve months, the Portland market has appreciated by 6.8%
• In 2015 I think we could expect appreciation right around 5% in the Portland area, which is a healthy amount of appreciation

Hopefully you have found this information helpful, and if you have any other questions, please don’t hesitate to contact me.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Selling your Portland home? Check out our free home value report
Buying a Portland home? Search all homes for sale

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Steve Schwab</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Selling your Portland home? Check out our free home value report
Buying a Portland home? Search all homes for sale

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Portland, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Now Is the Time to Buy</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/portland-5-reasons-to-buys.html</link>
        
          <category>Portland Real Estate Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Steve Schwab</author>
        <pubDate>2015-03-11 12:41:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Affordability is at an all-time high right now. Interest rates are low (below 4%), and loan products from Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac are allowing consumers to buy with only 3% down. Even rates for private mortgage insurance have dropped, and this can save you thousands of dollars over the life of your loan. It’s difficult for me to imagine a better time to purchase, and on top of these financial incentives, I have five more reasons why owning a home is beneficial to you.

“If you’re renting right now, I highly suggest you start considering a home purchase.”


  Home ownership leverages your money: If you purchase a home, it’s likely going to appreciate in price, so you own an investment that you should make a profit on. Other than regular maintenance, there is not a whole lot you have to do to profit off of this investment.
  You’re paying anyway: You have to pay for housing either way, so why help to pay off someone else’s mortgage when you rent a home? When you own a home, your monthly payments go towards an investment that you can gain equity in.
  It’s a forced savings account: You’re making a monthly payment, a portion of which goes toward your principal balance, and in 15 or 30 years, you will have the savings of your home’s value.
  Tax incentives: Property taxes are deductible, and mortgage interest is tax-deductible. There are many tax cuts that you receive when you own a home as opposed to when you pay rent on a property.
  A home protects against inflation: When inflation occurs, your home gains value, so your equity increases and your wealth does too.


If you’re renting right now, I highly suggest you start considering a home purchase. Homes are wonderful investments for the future, and there are actually a lot more benefits to home ownership than I could discuss in the time frame of this video.

If you need any help with buying or selling real estate in the Portland area, please feel free to contact me. I’m always happy to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Affordability is at an all-time high right now. Interest rates are low (below 4%), and loan products from Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac are allowing consumers to buy with only 3% down. Even rates for private mortgage insurance have dropped, and this can save you thousands of dollars over the life of your loan. It’s difficult for me to imagine a better time to purchase, and on top of these financial incentives, I have five more reasons why owning a home is beneficial to you.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Steve Schwab</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Affordability is at an all-time high right now. Interest rates are low (below 4%), and loan products from Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac are allowing consumers to buy with only 3% down. Even rates for private mortgage insurance have dropped, and this can save you thousands of dollars over the life of your loan. It’s difficult for me to imagine a better time to purchase, and on top of these financial incentives, I have five more reasons why owning a home is beneficial to you.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Portland, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Type of Market are We Seeing in Portland?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/feb-2015-market-update.html</link>
        
          <category>Portland Real Estate Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Steve Schwab</author>
        <pubDate>2015-02-09 16:29:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

A lot of our clients here in Portland have been asking us whether we’re in a buyer’s market or a seller’s market. The short answer is that we are in the midst of a seller’s market right now.

However, there are some fundamental differences between this market and the one we had in 2006. Asking price is absolutely critical in our market. You cannot ask too much or it will sit and go stale. Presentation is also key because buyers expect the best, and if you don’t deliver curb appeal you could miss out on a sale.

Another factor in our market right now is that we only have a 2.3 month supply of inventory. Keep in mind that this is an average, so this isn’t true for all neighborhoods and price points. Also consider that the average home price in Portland is up to $332,000, and a year ago that price was at $310,000. These prices are impacted by supply and demand, so a low inventory with a high demand will eventually raise prices up. We’re also seeing multiple offers on some homes, and that tends to push prices up as well.
In the last 12 months, we’ve seen a 6.2% appreciation in prices and home values.

“If you’re a buyer, you’ll probably pay less in a mortgage than what you pay monthly for rent.”

Interest rates are also at historic lows, so now is the time to take action and get on the market whether you’re a buyer or a seller. If you’re a buyer, you’ll probably find that you’ll pay less on a mortgage than what you pay monthly for rent.

Please don’t hesitate to contact us if you’re thinking about buying or selling your home in Portland. We’re always willing to help you in any way possible!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

A lot of our clients here in Portland have been asking us whether we’re in a buyer’s market or a seller’s market. The short answer is that we are in the midst of a seller’s market right now.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Steve Schwab</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

A lot of our clients here in Portland have been asking us whether we’re in a buyer’s market or a seller’s market. The short answer is that we are in the midst of a seller’s market right now.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Portland, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Steve Schwab</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Steve Schwab</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Portland Lifestyle Team - your professional Portland Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
