<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Houston Real Estate Podcast with Mike Gray</title>
    <link>localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Mike Gray Team - your professional Houston Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Mike Gray</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2017-04-14 14:21:36 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Mike Gray</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Mike@TheMikeGrayTeam.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Mike Gray</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Mike Gray</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Houston Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Mike Gray Team - your professional Houston Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Should You Approach Real Estate Investing?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/houston-real-estate-agent-should-you.html</link>
        
          <category>Houston real estate buyer tips</category>
        
        <author>Mike Gray</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-12 11:35:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

I’m asked by clients on almost a weekly basis about real estate investing. The questions usually boil down to, “Does buying an investment property make sense for me?”

As you may know, I invest in real estate myself and am a huge proponent of owning property. Whether it makes sense for you or not as someone who isn’t in the real estate business depends on your goal.

When buying real estate as an investment, you have to realize that you are buying a business and need to treat it as such. What are the costs involved? What will your return be? Can you get a better return by investing your money in some other way? These are all questions to consider.

“REAL ESTATE IS A GREAT LONG-TERM PLAY.”

One positive that real estate investing has is the ability to use leverage. If you put $100,000 toward a piece of property, you can own an asset worth $500,000. The tax advantages are numerous as well. You can write off capital gains, property taxes, and private mortgage insurance. Properties also tend to double in value every 20 years or so.

An investment property needs to meet the standards of the area you are buying in, not your personal standards. It’s important to do your due diligence up front when it comes to anything that is wrong with the home. The same goes for finding tenants. You need to look closely for any red flags. You can hire a property management company to handle all of this if you choose.

I look at real estate investing as a great long-term play that is as close to a safe bet as you can get. Most people regret not investing in real estate sooner once they start seeing those big returns down the line.

If you have any questions for us or want to know more about investing in real estate, give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

I’m asked by clients on almost a weekly basis about real estate investing. The questions usually boil down to, “Does buying an investment property make sense for me?”

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mike Gray</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

I’m asked by clients on almost a weekly basis about real estate investing. The questions usually boil down to, “Does buying an investment property make sense for me?”

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Whats So Important About Home Appraisals?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/houston-real-estate-agent-what-you-need.html</link>
        
          <category>Houston real estate buyer tips</category>
        
        <author>Mike Gray</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-28 09:47:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today I want to go over the subject of home appraisals and what you need to know about them.

First though, I want to thank you for helping our team get recognized as one of the top-20 luxury teams in Houston in 2016. Whether you’ve done business with us or referred us, we can’t thank you enough for your continued support, and we truly appreciate it.

Now, how does a home appraisal happen? If you purchase a home and you get a loan, your lender will require that an appraisal is done before your loan is approved. Although the true definition of a home sale transaction is a price that a willing buyer and seller agree on, the lender will require a third party to visit the property and give it a fair market value.

Typically, the lender will loan a percentage amount that’s agreed in the contract. If you’re putting 20% down on the loan, the bank will lend you the other 80% of what’s in the contract as long as the home appraises for the contract amount. The problem occurs when the home doesn’t appraise for the contract amount. When that happens, the bank will still loan the 80%, but only for the appraised amount—not the contract price.

“IF A HOME DOESN’T APPRAISE FOR THE CONTRACT PRICE, MANY DIFFERENT THINGS CAN HAPPEN. ”

Let’s say you’re purchasing a home for $1 million, you’re putting down $200,000, and the bank is loaning you $800,000. What happens if a $900,000 appraisal happens and results in a $100,000 difference? At that point, negotiations happen all over again, and there are four different options in which all parties can continue:


  The buyer can bring in an additional $100,000 to the closing table.
  The seller can reduce the price by another $100,000 to meet the lender’s needs.
  The buyer and seller can find some common ground and make up the difference. This is typically the most common.
  The buyer can walk away.


Is a home not appraising a common occurrence? Yes and no. A few years ago after the financial crisis, lenders were extremely cautious, so homes not appraising was a common occurrence. Fortunately, we don’t see that as much now.

One thing our team does is meet the appraiser and bring documentation to justify the purchase price. We’ve found this to be a very beneficial thing to do and something that is welcomed by appraisers. As you know, there are many intricacies within this city when it comes to real estate, so this gives them additional information. If you’re buying a home and getting a loan, make sure that you bring all the information you can to get the appraiser to justify the home’s value.

If you have any questions about this topic or are thinking about buying or selling a home, feel free to give me a call or shoot me an email. I’d be glad to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today I want to go over the subject of home appraisals and what you need to know about them.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mike Gray</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today I want to go over the subject of home appraisals and what you need to know about them.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title> Protesting Your Taxes This Year? Watch This First. </title>
        <link>localhost:4000/houston-real-estate-agent-how-to.html</link>
        
          <category>houston real estate</category>
        
        <author>Mike Gray</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-21 11:05:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

February is already here and that means it’s time to prepare for tax season. Today I’ll go over a couple ways to protest your property taxes if you need to.

There are two ways to protest your property taxes: hiring a company or doing it yourself. If you hire a company, they will take a percentage, so I’m going to give you a few tips on doing it yourself.

When you get the letter in the mail, you will send it back after checking to make sure you feel your property is over market value and that it’s not equivalent to other properties. If you only check one box, you can only protest under that pretense.

You also want to get a package from the county that shows what they will use against you. Do your research and find out what properties they will use to hold up their argument that your property is worth what was stated in the letter. They may use properties that are in a better location or that you know are worth more because of the age or updates. The more you know, the better prepared you’ll be.

If there is anything wrong with your property, take pictures. Some issues may be an old A/C unit, old roof, or anything that will help you determine that your home value is a little bit less. Make sure you take film photos instead of digital photos so you can physically present the pictures.

“THE MORE YOU KNOW, THE BETTER PREPARED YOU’LL BE.”

If you go to a formal hearing, bring five copies of your package with you. You’ll need three for the people representing the county, one to submit to the Harris County Appraisal District, and one for yourself.

You also want to bring a satellite photo. If your property is on a busy street or backs up to a commercial property, the satellite photo will show that it’s in a worse location.

Make sure you research the tax value of a home in your neighborhood and on your street. Are they of equal value? Are they being assessed the same? If they’re not, why not?

Additionally, wait until closer to the end of your protest time to submit your papers. If you submit your papers too early, you won’t have the chance to go and see if other properties similar to yours in your neighborhood have been reduced in value.

This is a great year to protest taxes, so if you have any questions, please feel free to reach out to me. I’m always happy to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

February is already here and that means it’s time to prepare for tax season. Today I’ll go over a couple ways to protest your property taxes if you need to.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mike Gray</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

February is already here and that means it’s time to prepare for tax season. Today I’ll go over a couple ways to protest your property taxes if you need to.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Has Happened in Houston Real Estate This Year?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/houston-real-estate-agent-quick-update.html</link>
        
          <category>houston real estate</category>
        
        <author>Mike Gray</author>
        <pubDate>2016-12-20 16:01:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

I am excited to bring you an update on the Houston real estate market as we near the end of 2016. Before we get to that, I just wanted to take a moment to thank everyone so much for their great support this year. I’m grateful for you, and it has been a pleasure to serve you.

Now, I want to talk about two things that have been happening in the real estate market you should be aware of.

The first thing is that the election is over. There has been a big sigh of relief now that it has finished. We have actually seen an uptick in activity since the results came out. Ultimately, we will have to wait until the first of the year to see how the numbers shake out.

The second thing is that increase in interest rates. They have increased significantly in the last 30 to 45 days. They were in the mid-3% range, but are now over 4%. Right now, you can get a 30-year fixed rate loan for 4.25%.

“WE’LL KEEP A CLOSE EYE ON THINGS FOR YOU.”

If you’re a buyer in Houston, be aware that we are expecting a positive movement and gradual increase in price and rates. This will affect affordability, especially for first-time buyers. However, we don’t expect this to have a negative impact on homeowners. If you look back at the last time we had a big interest rate movement, you will see that homes appreciated by 10% as a result. We will keep a close eye on this and we will be back with some projections in January.

We hope you have a merry Christmas, a happy Hanukkah, and a joyous New Year. Enjoy the holidays and we will see you in 2017. If you have any questions for me in the meantime, I’m just a phone call or email away. Talk to you soon!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

I am excited to bring you an update on the Houston real estate market as we near the end of 2016. Before we get to that, I just wanted to take a moment to thank everyone so much for their great support this year. I’m grateful for you, and it has been a pleasure to serve you.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mike Gray</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

I am excited to bring you an update on the Houston real estate market as we near the end of 2016. Before we get to that, I just wanted to take a moment to thank everyone so much for their great support this year. I’m grateful for you, and it has been a pleasure to serve you.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Where Is the Houston Market Headed?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/houston-real-estate-agent-november.html</link>
        
          <category>Houston Real Estate Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Mike Gray</author>
        <pubDate>2016-11-08 09:47:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

As you may have already seen, it’s been a very interesting year in the Houston real estate market.

August was a huge, record-breaking month, and in September, we were down by mere fractions. We’re still waiting for this October’s numbers still, but we know we’re up on a year over year basis. The average sales price of Houston homes is up 2% from last year, so we’re still seeing positive things in the market.

We do, however, think Upstream Energy is going to continue to be a bit of a drag on the market. Oil is back down, so there could be issues to work through into next year. When it comes to inventory, we’re currently at about four months, which is very low compared to the rest of the nation. To get a good idea of the market, though, you have to break it down by neighborhood. Some neighborhoods have very low inventory while others (especially in the oil sector) have very high inventory.

I also wanted to address the people who are thinking about selling their homes and considering waiting until spring to do so. This may or may not be the right thing to do. If you’re considering selling over the winter, I’d advise you to look at the inventory you’re competing against. How many signs are up in your neighbors’ yards? Some people think that winter is a bad time to sell, but we don’t have harsh winters here.

“WINTER COULD ACTUALLY BE THE PERFECT TIME TO SELL.”

The reality is that winter could be a great time for you to sell. Many times, December is our biggest month. That’s because winter buyers are truly motivated buyers; people don’t just go out and look at homes for fun between Thanksgiving and New Year’s. Buyers are also more serious at this time because they want to get their homestead exemption for this year’s taxes; you need to be in the home by January 1st to do that.

And on a final note, I have an interesting factoid for you: for the seventh year in a row, Houston is the number one destination for U-Haul trucks. You can look at U-Haul maps and see that there are a ton of lines coming in and not many going out, so we’re still a go-to city!

If you have any questions about these topics or you’re thinking about buying or selling a home in the Houston area, give me a call or send me an email today. I’d love to hear from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

As you may have already seen, it’s been a very interesting year in the Houston real estate market.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mike Gray</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

As you may have already seen, it’s been a very interesting year in the Houston real estate market.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Do Property Values Differ on Your Tax Bill? </title>
        <link>localhost:4000/houston-real-estate-agent-how-property.html</link>
        
          <category>Houston Real Estate Other</category>
        
        <author>Mike Gray</author>
        <pubDate>2016-10-11 12:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

What’s the difference between the market value and the appraised value of your property when you look at a tax bill?

The market value is what the country district thinks the property will sell for. They determine this by looking at comparable properties around the area. The appraised value is the value that you pay taxes on.

The appraised value could be lower based on any exemptions you might have. If you have a homestead exemption, for example, you’re going to be capped based on that value increasing 10% every year. If you’re not protesting your taxes, then that value could go up considerably.

“THE APPRAISED VALUE COULD BE LOWER BASED ON ANY EXEMPTIONS YOU MIGHT HAVE.”

You can’t protest taxes now—that happens after the beginning of next year when the new values come out, and it’s what the property is deemed to be worth on January 1st. The market has slowed a bit this year, so we’ll have to see what the values show next year.

If you have any more questions regarding this topic, please feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

What’s the difference between the market value and the appraised value of your property when you look at a tax bill?

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mike Gray</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

What’s the difference between the market value and the appraised value of your property when you look at a tax bill?

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Tips for Anyone That May Be in or Near Flood Areas</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/houston-real-estate-agent-is-your-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Houston Real Estate Homeowner Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mike Gray</author>
        <pubDate>2016-08-11 15:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

It’s no secret that recent flooding has devastated homes in the Houston area. Flood insurance has become a hot topic as of late, so we invited Mr. Li-Hsi “Leash” Yu, the president of Agency Yu, Inc., to come and talk to us about some benefits of having flood insurance that you may not even know you have.

It’s easy to say everyone should buy flood insurance, so today we’re going to discuss the severe repetitive loss database. If your home has flooded multiple times in the past, it may be on this database. It sounds bad, but it was created by FEMA to watch your claim activity and has some great benefits. If your home has flooded more than four times since 1978 and two of those floods were within 10 years of each other and repairs costed more than $5,000, your house is more than likely already on the list.

If your home is on the list, FEMA may provide funds to raise your home, buy it back, or make it less susceptible to floods in general. It would behoove a homeowner or a person that’s about to buy a home to see if the address is on the severe repetitive loss database. It could be very beneficial in the decision-making process.

“IF YOU ARE ON THE LIST, YOU SHOULD HAVE GOTTEN NOTICE AT RENEWAL.”

If you are on the list, you should have gotten notice at renewal of your flood insurance. If you haven’t received one or you’re curious if your home may be on the list, ask your insurance agent. If you’re buying a home and getting a flood insurance quote, it should disclose whether or not the home is on the database.

This isn’t a new program, it’s been around for quite a while. However, with the recent multiple floods, we think it’s a good thing for you to keep on your mind. One important note about the severe repetitive loss database is that if two floods happened within 10 days of each other, FEMA only considers that as one claim.

If you or someone you know has had to deal with repetitive flooding, you should give Leash a call. He can be reached at (713)-688-8881 or Leash@AgencyYu.com

If you have any other questions for us or if you’re looking to buy or sell a home in Houston, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

It’s no secret that recent flooding has devastated homes in the Houston area. Flood insurance has become a hot topic as of late, so we invited Mr. Li-Hsi “Leash” Yu, the president of Agency Yu, Inc., to come and talk to us about some benefits of having flood insurance that you may not even know you have.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mike Gray</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

It’s no secret that recent flooding has devastated homes in the Houston area. Flood insurance has become a hot topic as of late, so we invited Mr. Li-Hsi “Leash” Yu, the president of Agency Yu, Inc., to come and talk to us about some benefits of having flood insurance that you may not even know you have.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Could Your Stucco Be Damaging Your Houston Home?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/houston-real-estate-agent-is-your.html</link>
        
          <category>Houston Real Estate Homeowner Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mike Gray</author>
        <pubDate>2016-07-07 16:28:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

We’ve had a lot of questions lately about stucco from buyers and sellers in Houston, so I wanted to address the topic today. Today I’m joined by Kevin Harbison from Stucco Spec, our go-to guy for home inspections.

First we want to differentiate between the two types of stucco: cement-based (which we refer to as real stucco) and synthetic stucco (referred to as EIFS) which is made out of foam and a thin rendering of cement. The real stucco is actually concrete, and is thicker.

Most people don’t dislike stucco as a material itself but tend to dislike the way it is applied and maintained. The problem with stucco is water intrusion. For example, if a window is not caulked properly, water can get in behind the stucco and cause structural damage. Another important detail on homes for preventing water intrusion is flashing, which kicks away water and keeps it away from the house.

“WINDOWS SHOULD BE RESEALED EVERY FIVE TO SIX YEARS.”

Heat plays a factor here in Houston as well. It takes a toll on caulking, so windows should be resealed every five to six years, according to Kevin. There are specific sealants used, so he recommends always using a professional waterproofing company. If you have a stucco home that hasn’t received maintenance in six to 10 years, you want to walk around the home for a self-inspection. Check that your sealants are intact and soil is not touching the bottom of the stucco walls. You can always hire a proven professional like Kevin to make sure the inspection is done right.

If you have more questions about stucco or you’re interested in a stucco inspection, you can reach Kevin through Stucco Spec’s website. If you have real estate questions or are thinking about buying or selling a home, give me a call and let’s talk soon!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

We’ve had a lot of questions lately about stucco from buyers and sellers in Houston, so I wanted to address the topic today. Today I’m joined by Kevin Harbison from Stucco Spec, our go-to guy for home inspections.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mike Gray</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

We’ve had a lot of questions lately about stucco from buyers and sellers in Houston, so I wanted to address the topic today. Today I’m joined by Kevin Harbison from Stucco Spec, our go-to guy for home inspections.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Latest News in Houston Real Estate </title>
        <link>localhost:4000/houston-real-estate-what-to-expect-from.html</link>
        
          <category>Houston Real Estate Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Mike Gray</author>
        <pubDate>2016-05-09 15:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

This year, the numbers for the first quarter are down compared to last year. 2015 was a record year, so we anticipated these differences.

The $1 million and above price range is struggling right now. This category has seen an increase in inventory and a slowdown in sales. In fact, some areas in this price range have up to two years of inventory.

If you are trying to sell a home in that market, understand you should price according to market trends. Price according to where the market is going, not where the market has been. Otherwise, your property can sit on the market much longer than you anticipate.

“Price your home according to market trends.”

On the other hand, homes priced under $500,000 are in a hot market! Homes are selling quickly. Depending on the part of town you’re in, you may be seeing a lot of multiple offer situations.

This year, we predict home sales will decrease around 10% compared to 2015. Overall, the market favors buyers. Buyers will have more time to look at properties and ultimately, have more options to choose from. We are headed toward a more balanced market. Since Houston is so large, the market varies depending on where you are.

If you’re a buyer, now is a great time to buy. If you’re a seller, home prices are still trending upward, so it’s still a great time to sell. Prices aren’t appreciating as quickly as they did last year.

If you have any other questions, give me a call or send me an email. Additionally, if you were unfortunate enough to get water damage from all the rain last week, please reach out to us. We can put you in touch with contractors to help you with that. I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

This year, the numbers for the first quarter are down compared to last year. 2015 was a record year, so we anticipated these differences.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mike Gray</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

This year, the numbers for the first quarter are down compared to last year. 2015 was a record year, so we anticipated these differences.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Avoid Paying Higher Taxes on Your Houston Home</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/houston-real-estate-agent-tips-for.html</link>
        
          <category>Houston Real Estate Homeowner Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mike Gray</author>
        <pubDate>2016-04-13 13:12:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Tax season is here, and the biggest questions we’ve received lately have to do with protesting your taxes. If you’ve seen what I’ve seen, property tax assessments in the Houston area have gone up again. My short answer? Yes, you should protest your property taxes! I do every year because I want to keep my bases low.

There are a few options out there for people who want to protest their taxes. First, you can do it on your own, which means you’re going to go, sit down with HCAD, and try to convince them why your property taxes are too high. I don’t have the time to do this, so I usually hire a third party to do it for me. I have had some mixed success going that route, but I feel it’s worth it.

Although we’re in a normalizing market, property taxes have continued to go up. If you have a homesteaded property, they can go up no more than 10% plus any improvements you’ve made. In some cases, improvements to your home can increase your tax burden substantially. Even if you haven’t made improvements, these higher assessments will cost more and more money as the years go by.

“We highly recommend that everyone contests their property taxes.”

In short, we highly recommend that everyone contests their property taxes, especially if you have the time. If you’re interested in a third party to protest your taxes on your behalf, I would be happy to put you in touch with a great company I use. They typically charge 50% of what they end up saving you; if they don’t save you any money, you don’t have to pay them anything, so it’s not a bad deal.

If you have questions about this or any other topic, please don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We would love to hear from you soon!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mike Gray</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Mike Gray</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Mike Gray</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Mike Gray Team - your professional Houston Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
