<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Central PA Real Estate Podcast with Dave Hooke</title>
    <link>localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Dave Hooke Team LLC - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Dave Hooke</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2018-02-21 16:47:55 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Dave Hooke</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://i.imgur.com/EQG8hR1.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">News &amp; Politics</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Dave@hhande.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Dave Hooke</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://i.imgur.com/EQG8hR1.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the  Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Dave Hooke Team LLC - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="News &amp; Politics"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>4 Ways to Determine Home Value</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/4-ways-to-determine-home-value.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Dave Hooke</author>
        <pubDate>2018-02-20 17:00:42 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/+Video/2018/February/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+4+Ways+to+Determine+Home+Value.mp4</guid>
        <description>

How do you determine your home’s value? Today, we’ll be going over four different ways to do so. 

1. Assessed value. Simply go into your county’s tax assessment database. If you live in Cumberland County, for example, the website is www.CCPA.net. In most counties, the database will give you a summary of the tax assessment you’re paying your property taxes on. However, there is typically a margin of error involved in the county-assessed tax value of your home. Thankfully, it is possible to dispute your taxes and get them lowered if you can provide evidence that you are being overcharged. 

“While online valuation tools are commonly used to determine value, they do possess a margin of error.”

2. Online valuation tool. This common method of determining home value, which includes tools like Zillow’s Zestimate feature, has a significant margin of error. However, these online tools can be a good place to start if you’re simply looking for an estimate. Along with Zillow, you can also visit the valuation tool on my website. You can do so by visiting www.ViewCentralPAHouses.com and clicking on the “What’s Your Home Worth?” link.

3. Appraisal. Unlike the first two methods I listed, this option is not free. However, appraisals will provide you with a much more accurate result. Nevertheless, an appraisal is still only an opinion. If 10 different appraisers were to give you their opinion on your property, you would receive 10 different answers. 

4. Comparative market analysis. Like an appraisal, a comparative market analysis is an opinion of value. Instead of an appraiser, though, the opinion you receive using this method will come from a Realtor. When an agent performs this typically free service, they will review the interior of your home and then compare your property to similar homes in the surrounding area. It’s based on this information that they will determine your home’s value. 

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/+Video/2018/February/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+4+Ways+to+Determine+Home+Value.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/+Video/2018/February/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+4+Ways+to+Determine+Home+Value.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What are four methods you can use to determine your home’s value? Let’s find out.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What are four methods you can use to determine your home’s value? Let’s find out.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Does the Housing Shortage Mean to Buyers and Sellers?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/what-does-the-housing-shortage-mean-to-buyers-and-sellers.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Dave Hooke</author>
        <pubDate>2018-02-06 09:25:34 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/+Video/2018/February/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+Does+the+Housing+Shortage+Mean+to+Buyers+and+Sellers%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you live in South Central Pennsylvania, or in a number of different markets across the country, you’re probably experiencing a low-inventory market right now. Right now, we have about 40% less home inventory than we had at this point last year. That’s a significant shortage and something we haven’t seen in quite some time.

There are a number of reasons for this shortage. One that comes to mind is the recession’s effect on home building. It now takes builders and developers more time to get permits and construction can be slow to start out. If demand has eaten up the available inventory already, that could really affect the supply.

“This presents a fantastic opportunity for home sellers.”

The shortage means different things to you if you’re a buyer than if you’re a seller. If you’re a seller, this is a fantastic opportunity to get your home on the market. You can get closer to your asking price than ever before and have a quick closing, too. As long as your home isn’t overpriced, that is. Overpriced homes don’t sell in any kind of market.

If you’re a buyer on the other hand, there will be some challenges no doubt. When you find the right home, however, you should be prepared to act quickly or else someone will get the property before you.

If you’re thinking about selling your home in the spring market, I’d be happy to offer you a free, personalized home value estimate for the entire month of February. Just give me a call or send me an email and I’d be glad to help you out. If you have any other questions in the meantime, don’t hesitate to contact me.  I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/+Video/2018/February/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+Does+the+Housing+Shortage+Mean+to+Buyers+and+Sellers%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/+Video/2018/February/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+Does+the+Housing+Shortage+Mean+to+Buyers+and+Sellers%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Our market is suffering from low inventory. This presents a unique opportunity for sellers, however.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Our market is suffering from low inventory. This presents a unique opportunity for sellers, however.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3 Things You Can Control to Make Your House Saleable</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/3-things-you-can-control-to-make-your-house-saleable.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Dave Hooke</author>
        <pubDate>2018-01-22 06:08:58 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/+Video/2018/January/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+3+Things+You+Can+Control+to+Make+Your+House+Saleable.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There are three factors that are within a seller’s control that, if unaddressed, could prevent their home from selling.

1. Whether or not you’ve hired a broker or you’ve hired the right broker. If nobody knows that your home is for sale, nobody is going to buy it. The marketing of your property is what the broker should be doing to get your listing in front of as many consumers as possible. The quality of their marketing strategy matters as well, so evaluate exactly what it is your broker is doing to market your property.

2. The condition of your home. Not every house needs to be upgraded. You could have a house that’s well maintained where increasing the condition might make it sell for more money, but you won’t actually get a return on that investment. There are certain things you can do with regards to the condition that will improve the likelihood of your home’s sale, such as cosmetic repairs, staging, and professional cleaning. Ask your agent whether or not the project you want to begin will actually be worth the investment.

“If your property sits too long beyond the average days on market, studies show that you can end up with a below-market value sale.”

3. Price or patience? If you have a low motivation and don’t really care whether or not your home will sell, you can always wait long enough for the market to appreciated up to your price. Here’s a warning, however: if your property sits too long beyond the average days on market, studies show that you can end up with a below-market value sale. People will start to look at that property with suspicion—what’s wrong with it?—and it will stagnate. With that in mind, we always counsel people to price their property correctly to begin with, which increases the probability of an at-market or even above-market sale.

If you have any questions about these factors or anything else to do with real estate, including a free home value estimate or consultation, feel free to reach out to us. One of our team members will follow up as quickly as possible. Have a great day!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/+Video/2018/January/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+3+Things+You+Can+Control+to+Make+Your+House+Saleable.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/+Video/2018/January/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+3+Things+You+Can+Control+to+Make+Your+House+Saleable.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There are three things that can prevent a home from selling, all three of which are entirely under the seller’s control.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There are three things that can prevent a home from selling, all three of which are entirely under the seller’s control.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Does a Day in the Life of a Real Estate Agent Look Like?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/what-does-a-day-in-the-life-of-a-real-estate-agent-look-like.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Dave Hooke</author>
        <pubDate>2018-01-08 10:14:53 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/+Video/2018/January/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+Does+a+Day+in+the+Life+of+a+Real+Estate+Agent+Look+Like%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What does a typical day in the life of a real estate agent look like?

It really depends on whether the agent is a part-time agent or a full-time agent who is always busy. Today, I’ll give you a snapshot of the life of a full-time agent.

The first thing most agents do is wake up and go to the office. Agents can go to the office as early as 7 a.m., or they may get to the office at 9 a.m.

One of the first things they do when they get there is return any urgent emails or things that have come in from the night before.

As soon as they get through those, they will start generating more leads. Like any small business owner, the most important thing a real estate agent can do is keep their client base growing. Otherwise, they’ll run out of business. A typical agent spends about an hour and a half or two hours prospecting for new business.

“Agents don’t just show homes all day every day.”

Prospecting can take 10 or 12 different forms, from calling past clients to check in or asking for referrals all the way down to handwritten notes or marketing activities, like social media posts and website inquiry follow-up.

Once that’s done, the agent will get back to returning emails, phone calls, and text messages from clients, title companies, lenders, home inspectors, etc.

If they have time, the agent will take a lunch break. It can be hard to take a lunch as a full-time agent because our days tend to be a little chaotic.

After lunch, the agent will return remaining phone calls and emails before going on appointments. Appointments and showings are usually reserved for afternoons and evenings. If there aren’t any appointments until the evening, we might do some research. We might figure out the market value of a home or do analytical offer research, where we figure out what the house is worth before we help a buyer structure an offer.

Then, we go and do what everyone thinks agents do all day: We show homes or go on listing appointments. We don’t have showings or listing appointments every day, but we do have a few throughout the week.

Sometimes, agents are able to get home at a reasonable hour for dinner with the family. However, we often have to meet clients in the evening or on weekends for showings and listing appointments.

As a full-time agent, you have to be super flexible with your schedule. It’s important to have conversations with your spouse to make sure that you are both on the same page and can handle that flexible schedule.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/+Video/2018/January/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+Does+a+Day+in+the+Life+of+a+Real+Estate+Agent+Look+Like%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/+Video/2018/January/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+Does+a+Day+in+the+Life+of+a+Real+Estate+Agent+Look+Like%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What’s it like to be a full-time real estate agent? Today, I’ll give you a snapshot of a day in the life of a full-time agent.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What’s it like to be a full-time real estate agent? Today, I’ll give you a snapshot of a day in the life of a full-time agent.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Should You Budget Your Monthly Housing Allowance?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-should-you-budget-your-monthly-housing-allowance.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Dave Hooke</author>
        <pubDate>2017-12-21 09:20:09 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/+Video/2017/December/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Should+You+Budget+Your+Monthly+Housing+Allowance%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What percentage of your monthly income should you be spending on housing?

Here’s the thing: When you get pre-approved for a home loan or you talk to a bank about a mortgage, they’re typically going to figure out the maximum that they can approve you for. To calculate that, they’ll take your total monthly debt obligations and add that to your proposed monthly payment, which is principal interest, property taxes, and insurance (PITI).

When they get those two numbers and add them up, they like to see those two numbers be less than about 42% of your gross monthly income. That depends on your credit and a number of other variables, so talk to your mortgage broker to find out exactly what that percentage is.

Use that 42% as a rule of thumb—42% of your monthly income can be allocated for housing and debt obligations monthly.

“If you can stay below 32% of your gross monthly income, you’ll generally have some margin to plan for things that can’t be planned for.”

The next question is: Is that helpful for you and your family in the future? I always suggest that our clients don’t go up to that 42% mark. If you do, you’re typically going to have trouble saving and creating an emergency fund if something were to go wrong. It’s easy to get stressed out if you don’t have any margin in your budget at all.

We typically advise our clients, even though they may be pre-approved up to 42% of their gross monthly income, to keep their monthly debt obligations and housing allowance below about 32%. Way back in the 80s, the number was actually 25%. Its gone up for a number of reasons.

If you can stay below 32%, you’ll generally have some margin to plan for things that can’t be planned for. Obviously this differs from person to person; some people may expect to get a raise in the near future or pay off a loan. You should talk to your accountant or financial advisor just to make sure you run a budget before you make a final decision.

If you have any questions about real estate or anything at all, reach out to us by phone or email. We’ll follow up and take great care of you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/+Video/2017/December/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Should+You+Budget+Your+Monthly+Housing+Allowance%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/+Video/2017/December/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Should+You+Budget+Your+Monthly+Housing+Allowance%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>How much should you be spending each month on your housing payments? I have the answer.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>How much should you be spending each month on your housing payments? I have the answer.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Steps Can You Take to Protect Yourself Against the Equifax Hack?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/what-steps-can-you-take-to-protect-yourself-against-the-equifax-hack.html</link>
        
        <author>Dave Hooke</author>
        <pubDate>2017-12-07 04:28:14 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/+Video/2017/December/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+Steps+Can+You+Take+to+Protect+Yourself+Against+the+Equifax+Hack%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Roughly 143 million Americans were affected by the recent Equifax hack. If you’re like many of these people, you might be concerned enough about your personal data to have already taken steps to limit the damage.

But what if you’re entering the home buying process or, worse yet, have already signed a contract or applied for a loan?

If this is the case, the fallout could be extensive. For example, if you’ve signed a contract to buy a house and have applied for a mortgage and a fraudulent account starts to add a significant amount of debt in your name, that could negatively affect your credit score, delay your settlement, or cancel the loan altogether.

“There are three possible steps you can take to ensure your financial security.”

There are three possible steps you can take to ensure your financial security if you’re considering buying a home now or you’re in the home buying process:

1. Check your information. Even if you never used Equifax directly, they could still have your personal information. You can visit this website to see if you’ve been affected. You also have the option to enroll in their TrustedID Premier credit monitoring service.

2. Call your lender right away and let them know you may have been affected.

3. Consider doing a “credit freeze.” This is the most extreme method of preventing your information from getting stolen, but it’s also the most effective. If you don’t want to lock out all creditors, you can place a 90-day fraud alert on your credit that tells creditors to verify your identity before issuing any credit in your name.

If you have any questions about this or any other real estate topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/+Video/2017/December/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+Steps+Can+You+Take+to+Protect+Yourself+Against+the+Equifax+Hack%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/+Video/2017/December/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+Steps+Can+You+Take+to+Protect+Yourself+Against+the+Equifax+Hack%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re considering buying a home now or you’re in the home buying process, there are three possible steps you can take to ensure your financial security against the recent Equifax hack.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re considering buying a home now or you’re in the home buying process, there are three possible steps you can take to ensure your financial security against the recent Equifax hack.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The 3 Steps to Buying and Selling at the Same Time</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/the-3-steps-to-buying-and-selling-at-the-same-time.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Dave Hooke</author>
        <pubDate>2017-11-10 06:43:26 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/+Video/2017/November/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+3+Steps+to+Buying+and+Selling+at+the+Same+Time.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What are the three steps to buying and selling a home at the same time?

First, call a real estate agent so they can do a market analysis and give your home a value estimate. That will lay the foundation for what kind of equity you have to work with and help you determine if you can afford to buy a home before you sell your current one.

“Before you do anything, call a real estate agent.”

The second step is to talk to a trusted mortgage advisor to determine what mortgage financing options are out there for you and you can know what your down payment and closing costs expenses will be (or your cash outlay) when you make your purchase.

Third, reconsult with that same Realtor and give them the information you received about your down payment and closing cost expenses so you can compare it to the equity you have in your current home.

From there, you can make a final decision about what to do. There are two main options you can choose from.

The first is to buy a new home before selling your current one. Typically, you’ll use the equity in your home to cover the down payment and closing costs expenses.

Your next option is to sell your current home before you buy your next one. If you do this, your Realtor might advise you to add a contingency to the listing that makes the sale contingent on you finding suitable housing. This will ensure you’re not left without a place to stay in between transactions.

Hopefully, this gives you some context on buying and selling at the same time. If you or someone you know has any questions about this or any other real estate topic, don’t hesitate to give me a call or shoot me an email. I’d be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/+Video/2017/November/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+3+Steps+to+Buying+and+Selling+at+the+Same+Time.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/+Video/2017/November/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+3+Steps+to+Buying+and+Selling+at+the+Same+Time.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There are three steps you need to take if you want to buy and sell a home at the same time. These steps will make your course of action clear and simple.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There are three steps you need to take if you want to buy and sell a home at the same time. These steps will make your course of action clear and simple.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Should I Buy or Rent?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/should-i-buy-or-rent.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Dave Hooke</author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-27 05:50:04 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/+Video/2017/October/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+Should+I+Buy+or+Rent%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

We’d like to help you answer the question, “Is it better to buy or rent a home?” Generally speaking, there are obvious benefits to homeownership. For example, The Fed recently issued their Survey of Consumer Finances, in which they observed that homeowners on average have a net worth 36 times higher than that of home renters. From that perspective, the sooner you move into homeownership, the better!

Of course, there are other factors to consider. We’d like you to ask yourself three specific questions in determining whether this is the right time for you to buy a home.

1. Is it affordable? You can get a sense of affordability by examining your debt and income. If you add up your monthly debts (car and phone payments, credit card and utility bills, etc.) plus your projected house payment (monthly insurance, taxes, principle and interest) and then divide that by your gross income, you will get a percentage. In considering you for home financing, most banks will want that percentage to be below 42%. The lower this percentage, the better, as with a wider margin you will be able to save more of your income for emergencies. Another factor to consider regarding affordability is whether you have enough savings to cover the down payment plus the closing costs. While it’s better to have that money on hand, keep in mind there are creative mortgage programs that offer 0% down and 100% financing. We can help you explore those options.

“The Fed recently issued their Survey of Consumer Finances, in which they observed that homeowners on average have a net worth 36 times higher than that of home renters.”

2. How’s my credit? Finding your credit score is easy. There are a lot of credit reporting agencies out there. If you’d like help in choosing a credit agency to work with, contact us and we can introduce you to an agency that will provide a credit check. We can introduce you to a credit lender who will provide a free credit check and help you determine if your credit is healthy enough to make a home purchase.

3. Is the timing right? In considering homeownership, there are personal factors that may make buying a home difficult. For example, if it’s likely you may be moving again in three to five years, it may not be a good time to buy because you probably won’t recoup your closing costs when you resell your new home. But if you’re planning on staying for seven (or more) years, there’s a really good chance that the average annual appreciation is going to overcome your initial closing cost expense and leave you in a good financial position when you resell.

If you have any other questions about renting versus owning a home, or any other questions at all, please feel free to contact us. We offer free consultations and would love to talk to you at (717) 216-0860 or online at dave@hhande.com.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/+Video/2017/October/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+Should+I+Buy+or+Rent%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/+Video/2017/October/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+Should+I+Buy+or+Rent%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here are three questions you can ask yourself to determine if now’s the time for you to buy a home.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here are three questions you can ask yourself to determine if now’s the time for you to buy a home.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Has Our Local Market Changed Since 2016?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-has-our-local-market-changed-since-2016.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Dave Hooke</author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-13 07:18:40 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/+Video/2017/October/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Has+Our+Local+Market+Changed+Since+2016%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What’s been going on in the South Central Pennsylvania real estate market? Today, let’s take a look.

To see where we are, I’d like to compare the current numbers to what we saw last year. It’s actually a great time to be a seller in our area.

First of all, there were about 8,600 properties listed in our area between January and August of this year. Last year, that number was 9,200.

That isn’t the only number that has changed. In that same period in 2017, 6,466 properties were sold, compared to 6,399 properties from January through August of last year.

“It’s a great time to be a seller in our area.”

This shows us that there’s been an increase in demand but also a decrease of supply. Also, the number of sold homes has increased to 75%, meaning there’s been a 7% increase in sales.

Next comes my favorite statistic of those I’ve listed so far. Last year, the average sale price was $191,000, but this year it has increased to $201,000.

However, the average days on market has declined. Now, the average is 72 days in South Central Pennsylvania.

As a final note, the number of expired listings has decreased by 10%.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/+Video/2017/October/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Has+Our+Local+Market+Changed+Since+2016%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/+Video/2017/October/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Has+Our+Local+Market+Changed+Since+2016%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What’s been going on in our South Central Pennsylvania real estate market? Let’s take a look at some recent numbers.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What’s been going on in our South Central Pennsylvania real estate market? Let’s take a look at some recent numbers.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3 Reasons Your Home Isn’t Selling</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/3-reasons-your-home-isnt-selling.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Dave Hooke</author>
        <pubDate>2017-09-27 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/+Video/2017/September/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+3+Reasons+Your+Home+Isnt+Selling.mp4</guid>
        <description>

A lot of things can prevent a home from selling, but there are three of them that are within your control:

1. Marketing. This is our specialty. If you don’t have a broker or agent who is marketing your property, it’s likely not going to attract enough demand to sell. Even if you price it extremely low, the home still might not sell if the right buyer doesn’t see it. The higher quality marketing you have, the more reach your listing will have. If your home is out there on a ton of different websites and advertised with professional photography, it will drive demand and encourage more offers.

“You need all three of these things working together.”

2. Condition. You can have the best marketing in the world but if your home is in poor condition, it’s not going to sell. Decluttering and staging are important tasks to complete. Touching up paint, patching holes, and deep cleaning are also must-dos. The more desirable the condition, the more desirable the home is.

3. Price. If you’ve got good marketing and good condition but a ridiculously high price, the home won’t sell. It will just sit on the market. You can reduce the price, or you can wait a few years for a different market and (possibly) more appreciation.

These three things affect your home sale as much as anything else. If you have any questions at all, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We would love to hear from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/+Video/2017/September/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+3+Reasons+Your+Home+Isnt+Selling.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/+Video/2017/September/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+3+Reasons+Your+Home+Isnt+Selling.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>You can’t control everything when it comes time to sell your home. You can control these three important factors, however.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>You can’t control everything when it comes time to sell your home. You can control these three important factors, however.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Shouldn't You Do When Buying a Home?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/what-shouldnt-you-do-when-buying-a-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Dave Hooke</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-29 05:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/+Video/2017/August/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+Shouldn%2527t+You+Do+When+Buying+a+Home%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When it comes to buying a home, many people tend to research tips on what they should be sure to do throughout the process. Today, however, I’ll talk about six things you shouldn’t do when buying a home.

1. Don’t buy a home without an agent. In most states, you’re entitled to a buyer’s agent. Listing agents represent the best interests of the sellers, as opposed to being primarily concerned with yours. When you begin the process of searching for a home, interview a few different agents who are highly recommended within your community. Preferably, you should find someone with strong references you can call. It’s also important that your agent’s personality meshes well with your own.

2. Don’t use the first mortgage lender you speak with. Any professional you work with should be someone you click with. As is the case with your agent, interview a few different people to make sure you are going to be working with someone who will be able to provide you quality, customized service.

3. Don’t understate your budget. When you’re hiring the professionals mentioned in the first and second steps, be sure to provide them with truthful information. You want to find a home that will truly meet your needs.

“It’s important that your agent’s personality meshes well with your own.”

4. Don’t make lowball offers. While some people may think that this is a good way to negotiate, it can actually drive away sellers and break a deal entirely. Instead, make a reasonably low offer that is structured with a couple of wins for the seller. The offer should provide benefits, whether with contingencies or otherwise, to the seller, while still being a good deal for you. A reasonable offer is more likely to land you with a response you’re happy with, even if it’s still a little low.

5. Don’t forget to budget for closing costs. Closing costs should be factored in before you become too serious about a given house. When considering whether to buy a particular home, have a discussion with your agent and mortgage lender about what the closing costs might look like so that you can have a better idea of what you’ll be paying, in total, at the end of the deal.

6. Don’t make big purchases after contract. Large, costly purchases can be detrimental to your credit. Things like trips, appliances, or furniture can actually affect your loan approval. Hold off on purchases like these until after closing.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/+Video/2017/August/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+Shouldn%2527t+You+Do+When+Buying+a+Home%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/+Video/2017/August/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+Shouldn%2527t+You+Do+When+Buying+a+Home%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>When buying a home, there are certain things you should absolutely avoid. Today, I’ll be discussing six things not to do during the home purchase process.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>When buying a home, there are certain things you should absolutely avoid. Today, I’ll be discussing six things not to do during the home purchase process.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 Factors to Think About When Flipping a Home</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/5-factors-to-think-about-when-flipping-a-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Dave Hooke</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-15 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/+Video/2017/August/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+Factors+to+Think+About+When+Flipping+a+Home.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you plan on flipping a home for profit, there are five variables that you should consider:

1. The seller’s motivations. If the seller is under duress or the property is owned by the bank, you will stand a better chance of buying low and maximizing your profit.

2. Location, location, location. It’s not the oldest adage in the real estate industry for nothing. Make sure that the property you’re buying is in a location, area, or community where home values are trending upward. Do your market research and verify that before you do your property flip.

3. The design of the property as it relates to supply and demand. For example, in South Central Pennsylvania, a lot of people are looking to downsize into one-level homes over the next decade due to the demographics of our population. Demand is very high for ranch homes or other single-level properties, but supply is low and there aren’t many new construction properties that meet this description. So, find a good area with a ranch home that you can flip for maximum profit.

“Do your market research and find an area where values are on the rise.”

4. Your offer structure. Remember, cash is king in the world of real estate. If you make a clean offer, you may be able to make the seller come down lower on the sale price. When at all possible, pay for your property with cash, don’t include any contingencies, and offer a quick settlement.

5. Risk versus reward. Sometimes it makes more sense to make a little bit of money in a short amount of time than it is to go for a highly speculative windfall that may take more time. Those types of properties only work if a number of variables fall into place. Even mature, experienced real estate investors typically avoid those big risks and hedge their bets on more certain real estate investments.

If you have any other questions about purchasing a property to flip or would like to see a list of foreclosure properties, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/+Video/2017/August/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+Factors+to+Think+About+When+Flipping+a+Home.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/+Video/2017/August/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+Factors+to+Think+About+When+Flipping+a+Home.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>How do you know which property to invest in if you plan on flipping houses? There are five factors you should consider.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>How do you know which property to invest in if you plan on flipping houses? There are five factors you should consider.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Does the Recent Rate Hike Affect the Real Estate Market?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-does-the-recent-rate-hike-affect-the-real-estate-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Dave Hooke</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-02 06:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/+Video/2017/August/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Does+the+Recent+Rate+Hike+Affect+the+Real+Estate+Market%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What does the Federal Reserve’s recent rate hike mean for real estate?

In June 2017, the Federal Reserve increased the federal funds rate by about 0.25%, and they’re expected to continue to do so over the course of 2017. Whenever there is movement by the Fed, it often garners a lot of attention, but I don’t think these increases will have a detrimental impact on real estate, at least in the short term.

Why?

For one thing, mortgage interest rates have actually moved down in the wake of the recent increase. In fact, it’s pretty common for mortgage interest rates to move in the opposite direction of the federal funds rate, at least in the short term, and this has happened the last couple of times the Fed increased its federal funds rate.

“The real estate market continues to be extremely healthy.”

Secondly, the economy continues to do relatively well. Unemployment is relatively low, household spending is up, and we’ve seen three years of growth. In those last three years, we’ve also seen increases in equity for homeowners all across the U.S. All of that equals potentially more stimulation for our economy.

Third, even though federal rate increases tend to cool off the economy, many experts believe that a number of variables particular to our situation point to a stimulation of our economy. Interest rates have been so low for so long that most experts think that increases in rates will ease pressure in the financial system and incentivize more mortgage lending. For example, since the Fed starting increasing their rates in December 2016, mortgage lending has increased overall by about 2.5% year over year.

In summary, the real estate market continues to be extremely healthy, whether you’re a buyer or a seller.

If you’re thinking about buying or selling a home or have any questions, please don’t hesitate to reach out to us by phone or email. We’d be happy to take care of you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/+Video/2017/August/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Does+the+Recent+Rate+Hike+Affect+the+Real+Estate+Market%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/+Video/2017/August/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Does+the+Recent+Rate+Hike+Affect+the+Real+Estate+Market%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Despite some misgivings, the recent federal funds rate increase is actually a good thing for our real estate market. Allow me to explain why.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Despite some misgivings, the recent federal funds rate increase is actually a good thing for our real estate market. Allow me to explain why.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Are 3 Easy Ways to Increase Your Home’s Value?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/what-are-3-easy-ways-to-increase-your-homes-value.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Dave Hooke</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-13 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/+Video/2017/July/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+Are+3+Easy+Ways+to+Increase+Your+Homes+Value%253F+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>

What are three simple ways you can increase your home’s value?

First, get handy. As homeowners, we can often get into a lull of letting small, non-urgent things go. Over time, these things can add up to being very urgent, large-ticket items that cost you thousands of dollars. When you see a minor maintenance item, make sure you fix it or get a handyman to do so. It will save you money and your home will sell for more money because it’ll look and feel better-maintained.

“Keeping your home well-maintained will save you time and money.”

Second, remember that cleanliness matters. There’s a huge correlation between the cleanliness of a home and a home that hasn’t been cleaned over time. Do yourself a favor and schedule a weekly full cleaning of your house so a habit is formed. Things like bugs and rodents that can get into your garage, basement, attic space, and other corners of your home that you don’t go into and can really add up over time. It also helps to have a contract with a pest control company.

Lastly, think outside the box. There’s another huge correlation between first impressions and the curb appeal of a house and what a property sells for. If you get into a habit of letting your lawn and other parts of your landscaping go, that can add up when it’s time to put your home on the market. Pay attention to your lawn, the mulching, the edging, the aerating, and other things like that. If those basic items are taken care of year after year, it shows buyers that you’ve maintained the exterior of your home, and it will correlate to an average of a 100% return on investment for both your time and money.

If you have any questions about increasing the value of your home or you’d like a free consultation, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d be happy to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/+Video/2017/July/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+Are+3+Easy+Ways+to+Increase+Your+Homes+Value%253F+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/+Video/2017/July/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+Are+3+Easy+Ways+to+Increase+Your+Homes+Value%253F+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you want to increase the value of your home, get handy, keep your house clean, and think outside the box regarding the exterior.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you want to increase the value of your home, get handy, keep your house clean, and think outside the box regarding the exterior.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Take These 3 Steps When Buying Your First House</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/take-these-3-steps-when-buying-your-first-house.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Dave Hooke</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-29 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Videos/2017/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+first-time+homebuyers+Real+Estate.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’re a new homebuyer, you can protect yourself by following these three tips.


  Know what you can afford: The cost of the house is only one cost in the overall transaction and homeownership. There are also closing costs, taxes, utilities, ongoing maintenance, insurance, and possibly even homeowners association fees that you need to factor into your budget. Once you have a clear picture of these costs, compare them to your monthly income to get the overall picture of what you can afford. 
  Choose your lender wisely: Don’t make the mistake of choosing a lender based solely on the lowest rate. Their level of experience in the industry and how well you connect with them personally also matter. A good lender can make a custom mortgage solution based on your financial profile, so choose wisely. I always recommend talking to friends or family members who have done this before for a referral. You can also ask your local real estate advisor. 
  Make sure not to overlook the details: We recommend whole house inspection contingencies and others in a real estate transaction. Be sure to look over the sales contract and don’t overlook the items in the ‘included’ or ‘excluded’ sections of it. That will help you ensure that you and the seller are on the same page in terms of what they intend to leave and what they intend to take. Additionally, things like zoning can go overlooked, which can be costly. Look up the zoning for your property so you understand it fully. 


“Even real estate consultants and attorneys can overlook things like reviewing the deed.”

Even real estate consultants and attorneys can overlook things like reviewing the deed and any restrictions that apply to the property you’re buying, so be sure to review all these details. If you have any questions or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home here in the Central Pennsylvania market, give us call or send us an email soon. We look forward to helping you.
 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Videos/2017/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+first-time+homebuyers+Real+Estate.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Videos/2017/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+first-time+homebuyers+Real+Estate.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you're buying your first home, take these three steps to protect yourself throughout the whole process.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you're buying your first home, take these three steps to protect yourself throughout the whole process.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Should I Have Real Estate in My Retirement?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/should-i-have-real-estate-in-my-retirement.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Dave Hooke</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-07 10:41:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+Should+You+Invest+in+Real+Estate%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I want to talk to you about investing in real estate as part of your retirement plan. I’m a little biased because I have invested in real estate as part of my own retirement, but I’ll do my best to be objective. Here are some pros and cons of investing in real estate:

Cons


  You need active knowledge about the industry. If you want to invest in real estate locally, you have to learn about the industry and understand its inner workings.
  You have to actively manage the properties. This can be time consuming because you will be actively managing maintenance calls, setting up showings, and running the properties. Unless you have a ton of capital, you’ll be doing all these things yourself.
  You need a significant amount of capital. There are stories about ways to get creative and put little or no money down, but those are the exception, not the rule.


Pros


  You’ll get a significantly higher return on your investment. This is assuming you’re in a decently appreciating market like south-central Pennsylvania and you’re holding the property for the long-term, not just short-term sales.
  There are significant tax advantages to investing in real estate. It’s best to speak with an accountant about the details, but if you buy enough real estate, those tax advantages do add up over the years.
  You can eliminate most of the risks involved in investing in real estate if you’ve taken the time to understand the industry and you’re investing in a market that remains moderately stable and isn’t as volatile as some of the other markets in our nation. This is especially true with long-term ownership and residential rental properties.


“A good strategy is to buy a property at or around the birth of a child.”

One of the strategies that I particularly love is buying a property at or around the time of the birth of a child. You can then pay it down and use tax-free refinance income or equity to pay for all or part of the child’s college education. You can then pay it back down and do the same thing to supplement your retirement income later down the road. You’re using the same property for a dual purpose, and it makes the investment valuable to you and your family.

I think that real estate investment is a great way to save for retirement alongside other investments like securities and other investment tools and is a great way to get you farther in reaching your retirement goals.

If you have any questions about real estate or anything else in the real estate market, please don’t hesitate to reach out. I’d be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+Should+You+Invest+in+Real+Estate%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+Should+You+Invest+in+Real+Estate%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Should you invest in real estate as part of your retirement? Today I’ve listed some pros and cons to help you decide if this is right for you.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Should you invest in real estate as part of your retirement? Today I’ve listed some pros and cons to help you decide if this is right for you.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>First Quarter Market Update</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/first-quarter-market-update.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Dave Hooke</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-19 10:19:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+South+central+Pennsylvania+market+update.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What’s happening the south central Pennsylvania market right now?

According to the National Association of Realtors, we’ve seen an $11,800 increase in average residential home values in the first four months of 2017 compared to the first four months of 2016. That’s a pretty significant bump; about 6.7% appreciation. We haven’t seen that kind of appreciation since the 2007 and 2008 market.

We’ve also seen a change in inventory levels. In the first four months of 2017, there were actually 471 fewer homes for sale than the same time last year, which is about a 10% decline. Conversely, 139 more homes sold this year compared to last year; a 5.3% increase in sold homes.

“Our market is a very strong seller’s market.”

When you have fewer homes listed and more homes sold, you get a decline in inventory. Any time you have a decrease in supply and demand that stays the same or increases, you get an increase in average prices.

Our market is a very strong seller’s market. In fact, it’s one of the stronger seller’s markets that I’ve seen in my 15 years in real estate. We haven’t quite reached the point I thought we were at in 2007 and 2008, but we are seeing homes going on the market and getting a barrage of showings. This can be inconvenient for sellers, but if homes are priced right, they might receive multiple offers.

If you have any questions at all about real estate or you’re thinking of selling your house, give me a call or send me an email. I’d be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+South+central+Pennsylvania+market+update.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+South+central+Pennsylvania+market+update.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What's going on in our market right now? It's hot for sellers due to the number of available homes going down and the demand for homes going up.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What's going on in our market right now? It's hot for sellers due to the number of available homes going down and the demand for homes going up.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The 5 Hidden Costs of Buying a Home</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/the-5-hidden-costs-of-buying-a-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Dave Hooke</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-05 05:42:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+5+hidden+costs+of+homeownership.mp4</guid>
        <description>

As a homeowner, there are five hidden costs that you might run into:

1. Closing costs: Everyone knows about the down payment when you buy a house, but many forget about the closing costs like the transfer tax, title insurance, and lender fees to name a few.

2. Furniture:Study after study has shown that the amount you’ll spend on furniture is the most commonly underestimated cost in buying a home. Make sure you consider (and overestimate) the money you’ll spend on furniture and decor before you get a mortgage pre-approval and decide on your purchase price range.

“Don’t forget about the maintenance costs you could have five to 10 years down the road.”

3. Ongoing maintenance: Most people think about paint, carpet, and other things that you take care of when you first buy a home. However, many people also forget that the furnace might go out after 10 years or the roof will need to be replaced. These things can sneak up on you if you’re not saving money each month in an account for emergencies and deferred maintenance.

4. Taxes and insurance: Property tax, school tax, county tax, and insurance are often overlooked and cost a good bit of money.

5. Utilities: Most people think of electric and heat, but you can’t forget to factor in costs like your water and trash bills if you’re in a public municipality.

Make sure you know everything you need to calculate before you decide how much you want to spend on a home. If you have any questions about figuring out these costs or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home, give us a call or send us an email soon. We’d be happy to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+5+hidden+costs+of+homeownership.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+5+hidden+costs+of+homeownership.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>When you buy a house, don't forget to account for these five costs that tend to go overlooked.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>When you buy a house, don't forget to account for these five costs that tend to go overlooked.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Do You Have What It Takes to Sell Your Own House?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/do-you-have-what-it-takes-to-sell-your-own-house.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Dave Hooke</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-19 11:01:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+List+Your+House+Without+a+Realtor.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you don’t need a Realtor, how do you sell your home on your own?

It might sound like I’m about to give away all my secrets, but the truth is that we really want to serve the community. If you think you’re experienced enough to sell your own house, I absolutely think you should.

There are four main things a Realtor brings to the table, so here’s how you might be able to do them on your own:

1. Guidance through the process with paperwork and documentation: If you’ve done this before, you might be familiar with disclosure agreements, the agreement of sales, and the contracts needed. If you haven’t done this on your own, you should consult with an attorney and pay them hourly to help you with the documents to give you peace of mind.

2. Setting a pricing strategy: It’s best to hire an appraiser for a valuation which you can use to set the price for your house.

“If you’re experienced enough to sell your own house, you absolutely should.”

3. Exposure and marketing: This is the primary reason to hire a Realtor because without them, you won’t get the exposure of the MLS and other agents bringing buyers to your home. However, you can create some demand with high-definition photography, compelling advertising, and things like social media, Craigslist, and Zillow to get the word out.

4. Negotiation: Most people think this is all about a line in the sand, but we call that competitive negotiation. Collaborative negotiation is more complex and used less, but can often get you much further toward what you want. It’s about asking the right questions, learning about the other party, and crafting a proposal that’s a win-win for both. Come up with a list of questions to ask buyers to find out why they’re moving, their timeline, and what’s important to them.

If you have any questions at all for us—even if you’re thinking of selling on your own—we’re always happy to help. Just give us a call or send us an email and we’d be happy to help you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+List+Your+House+Without+a+Realtor.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+List+Your+House+Without+a+Realtor.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Do you think you can sell your house on your own? Breaking down exactly what a Realtor offers can help you determine whether you're qualified to take this task on.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Do you think you can sell your house on your own? Breaking down exactly what a Realtor offers can help you determine whether you're qualified to take this task on.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Are My 5 Incredible Tips for First-Time Home Sellers?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/what-are-my-5-incredible-tips-for-first-time-home-sellers.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Dave Hooke</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-29 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+incredible+tips+for+first-time+sellers.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Here are five incredible tips you can use as a first-time home seller to ensure a fast and lucrative home sale:

1. Hire your agent based on a written marketing plan. Any agent can come into your home and throw out a price that’s attractive. The question is whether they can get it for you or not. Make sure you ask your agent for a written marketing plan that you understand and ask them questions about their experience. Also, make sure they’re a good personality fit for you. We always counsel our sellers to interview two or three agents so they choose the one who’s the best fit.

2. Price your home accurately. That experienced agent you hired with a written marketing strategy should have a thorough, comparative market analysis (CMA) done so you can not only understand what price range they’re advising you on, but the why behind that price range. That is critical to getting a buyer to make a great offer at the ideal price. Also, ask your agent to help guide you where you should position your home within that price range based on your goals and motivations—not theirs.

3. Ask your agent for a consultation to help you prepare your home for sale. This can include two things. The first is a walkthrough consultation with a list of items that are cost-effective ways to maximize your home value. The second thing they can do is advise you on staging your home. A staged home tends to sell faster and for more money.

“Make sure your agent is a good fit for you overall.”

4. Be flexible on your showings. There’s nothing worse than declining a showing from an out-of-town buyer who’s only in town for a day or two only to find out later that they pulled the trigger on a different home.

5. Insist on professional photography. More and more agents are electing to use professional photography, and it does cost money. But it’s more critical than ever to make sure your home has clear, clean, high-definition photos. It will make your home stand out, garner more showings, and sell for a greater amount of money.

If you have a question about the value of your home or want a consultation, please don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d be happy to take care of you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+incredible+tips+for+first-time+sellers.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+incredible+tips+for+first-time+sellers.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Selling your home for the first time doesn’t need to be difficult or stressful. Here are five tips to ensure that your first home sale goes off without a hitch.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Selling your home for the first time doesn’t need to be difficult or stressful. Here are five tips to ensure that your first home sale goes off without a hitch.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Truth About Current Down Payment Requirements</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/the-truth-about-current-down-payment.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Dave Hooke</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-16 14:56:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

What are the current down payment requirements for getting into a home?

First of all, according to the National Association of Realtors, the majority of people in the United States think that you need 20% down to purchase a home. That is simply not true.

To give you some perspective, the median down payment for first-time homebuyers has been 5% for decades. There are many programs available to buyers that only require 3% down, and there are some special loan programs that don’t require any money down. You can even get grant money for closing cost assistance to get into a home.

Ultimately, you need to talk to a local mortgage provider to assess your financial needs and profile so they can recommend a custom mortgage solution. Now may be the right time for you to make your first or second home purchase.

If you need a list of local lenders or if you have any other questions, give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What are the current down payment requirements for purchasing a home? Despite what you might think, you don’t actually need to put 20% down.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What are the current down payment requirements for purchasing a home? Despite what you might think, you don’t actually need to put 20% down.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3 Reasons You Should Be Selling Your Home in 2017</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/3-reasons-you-should-be-selling-your-home-in-2017.html</link>
        
        <author>Dave Hooke</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-27 11:28:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+3+Reasons+to+List+Your+Home+This+Year.mp4</guid>
        <description>
If you’ve been thinking about selling your home this year, you need to pull the trigger. Here are three reasons why.


  Mortgage interest rates are still low. Although interest rates have been rising since October, the 30-year fixed home mortgage rate is still historically low. This means buyers still have plenty of buying power in the market right now.
  Inventory is shrinking. In 2007, according to the National Association of Realtors, home inventory was just about 4 million homes for sale and in 2016, fewer than 2 million homes were for sale. Right now, home sellers have way less competition.
  Home prices are rising. We have had 54 months of non-stop home appreciation. In fact, the median home price since November of 2015 has increased by 6.8%, which means right now is a great time to get the most money for your home.


If you or anyone you know is looking to take advantage of this market and would like a free home value estimate, my team and I would be happy to give you all the information you need to make an informed decision on whether to sell your home or not.

As always, if you have any questions please feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+3+Reasons+to+List+Your+Home+This+Year.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+3+Reasons+to+List+Your+Home+This+Year.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
If you’ve been thinking about selling your home this year, you need to pull the trigger. Here are three reasons why.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
If you’ve been thinking about selling your home this year, you need to pull the trigger. Here are three reasons why.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3 Reasons Why You Can’t Trust a Zestimate</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/3-reasons-why-you-cant-trust-a-zestimate.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Dave Hooke</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-09 15:26:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+problem+with+Zillows+Zestimates.mp4</guid>
        <description>
A lot of people ask whether the home value they find on Zillow, also known as a Zestimate, is accurate. Can you really trust that Zestimate?

Zestimates work almost the same way as a tax assessment: Zillow’s algorithm takes the sale prices of homes that are similar to yours and in the same area, then it compares that information to your property’s square footage in order to come up with an estimate on the value of your property.

Unfortunately, the reality is that, although they can be accurate sometimes, Zestimates are often incorrect. On average, the Zestimate has a margin of error of about 20%.

There are three factors that impact the accuracy (or inaccuracy) of your Zestimate:


  Your property’s location. If you live in a cookie-cutter subdivision that has a lot of like-kind houses and a high number of recent sales, then it’s highly likely that your Zestimate will be more reflective of the accurate value of your home. However, if your property is in a very unique area or if you have a rural property with a lot of unique features, then it’s less likely that the Zestimate will be accurate.
  Your property’s condition. If you made a lot of recent updates, the homes around you are not similar, or if your home has unique features such as a finished basement, a Zestimate will probably not factor those features into its calculation.
  Your property’s location in relation to recent sales. For example, you may live in that cookie-cutter subdivision, but if you live on the edge, then the algorithm will take properties outside of the subdivision into consideration when calculating your Zestimate. Those properties might just be a block away but if they are completely different than yours, that will definitely throw off your Zestimate. If you live in a subdivision where all the homes are bigger than yours or sit on a larger lot, then your Zestimate will also be incorrect.


Your Zestimate really depends on those three factors in your local real estate market.

If you would like a more customized and accurate home value estimate, give us a call. This spring, we are offering a free, no obligation, maximum home valuation. Our representatives will go through your home, give you a detailed estimate of value, and provide a list of suggestions that you can use to maximize your home’s value. In other words, we will give you a list of things that will get you a good return on investment and increase your overall sales price.

If you have any questions, please don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+problem+with+Zillows+Zestimates.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+problem+with+Zillows+Zestimates.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Can you trust Zillow’s Zestimates to come up with the correct value for your home? Unfortunately, the answer is no, and there are three reasons why.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Can you trust Zillow’s Zestimates to come up with the correct value for your home? Unfortunately, the answer is no, and there are three reasons why.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 Sale-Killing Mistakes to Avoid in Your Listing Photos</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/5-sale-killing-mistakes-to-avoid-in-your-listing-photos.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Dave Hooke</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-24 11:59:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+sale-killing+listing+photo+mistakes.mp4</guid>
        <description>
When you sell your home, the listings photos are an incredibly important part of getting prospective buyers into it. However, there are five sale-killing mistakes that you need to avoid when you take your listing photos:


  No more corners. For some reason, sellers love to take pictures of the corners of different rooms in their home. Nothing is gained from buyers looking at the corners of a room; instead, photograph focal points in each room.
  The grass is always greener. Photos of nature surrounding your home make sense if you are focusing on some kind of flora or fauna. However, a close-up on the bark of your tree or a patch in your lawn does not make sense. Take a broad picture of your home with nature behind it or highlight some specific aspect of your landscaping.
  On the outside looking in. Don’t just take exterior photos of your home. If you do, the buyer will wonder what is wrong with the home. Make sure there are plenty of high definition photos of the interior of your home.
  A haunted look doesn’t help. If your photos make your home look menacing, make sure you redo them. Dark, grainy photos with unclear shadows can make your home look haunted. Pictures that you take on your phone won’t make the cut, either. Make sure you have quality, professional photos.
  Let the sunshine in. It is a scientific fact that bright, well-lit homes sell faster and for more money. Give the public what they want and make sure your home is as bright as possible.


If you have any other questions about listing photos or the home selling process in general, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+sale-killing+listing+photo+mistakes.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+sale-killing+listing+photo+mistakes.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Listing photos are an important part of the home selling process. However, there are five sale-killing mistakes you need to avoid when taking listing photos.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Listing photos are an important part of the home selling process. However, there are five sale-killing mistakes you need to avoid when taking listing photos.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Holiday Decor Can Amp Up Your Curb Appeal</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-holiday-decor-can-amp-up-your-curb-appeal.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Dave Hooke</author>
        <pubDate>2016-12-14 10:45:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+4+ways+to+boost+curb+appeal+with+holiday+decor.mp4</guid>
        <description>
Certain holiday decor can really amp us your home’s curb appeal. Today, I wanted to give you a list of the top four ways to utilize it:


  Highlight your home’s architecture. Consider edging your home’s roof, windows, or trim with holiday decorations to take advantage of and highlight your home’s architecture.
  Landscaping. Net lights make decorating with your landscape so easy that your kids can do it. Lay them over your hedges and take advantage of all the landscaping aspects that your home offers.
  Spread the love. Gates, walkways, fences, and your entryway are great opportunities to extend your decor to your entire front yard.
  Don’t forget about your front door. This can be as easy as adding a wreath. Whether you go with store bought or homemade, the opportunities are endless.


These four tips will really help you boost that curb appeal, whether you’re selling or not.

I hope you enjoyed this topic and all the topics we discuss in our videos. If you have any feedback for us or topics you’d like to learn more about, reach out to us anytime via phone or email. We look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+4+ways+to+boost+curb+appeal+with+holiday+decor.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+4+ways+to+boost+curb+appeal+with+holiday+decor.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Whether you're selling your home or just want it to look great, you can use holiday decor to seriously boost your curb appeal. I have four ways to share with you today.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Whether you're selling your home or just want it to look great, you can use holiday decor to seriously boost your curb appeal. I have four ways to share with you today.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Can You Do to Save for a Down Payment?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/what-can-you-do-to-save-for-a-down-payment.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Dave Hooke</author>
        <pubDate>2016-12-13 12:08:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+ways+to+save+for+a+down+payment.mp4</guid>
        <description>
When buying a home, it’s very important that you have your down payment ready to go. Here are a few unique options to help you save for a down payment:


  Consider crowdsourcing your home.
  Ask the seller for help. Asking the seller to assist with closing costs is a common way to free up more money for your down payment. Ask your lender what the limits for closing costs are on your loan program, and then ask your Realtor to help negotiate for the seller to pay the closing costs on your behalf.
  Look into government options. The department of Housing and Urban Development, or HUD, has a site with links to all 50 states. These links provide information on different options to help you get the home of your dreams. There is also the Good Neighbor Next Door program, which provides closing cost assistance for teachers, firefighters, police officers, and more. Of course, there is also the VA loan, which helps veterans purchase homes.
  Check with your employer. Some employers offer programs to help low-to-moderate income employees purchase a home.
  Take advantage of special lender financing options, such as a USDA or FHA loan. You may have to meet certain income requirements in order to qualify for one of these loans. The property has to meet certain requirements as well, but these are great options to help buyers get the home of their dreams.


Of course, you can always combine some of these options to get the home that you want. If you have any questions about any of these five methods, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+ways+to+save+for+a+down+payment.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+ways+to+save+for+a+down+payment.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Every buyer knows that they need a down payment in order to purchase a home. Today, I’ll go over five unique options you can use to save for your down payment.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Every buyer knows that they need a down payment in order to purchase a home. Today, I’ll go over five unique options you can use to save for your down payment.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>7 Questions to Ask Before Hiring an Agent</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/7-questions-to-ask-before-hiring-an-agent.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Dave Hooke</author>
        <pubDate>2016-11-29 13:02:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+Finding+the+best+agent+to+sell+your+home.mp4</guid>
        <description>
If you are planning on selling your home, how can you make sure that you select the best agent for the job? We have seven questions that you should ask when interviewing agents in order to hire the best one.


  How long have you been selling homes? You wouldn’t want to go to a doctor who’s just one year out of medical school. It’s helpful to have an agent that’s been in the business a while and has some experience under their belt.
  How many homes did you sell last year? A lot of agents like to tout the success of their company. Ask them how they have done year to year. Ask them to bring that data along to the interview. Again, it’s helpful to work with an agent who has a lot of experience. You could have a long-time veteran agent who has been in the industry for 20 years but only sells two homes a year, or you could have an agent who’s been working for four years but sells 30 to 40 homes a year. The second agent would have more experience.
  How are you going to market my home? It’s important to have a detailed marketing plan that is written down.
  Will you represent me exclusively? In Pennsylvania, an agent can represent you the seller, or the buyer, or both. If an agent is going to do dual agency, make sure that you understand it and consent to it.
  How will you keep me informed? We find that communication is one of the most important things to our sellers and clients. Ask them what their communication plan is and how often they intend to talk to you.
  Can you provide references? Ask for three or more references and ask for contact information. Make sure that you follow up with them so you can see what their experience was working with this agent.
  Are you a Realtor? Not all real estate agents are Realtors. If your agent is a Realtor, that means they are a member of the National Association of Realtors, which has been a champion for professionalism and ethics in real estate for over a century.


Those seven questions will help you pick the best agent for the job. If you have any other questions about hiring an agent or selling your home, give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+Finding+the+best+agent+to+sell+your+home.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+Finding+the+best+agent+to+sell+your+home.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>When hiring an agent to sell your home, make sure to ask them these seven questions in order to pick the best one for the job.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>When hiring an agent to sell your home, make sure to ask them these seven questions in order to pick the best one for the job.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Do You Need to Know About Home Inspections?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/what-do-you-need-to-know-about-home-inspections.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Dave Hooke</author>
        <pubDate>2016-11-14 11:04:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+things+you+should+know+about+home+inspections.mp4</guid>
        <description>
As a home buyer, what are the five most important things to know about home inspections?


  You can choose your own inspector. You can get a referral from a real estate agent or someone else who’s recently bought a home or just  look up the National Association of Home Inspectors. This is an association that home inspectors are typically members of if they’re qualified. If they’re members of that association, they’ve typically completed a training program, shown competence in the home inspection trade, and completed a written exam.
  Inspections are not a pass/fail process. A lot of our clients believe that the inspection is a black and white result, but that’s not the case. On the contrary, home inspections are often general reports that consist of 20 to 40 pages of general information about the home which you can use for many years into the future in reference to the structural elements of your home. They do include a list of material defects and (usually) safety issues, and it’s your responsibility to determine if those things are concerning enough to impact whether you’re going to purchase the home or not.
  Inspections are intended for adverse conditions. They’re not necessarily just for cosmetic issues. We advise that you attend the inspection just so you can talk with the home inspector about what’s important and what’s not, in their opinion. No house is perfect; all of them have some adverse conditions and defects that are listed in the inspection.
  Our agreements of sale in Pennsylvania allow the home buyer three different options as the result of the inspection period. The first option is to accept the property based on the information in the report. The second option is to terminate the agreement and get your earnest money back. The third (and most common) is to ask the seller to repair some of the items that came up in the report.
  Home inspectors are not specialists. They are more like general practitioners that are going to give you information about all aspects of the home. We advise that you consult a specialist like an electrician or a plumber if there is a major issue that needs to be addressed. Do this before you choose any of the options discussed in number four.


If you have any questions about home inspections or anything else related to real estate, please don’t hesitate to give us a call or shoot us an email. We look forward to talking with you soon!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+things+you+should+know+about+home+inspections.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+things+you+should+know+about+home+inspections.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re a home buyer, there are five things you need to know about how home inspections function.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re a home buyer, there are five things you need to know about how home inspections function.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>2 Things You Need to Know About Short Sales</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/2-things-you-need-to-know-about-short-sales.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Dave Hooke</author>
        <pubDate>2016-10-31 15:04:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-What+should+you+know+about+short+sales%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>
What is a short sale? There a few things you need to know about short sales if you’re thinking about purchasing one.

A short sale is the sale of a property where the proceeds net the lender less money than what is owed to the lender on the mortgage note.

For example, if you sign a mortgage note that you owe a lender $100,000 and you sell the property for $90,000, it would be considered a short sale.

What a lot of people don’t know is that you can actually sell a property for more than what is owed to the lender in some cases, and it would still qualify as a short sale. As an example, if you owe $100,000 to a lender and you sell a property for $105,000, but your closing costs are $7,000, it would only net the lender $98,000, resulting in a short sale.

The other important thing to know about a short sale is that it requires a lender’s approval for the sale to go through. This differs from regular sales in which only the owner’s approval is required. The lender’s approval is required when you’re giving them less than what is owed to them.

Why would a lender ever consider accepting less than what is owed to them? Well, if the lender reviews all of the owner’s tax returns, verifies their employment, and finds out that the owner is completely insolvent, they know that there is no chance that they would ever get paid what was owed to them without selling the property. In this case, they’ll consider accepting less money over foreclosing on the property, which takes months or even years and an involves a lot of fees in some cases.

What should you know if you’re considering buying a short sale property?Statistically, short sales have a higher chance of going for less than market value than standard sales do.You have to be incredibly patient when buying a short sale property. The transaction on a short sale can take up to six months or even longer to get the bank’s approval. This is due to the amount of time it takes the bank to verify the owner’s insolvency and to determine that a short sale is in their best interest.If you have any questions about short sales or anything else related to real estate, please don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I’d be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-What+should+you+know+about+short+sales%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-What+should+you+know+about+short+sales%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What are short sales and what should you know about them? Here are a few things to keep in mind if you’re thinking about buying a short sale property.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What are short sales and what should you know about them? Here are a few things to keep in mind if you’re thinking about buying a short sale property.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4 Tips to Help You Win the Home You Want</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/4-tips-to-help-you-win-the-home-you-want.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Dave Hooke</author>
        <pubDate>2016-10-10 16:34:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+4+ways+to+make+your+home+offer+stand+out.mp4</guid>
        <description>
The market is extremely hot for sellers right now, and as a home buyer, it may not be as easy to get your offer accepted as it has been in the past. Here are a few tips to help make your offer stand out and win you the home you want:


  Keep your offer simple and straightforward. This is especially important if there are multiple buyers making offers on the same property. This doesn’t necessarily mean that you should neglect important aspects of the transaction that concern you. Just keep in mind that if there is something you can do to eliminate a contingency, your offer will be simpler, and therefore much more attractive to the seller.
  Consider writing a personal letter to the seller. I know that this may sound cliché, but personal letters really do make a difference. Statistically, it’s been shown that offers which appeal to the seller emotionally have a better chance of standing out and being accepted than other offers do. If you and your family are really excited about this home and all of its features, let the seller know all of the specifics. Compliment the way that the seller has maintained the home, include your vision of it for your family, and make sure that the letter is personalized. Don’t hesitate to include a picture of you and your family within the letter for maximum impact.
  Have your loan officer personally follow up with the seller or listing agent. This is probably my favorite tip and the one that is the most neglected. This will make a huge impact because one of the biggest concerns for a seller is the strength of your financial situation. Most buyers will have a pre-approval letter included with their offer, but very few will have their lender call the seller personally to explain that they’ve looked over all of your financials and have determined that you are completely qualified to buy the home. A loan officer that is confident in you as a buyer will give the seller peace of mind when it comes to reviewing your offer.
  Be ready to act swiftly in the event of a counteroffer. Strike while the iron is hot and don’t take multiple days to respond to a counteroffer. Instead, quickly consider whether you’re going to accept the counteroffer or quickly counter the counteroffer to keep the ball rolling.


These tips can make a world of difference when submitting your offer and may even help win you the home that you want in the end. If you have any other questions about buying or selling a home in our market, please don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to speaking with you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+4+ways+to+make+your+home+offer+stand+out.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+4+ways+to+make+your+home+offer+stand+out.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>In this hot seller’s market how do you make your home offer stand out from the rest? Here are four steps I suggest you take.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>In this hot seller’s market how do you make your home offer stand out from the rest? Here are four steps I suggest you take.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3 Reasons Why Fall Is a Great Time to Sell Your Home</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/3-reasons-why-fall-is-a-great-time-to-sell-your-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Dave Hooke</author>
        <pubDate>2016-09-26 12:31:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+Fall+is+a+great+time+to+sell+a+home.mp4</guid>
        <description>
We all know that a lot of people in the South Central Pennsylvania area list their homes on the market in early spring with a lot of those homes going under contract in early summer. But what about fall? How good is the fall selling season going to be? Each year is different, but I think that there’s something special about the fall season this year. Here are three things to keep in mind:


  The bulk of spring listings are expiring. Many of the homes still on the market were listed in spring, and as a result, there is less competition, particularly when you consider how your home will stand out as a new listing and fewer days on the market that your listing will boast.
  Fall home buyers are more serious. These buyers have been looking at listings for months, and they are eager to conclude their search and move in comfortably before the holidays.
  Interest rates are still at all-time lows. There is a threat that’s looming in people’s minds that rates are going to increase sooner rather than later. In a normal year, people may postpone their decision to buy a home until the spring, but this year I sense that these low interest rates will create some additional demand.


First, you have to prepare your home to account for the particular fall conditions. For example, you need to check the HVAC system and replace your furnace filter so your home will be warm and smell fresh. Get it tuned up and call an HVAC contractor to inspect it. Also, make sure to turn on all the lights; you’ve got to compensate for the shorter, cloudier days. Cleaning up the yard is also a must in order to maximize your curb appeal.

The second thing you need to do is price your home appropriately. You can always give our team a call and we’ll give you a free, no-obligation consultation to get an estimate on your home.

If you have any other questions about selling this fall, don’t hesitate to give me or my team a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+Fall+is+a+great+time+to+sell+a+home.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+Fall+is+a+great+time+to+sell+a+home.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Contrary to popular belief, the fall is actually a great time to sell a home. You may not see as many buyers as you would in the spring and summer, but you can be sure that fall buyers are more serious.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Contrary to popular belief, the fall is actually a great time to sell a home. You may not see as many buyers as you would in the spring and summer, but you can be sure that fall buyers are more serious.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Turn a Lowball Offer into a Home Run in 5 Steps</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/turn-a-lowball-offer-into-a-home-run-in-5-steps.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Dave Hooke</author>
        <pubDate>2016-09-08 12:05:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+steps+to+turn+a+lowball+offer+into+a+home+run.mp4</guid>
        <description>
If you’re selling your home in South Central Pennsylvania and you receive a lowball offer on it from a potential buyer, you may be wondering whether it’s still possible to get a great deal on your home. Today I’d like to share five steps you should take that will help you turn that lowball offer into a home run:


  Don’t be insulted by a lowball offer. Your first instinct when receiving a low offer on your home may be to get defensive. This is the most unproductive thing you can do. Try not to get emotional, keep an objective perspective, and realize that this buyer may not be doing this solely to make a personal attack on you or your home. It’s possible that they’ve been misinformed about starting with a low offer, and many times these people are expecting a counteroffer.
  Respond gracefully. Grace can go a long way. Put yourself in the buyer’s shoes: if a seller launches a personal attack on you after making an offer, are you likely to come up on your price? The odds of the buyer coming up on their offer are much stronger when you respond with a graceful offer because you’re approaching them in a collaborative and positive way.
  Write a strategic counteroffer. Don’t feel pressured to come down and meet the buyer halfway just because they lowballed you. It’s okay to give a little bit in good faith, but if your home is priced reasonably, there’s no reason you should slash your price.
  Expect a counter to your counteroffer. It’s natural for this negotiation to feel a bit like a chess game, and you may counter back and forth a few different times. This is okay; just try your best to be patient.
  Focus on things other than price. Get creative with terms like the settlement date, included appliances, and financing or inspection contingencies. One thing that you can rest assured in knowing is that if there are a lot of inspection contingencies, there may be repair requests later on. If this is the case, you could potentially turn a lowball offer into an as-is sale.


If you have any questions about lowball offers or real estate in general, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I’d be happy to point you in the right direction!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+steps+to+turn+a+lowball+offer+into+a+home+run.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+steps+to+turn+a+lowball+offer+into+a+home+run.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
If you’re selling your home in South Central Pennsylvania and you receive a lowball offer on it from a potential buyer, you may be wondering whether it’s still possible to get a great deal on your home. Today I’d like to share five steps you should take that will help you turn that lowball offer into a home run:

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
If you’re selling your home in South Central Pennsylvania and you receive a lowball offer on it from a potential buyer, you may be wondering whether it’s still possible to get a great deal on your home. Today I’d like to share five steps you should take that will help you turn that lowball offer into a home run:

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Happens If the Home You’re Buying Doesn’t Appraise?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/what-happens-if-the-home-youre-buying-doesnt-appraise.html</link>
        
        <author>Dave Hooke</author>
        <pubDate>2016-08-29 12:01:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+Top+appraisal+tips+for+home+buyers.mp4</guid>
        <description>
As a buyer, what happens if the appraisal on the home you’re about to purchase comes in too low? There are four main options you can explore:


  Cancel the transaction. This may be the best option for you, even though it’s a heartbreaker. If your appraisal comes in below purchase price, analyze your sales contract, consult with your attorney or Realtor, and determine if you have a financing or appraisal contingency. If you do, then you have the right to walk away from the transaction or renegotiate the transaction down to the appraised value.
  Come up with more cash. Only do this if you really want the property. If you’re concerned about resale or think that the appraisal is valid, you would essentially be overpaying for the home. However, a lot of customers look at the appraisal and think, “I really want this to be my home for many years.” In that instance, you might not care about the appraisal.
  Get creative with your lender. Talk to your lender and see if you have other collateral, like another property, that you can borrow against. You might be able to do a first and second loan on the property that will finance the difference in cash. With interest rates as low as they are, this can be an attractive option.
  Challenge the appraisal. Be careful if you decide to go this route; appraisers can get defensive and this is their expertise. First, consult with your attorney or real estate agent to determine if there are any errors in the appraisal. Then, call the appraiser. Be empathetic, not confrontational. Maybe the appraiser missed a comparable property, or maybe there was an error in the lot size. If you take a competitive approach, the appraiser’s defenses will go up and you won’t get anywhere. Take a more collaborative approach instead.


Remember, if that appraisal comes in lower than the price you offered, you do have a few options. If you have any questions, please don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+Top+appraisal+tips+for+home+buyers.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+Top+appraisal+tips+for+home+buyers.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
As a buyer, what happens if the appraisal on the home you’re about to purchase comes in too low? There are four main options you can explore:

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
As a buyer, what happens if the appraisal on the home you’re about to purchase comes in too low? There are four main options you can explore:

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 Steps to Help You Get the Home You Want</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/5-steps-to-help-you-get-home-you-want.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Dave Hooke</author>
        <pubDate>2016-08-17 11:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

How do you get the home you want in a competitive market like the one we’re experiencing now? There are five things you can do to help you compete in this market and snag the home you’re looking for:


  Get pre-approved. Without pre-approval, you won’t have peace of mind about your monthly mortgage payment or what your interest rate might be, and you’re not putting yourself at the top of the list of offers on the home in the first place. It’s also a good idea to ask your lender about a good-faith estimate of your closing costs just to get an idea of the breakdown between them and your down payments.
  Be informed about what you’re looking for. I’d advise making two lists. One is a list of your needs – things like financial boundaries, location, and the number of bedrooms – and the other is a list of wants – whether you want a 2-car garage or a 3-car garage, or how much square footage you’d like. Having these two lists will allow you to narrow down your options from all of the inventory out there.
  Interview a Realtor before working with them. Keep in mind that there are more than 1,800 real estate agents in our market alone. It’s critical that you sit down and talk to a Realtor, or maybe a few Realtors, before deciding on one to work with. Have a 15 or 20-minute conversation with the Realtor and ask them questions about their credentials, how long they’ve been selling homes, their fee structure, and what they do to service their clients. If a Realtor’s personality does not fit well for you, or their credentials don’t match your needs, interview another Realtor.
  Create your own search on a real estate website that you’re comfortable with. This may seem like it contradicts the point above, but while your Realtor is out setting up searches for you, keep an eye out on your own for homes that your Realtor may have missed. All things considered, the value of a Realtor lies in the counsel they provide throughout the home buying process, as well as their ability to represent your best interests when making an offer on the home you want.
  Make sure you are prepared to make a quick offer. If a home that you like is listed on the market, it’s probably priced well and in relatively good condition for its price. Chances are, a lot of other potential buyers are going to like that home for the same reasons. So when you see a home you like, be sure to let your Realtor know that you’re going to be prepared to write a contract on the spot, or shortly after you see the property. You don’t want to do this if you feel pressured or aren’t comfortable with the property, but waiting a few days could potentially allow another buyer to snatch it out from under you.


If you’ve got any other questions for us, or you want a free consultation, we’d love to be one of the real estate offices that you interview to see if we can add value to your home buying experience. We’ll get you set up and sent off in the right direction.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

How do you get the home you want in a competitive market like the one we’re experiencing now? There are five things you can do to help you compete in this market and snag the home you’re looking for:

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

How do you get the home you want in a competitive market like the one we’re experiencing now? There are five things you can do to help you compete in this market and snag the home you’re looking for:

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 Quick Ways to Add Value to Your Central PA Home</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/5-quick-ways-to-add-value-to-your-central-pa-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Dave Hooke</author>
        <pubDate>2016-07-28 15:04:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+ways+to+add+value+to+your+home.mp4</guid>
        <description>
If you’re planning on selling your home this summer, there are five things you can do to increase your home’s value:


  Paint. I always recommend a fresh coat of paint. If you don’t have an eye for color, a coat of crisp white paint can go a long way. If you do have an eye for color, consider a light sand tone or shade of gray. A fresh coat of paint will give your house a nice finish and you will cover fingerprints and stains throughout the house.
  Address your front door. A bright red or yellow door can differentiate your home from the rest of the properties on your street and make a great first impression on the buyer.
  Increase your curb appeal. Landscaping is the name of the game. When buyers drive by, you want your landscaping to pop. Make sure you put down fresh mulch, edge and weed your lawn, and plant fresh flowers. If you can’t plant fresh flowers, at least bring in a few potted flowers by the front door.
  Make quick bathroom updates. Install some new fixtures, paint the cabinets, or get a new vanity. Even just adding nice, fluffy towels, a fresh shower curtain, or a new rug can make your bathroom look new again (even if it really needs to be gutted).
  Clean and declutter. If you don’t do any of the other things, make sure you clean and declutter. We all live in our homes and have useful, convenient things on every open surface. Clean off your countertops, nightstands, shelves, and more. Throw out old magazines. Take down personal photos. You have to pack anyway, so put some things in boxes and store them so your home looks bigger and cleaner when buyers walk through it.


If you have any questions about getting your home ready for the market, give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+ways+to+add+value+to+your+home.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+ways+to+add+value+to+your+home.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
If you’re planning on selling your home this summer, there are five things you can do to increase your home’s value:

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
If you’re planning on selling your home this summer, there are five things you can do to increase your home’s value:

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Elections Historically Affect the Real Estate Market</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-elections-historically-affect-the-real-estate-market.html</link>
        
        <author>Dave Hooke</author>
        <pubDate>2016-07-15 10:40:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+an+election+year+affects+the+market.mp4</guid>
        <description>
According to a Huffington Post article written by David Cross, real estate values continue to increase on average during an election year, but usually at a slightly slower pace than the year before or the year after. I’ve included a graph to help you get a picture of what that looks like. In general, according to historical averages, prices increased the year before at a 6% rate. During the election year itself, the increase slowed to 4.5%. Then in the year after, the rate went back up to 5.3%.

According to that information (and after doing some additional research), Cross didn’t deduce any correlation as to why the market slowed during election years. One thing to keep in mind, however, is that this information is not market-specific. Meaning it doesn’t necessarily represent this specific market, this specific time of year, and this specific election.

In South Central Pennsylvania, for instance, real estate is continuing to increase at a moderate rate compared to last year. In fact, according to the MLS, it will increase at a faster rate than last year. This is obviously in opposition to the graph’s information. Overall, things like interest rates and other economic variables can have an impact on what home values do, even if - on average - they increase at a slower rate.

If you have any questions on what your home is doing this year, would like a free home value estimate, or just have a general real estate question, please don’t hesitate to contact me or my staff by phone or email!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+an+election+year+affects+the+market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Hooke/Central+PA+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+an+election+year+affects+the+market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
According to a Huffington Post article written by David Cross, real estate values continue to increase on average during an election year, but usually at a slightly slower pace than the year before or the year after. I’ve included a graph to help you get a picture of what that looks like. In general, according to historical averages, prices increased the year before at a 6% rate. During the election year itself, the increase slowed to 4.5%. Then in the year after, the rate went back up to 5.3%.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
According to a Huffington Post article written by David Cross, real estate values continue to increase on average during an election year, but usually at a slightly slower pace than the year before or the year after. I’ve included a graph to help you get a picture of what that looks like. In general, according to historical averages, prices increased the year before at a 6% rate. During the election year itself, the increase slowed to 4.5%. Then in the year after, the rate went back up to 5.3%.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3 Reasons to Downsize with a New Home</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/central-pa-real-estate-agent-more-money.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate Tips</category>
        
        <author>Dave Hooke</author>
        <pubDate>2016-06-30 12:47:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

At a certain point, you don’t need a large home anymore. Maybe the kids are off to college or you’re just looking for something that requires less upkeep. In a world where bigger often seems better, sometimes less is more. Here are three benefits to downsizing with your next home:


  More money: If you are looking to get into a smaller home than the one you have now, it frees up equity in your current home and will result in lower mortgage, tax, and insurance payments. You’ll have to spend less on upkeep and maintenance as well.
  More time: This is a big one. A smaller home means you spend less time cleaning and upkeep. That means more time for you to do the things you like to do, like spending time with your family.
  Increased efficiency: A smaller home needs fewer resources to heat and cool it, reducing your carbon footprint.


There are plenty more things to think about when downsizing, but most people start with asking the simple question, “What can I get for my home?” and “What kind of home could I buy in this market?”

If you have any questions for us, give us a call or send us an email. Dave would be happy to come out to your home and give you a free home value estimate. Just call or email us saying, “I’d like Dave to give me a free home value estimate” and we’ll get it done for you! We look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

At a certain point, you don’t need a large home anymore. Maybe the kids are off to college or you’re just looking for something that requires less upkeep. In a world where bigger often seems better, sometimes less is more. Here are three benefits to downsizing with your next home:

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

At a certain point, you don’t need a large home anymore. Maybe the kids are off to college or you’re just looking for something that requires less upkeep. In a world where bigger often seems better, sometimes less is more. Here are three benefits to downsizing with your next home:

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 Factors That Influence Home Value</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/central-pa-real-estate-agent5-pointers.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Dave Hooke</author>
        <pubDate>2016-06-16 10:12:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

What are the five most important factors that affect the value of a home?


  Current location: Home value is influenced by a home’s location, depending on the neighborhood, municipality, values of surrounding homes, and even school district.
  Future location: Although many sellers focus on current location, it’s critical to consider the future location. Think about what’s trending, any new developments, and property taxes in a prospective neighborhood.
  Market timing: The state of the economy, interest rates, and other market trends will dramatically affect home value.
  Zoning changes: If you’re located in a residential neighborhood, this might not impact you as much. However, if you’re in a metropolitan or downtown area, it’s important to keep an eye on zoning, especially if changes are occurring in surrounding properties.
  Condition: Your home needs to be maintained to be in fair condition. The three most important rooms in your home include the kitchen, master bedroom, and master bathroom. Other bathrooms are important as well. Don’t overlook condition.


If you’re thinking about buying or selling a home in Southcentral Pennsylvania, give me a call or send me an email. I’d be happy to answer any real estate questions you might have!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

What are the five most important factors that affect the value of a home?

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

What are the five most important factors that affect the value of a home?

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The 4 Types of Returns on Investment Properties</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/central-pa-real-estate-agent-is-real.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Dave Hooke</author>
        <pubDate>2016-06-03 14:12:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

A lot of people ask me to help them understand the benefits of investing in real estate. I want to share some insights into long-term investing, like rental property ownership. There are 4 different types of return on real estate to calculate.


  Cash flow. This would be different from your gross rents and your monthly expenses. If your expenses like the mortgage payment, taxes, insurance, and management are less than your gross rents, you have positive cash flow.
  Annual appreciation. If you buy a property for $100,000 and next year it’s worth $102,000, we can say it appreciated by $2,000 and that’s another return.
  Increase in equity annually. If you get a loan from the bank and it’s $100,000, every time you make a mortgage payment, that loan balance is going to be reduced. That reduction represents an increase in equity or net worth that’s accrued to you. This is often the biggest one.
  Tax. This one has to do with your tax accountant so it’s important to talk to them first. They will probably depreciate the property over 27.5 years. By depreciating the property, you can get gains on income tax write-offs that you wouldn’t have before the property ownership.


One of the benefits of real estate ownership has to do with if you’re a growing family. For instance, my wife and I bought real estate so that over the course of 18 to 20 years, we might be able to help pay for our son’s college education. It’s a great incentive to consider the benefits of real estate investing. But it’s not for everyone - there can be management headaches and maintenance issues and things that can be quite speculative. It’s important to talk to an expert or a financial advisor to decide if it’s a good idea for you and your family.

Please don’t hesitate to reach out with any more questions you may have for me!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

A lot of people ask me to help them understand the benefits of investing in real estate. I want to share some insights into long-term investing, like rental property ownership. There are 4 different types of return on real estate to calculate.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

A lot of people ask me to help them understand the benefits of investing in real estate. I want to share some insights into long-term investing, like rental property ownership. There are 4 different types of return on real estate to calculate.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Happens After Your Offer Is Accepted in Central PA?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/central-pa-real-estate-agentso-your.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Dave Hooke</author>
        <pubDate>2016-05-23 13:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

So you’re shopping for homes, you make an offer on the one you want, and the offer is accepted. Now what?

The first thing I want to say is that it’s not time to celebrate yet; we still have work to do before we get to close on the home. That can take up to 60 days after the offer is accepted. The first thing we can do is write out our earnest money deposit check. That’s the money that we give to the listing agent for the seller, which typically gives them peace of mind knowing they can take their property off the market, because you’re a serious buyer.

Secondly, we’ll schedule and coordinate our inspections, and attend them. This includes inspections for termites, radon, water, septic, and others depending on the property. After we review, we can decide if there are repairs to negotiate with the seller. The third thing we’ll do is make our mortgage application and make sure that the bank appraisal has been ordered, so the bank can review the property, make sure the value is there and review our financial statements. Assuming they approve our loan, we’ll get a loan commitment letter.

The fourth thing to do is schedule the final or pre-settlement walkthrough. This is our chance to walk through the property and make sure everything is in order before we settle on the property. Then we’ll attend the settlement at the title company of our choice, sign a whole lot of documents, and take the keys to the property.

Then, it’s time to celebrate!

Thanks as always for watching. Please reach out to us with any questions you have, whether you’re local or not.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

So you’re shopping for homes, you make an offer on the one you want, and the offer is accepted. Now what?

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

So you’re shopping for homes, you make an offer on the one you want, and the offer is accepted. Now what?

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How the Dave Hooke Team had great communication while helping us sell our home and buy another.</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-dave-hooke-team-had-great_17.html</link>
        
          <category>Client Testimonial</category>
        
        <author>Dave Hooke</author>
        <pubDate>2016-05-17 13:32:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>
“It was great. They were very professional, they kept us informed through every bit of the process and the house sold quickly. I thought that they were very good at communicating with us during the process. Just keeping in touch, letting us know what’s going on, how it’s working out. I mean in three weeks we had an offer, so it wasn’t a long process but yet we didn’t close on the home until a month later because of the house we were holding off on buying that home. During that process they were making sure that everything was going smooth with the buyers and their process with regards to loan approval.”

-Jim Degaettano
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
“It was great. They were very professional, they kept us informed through every bit of the process and the house sold quickly. I thought that they were very good at communicating with us during the process. Just keeping in touch, letting us know what’s going on, how it’s working out. I mean in three weeks we had an offer, so it wasn’t a long process but yet we didn’t close on the home until a month later because of the house we were holding off on buying that home. During that process they were making sure that everything was going smooth with the buyers and their process with regards to loan approval.”

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
“It was great. They were very professional, they kept us informed through every bit of the process and the house sold quickly. I thought that they were very good at communicating with us during the process. Just keeping in touch, letting us know what’s going on, how it’s working out. I mean in three weeks we had an offer, so it wasn’t a long process but yet we didn’t close on the home until a month later because of the house we were holding off on buying that home. During that process they were making sure that everything was going smooth with the buyers and their process with regards to loan approval.”

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Should You Buy or Sell First in Central PA?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/central-pa-real-estate-agent-buying-and.html</link>
        
          <category>Buying and Selling at the Same Time</category>
        
        <author>Dave Hooke</author>
        <pubDate>2016-05-04 10:40:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Can I buy a home and sell a home at the same time?

There are two ways you can complete that transaction. First, you can put your home on the market, sell it, and then purchase a home. Or you can wait to list, purchase a home, own two homes, and then sell your old home. There are pros and cons to each decision and it’s important to find out which is the best way for you.

If you decide you’re comfortable owning two homes, you can wait to put your home on the market until you find the perfect property. Once you settle in, then you can sell your home. There is less stress and pressure to find a property with this method. However, there is some increased financial pressure that comes with owning both homes.

Conversely, if you decide to sell your home first, you won’t have to own two properties at once. That eliminates the financial burden, but you are under more pressure to make a quick decision on a property. You might wind up rushing the decision and finding a property that doesn’t work out, or you will have to find temporary housing while you find the right home. While you can rent a house until you find the next property, that does place an added burden of moving twice in a short period of time.

If you’re not sure which option is right for you, contact a Realtor and a local mortgage lender. The Realtor will conduct a market analysis on your home to see how much equity you have in your current property, and the lender will let you know what kind of mortgage you qualify for. That way, you know which option you can afford.

If you have any questions, give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Can I buy a home and sell a home at the same time?

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Can I buy a home and sell a home at the same time?

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Dave Hooke helped us sell two houses in a tough market and achieved full-price offers.</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-dave-hooke-helped-us-sell-two.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate Testimonials</category>
        
          <category>Happy Clients</category>
        
        <author>Dave Hooke</author>
        <pubDate>2016-04-21 15:05:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>
“We had a couple, course everybody knows the great recession we just came out of, and we had some problem houses that took a long time on the market and we asked Dave  to come in and try to market them and sell them he accomplished that on two different occasions achieving full-price offers in a very reasonable amount of time and it was just really helpful for our business. Would you Recommend him to someone else? Oh Absolutely, absolutely. Just did that today in fact.”


  
    
      -Dave Thompson
      Custom Builder
      Home Designs Unlimited
    
  

</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
“We had a couple, course everybody knows the great recession we just came out of, and we had some problem houses that took a long time on the market and we asked Dave  to come in and try to market them and sell them he accomplished that on two different occasions achieving full-price offers in a very reasonable amount of time and it was just really helpful for our business. Would you Recommend him to someone else? Oh Absolutely, absolutely. Just did that today in fact.”

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
“We had a couple, course everybody knows the great recession we just came out of, and we had some problem houses that took a long time on the market and we asked Dave  to come in and try to market them and sell them he accomplished that on two different occasions achieving full-price offers in a very reasonable amount of time and it was just really helpful for our business. Would you Recommend him to someone else? Oh Absolutely, absolutely. Just did that today in fact.”

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Are Sellers Accepting as a Fair Price for Their Home? </title>
        <link>localhost:4000/central-pa-real-estate-agent-what-is.html</link>
        
          <category>Central PA Home Offer Acceptance</category>
        
        <author>Dave Hooke</author>
        <pubDate>2016-04-21 12:10:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

What will a seller accept as a fair price for their home? Many people ask this question, but the only true answer is it really depends on the given market. That’s why it’s important to work with a real estate professional who has the tools to do a market analysis and give you a more definite answer.

In the Central Pennsylvania market, sellers have accepted, on average, about 2.7% less than their asking price. As a general rule of thumb, you probably won’t ruffle anybody’s feathers if you offer 5% less than asking price, but it does differ from market to market.

In order to ensure you don’t overpay for a home or miss out on a home by making too low of an offer, seek out a local buyer’s agent in your market and ask them to do a market analysis. They can find homes just like the one you’re interested in, figure out what they sold for, and then give you an opinion of value of the one you’re putting an offer on. They can also inquire about the motivation of the homeowner, talk to the listing agent, and negotiate on your behalf to get you the best possible value for the home you like!

If you need real estate assistance, or if you have questions of any kind, real estate related or not, please don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We would love to hear from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

What will a seller accept as a fair price for their home? Many people ask this question, but the only true answer is it really depends on the given market. That’s why it’s important to work with a real estate professional who has the tools to do a market analysis and give you a more definite answer.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

What will a seller accept as a fair price for their home? Many people ask this question, but the only true answer is it really depends on the given market. That’s why it’s important to work with a real estate professional who has the tools to do a market analysis and give you a more definite answer.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title> Central Pennsylvania Real Estate Market Update </title>
        <link>localhost:4000/central-pa-real-estate-agent-whats.html</link>
        
          <category>Central PA Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Dave Hooke</author>
        <pubDate>2016-04-05 16:11:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

What’s the market like in South Central Pennsylvania? Unfortunately, the national news focuses on data taken from 11 metropolitan areas in the United States. You really need to talk to a local expert to figure out what the real estate market in your area is like. Fortunately, I’m here to provide that hyperlocal insight for our area!

For the first time in six years, our housing market is improving.  The average value of real estate in our area has finally started to increase over the last 12 months. We hope that appreciation continues in 2016!

The average days on market has dropped from 96 to 89 days on market, so homes are selling faster than they were last year as well.

Finally, the number of homes sold in the past 12 months has increased by almost 900 homes. That’s an increase of over 5%.

With these market conditions and historically low interest rates, now is a great time to buy or sell a home. If you have any questions, give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

What’s the market like in South Central Pennsylvania? Unfortunately, the national news focuses on data taken from 11 metropolitan areas in the United States. You really need to talk to a local expert to figure out what the real estate market in your area is like. Fortunately, I’m here to provide that hyperlocal insight for our area!

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

What’s the market like in South Central Pennsylvania? Unfortunately, the national news focuses on data taken from 11 metropolitan areas in the United States. You really need to talk to a local expert to figure out what the real estate market in your area is like. Fortunately, I’m here to provide that hyperlocal insight for our area!

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Dave Hooke</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Dave Hooke</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Dave Hooke Team LLC - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
