<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Milford Real Estate Podcast with Josh Lioce</title>
    <link>http://lioceteamblog.com</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://lioceteamblog.com"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Lioce Properties Inc. - your professional Milford Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Josh Lioce</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2017-10-06 15:19:17 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Josh Lioce</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://lioceteamblog.com/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Milford, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Josh@LioceTeam.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Josh Lioce</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Josh Lioce</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://lioceteamblog.com/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Milford, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Milford Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Lioce Properties Inc. - your professional Milford Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Can You Increase Your Home's Curb Appeal?</title>
        <link>http://lioceteamblog.com/how-can-you-increase-your-homes-curb.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Josh Lioce</author>
        <pubDate>2017-09-05 13:53:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/+Videos/2017/September/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Can+You+Increase+Your+Home%2527s+Curb+Appeal%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The first impression people have of your home will be based on its curb appeal. Today, I’ve got some easy ways to add some vibrancy to the exterior of your property.

Buying a Milford home? Get a full Home Search
Selling your Milford home? Get a free Home Value Report

When people see your home, their first impression will be based on the exterior. For this reason, curb appeal is incredibly important. Today, I’ve got some quick fixes and simple tips that you can use to boost the curb appeal of your property.

If your home is looking a little drab, you should focus on ways to make a quick impact on the home. To do this, you should determine if the exterior of the home needs a fresh coat of paint or be power washed.

Paint can actually go a long way in improving the appearance of a home. However, take your time. Don’t merely throw on a coat of paint.

Before you do, make sure to scrape off the old paint in places where it might cause unsightly texture beneath the fresh coat. Take your time when power washing, too.

“A LITTLE FRESH PAINT CAN GO A LONG WAY.”

But what if it’s your yard that is lacking luster? If you have an upcoming home showing and lack the time to mulch, you still have options. Getting already potted plants to put outside your home can add a lot of vibrancy to your home’s curb appeal.

Also remember not to neglect the appearance of your front door. As the entrance to your home, your front door is the focal point of your home. Repainting can go a long way, but sometimes a total replacement is a better option. It all depends on the condition of your home and the door itself.

The final way to boost your curb appeal is something many people forget: your mailbox. Your mailbox is a feature of your home that people see easily as they drive past or approach your home.

While most people tend not to notice a mailbox, they will certainly pay attention to one that is especially attractive. For a quick, easy impact on your front yard—update your mailbox.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/+Videos/2017/September/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Can+You+Increase+Your+Home%2527s+Curb+Appeal%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://lioceteamblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/+Videos/2017/September/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Can+You+Increase+Your+Home%2527s+Curb+Appeal%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

The first impression people have of your home will be based on its curb appeal. Today, I’ve got some easy ways to add some vibrancy to the exterior of your property.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Josh Lioce</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

The first impression people have of your home will be based on its curb appeal. Today, I’ve got some easy ways to add some vibrancy to the exterior of your property.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Milford, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 Things You Need to Know If You're Buying a Property with an HOA</title>
        <link>http://lioceteamblog.com/5-things-you-need-to-know-if-youre.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buying Tips</category>
        
        <author>Josh Lioce</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-22 13:49:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+Things+You+Need+to+Know+If+You%2527re+Buying+a+Property+with+an+HOA+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I wanted to take some time to talk to you about some things you should consider before buying a property governed by a homeowner’s association.

Buying a Milford home? Get a full Home Search
Selling your Milford home? Get a free Home Value Report

Before you purchase a property with an HOA, I’ve listed five things that you should take into consideration:

1. What is the cost of the association? What are the monthly costs going to be and what will be included in the membership? The HOA membership dues are an automatic payment that you will need to pay on top of your mortgage payment and other taxes, so make sure it’s something that you can budget in and are comfortable with.

2. Understand what you’re actually paying for and what you’re obligated to do in regards to maintenance or upkeep. There are certain HOAs that are going to take care of all the groundskeeping, and others that will require you to take care of it yourself.

3. What are the rules? Understanding those rules and regulations will help you make a better decision about the neighborhood you’re moving into. Sometimes it will be in regards to what facilities you can use and when they’re open. Other times it will be about which days you can set out your trash, where you can park specific vehicles (or if you can park commercial vehicles in the driveway at all), and other regulations. If you don’t follow the HOA rules, then it could result in fines or expulsion from the HOA.

“UNDERSTANDING THOSE RULES AND REGULATIONS WILL HELP YOU MAKE A BETTER DECISION ABOUT THE NEIGHBORHOOD YOU’RE MOVING INTO.”

4. Are you happy with the way a property looks? When you’re buying a property with an HOA, you more than likely won’t have control over certain things, like the colors of the house or front door, what can be hung from the porch, or if you can have a screen door. Make sure that you like the way everything looks when you buy your property, because you may not be able to change it.

5. Can you get involved in the HOA? Is it a small board or more of an open, town hall feel? See if you’re able to join that HOA so you can have a say in how it impacts your neighborhood.

Be sure to consider these things carefully before purchasing a home. If you have any additional questions or you’re looking to buy or sell a home, please give me a call. I’d be happy to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+Things+You+Need+to+Know+If+You%2527re+Buying+a+Property+with+an+HOA+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://lioceteamblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+Things+You+Need+to+Know+If+You%2527re+Buying+a+Property+with+an+HOA+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today I wanted to take some time to talk to you about some things you should consider before buying a property governed by a homeowner’s association.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Josh Lioce</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today I wanted to take some time to talk to you about some things you should consider before buying a property governed by a homeowner’s association.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Milford, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 Tips to Protect Yourself During Your Move</title>
        <link>http://lioceteamblog.com/5-tips-to-protect-yourself-during-your.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buying Tips</category>
        
        <author>Josh Lioce</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-08 15:12:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today I wanted to take some time to talk to you about some things you should consider before buying a property governed by a homeowners association.

Buying a Milford home? Get a full Home Search
Selling your Milford home? Get a free Home Value Report

If you want to make sure you and your property are protected during a move, here are five essential tips you should follow.

First, do your research. Don’t just look in the phone book for the cheapest person. Look into Yelp, Facebook, and other similar online sites for reviews on movers. When you see one you like, ask for a referral from someone who used them. You don’t want to hire a person who’s never done this before—there are plenty of real estate horror stories that started that way.

Second, verify your mover is licensed, insured, and meets any and all federal requirements to travel for your move—especially if you’re traveling via interstate. If you are traveling via interstate, stick to one of the national mover companies like Atlas or Mayflower or at least a local company that’s affiliated with these national movers.

Third, watch out for the lowball bid. I’ve seen many instances of movers giving a person an extremely low bid, only to up their prices once the move starts. If something seems too good to be true, it typically is.

“DON’T JUST LOOK IN THE PHONE BOOK FOR THE CHEAPEST PERSON.”

Fourth, have a contingency plan. I always tell people to move out the day before their closing happens. That way if something unplanned happens, like the truck not showing up on time or not showing up at all, you have a day to deal with it. Get out the day before, put your belongings in storage overnight, and relieve some stress knowing that everything is taken care of and ahead of schedule.

Lastly, protect yourself. If your mover offers insurance packages that help protect your information, pay a little extra for it. This will give you peace of mind that your stuff is protected. Whether it’s a short-distance move or a long-distance move, it’s smart to pay to have your stuff protected and you’ll be glad you did it.

If you have any questions about how to protect yourself during your move or any other real estate topics you can think of, feel free to give me a call or shoot me an email. I’d be happy to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://lioceteamblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today I wanted to take some time to talk to you about some things you should consider before buying a property governed by a homeowners association.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Josh Lioce</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today I wanted to take some time to talk to you about some things you should consider before buying a property governed by a homeowners association.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Milford, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4 Things That Can Make or Break Your Milford Home Sale</title>
        <link>http://lioceteamblog.com/4-things-that-can-make-or-break-your.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Josh Lioce</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-06 13:29:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/+Videos/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+4+Things+That+Can+Make+or+Break+Your+Milford+Home+Sale.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you want to sell your house here in the Milford area, these four things can be the determining factor in how successful your sale is.

Buying a Milford home? Get a full Home Search
Selling your Milford home? Get a free Home Value Report

When you list your home, there are four things that can make or break your sale.

1. Pricing it right from the beginning: In a hot market like ours here in the Milford area, many sellers think they can test the market by pricing too high. As things start to cool down in the summer and fall months, though, inventory will rise and you’ll want to avoid that mindset and price your home right at market value. The closer the price is to the real value, the more activity you’ll get, and you can even get your house into a bidding war—which is ultimately what you want.

2. Amp up your marketing: The days of agents or homeowners taking their own marketing photos are long gone. Hire a professional photographer to shoot the home whether it costs $100,000 or $1 million. This is a must because of their ability to get the most out of the lighting, the angles, and the skyline. Many people make real estate decisions based on the photos they see online. Focus on social media as well; Facebook, LinkedIn, and Twitter should all give your property exposure. It will generate more activity on the home.

“THE DAYS OF REALTORS TAKING PHOTOS OF HOMES ARE LONG GONE.”

3. Staging: I don’t necessarily mean hiring a stager to advise you, but to instead use what you have and take a decluttering approach. Make sure you remove all the extra stuff and make sure you utilize what’s available in each room. You want to stage the property by opening up floor space to showcase square footage. It will not only improve the home’s photography, it will help buyers gets a better feel for the space.

4. Be prepared to receive multiple offers: Our market has very tight inventory so we’re seeing many more multiple offer situations than in the past, so it’s important to have a gameplan for it. If it’s not handled carefully and professionally, you could squander an amazing opportunity and even lose the offers. This will help you maximize the value of your home.

I hope you found this information helpful. If you have any questions or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home here in the Milford market, give me a call or send me an email soon. I’d be happy to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/+Videos/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+4+Things+That+Can+Make+or+Break+Your+Milford+Home+Sale.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://lioceteamblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/+Videos/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+4+Things+That+Can+Make+or+Break+Your+Milford+Home+Sale.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you want to sell your house here in the Milford area, these four things can be the determining factor in how successful your sale is.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Josh Lioce</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you want to sell your house here in the Milford area, these four things can be the determining factor in how successful your sale is.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Milford, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4 Key Factors in Determining in the Strength of an Investment Property</title>
        <link>http://lioceteamblog.com/4-key-factors-in-determining-in.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buying Tips</category>
        
        <author>Josh Lioce</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-22 13:02:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+4+signs+of+a+solid+investment+property.mp4</guid>
        <description>

How do you determine whether an investment property is a good fit for your goals? Focus on these four areas before closing the deal.

Buying a Milford home? Get a full Home Search
Selling your Milford home? Get a free Home Value Report

There are four key areas you need to be aware of when looking to buy a good investment property:

1. Projected income: You want to make some money or at least cover your expenses. A good rule to follow is the 1% rule: If the property costs $400,000, you should hope to make about $4,000 a month in income. This will tell you whether it’s in line with your investment goals.

2. The tenant situation: Is there a lease in place with existing tenants? How long have they been there? What’s their rental history? You also want to understand the management aspect and any issues a management company has faced, like tenants who have been late paying rent. This will help you understand what you’re buying and avoid buying into a bad rental situation.

“THE PERFECT PROPERTY WITH NO ISSUES OR FUTURE DEFERRED MAINTENANCE DOESN’T EXIST.”

3. Condition of the property: You won’t find a property that’s perfect with everything ready to roll that lets you sit back for 30 years and enjoy the rental income because it doesn’t exist. Issues will always come up, so it’s important to understand what needs to be done in the short term and what you should be prepared to shell out some cash for. For example, needing a new roof obviously isn’t ideal, but it won’t disrupt the building. On the other hand, if the plumbing needs to be replaced, it will be both a huge expense and disruptive since you’ll have to tear into the units and common areas of a rental property. You might even need to have a vacant building if any tenants are displaced by issues like this.

4. Understand the utilities: Be aware of all the utilities there, what is and isn’t separately metered, and how you’ll deal with it in terms of each individual unit. For example, if the gas is on a single meter, you’ll probably include it in rent. If you have separate meters, you can charge everybody individually. Most importantly, make sure that if you’re trying to pass along costs, you’re not violating any laws or state/town regulations.

If you have any questions about owning investment properties or you’re considering buying one, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I’m always glad to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+4+signs+of+a+solid+investment+property.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://lioceteamblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+4+signs+of+a+solid+investment+property.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

How do you determine whether an investment property is a good fit for your goals? Focus on these four areas before closing the deal.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Josh Lioce</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

How do you determine whether an investment property is a good fit for your goals? Focus on these four areas before closing the deal.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Milford, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Get Your Home Ready for Summer With These 5 Maintenance Tips</title>
        <link>http://lioceteamblog.com/get-your-home-ready-for-summer-with.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Selling Tips</category>
        
        <author>Josh Lioce</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-07 14:28:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+Get+your+home+ready+for+some+sun+%2526+fun.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Now that summer is officially here, there are a few things you need to do to do around your property to make sure it’s ready for the season.

Buying a Milford home? Get a full Home Search
Selling your Milford home? Get a free Home Value Report

As we head into summer, there are five things you should focus on to prepare your property for the season.

First, inspect all your brick and stone patios and walkways. Hardscapes and brick material can freeze and shift over the winter, so make sure you fix that for both safety and aesthetic reasons.

Second, feed your lawn. We’ve been lucky so far because this spring produced plenty of rain, which wasn’t good for your outdoor activity schedule but good for the grass. Continue to feed your grass and replenish it with nutrients. The more time you spend doing this, the greener and lusher it will be.

Third, check the condition of your fences. This is especially important if you have a wooden fence, as wood is more prone to take a beating over the winter. Make sure no pieces have fallen off, and if they have, tack them back on securely. From an aesthetic standpoint, another thing you can do to those wooden stockades or wooden picket fences is power wash them. This will make it look like it did the day you installed it.

“THE SEASON IS UPON US TO GRILL AND BARBECUE.”

Fourth, mulch your flower and vegetable beds. You may be a few steps ahead of me with this tip. Personally, I like to wait to address my mulch beds until as late as early June. Make sure your flower and vegetable beds are getting enough water and you continue to weed them.

Lastly—and most importantly—get your grill in gear! I love to grill pretty much all season, and if you’re like me, there are a few maintenance tasks you need to take care of with your grill. Check your grates to make sure they’re clean and in good condition. Also check all the heat diverters in the grill, the propane hookups, and the drip pan. If your igniter switch is faulty, you can go to your local hardware store, buy a new one, and ask a professional how to install it. This will add years to your grill’s lifespan and allow you to enjoy your backyard in style.

If you have any questions about how to get your home ready for summer or you’re thinking about buying or selling a home, don’t hesitate to give me a call or shoot me an email. I look forward to speaking with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+Get+your+home+ready+for+some+sun+%2526+fun.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://lioceteamblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+Get+your+home+ready+for+some+sun+%2526+fun.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Now that summer is officially here, there are a few things you need to do to do around your property to make sure it’s ready for the season.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Josh Lioce</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Now that summer is officially here, there are a few things you need to do to do around your property to make sure it’s ready for the season.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Milford, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4 Ways to Make Your Home Stand out to Buyers</title>
        <link>http://lioceteamblog.com/4-ways-to-make-your-home-stand-out-to.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Selling Tips</category>
        
        <author>Josh Lioce</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-24 10:22:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+4+ways+to+endear+your+home+to+the+market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you plan to sell your house, there are four things that a recent Realtor.com survey revealed will go a long way in appealing to buyers.

Buying a Milford home? Get a full Home Search
Selling your Milford home? Get a free Home Value Report

There are certain things that homebuyers want in a home and certain ways you can give it to them. According to a recent Realtor.com survey, these four things will make your home more attractive to buyers:

1. A kitchen that impresses: Spend a lot of time and thought updating the kitchen. This could include updated countertops, appliances, cabinets, and hardware, which can all make the home more attractive and modern. If your countertops and cabinets are in good shape, you can pull this off by just updating appliances.

2. The great outdoors: You can’t change the size of your yard, but you can make it inviting. Get rid of all the junk lying around, update the landscaping, and keep your grass freshly mowed. Make sure you have tables, chairs, or a fire pit; whatever will make people think of it as a nice place to play or relax and have company over.

3. A garage: People 55 and older actually prefer having a garage to a living room. Having a garage is huge, so make sure you give yourself enough time to get rid of all the clutter and make it open. If you’re lucky enough to have a 2-car garage, really showcase that space. People love garages not just to park their cars in, but to have space for certain tasks.

4. Avoid making rooms specific to your style or use: For example, don’t turn a bedroom into a dressing room or a photography darkroom. If you turn any spaces into a specific functioning space, make sure it is easy to convert it back or make it appear very neutral.

“YOU CAN’T CHANGE THE SIZE OF YOUR YARD, BUT YOU CAN MAKE IT INVITING.”

Remember, you want to set your house up in a way that you enjoy, but you don’t want anything so permanent that it can’t be changed back. If you have any other questions about appealing your home to buyers or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home here in the Milford area, give me a call or send me an email. I’m here to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+4+ways+to+endear+your+home+to+the+market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://lioceteamblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+4+ways+to+endear+your+home+to+the+market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you plan to sell your house, there are four things that a recent Realtor.com survey revealed will go a long way in appealing to buyers.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Josh Lioce</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you plan to sell your house, there are four things that a recent Realtor.com survey revealed will go a long way in appealing to buyers.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Milford, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Selling Your First Home? Follow These 4 Tips</title>
        <link>http://lioceteamblog.com/selling-your-first-home-follow-these-4.html</link>
        
        <author>Josh Lioce</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-08 15:51:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+4+tips+for+listing+your+first+home.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’re getting ready to sell your home for the first time, these four tips will help you out.

Buying a Milford home? Get a full Home Search
Selling your Milford home? Get a free Home Value Report

If you plan to sell your first house, there are four key tips you should follow:

1. Price your home accurately: The price is very important, so hire someone who knows your market instead of someone who dabbles or does real estate on the side. Pricing your home too high can be a killer for your first two or three weeks by making the other homes for sale in the area look better. Underpricing can create enough chaos and bids that the eventual winner might get cold feet.

2. Make sure your Realtor can help you prepare your home for sale: The preparation isn’t necessarily about staging, but using what you have and focusing on opening up the space, cleaning it as well as you can, and making it feel as big as possible. People focus on square footage and floor space.

“BUYERS FOCUS ON SQUARE FOOTAGE AND FLOOR SPACE.”

3. Be flexible with showings: Do your best to be available to leave the home if you work from home or have kids. The more open you are to showings, the quicker your home will sell.

4. Insist on professional photography from your Realtor: Don’t listen if they say they have an iPhone or a camera of their own unless they’re also a professional real estate photographer. You want a professional who truly knows how to capture a home. Pictures make all the difference online, and many buyers will decide whether they even want to see your home in person just by clicking a photo.

If you have any other questions about selling a home, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I’m always happy to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+4+tips+for+listing+your+first+home.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://lioceteamblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+4+tips+for+listing+your+first+home.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you’re getting ready to sell your home for the first time, these four tips will help you out.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Josh Lioce</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you’re getting ready to sell your home for the first time, these four tips will help you out.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Milford, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 Things You Can Expect During Your First Year of Homeownership</title>
        <link>http://lioceteamblog.com/5-things-you-can-expect-during-your.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buying Tips</category>
        
        <author>Josh Lioce</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-21 13:39:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+to+expect+as+a+new+homeowner.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I’m going over five things you can expect during your first year of homeownership.

Buying a Milford home? Get a full Home Search
Selling your Milford home? Get a free Home Value Report

What can you expect during your first year of homeownership? You’ve done all of the work of closing on your first home, but there are five things you should be prepared for now that you’re all moved in:

1. Something is going to break. Prepare yourself mentally and financially for something to go wrong. It might be your dishwasher or perhaps your A/C, but something is going to break. Just remember when it happens that it’s not the end of the world and that’s why you have home insurance.

2. You’ll get a ton of junk mail. You’ll get ads from everywhere, but you’ll also get some great coupons and other valuable offers. Throw out the junk, but make sure you hold onto the good stuff.

3. Your social circle is going to expand. You’re part of a community now, so get to know it! Say hi to people when taking out your trash or working in the yard and you’ll start to build lifelong friendships.

“IT MIGHT BE YOUR DISHWASHER OR PERHAPS YOUR A/C, BUT SOMETHING IS GOING TO BREAK.”

4. Your dreams will meet reality. You might have some great plans to add on a sunroom or embark on a grand remodel, but you’ll realize those plans might have to take a back seat for awhile. It costs a lot of money to furnish a home, and having beds for the bedrooms and living room furniture for the living room is going to be a priority over that sunroom.

5. It’s going to cost more than what you planned for. Furniture, drapes, kitchen appliances, and everything else you’ll need for your new space is going to add up. Don’t get too stressed! Learn to rebudget and keep moving forward.

If you have any other questions about what to expect during your first year of homeownership, or if you are looking to buy or sell a home, please feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+to+expect+as+a+new+homeowner.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://lioceteamblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+to+expect+as+a+new+homeowner.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today I’m going over five things you can expect during your first year of homeownership.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Josh Lioce</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today I’m going over five things you can expect during your first year of homeownership.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Milford, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Proper Etiquette When Attending an Open House</title>
        <link>http://lioceteamblog.com/the-proper-etiquette-when-attending.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buying Tips</category>
        
        <author>Josh Lioce</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-22 13:18:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+Dos+and+donts+during+open+houses.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I’m answering four common questions I get about proper open house etiquette.

Buying a Milford home? Get a full Home Search
Selling your Milford home? Get a free Home Value Report

More open houses are popping up as we get into the spring market, so today I want to go over proper open house etiquette for homebuyers.

1. Can I use the bathroom? If you gotta go, you gotta go. However, if there are a lot of people at a showing, you want to make sure you’re not hindering their ability to see the property. If you do use the restroom during a showing, make sure you leave it how you found it!

2. Can I bring my coffee? Most everyone in the current buyer pool loves their coffee. If you need that morning or mid-afternoon pick-me-up, make sure it’s in a container with a lid. You don’t want to be walking around someone’s home with a mug full of coffee.

3. Can I bring in my food? No. Never bring in food during a showing.

“NEVER TAKE A SELFIE WITH A PROPERTY.”

4. Can I peek in the closet? Of course! You’re looking at the home with the possibility of purchasing it, which means you need to know what sort of space the home offers. Just remember to be mindful when peering into personal spaces. For example, don’t open the drawers of dressers or go through anything that won’t be staying with the property. Also, on the subject of respecting privacy and personal space, never take a selfie with the property.

5. Can I sit on the furniture? If you want to sit for a second to get the feel of a room or if you have a health condition that hinders your physical capabilities, it’s fine to take a seat. However, lounging on the furniture can come across as disrespectful. You’re there to look at the home and gauge if it’s right for you, so make sure you’re respectful during that process.

If you are looking to buy or sell a home, or if you have any other questions, please feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+Dos+and+donts+during+open+houses.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://lioceteamblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+Dos+and+donts+during+open+houses.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today I’m answering four common questions I get about proper open house etiquette.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Josh Lioce</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today I’m answering four common questions I get about proper open house etiquette.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Milford, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The 4 Things You Need to Know About Home Inspections</title>
        <link>http://lioceteamblog.com/the-4-things-you-need-to-know-about.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buying Tips</category>
        
        <author>Josh Lioce</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-09 13:24:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+4+things+to+know+about+home+inspections.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’re thinking about purchasing a home, you’ll need to order a home inspection. I want to share four things you should know before starting that process.

Buying a Milford home? Get a full Home Search
Selling your Milford home? Get a free Home Value Report

Today I want to share four things you need to know before you order a home inspection.

1. You get to choose the inspector. You’ll want to make sure they’re an NAHI certified home inspector, and you get can choose one either by looking at a list of local inspectors or by getting a referral, which is what I recommend. Also, don’t be afraid to compare prices and services different home inspectors offer.

2. Home inspections are not meant to point out cosmetic flaws. Many people will get hung up on a rip in a rug or a crack in the tile. Cosmetic repairs of that nature will be addressed by yourself and your agent, not by your home inspector.

3. A home inspection covers the basics. It will cover the condition of your systems, such as your HVAC, and structural issues of any kind. It will also cover any potential maintenance issues. You’re paying for the inspection, so make sure you follow along with the inspector and listen to everything they have to say.

4. The home inspector is not responsible for things they can’t see. For example, if you buy a home and there is an issue found behind the walls years later, the home inspector is not accountable for that. You need to be comfortable with the home inspection as a whole because there are going to be certain parts of the structure that just can’t be seen.

“STICK WITH YOUR HOME INSPECTOR DURING THE INSPECTION TO GET TIPS AND HELPFUL THOUGHTS ABOUT THE HOME.”

If you have any other questions about home inspections, or if you have any other real estate questions, please feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I’m always happy to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+4+things+to+know+about+home+inspections.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://lioceteamblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+4+things+to+know+about+home+inspections.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you’re thinking about purchasing a home, you’ll need to order a home inspection. I want to share four things you should know before starting that process.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Josh Lioce</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you’re thinking about purchasing a home, you’ll need to order a home inspection. I want to share four things you should know before starting that process.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Milford, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Steps Should You Take Before Buying a Home?</title>
        <link>http://lioceteamblog.com/what-steps-should-you-take-before.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buying Tips</category>
        
        <author>Josh Lioce</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-10 12:04:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+steps+to+a+successful+home+purchase.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you are looking to buy your first home, make sure you follow these five steps to ensure a successful purchase.

Buying a Milford home? Get a full Home Search
Selling your Milford home? Get a free Home Value Report

If you’re a first-time homebuyer looking to make a purchase in 2017, follow these five steps to ensure you end up in your dream home.

1. Make sure you’re working with the right agent. You might have a friend or relative with their real estate license who may or may not sell a home or two a year. However, having a personal relationship with them doesn’t necessarily make them the best choice. You need to make sure your agent understands the marketplace, knows about inventory, can manage the transaction well based on experience, and has great relationships with local lenders.

2. Don’t be afraid to talk to multiple lenders or mortgage brokers. Talking to more than one person will allow you to understand the different options available to you. You don’t have to go forward with a full application until you’ve weighed all your options and picked a direction to go in.

3. Mind your credit score. Moving forward, your score is going to have an important role, either positively or negatively, on what loan product you are able to qualify for. Make sure you are not missing any payments on credit cards, opening new credit cards, or making large purchases that will have a negative impact on your credit score. On the flip side, paying something large off might not have the effect you want it to, so talk to your lender before any large financial decisions are made.

4. Stay at your job. Leaving your job can have an immediate impact on your ability to get a loan. If you really want to change your job, do it before you start the process of getting approved, or wait until after closing.

5. Take your time. Don’t rush this process, especially if you are looking for your first home. Looking at homes for the first time is exciting, and you might be tempted to jump on something because of lack of inventory. However, you need to see enough homes to truly understand what you want in a home. Make sure what you’re writing an offer on is exactly what you’ve been looking for.

“MAKE SURE THE AGENT YOU’RE WORKING WITH IS EXPERIENCED AND UNDERSTANDS THE MARKET.”

If you have a question you’d like me to make a video for, or if you have any other real estate related questions you would like to chat about, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+steps+to+a+successful+home+purchase.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://lioceteamblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+steps+to+a+successful+home+purchase.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you are looking to buy your first home, make sure you follow these five steps to ensure a successful purchase.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Josh Lioce</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you are looking to buy your first home, make sure you follow these five steps to ensure a successful purchase.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Milford, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4 Rules for Selling a Home With a Pet</title>
        <link>http://lioceteamblog.com/4-rules-for-selling-home-with-pet.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Selling Tips</category>
        
        <author>Josh Lioce</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-24 09:20:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+sell+a+house+that+has+pets.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’re selling your home and you have pets, following these four steps will ensure that they don’t harm the sale.

Buying a Milford home? Get a full Home Search
Selling your Milford home? Get a free Home Value Report

If you’re selling your home and you have pets, you have to prepare for the market a little bit differently. Here are four essential steps you can take so that your home sale goes off without a hitch:

1. Remove any pets from the home during any showings. Having a dog that’s upset and lurking around, for example, while a buyer is walking through the house represents a huge liability if worse comes to worse and that dog decides to bite that buyer. In fact, your insurance company might not even cover that. Even if they’re inside a crate or otherwise restrained, a pet’s presence alone can be distracting to buyers.

2. Prepare your backyard. Because I have two dogs myself, you and I both know that the backyard can turn into a landmine area for pet owners. To make this area look presentable, pick up any droppings and repair any spots that have been dug up or torn out. If you see any discoloration, try and lay down some new sod if you can. And, of course, keep your pets out of this area during any showings.

3. Eliminate any odors. Odors can be a real estate deal-killer, and pet odors are very strong in particular. You might not notice it, but if someone like your Realtor mentions that they can smell pet odor, have your carpet steamed and cleaned and replace any bedding or specialized pillows. Do your best to neutralize this smell, because it can affect not only the saleability of your home but also the value you ultimately get for the sale price.

4. Get rid of any pet hair. If your dog is an excessive shedder, do your best to brush them outside and give them frequent baths. If a buyer has allergies, any kind of dander can cause those to flare up, which can send them running out the door. Also, your home won’t look well-kept if every area of it is coated in pet hair.

“YOU MIGHT NOT REALIZE YOUR HOME HAS A PET ODOR, BUT OTHERS WILL.”

Following these steps will greatly improve your home’s saleability. If you have any more questions about this topic, feel free to reach out to me. I’d love to talk with you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+sell+a+house+that+has+pets.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://lioceteamblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+sell+a+house+that+has+pets.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you’re selling your home and you have pets, following these four steps will ensure that they don’t harm the sale.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Josh Lioce</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you’re selling your home and you have pets, following these four steps will ensure that they don’t harm the sale.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Milford, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4 Inexpensive Ways to Prepare Your Home for the Market</title>
        <link>http://lioceteamblog.com/4-inexpensive-ways-to-prepare-your-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Josh Lioce</author>
        <pubDate>2016-12-29 11:42:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+4+things+you+should+do+before+selling.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Preparing your home for sale is a process, but it doesn’t have to be a complicated one. Here’s what we recommend for home sellers.

Buying a Milford home? Get a full Home Search
Selling your Milford home? Get a free Home Value Report

People ask me all the time about what they need to do to prepare their home for sale on the market. Here are four things I would focus on if I was getting ready to list my home:

1. Decluttering. I walk into homes all the time that are cluttered. When you have lived in a place for a while (or you have kids), this happens. When you get ready to sell, however, you should do all you can to declutter your rooms and get all the little items and knick knacks out. If you can stack things neatly in a spare unfinished room or a garage, that’s great. You could also invest in a storage pod or storage locker while you show it.

2. Flooring. This is another area to really focus in on. It’s one of the first things potential buyers will take note of. If your flooring is outdated or damaged, it makes the rest of the house look bad. You don’t have to have brand-new flooring or high-end carpet, but giving everything a deep, professional cleaning will pay dividends in the end.

3. Paint. Fresh paint goes a long way. Not only does it make the house smell fresh and clean, it makes it look that way too. Scuffed white trim looks awful. A fresh coat of paint will have a big impact, especially on those high-traffic areas. Get rid of those fingerprints on the walls, too. Fresh paint has a big impact on showability and value.

4. A deep cleaning. This isn’t just a tidying up of the house we are talking about. You may even want to hire a cleaning company to come in and do an extensive, deep cleaning. There are many areas of your home that are often neglected that will really stand out if they are sparkling clean, like your windows, walls, appliances, cabinets, and baseboards..

“TAKE OUR ADVICE AND YOU WILL SELL FASTER FOR MORE MONEY.”

These are just four of the least expensive things you can do to prepare your home for sale. Take our advice and focus on these areas and your home will sell for more money and faster than your competition. I guarantee it. If you have any questions for me in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+4+things+you+should+do+before+selling.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://lioceteamblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+4+things+you+should+do+before+selling.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Preparing your home for sale is a process, but it doesn’t have to be a complicated one. Here’s what we recommend for home sellers.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Josh Lioce</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Preparing your home for sale is a process, but it doesn’t have to be a complicated one. Here’s what we recommend for home sellers.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Milford, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Buying a House This Season Could Be the Smartest Choice Youll Ever Make</title>
        <link>http://lioceteamblog.com/buying-house-this-season-could-be.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buying Tips</category>
        
        <author>Josh Lioce</author>
        <pubDate>2016-12-15 13:02:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+Why+buying+a+home+now+is+so+smart.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’re in the market to buy a home, doing so during the holidays might end up being the best decision of your life. There are a few reasons why.

Buying a Milford home? Get a full Home Search
Selling your Milford home? Get a free Home Value Report

Buying a home over the holidays could end up being the smartest decision you’ll ever make. There are a few reasons why:

1. There is less competition. Bidding against other people when there is a lot of activity and little inventory makes it very difficult for a first-time home buyer to get into the marketplace. It can be hard when properties get priced above what you’re ready or able to pay for. It can also be intimidating to be in a bidding situation where you need to react very quickly and, sometimes, spend more money than you’re ready to spend. During the holidays, inventory may still be low, but competition also slows down.

2. Sellers who have their home on the market during the holidays tend to be more serious and motivated to sell. Many sellers will take their home off the market during this time because they want to focus on the holidays. The sellers who keep their home on the market over the holidays are very focused on selling. They also tend to be more reasonable and open to negotiation.

3. A home you love is a great gift to yourself. During the holidays, you always want something for yourself and your family—what better gift than a new home? Think of buying at this time as you are buying yourself a big Christmas gift.

“THINK OF IT LIKE A BIG CHRISTMAS GIFT FOR YOURSELF AND YOUR FAMILY!”

If you have any other questions about buying a home this season, don’t hesitate to give me a call and take advantage of this favorable market. Happy Holidays!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+Why+buying+a+home+now+is+so+smart.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://lioceteamblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+Why+buying+a+home+now+is+so+smart.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you’re in the market to buy a home, doing so during the holidays might end up being the best decision of your life. There are a few reasons why.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Josh Lioce</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you’re in the market to buy a home, doing so during the holidays might end up being the best decision of your life. There are a few reasons why.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Milford, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Is the Time Right to Stop Renting and Buy a House?</title>
        <link>http://lioceteamblog.com/is-time-right-to-stop-renting-and-buy.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buying Tips</category>
        
        <author>Josh Lioce</author>
        <pubDate>2016-11-28 12:29:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+Rent+or+buy%253F+5+key+considerations.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Are you renting now but thinking about jumping in and buying your first home? There are five key things you need to consider when making this decision.

Buying a Milford home? Get a full Home Search
Selling your Milford home? Get a free Home Value Report

If you’re currently renting, should you buy your first home or continue renting in our market? There are five key things you need to think about to make this decision.

1. Are you financially prepared? You’ll need to make some form of down payment, and even if you’re financing 100% of the home, you’ll still need to put down a somewhat sizable deposit at offer, purchase, and sale. You’ll also need closing costs, which can be around $5,000 to $7,000 to pay for the loan, attorney’s fees, and other closing costs. Then there are out-of-pocket costs like the home inspection, the first year’s home insurance, or an appraisal to consider. You also should have some reserves so your savings doesn’t run completely dry.

2. Be prepared to compromise. You may want the $100,000 kitchen and all the amenities of a dream home, but it’s your first home, so you may have to back off a bit to find a home that fits you.

3. Are you emotionally ready? When you rent, you call the landlord if your fridge or microwave breaks, and if the rent goes up, you can move out and move on. If you’re a homeowner, you need to be ready to pay higher taxes and replace things when they break.

“ARE YOU EMOTIONALLY READY?”

4. Will owning a home pay off in the long run? Outside of the recent crash from 2007, real estate has always provided positive growth and gain. Most likely, when you buy, you’ll pay the same (or even less) than you would in rent. Even if you’re not, there are the advantages of taxes, depreciation, and overall equity gains that you don’t get by renting.

5. Has your lifestyle outgrown renting? Have you had kids? Do you need more space inside and outside your home? If you’re having these thoughts it’s probably time to start considering buying.

If you have any more questions about renting versus buying, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. I hope to hear from you soon!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+Rent+or+buy%253F+5+key+considerations.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://lioceteamblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+Rent+or+buy%253F+5+key+considerations.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Are you renting now but thinking about jumping in and buying your first home? There are five key things you need to consider when making this decision.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Josh Lioce</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Are you renting now but thinking about jumping in and buying your first home? There are five key things you need to consider when making this decision.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Milford, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Can You Successfully Sell Your Home in the Fall or Winter?</title>
        <link>http://lioceteamblog.com/how-can-you-successfully-sell-your-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Josh Lioce</author>
        <pubDate>2016-11-14 13:14:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+Top+tips+for+selling+in+the+fall+%2526+winter.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There are a few things sellers need to do in order to sell their homes during the fall or winter. Today I have my top fall and winter selling tips to help you do just that.

Buying a Milford home? Get a full Home Search
Selling your Milford home? Get a free Home Value Report

Today I’m here with the top tips to sell your home in the fall or winter.

First of all, you need to pay close attention to curb appeal. Don’t get too excited and buy every pumpkin, gourd, or fall decoration out there. There is a fine line between having a nice, decorated farmer’s porch and a full-blown farmer’s market. Go easy on the exterior decorations.

Although people expect the leaves to fall, you should work to keep your yard somewhat clear, especially during a showing or open house. The same thing holds true for the winter. We all expect snow, but you need to keep your driveways and walkways clear. Your home should look nice and accessible in either season.

Next, go easy on the holiday decorations. Having some nice decorations for the fall or winter can make your home feel warm, inviting, and cozy, but going crazy with decorations can be a turnoff. Don’t buy every blow-up snowman from Lowe’s and throw them in your yard. Don’t get three different Christmas trees and scatter them throughout the house. You can absolutely decorate for the holidays, especially if you have small kids, but just make sure it’s tastefully done if your home is on the market.

“DON’T GO OVERBOARD ON THE HOLIDAY DECORATIONS.”

Let there be light. As it starts to get darker outside, it’s important to make sure that your blinds are open during the day to let in the natural light. In the late afternoon or evening, leave your lights on. Set exterior lights to a timer and light up the inside of your home before you leave. If you have energy-efficient light bulbs, make sure you turn them on early so they have time to warm up. You want people to walk into a home that is warm and bright, not dim and gloomy.

Finally, make the fireplace a focal point. If there is peeling paint, repaint it. Clean it out, get a new grate, and make sure the wood is neatly stacked so that it looks fantastic. If you are comfortable leaving your gas or wood burning fireplace on for showings, go ahead. Just make sure the screen is in place. That way, buyers will walk into your warm, inviting home and think, “Wow! I would love a fireplace.”

These are just a few things you can do to make sure your home sells in the fall and winter. If you have any other questions about preparing your home for the market, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+Top+tips+for+selling+in+the+fall+%2526+winter.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://lioceteamblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+Top+tips+for+selling+in+the+fall+%2526+winter.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

There are a few things sellers need to do in order to sell their homes during the fall or winter. Today I have my top fall and winter selling tips to help you do just that.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Josh Lioce</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

There are a few things sellers need to do in order to sell their homes during the fall or winter. Today I have my top fall and winter selling tips to help you do just that.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Milford, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4 Tips to Help You Win the Milford Home You Want</title>
        <link>http://lioceteamblog.com/4-tips-to-help-you-win-milford-home-you.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buying Tips</category>
        
        <author>Josh Lioce</author>
        <pubDate>2016-10-28 14:18:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+4+ways+to+make+your+home+offer+stand+out.mp4</guid>
        <description>

In the hot Milford seller’s market, how do you make your home offer stand out from the rest? Here are four steps I suggest you take.

Buying a Milford home? Get a full Home Search
Selling your Milford home? Get a free Home Value Report

The Milford market is extremely hot this fall, and as a home buyer, it’s likely that you’ll find yourself in a multiple offer situation. Here are a few tips to help make your offer stand out to sellers and win you the home you want:

1. Be simplistic with your offer. Less is more when it comes to your offer. Focus on the basics, write as strong an offer as you can based on the guidance of your buyer’s agent, and don’t let cosmetic issues concern you. If you’re a first-time home buyer, don’t worry about the cracked tile in the floor or asking for extra contingencies. Make sure your offer is clean, basic, and as aggressive as possible.

2.Consider writing a personal letter to the seller. Take the time to either write a personal letter to the seller or, even better, ask your agent to shoot a video message in which you tell the seller how much you love their home and how you plan on continuing their legacy of proud homeownership in the property. A personal video message, which is even more powerful than a personalized letter, is going to have a major impact on the presentation of your offer. Just like a letter, you can’t guarantee that the listing agent will share it with the sellers, but I guarantee you that a listing agent has never received a personalized video from a buyer to the seller.

“A PERSONALIZED VIDEO MESSAGE CAN MAKE A WORLD OF DIFFERENCE TO A SELLER.”

3. Have your agent deliver your offer in person. Obviously, ask your agent if they are comfortable doing this. After your offer has been submitted to the agent and that agent has forwarded the seller your personalized video and your offer terms, ask your agent to spend five minutes with the seller to explain the offer in more detail and make sure they’ve seen your personalized video. This is your chance to let the seller learn more about your family, explain why you’re coming to town, and establish a real connection with you. Again, this is something that no other buyer agent will be doing.

4. Present a clean pre-approval with your offer. Make sure your pre-approval is clear about what you can afford, is concise about your loan program, and states that you are approved. Stay away from letters that say “pre-qualified” and make sure it is as strong and as powerful a letter from a lender as possible. Secondly, ask the loan officer to follow up with the listing agent directly. Give your loan officer permission to call the listing agent and divulge as much information about you as they can, especially the information that positions you as a strong client with solid finances.

These tips can make a world of difference when submitting your offer to a seller. If you have any other questions about buying or selling a home in our market, please don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to speaking with you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+4+ways+to+make+your+home+offer+stand+out.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://lioceteamblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+4+ways+to+make+your+home+offer+stand+out.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

In the hot Milford seller’s market, how do you make your home offer stand out from the rest? Here are four steps I suggest you take.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Josh Lioce</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

In the hot Milford seller’s market, how do you make your home offer stand out from the rest? Here are four steps I suggest you take.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Milford, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Should You Do With a Lowball Offer?</title>
        <link>http://lioceteamblog.com/what-should-you-do-with-lowball-offer.html</link>
        
        <author>Josh Lioce</author>
        <pubDate>2016-10-17 12:48:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+Turning+a+lowball+offer+into+a+home+run.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you receive a lowball offer on your home, don’t fret. There are five steps you can take that will turn that offer into an advantage.

Buying a Milford home? Get a full Home Search
Selling your Milford home? Get a free Home Value Report

If you’re a home seller, what should you do if you receive a lowball offer? There are five important steps to follow if you want to turn it into an advantage:

1. Don’t get insulted, and don’t take it personally. This is just an offer on paper. You don’t know if that buyer has been coached to write a lowball offer or if they’re coming from an area or part of the country where lowball offers are common. Take a deep breath and be excited that you have an offer to start negotiating with.

2. Respond gracefully. Thank the buyer and the agent for their offer. Thank them for taking the time to put it forth and tell them that you hope that it comes together and you can both come to mutually agreeable terms. This will demonstrate that you’re happy that your offer is on the table and you’re happy to work with them.

“A LOWBALL OFFER IS JUST AN OFFER ON PAPER—DON’T TAKE IT PERSONALLY.”

3. Write a strategic counteroffer. Make sure you and your agent sit down and discuss how to respond to this. The offer, no matter where it is, should not affect how you negotiate your price. You and your agent should have a strategic plan to go back and give a counteroffer, the terms and conditions you’re willing to accept, and a reason to give to the buyer explaining why it’s not close to their number. A good agent will have this ready to go before you even ask.

4. Expect a counteroffer to your counteroffer. The buyer isn’t going to accept your counteroffer right out of the gate. Once they come back with their counteroffer, you’ll want to present your bottom line if they don’t meet your number. Be ready for your next move to be your best and final approach.

5. Hold firm to your bottom line requirements. When you present your best and final offer, do not jump at another counteroffer if they go that direction. If that happens, thank them for their effort and their attempt and tell them you’re going to seek other offers. Hopefully, their response to your next bottom line is acceptance of your terms.

If you have any more questions or have a topic in mind you’d like to see me discuss, please don’t hesitate to email me or give me a call. I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+Turning+a+lowball+offer+into+a+home+run.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://lioceteamblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+Turning+a+lowball+offer+into+a+home+run.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you receive a lowball offer on your home, don’t fret. There are five steps you can take that will turn that offer into an advantage.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Josh Lioce</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you receive a lowball offer on your home, don’t fret. There are five steps you can take that will turn that offer into an advantage.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Milford, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The 4 Worst Pieces of Advice Sellers Usually Get</title>
        <link>http://lioceteamblog.com/the-4-worst-pieces-of-advice-sellers.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Selling Tips</category>
        
        <author>Josh Lioce</author>
        <pubDate>2016-10-03 11:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/%25289-23-2016%2529+Things+sellers+hear+and+believe.mp4</guid>
        <description>

“Only sell your home during the spring,” and, “Hold off until the market gets busier,” are just two examples of bad advice sellers usually get.

Buying a Milford home? Get a full Home Search
Selling your Milford home? Get a free Home Value Report

Here are four of the worst pieces of advice that sellers sometimes get and actually believe in regard to selling their home:

1. “Only sell your home in the springtime.” While it’s true that spring is the busiest time to sell a home, it’s also the most competitive. You have to sell your home when you’re ready, and you have to listen to your real estate agent for advice on when the best time is to sell in your community. Real estate is microlocal, so you have to pay attention to the trends happening in your area. If you want to stand out, you might want to avoid selling during the busiest season. Remember—any time is a good time to sell just as long as you’re motivated, priced right, and ready to go to market.

2. “If the market’s slow, hold off until things get busier.” If you’re selling and buying and you wait until things are busier or when prices go up, your own purchase price will go up too. Again, only sell your home when you’re ready. Don’t wait for things to get busier or slower; take advantage of the marketplace as it is. If it’s not that busy, you’ll have an easier time finding what you want and you won’t face as much competition.

“REAL ESTATE IS AN EMOTIONAL SALE.”

3. “Don’t stage or fix anything; let the buyers use their imaginations.” Most consumers don’t have an imagination. Real estate is an emotional business. When they walk into a home, consumers are either going to fall in love with a home or hate it. They’re going to know within seconds or minutes if it’s the home for them. Confer with your agent and prepare a plan to do all the right things that make the consumer fall in love with your home.

4. “Professional photography is not important.” On the contrary, photography is one of the most important things that your agent is going to do for your listing when it comes onto the market. People actually click past listings or decide to not even drive by them based on pictures  they see online. Make sure you invest in professional photography and that your home is ready for it. Use that photography to capitalize on the ability to market your property online to as many people as possible.

If you have any questions about this topic, don’t forget to give me a call or shoot me an email. I’d be happy to help in any way I can.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/%25289-23-2016%2529+Things+sellers+hear+and+believe.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://lioceteamblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/%25289-23-2016%2529+Things+sellers+hear+and+believe.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

“Only sell your home during the spring,” and, “Hold off until the market gets busier,” are just two examples of bad advice sellers usually get.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Josh Lioce</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

“Only sell your home during the spring,” and, “Hold off until the market gets busier,” are just two examples of bad advice sellers usually get.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Milford, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>6 Key Points Not to Overlook When Buying a Home</title>
        <link>http://lioceteamblog.com/6-key-points-not-to-overlook-when.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buying Tips</category>
        
        <author>Josh Lioce</author>
        <pubDate>2016-09-16 14:23:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

There are six important things that I see many home buyers forget to do over
 the process of buying a home.

Today I wanted to talk about six common things that buyers forget to do when buying a home.

1. Factor in other expenses during the process. You need to think about the home inspection cost because you won’t get that back even if the deal falls apart. Also consider the cost of the appraisal, which is a fee you pay before closing. Then there’s the homeowners insurance binder for the whole year, which is also a fee you pay up front. Speak with your agent to better understand all of the additional expenses you’ll have before you pay the closing costs.

2. Consider the home’s resale value. When you buy, you have to think like a seller. Understand the location, and think about what your resale value would be if something happened and you had to sell quick and/or unexpectedly.

3. Root out any restrictions. Make sure your agent and attorney discuss any restrictions on the deed with you, like easements, right of way, or things you’re allowed to do in your subdivision. Make sure you have a good understanding of those restrictions and how they will limit your use of the land.

4. Make sure any work completed by the previous homeowner was done with a permit or to code. For example, if the seller discloses that they had their basement renovated, make sure you or your agent does due diligence to make sure the proper permits were pulled and signed off by the town, and that there are no open permits. This will help you down the road if you choose to pull another permit.

5. If you are buying a condo, get the scoop of the homeowners association. Make sure you request all the documents, the rules and regulations, and most importantly, make sure you request a copy of the budget. That way, you can see if the budget is in check, and you can see the reserve account and whether it is full. The reserve account is for things like damage to the roof. If that reserve account is weak, you’ll have to come up with a lot of money in a special assessments.

6. Do your homework on the neighborhood. Drive by the home at different times during the day, like at night and right after school, for instance. You want to really get an understanding of the area so you can ensure that the home has what you’re looking for, neighborhood-wise.

“WHEN YOU BUY A HOUSE, DON’T FORGET TO THINK ABOUT FUTURE RESALE.”

Hopefully you found these tips helpful for your next home purchase. If you have questions about any of these points or any part of a real estate transaction, give me a call or send me an email. I’d love to help you out.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://lioceteamblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

There are six important things that I see many home buyers forget to do over
 the process of buying a home.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Josh Lioce</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

There are six important things that I see many home buyers forget to do over
 the process of buying a home.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Milford, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Low Appraisals Affect Buyers and Sellers</title>
        <link>http://lioceteamblog.com/how-low-appraisals-affect-buyers-and.html</link>
        
          <category>Appraisals</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate Tips</category>
        
        <author>Josh Lioce</author>
        <pubDate>2016-09-01 16:22:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+happens+when+an+appraisal+comes+in+low%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Whether you are or buying or selling a home, an appraisal is an important part of the transaction for you. So what happens if the appraisal comes in low?

There are basically three things that can happen:

1. You can challenge the appraisal. Reach out to the lender and tell them that you think it’s inaccurate or that they’ve missed something important. If the lender allows a challenge, you can give them some data or information that shows that the home’s value is higher than what they’ve deemed it to be.

2.Negotiation. If the difference between the asking price and the appraisal is $10,000, for example, the buyer and seller can negotiate that difference. There will typically be a more aggressive negotiation from the seller than the buyer. If the seller agrees to come down $7,000, the buyer will need to come up with an additional $3,000 to make up the difference. There are plenty of options for this. The seller could come down the full $10,000 or the buyer could come up and cover the full $10,000 in cash. It depends on the motivations of the buyer and seller and the market conditions, among other things.

3. The deal dies. You basically just cancel the deal if the buyer and seller can’t come to terms in the negotiation.

“THE BUYER AND SELLER CAN NEGOTIATE THE DIFFERENCE BETWEEN THE APPRAISAL AND THE SALE PRICE.”

Hopefully this situation doesn’t happen to you as a buyer or seller, but I hope this topic was helpful for you. If you have a low appraisal, always consult your real estate advisor for help to work through it the best way possible.

If you have any questions for me about appraisals or you’re thinking about buying or selling a home in Milford, give me a call or send me an email. I’d love to hear from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+happens+when+an+appraisal+comes+in+low%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://lioceteamblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Lioce/Milford+MA+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+happens+when+an+appraisal+comes+in+low%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Whether you are or buying or selling a home, an appraisal is an important part of the transaction for you. So what happens if the appraisal comes in low?

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Josh Lioce</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Whether you are or buying or selling a home, an appraisal is an important part of the transaction for you. So what happens if the appraisal comes in low?

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Milford, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Josh Lioce</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Josh Lioce</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Lioce Properties Inc. - your professional Milford Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
