<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Montgomery County Real Estate Podcast with Diane Cardano</title>
    <link>localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Cardano Realtors - your professional Montgomery County Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Diane Cardano</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2017-11-22 14:09:58 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Diane Cardano</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Montgomery County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Diane@CardanoHomeServices.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Diane Cardano</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Diane Cardano</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Montgomery County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Montgomery County Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Cardano Realtors - your professional Montgomery County Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>Our Room by Room Review Can Tap Into Any Home's Potential</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/want-to-polish-your-homes-potential.html</link>
        
          <category>RoombyRoom Reviews</category>
        
        <author>Diane Cardano</author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-25 15:42:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Diane+Cardano/Suburbs+of+Philadelphia+Real+Estate+Home+selling+tips+will+keep+thousands+of+dollars+in+your+pocket.mp4</guid>
        <description>

These tips will keep money in your pocket, just watch this short video! Save thousands by using this one strategy, Room by Room Review. Give your home the opportunity to work for you! Go to www.FreeRoomByRoom.com.

Buying a home? Click here to perform a full home search
Selling a home? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Call me at 215-576-8666 for a FREE home buying or selling consultation

It’s almost the end of the year, and many of you may be thinking about the possibility of selling your home in 2018.

So, what can you do right now to prepare? What I recommend is to get a room-by-room review. Doing this will help you to have a quick, lucrative, and stress-free transaction.

A room-by-room review is a free 30-minute appointment where we send out a listing specialist to evaluate your home’s current saleability. The agent will be able to give you tips on staging, paint colors, and decluttering.

This review is like having a real estate doctor make a house call for your home. Some home seller seminar graduates aren’t aware of how important it is to take advantage of this opportunity months or even years ahead of when they plan to sell.

Some people may think their home isn’t ready for this sort of room-by-room review, but the point is that it doesn’t have to be. This review can help sellers put together a plan of action. The agent who assists you will look past any clutter to let you know where you should begin, and how to concentrate your efforts moving forward.

Give your home a chance to shine and get top dollar by scheduling your free room-by-room review. We’ve been doing this service for years, and we have tons of testimonials from seller seminar graduates who were able to sell within 26 days or less.

“GIVE YOUR HOME A CHANCE TO SHINE AND GET TOP DOLLAR BY SCHEDULING YOUR FREE ROOM-BY-ROOM REVIEW.”

Pat Ingram is one of these happy sellers. She initially didn’t quite agree with some of my ideas, but once she implemented them she was able to sell in just three days.

To see just how well this service can work for you, go to www.FreeRoomByRoom.com to schedule an appointment.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Diane+Cardano/Suburbs+of+Philadelphia+Real+Estate+Home+selling+tips+will+keep+thousands+of+dollars+in+your+pocket.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Diane+Cardano/Suburbs+of+Philadelphia+Real+Estate+Home+selling+tips+will+keep+thousands+of+dollars+in+your+pocket.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

These tips will keep money in your pocket, just watch this short video! Save thousands by using this one strategy, Room by Room Review. Give your home the opportunity to work for you! Go to www.FreeRoomByRoom.com.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Diane Cardano</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

These tips will keep money in your pocket, just watch this short video! Save thousands by using this one strategy, Room by Room Review. Give your home the opportunity to work for you! Go to www.FreeRoomByRoom.com.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Montgomery County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>This Market Report Is Hot off the Press</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/homeownership-rates-are-increasing.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Diane Cardano</author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-11 13:47:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Diane+Cardano/Suburbs+of+Philadelphia+Real+Estate+Homeownership+rates+are+increasing.mp4</guid>
        <description>

This market report is hot off the press! Learn about what the increase in homeowners recently means for buyers and sellers.

Buying a home? Click here to perform a full home search
Selling a home? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Call me at 215-576-8666 for a FREE home buying or selling consultation

I am back with the September edition of the hot-off-the-press market report!

Summer’s over and homes are still flying off the market. More and more people are jumping into homeownership. Market Watch quotes consumer confidence rose in July to the second-highest level in 16 years.

Americans shrugged off all the drama of President Trump’s Washington, and took heart in the best labor market in a decade. Homeownership rates in the US actually went up 63.7%—the highest rate in three years.

The bottom line is that the economy is strong and improving. Interest rates remain low, and employment is high. When combined with the coming demographic shift as more millennials enter the prime household creating years, this suggests that the housing market is on a steady course for the foreseeable future.

As a matter of fact, people were surveyed with this question: “What would be the best way to invest your money—money that you wouldn’t need for 10 years or so?” Sure enough, real estate was the No. 1 answer.

Another reason why more and more people are becoming homeowners is wealth. According to state representative Loretta Sanchez, homeownership is the first rung on the ladder of wealth creation in our nation. The average worth of a family that owns a home is $225,000, while that of one who is renting is only $5,000. This means that the net worth of a homeowner is 45 times more than a renter.

“THIS MEANS THAT THE NET WORTH OF A HOMEOWNER IS 45 TIMES MORE THAN A RENTER.”

Of course, because more people are becoming homeowners, the supply of homes continues to be very low. This makes the current market an even better time to sell. That’s why my coming-soon listing program is so vital in this new market.

Check out these next stats:


  Homeowners who sold in the second quarter realized an average price gain of $51,000 since the purchase—the highest average price gain for home sellers since 2007.
  This represented an average return of 26% on the previous purchase price of the home.
  Homeowners who sold in the second quarter of 2017 had owned an average of 8.05 years.


Additionally, mortgage rates are projected to go up by next year, which could cause some buyers not to be interested in moving anymore. Waiting will cost more in price and interest rate for the buyer, making your home less affordable for buyers, and possibly lowering the value of your home.

These next statistics always make me chuckle. The difference between what a homeowner believes their house is worth and what the appraiser thinks its worth is just short of a 2% difference. When selling, I run the home through my pinpoint pricing analysis to make sure that we get the price that the home will appraise for, and save thousands for my clients.

If you’re thinking of selling in the next three months or three years, come to one of my home selling seminars—the next one is January 20th at the Hilton Garden Inn in Fort Washington. It’s a great way to get information and tips on how to sell your home, and I’ll give you my eight secret strategies guaranteed to save you thousands on buying a home. Visit HomeSharkSeminar.com or give us a call.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Diane+Cardano/Suburbs+of+Philadelphia+Real+Estate+Homeownership+rates+are+increasing.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Diane+Cardano/Suburbs+of+Philadelphia+Real+Estate+Homeownership+rates+are+increasing.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

This market report is hot off the press! Learn about what the increase in homeowners recently means for buyers and sellers.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Diane Cardano</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

This market report is hot off the press! Learn about what the increase in homeowners recently means for buyers and sellers.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Montgomery County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Unlock Your Success With 3 Tips for Getting Top Dollar</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/3-tips-youll-learn-at-my-upcoming.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Selling Tips</category>
        
        <author>Diane Cardano</author>
        <pubDate>2017-09-20 11:53:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Diane+Cardano/Suburbs+of+Philadelphia+Real+Estate+3+tips+you'll+learn+at+my+upcoming+seminar.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I’ve got three great tips on getting top dollar for your home. But if you want to hear my full advice, join me at my upcoming seller’s seminar.

Buying a home? Click here to perform a full home search
Selling a home? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Call me at 215-576-8666 for a FREE home buying or selling consultation

Today I want to go over the three things you need to do to get top dollar for your home. Low inventory means that homes are selling quickly and sellers have the advantage, but why not aim for getting even more money in your pocket?

When you’re thinking of selling one, two, or even three years from now, there are three things you can do to ensure your success down the line.

1. Start way earlier than you think. Consider Noah when he was building the arc. When he was building the boat and gathering the animals, he did so well in advance. This is exactly the mindset you need to apply to selling your home. Come to one of my home seller seminars, where we’ll teach you eight secret strategies to getting you top dollar. This will guarantee you a quick sale and more money in your pocket. People who come to our seminars are getting their homes off the market in just seven days and for at or above list price.

2. Crush the competition. Imagine a sports game where the final score ended up being something like 101 to three. This would make for an amazing win and an amazing story, and that’s exactly what you should aim for in your transaction. Having a competitive mentality will help put you far ahead of the competition. There are other homes out there that want to sell too; you need to make sure that your home is better than the rest.

3. Have buyers lined up outside of your door. This is something that happens at every one of our open houses. If you follow these first two steps, this is going to be the result. If you have this vision and follow through, it can come true for you too.

“HAVING A COMPETITIVE MENTALITY WILL HELP PUT YOU FAR AHEAD OF THE COMPETITION.”

You can learn all of these things at my upcoming Home Selling Sharks Seminar on October 7th at the Hilton Garden Inn. Free breakfast will begin at 8:30 a.m. and the seminar will start at 9:30 a.m. There will also be a meet and greet with various speakers during the breakfast.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Diane+Cardano/Suburbs+of+Philadelphia+Real+Estate+3+tips+you'll+learn+at+my+upcoming+seminar.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Diane+Cardano/Suburbs+of+Philadelphia+Real+Estate+3+tips+you'll+learn+at+my+upcoming+seminar.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today I’ve got three great tips on getting top dollar for your home. But if you want to hear my full advice, join me at my upcoming seller’s seminar.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Diane Cardano</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today I’ve got three great tips on getting top dollar for your home. But if you want to hear my full advice, join me at my upcoming seller’s seminar.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Montgomery County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What's Going On in Our Local Market?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/watch-this-exclusive-market-update.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Diane Cardano</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-29 11:46:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

What is going on in our local market? Today, I’m bringing you an update of the latest numbers for the suburbs of Philadelphia.

Buying a home? Click here to perform a full home search
Selling a home? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Call me at 215-576-8666 for a FREE home buying or selling consultation

While today’s market may have cooled off slightly from previous years, demand is absolutely hot.

As someone who has been in real estate for 25 years, I can say that I’ve never seen an August with demand quite like what we’re seeing right now. Buyer demand is far outpacing our supply.

“I’VE NEVER SEEN AN AUGUST WITH SUCH HIGH DEMAND.”

Financing is still available, which is great news. Even though prices continue to rise, homes are actually becoming more affordable.

Contrary to what many people tend to believe, renting can actually be much more expensive than buying. For example, the percentage of income needed to afford median rent is now 29.2%. The percentage of income needed to buy a median home is actually much lower—just 15.8%.

As more and more renters become buyers, demand continues to rise. The share of home shoppers who are renters has gone up from 45% in the first quarter of 2015 to 55% in the first quarter of this year.

Now is a great time to buy. This is especially the case since Freddie Mac is projecting that mortgage rates will increase.

Additionally, high demand and rising home values mean that there are also a lot of opportunities for sellers in today’s market. Homes are selling very quickly. I’ve personally helped many sellers to obtain top dollar by using two of my websites: www.ComingSoonListings.com and www.PreHouseInspection.com.

Many owners are finding that they are able to get more than they expected from their home. The more equity you have, the better position you’ll be in when it comes time for you to make your move.

Whether you’re thinking of selling now or later, we hope you’ll join us at our Home Selling Sharks Seminar on October 7th, 2017 at the Hilton Garden Inn. Breakfast begins at 8:30 a.m. and the seminar will begin an hour later at 9:30 a.m. For more information on that, you can visit www.homesharkseminar.com.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

What is going on in our local market? Today, I’m bringing you an update of the latest numbers for the suburbs of Philadelphia.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Diane Cardano</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

What is going on in our local market? Today, I’m bringing you an update of the latest numbers for the suburbs of Philadelphia.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Montgomery County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Prices to RISE in 2018 - GET PREPARED!</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/1-secret-trick-before-you-list.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Selling Tips</category>
        
        <author>Diane Cardano</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-25 13:35:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Diane+Cardano/Suburbs+of+Philadelphia+Real+Estate+1+secret+trick+before+you+list.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Using this one strategy, sellers can feel confident that they are getting the most money in the least amount of time.

Buying a home? Click here to perform a full home search
Selling a home? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Call me at 215-576-8666 for a FREE home buying or selling consultation

When it comes to selling a property, it is never too early to get a jump start on the process. Today, we want to let you in on a secret that can save you thousands: a pre-marketing home inspection.

We teach future home sellers each month at our seminar how to sell for up to 18% more. One of the ways to do this is by fighting off the “staging shark.” Real estate is a new world these days, and it’s a world where differentiating your home from the others is essential.

I’ve taught over 1,000 home sellers so far, and from doing so I’ve learned that most sellers want three key things. They want to sell for the most money, in the least amount of time, and they want to sell hassle free.

Having a pre-marketing home inspection takes care of all three of these points. When you get your home inspection taken care of prior to listing, you’re saving yourself a lot of money. If you discover anything in your property that needs a repair, you can choose from Cardano’s List—a compilation of business contractors my team and I trust to meet your needs.

When you have your inspection done in advance, you can have repairs done at your own pace and with your own preferred contractors instead of ones chosen by the buyer.

Additionally, buyers love being able to read home inspection reports as well as any receipts from the repairs you’ve made. This makes buyers more comfortable and will let them make you a clean offer at top dollar. In fact, a recent statistic says that 100% of home buyers feel more comfortable buying a pre-inspected home.

“100% OF HOME BUYERS FEEL MORE COMFORTABLE BUYING A PRE-INSPECTED HOME.”

A pre-home inspection also saves you time, since most buyers won’t feel the need to perform another after seeing your report. This eliminates the 14 to 21-day contingency period, and offers tend to be submitted in just days.

This strategy means home sellers don’t need to worry about a buyer backing out because of a home inspection. All cards are on the table. Sellers will be able to put their market on the home feeling confident that they’ve already taken care of all repairs.

So make sure that when you’re listing your home, you choose an expert advisor who utilizes this strategy.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Diane+Cardano/Suburbs+of+Philadelphia+Real+Estate+1+secret+trick+before+you+list.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Diane+Cardano/Suburbs+of+Philadelphia+Real+Estate+1+secret+trick+before+you+list.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Using this one strategy, sellers can feel confident that they are getting the most money in the least amount of time.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Diane Cardano</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Using this one strategy, sellers can feel confident that they are getting the most money in the least amount of time.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Montgomery County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Do Rising Home Prices Mean for You? </title>
        <link>localhost:4000/prices-are-on-rise.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Diane Cardano</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-07 14:03:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Diane+Cardano/Suburbs+of+Philadelphia+Real+Estate+Prices+are+on+the+rise.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Home prices are continuing to rise. What does that mean for you?

Buying a home? Click here to perform a full home search
Selling a home? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Call me at 215-576-8666 for a FREE home buying or selling consultation

Today I’ve got the July edition of the Hot Off The Press Market Report. It’s real juicy this month, and we’re going to focus on pricing because prices continue to be an issue.

Prices are continuing to rise, and we’re going to see more and more headlines about prices as we move through the rest of the summer. However, they’re going to be talking more about the challenges of these rising prices.

Right now, interest rates are said to be rising, so buyers are a little nervous. This is not just the first-time homebuyer that’s nervous, but the trade-up seller that’s also being affected. Prices are higher than they were during the housing boom in 2006.

Some people are saying that this is evidence of the housing market heading for another crash. That is not the case. When you compare the current price increases with what normal appreciation would have looked like if there wasn’t a bust in 2008, then we’re right on track with current prices.

Home values are where they should be, and now is the time to sell. In the last 12 months, prices have gone up 6% nationally and, in most markets, the level of appreciation is actually accelerating.

“HOME VALUES ARE WHERE THEY SHOULD BE, AND NOW IS THE TIME TO SELL.”

There will be a surge in prices in this fall market, so get me to your home right now so we can get your home ready to sell by the time fall comes.

We offer a free room-by-room consultation online at FreeRoomByRoom.com, and if you’re thinking of selling in 2018, come to our next Home Selling Sharks Seminar. Our next seminar is October 14, 2017 at 8:30 a.m. at the Hilton Garden Inn in Fort Washington, PA.

If you have any other questions or you’re looking to buy or sell your home, give us a call. We’d be happy to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Diane+Cardano/Suburbs+of+Philadelphia+Real+Estate+Prices+are+on+the+rise.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Diane+Cardano/Suburbs+of+Philadelphia+Real+Estate+Prices+are+on+the+rise.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Home prices are continuing to rise. What does that mean for you?

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Diane Cardano</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Home prices are continuing to rise. What does that mean for you?

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Montgomery County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Home Values Up in 2nd Quarter 2017</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/suburbs-of-philadelphia-real-estate-tax.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Diane Cardano</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-22 09:32:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Diane+Cardano/Suburbs+of+Philadelphia+Real+Estate+Tax+advantages+of+homeownership.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Our spring season was crazy—but why? Homeowners are realizing the tax advantages of owning a home.

Buying a home? Click here to perform a full home search
Selling a home? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Call me at 215-576-8666 for a FREE home buying or selling consultation

Thank you for joining me for another Hot Off the Press market report. We had an incredible spring, where 90% of the metro areas are boasting year-over-year gains. Why is this happening?

Buyers are starting to realize the tax advantages of homeownership right now. I looked at the four major tax advantages of home ownership, according to the Tax Policy Center’s Briefing Book.

1. Mortgage Interest Deduction. “Homeowners who itemize deductions may reduce their taxable income by deducting any interest paid on a home mortgage.”

2. Property Tax Deduction. “Homeowners who itemize deductions may also reduce their taxable income by deducting property taxes they pay on their homes.”

3. Imputed Rent. “The return on homeownership is excluded from taxable income.”

4. Profits from home sales. “Homeowners may exclude from taxable income up to $250,000 of capital gains on the sale of their home.”

Americans still think that real estate is the American Dream. 34% believe that real estate is the best long-term investment.

Why are prices going up? It is generally a result of supply and demand. As a nation, we are at 3.8 months of inventory. That’s nothing! That’s what’s driving prices up, but not in every price range.

Right now, we have way less than six months inventory for first-time buyer homes, so we have a seller’s market. A little more inventory for move-up homes will bring it closer to a neutral market. In the premium market, we’re in a buyer’s market because we have more than seven months of inventory and in our area, more than nine months of inventory.

“INVENTORY IS HISTORICALLY LOW COMPARED TO THE LAST SIX YEARS.”

June is our “Celebrate National Homeownership Month.” Homebuyers want more privacy, a place for their family to grow, some stability, control over their future, and putting their hard-earned money to work for them.

Homeowners: if you have any thoughts about moving, you need to get started now. There’s not a lot of inventory on the market. In the next few weeks, we’ll talk about some great tips for homeownership.

If you have any questions or you’re looking to buy or sell a home, give me a call. I’d be happy to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Diane+Cardano/Suburbs+of+Philadelphia+Real+Estate+Tax+advantages+of+homeownership.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Diane+Cardano/Suburbs+of+Philadelphia+Real+Estate+Tax+advantages+of+homeownership.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Our spring season was crazy—but why? Homeowners are realizing the tax advantages of owning a home.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Diane Cardano</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Our spring season was crazy—but why? Homeowners are realizing the tax advantages of owning a home.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Montgomery County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why You Should Avoid the Traditional Real Estate Process</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/suburbs-of-philadelphia-real-estate-why.html</link>
        
          <category>Buyer and Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Diane Cardano</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-24 17:17:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Diane+Cardano/Suburbs+of+Philadelphia+Real+Estate+Why+you+should+avoid+the+traditional+real+estate+process.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The traditional real estate process is no longer a method that works for sellers, and I’ll tell you why.

Buying a home? Click here to perform a full home search
Selling a home? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Call me at 215-576-8666 for a FREE home buying or selling consultation

The traditional real estate process is lengthy and confusing for sellers. The first step that agents usually take is the listing interview, where they may be afraid of giving staging suggestions to the owner of the property for fear of insulting the owner. They’ll suggest a starting price and put the house on the market immediately without taking the time to adequately stage the home.

The seller will sign a long-term listing contract with no “easy out guarantee” in case they aren’t satisfied, and after a month on the market they’ll put the price reduced sign out on the front lawn. Does that sound like a successful process to you?

The average traditional Realtor lists one to two homes a year. They might not own a digital camera. The photos on the MLS may not be updated as the seasons change. They don’t do premarketing or a pre-inspection on the home, and one broker monitors hundreds of agent’s listings in those large corporate real estate offices you think of. There are no systems for monthly marketing meetings, either.

There are so many unstaged homes with ineffective pictures online that a well-staged home will stand out from the competition and be noticed. Something as simple as updating photos to match the current season will make a world of difference to potential buyers.

“THERE ARE SO MANY UNSTAGED HOMES WITH INEFFECTIVE PICTURES ONLINE THAT A WELL-STAGED HOME WILL STAND OUT FROM THE COMPETITION AND BE NOTICED.”

In my next video, I’ll take you through the four steps in what I like to call the new world of real estate. These steps will help you list your home for the price you want and sell it quickly.

If you have any questions about real estate or you would like to know more on this topic, please don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Diane+Cardano/Suburbs+of+Philadelphia+Real+Estate+Why+you+should+avoid+the+traditional+real+estate+process.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Diane+Cardano/Suburbs+of+Philadelphia+Real+Estate+Why+you+should+avoid+the+traditional+real+estate+process.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

The traditional real estate process is no longer a method that works for sellers, and I’ll tell you why.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Diane Cardano</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

The traditional real estate process is no longer a method that works for sellers, and I’ll tell you why.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Montgomery County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Professional Pictures Can Land $10k More When Selling Your Home</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/professional-pictures.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Selling Tips</category>
        
        <author>Diane Cardano</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-28 15:14:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Diane+Cardano/Suburbs+of+Philadelphia+Real+Estate+Professional+pictures+can+land+%2410k+more+when+selling+your+home.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When is the best time to take exterior photos of your home? How should you stage the exterior so that your listing stands out to potential buyers?

Buying a home? Click here to perform a full home search
Selling a home? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Call me at 215-576-8666 for a FREE home buying or selling consultation

Your listing photos are key to a successful home sale. When it comes to exterior photos, you should make sure those are taken when your house looks its best.

It’s important that you plan ahead for exterior photos. Make repairs to the outside of your home, cut down any trees you’ve been wanting to get rid of, and consider power washing or painting your home.

Now that it’s spring, your home probably looks really good right now. We offer to do a free video and photoshoot of your home, and we can come over after your landscapers are done to take some great photos and video for your listing.

We use a flip camera or iPad to film your home; that way, we can post your listing to social media right away. Make sure that you work with a Realtor who is tied into social media.

“WORK WITH A REALTOR WHO UNDERSTANDS HOW TO USE SOCIAL MEDIA.”

If you aren’t planning on selling your home quite yet, we can post your listing photos to our ‘Coming Soon’ listings page on our website. For example, if you are selling your house in the fall, odds are your buyer needs to sell their current home before they can purchase a new one. Move-up buyers use ‘Coming Soon’ listings to secure housing after their home sale.

These are just a few of the top tips that I like to share at our Home Selling Sharks Seminars. Visit HomeSellingSharks.com to sign up for our next monthly seminar. In the meantime, if you have any real estate questions, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Diane+Cardano/Suburbs+of+Philadelphia+Real+Estate+Professional+pictures+can+land+%2410k+more+when+selling+your+home.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Diane+Cardano/Suburbs+of+Philadelphia+Real+Estate+Professional+pictures+can+land+%2410k+more+when+selling+your+home.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

When is the best time to take exterior photos of your home? How should you stage the exterior so that your listing stands out to potential buyers?

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Diane Cardano</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

When is the best time to take exterior photos of your home? How should you stage the exterior so that your listing stands out to potential buyers?

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Montgomery County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Real Estate Wave is Building - Jump In</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/suburbs-of-philadelphia-real-estate.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Diane Cardano</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-10 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Diane+Cardano/Suburbs+of+Philadelphia+Real+Estate+Real+Estate+Market+is+Exploding.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Home prices and interest rates are both going up in our market; however, as you’ll see, this is good news for both buyers and sellers.

Buying a home? Click here to perform a full home search
Selling a home? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Call me at 215-576-8666 for a FREE home buying or selling consultation

Hello raving fans and welcome to the latest edition of my Hot Off the Press Market Report.

Spring is here and people are very confident about the economy right now. Prices are rising—they went up an average of 7.2% across the United States compared to last year. In the video above, I have a few slides to show you that reveal some interesting numbers about our current market and what the future holds for buyers and sellers.

The first is a home price expectation survey of where experts project prices will be over the next five years. There are three different projections ranging from most optimistic to most pessimistic. Overall, they are all projecting prices to rise at least 6.3%, and the most optimistic predicts an increase of 26.7% over the next five years.

These are important figures, and I mention them because as I take these projections and apply them to a house purchased in January 2017, you can see they have a considerable impact on that home’s equity just based on appreciation. Year over year, if you would’ve bought that house for $250,000, it would be worth $292,000 in five years. That means you and your family’s net worth would increase by almost $43,000 just by purchasing a home.

The chief economist from Quicken Loans says “Tight inventory has been a key to contributing factor to the year over year growth in home value prices. This steady growth could very well lead to more availability, driving homeowners to consider cashing in on their growing equity by putting their home on the market.”

He is 100% correct. With prices going up, there’s more equity in every single homeowner’s home. I want to make sure you are aware of that equity, and if you decide to make a move, I’ll help you understand that you have the ability to move because there is extra equity in the house. If you are looking to making a move, now might be a great time.

“IF YOU’RE LOOKING TO MAKE A MOVE, NOW MIGHT BE A GREAT TIME.”

Interest rates are projected to go up along with prices this year. If you’re looking to buy a house right now, you should be aware of the two things that will determine what you pay on a monthly basis: interest rates and the original price. Both of them are increasing, which is phenomenal.

There is no reason to wait to buy right now; if you wait, you’ll only pay more. Do increases in prices and rates mean that people will stop buying homes? No! Since 1988, the median asking price for rents has steadily increased. Historically, the cost of renting is much higher than the cost of buying. The percentage of income needed to afford median rent is 29.2%, while the percentage of income needed to afford a median home is just 15.8%.

As I keep saying, if you’ve had any thoughts about moving, now’s the time. There are not enough homes on market and there are lots of buyers who can’t find homes. If you’re thinking you can’t get a mortgage, don’t decide anything before you talk to one of our trusted lenders. Just call us at 215-576-8666 for their contact information.

Are you, or someone you know, going to be selling their home within the next 2 years? Sign up for our FREE Home Selling Shark Seminar Tuesday, June 20, 2017 at 6:00 p.m @ The Hilton Garden Inn, Fort Washington.  Sign up now! www.HomeSharkSeminar.com seating is very limited for our Spring Seminar and our event will fill up fast!

Stay tuned for my next video where I’ll address the topic of home staging. If you have any other questions in the meantime, feel free to contact me any way you can. I’d be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Diane+Cardano/Suburbs+of+Philadelphia+Real+Estate+Real+Estate+Market+is+Exploding.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Diane+Cardano/Suburbs+of+Philadelphia+Real+Estate+Real+Estate+Market+is+Exploding.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Home prices and interest rates are both going up in our market; however, as you’ll see, this is good news for both buyers and sellers.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Diane Cardano</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Home prices and interest rates are both going up in our market; however, as you’ll see, this is good news for both buyers and sellers.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Montgomery County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Booming Spring Market Is Upon Us</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/suburbs-of-philadelphia-real-estate.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Diane Cardano</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-13 15:08:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Diane+Cardano/Suburbs+of+Philadelphia+Real+Estate+Your+March+market+update.mp4</guid>
        <description>

We’re creeping up on the second quarter of 2017, which means that interest rates are rising and many home sellers are about to enter the market.

Buying a home? Click here to perform a full home search
Selling a home? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Call me at 215-576-8666 for a FREE home buying or selling consultation

Welcome to my latest market report! Today I’m coming to you live from Hawaii, so let’s jump right into the news.

Right now, research shows that people are very confident in the economy, the job market, and what’s taking place in real estate. In fact, a recent Gallup poll states that Americans view the economy more positively since the election in November than they did in the previous nine years.

Now I have a question for you: When do you think most listings come on the market? The answer is the second quarter of each year, which is coming up.

This means if you’re thinking about selling your home but waiting until April, May, or June to put it on market—don’t! That’s when everyone else puts their homes on the market. We know that buyers are out there right now and we can get your house sold quickly. Let’s put it on the market now before the rest of the competition—including some new construction in many markets—hits the market too.

“IF YOU’RE THINKING ABOUT SELLING YOUR HOME, DON’T WAIT UNTIL SPRING.”

I’m not the only one saying this. Jonathan Smoke, the chief economist at realtor.com, stated in his latest article that “In most markets most years, the optimal time to list is in the spring so that the maximum number of potential buyers view the home. This year, the conventional wisdom of buying and selling may need to change. Inventory levels at the beginning of 2017 are at multi-year lows. Sellers now face very little competition.”

If you’re a move-up buyer or just want to buy another home, pay very close attention to interest rates. The 30-year fixed rate skyrocketed at the end of 2016 and then came down a little bit, but now it looks like it’s bouncing around. I don’t think this will have a major impact on how many people will buy houses.

Also, in a recent survey of loan officers that asked them how they thought rising rates will impact demand for purchase mortgages, 16.7% said it would have no impact because there is not enough supply to fulfill current demand. Another 16.7% said rising rates will weaken demand. I agree with that assertion. The vast majority of people moving on—they’re just going to have to pay more.

If you’re a first-time buyer or a seller who’s thinking about buying, you have to take into consideration that if you wait until later in the year, you will have to spend more money. The Mortgage Bankers Association, Fannie Mae, and the NAR are all projecting that interest rates will continue to rise throughout the year.

As you can see in the slide in the video above, if we average out the mortgage rate projections of the next three quarters, interest rates are going to be almost a half a point higher this time next year than they are right now. Why would anybody wait until the end of the year when they know they’ll pay more on an interest rate?

Some people assume that because interest rates are going up, prices will decrease. That’s not what the experts think. In the past month, home prices have risen 1.1%, and it’s likely going to rise even further. As the CoreLogic Chief Economist Frank Nothaft said, “Very low mortgage rates sparked demand, and with inventories low, the result has been a pickup in home-price growth.”

If you want to sell your home fast in 26 days, we have two Home Selling Shark Seminars coming up this month. The first is a breakfast seminar on March 25th from 8:30 a.m and 9:30 a.m. The second is an evening seminar on March 28th. They will both be held at the Hilton Garden Inn in Ft Washington, PA. To sign up, just go to www.HomeSharkSeminar.com.

We are also having Homebuyer Workshop on March 23rd at 6 p.m. at the Abington Township Library. For more details on that, just visit www.CardanoBuyerWorkshop.com.

If you have any questions about our market or are thinking about buying or selling a home, please don’t hesitate to reach out to me. In the meantime, be on the lookout for my next video where I’ll discuss different parts of the staging process in the home sale.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Diane+Cardano/Suburbs+of+Philadelphia+Real+Estate+Your+March+market+update.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Diane+Cardano/Suburbs+of+Philadelphia+Real+Estate+Your+March+market+update.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

We’re creeping up on the second quarter of 2017, which means that interest rates are rising and many home sellers are about to enter the market.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Diane Cardano</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

We’re creeping up on the second quarter of 2017, which means that interest rates are rising and many home sellers are about to enter the market.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Montgomery County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Do Buyers or Sellers Hold the Edge in Our Market?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/do-buyers-or-sellers-hold-edge-in-our.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Diane Cardano</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-15 15:32:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Diane+Cardano/Suburbs+of+Philadelphia+Real+Estate-+Your+February+market+report.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Going forward in 2017, there are plenty of reasons both buyers and sellers should jump into the market.

Buying a home? Click here to perform a full home search
Selling a home? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Call me at 215-576-8666 for a FREE home buying or selling consultation

Today I’m back with your latest market update! Let’s dive right into what’s been happening lately.

Interest rates have jumped up the last two months, and most experts are projecting that they’ll settle somewhere in the 4.5% and 5% range later on. This might cause buyers to get apprehensive about purchasing homes, so if you want to sell your house, you should put it on the market right now. If you wait, not only will the value of your existing home diminish, but later on in the year, as a move-up or move-down buyer, you’ll have to pay a higher interest rate on your new home.

In the video above, I’ve provided a slide depicting mortgage rate projections all the way into the first quarter of 2018.

“IF YOU WANT TO SELL YOUR HOUSE, YOU NEED TO ACT FAST.”

The annual average for the 30-year fixed rate mortgage was 3.65% in 2016, which is the lowest annual average ever recorded by Freddie Mac. Even though interest rates are creeping up, it’s still a great time to buy. If you have considered renting because interest rates are going up, just know that rent will always be going up too.

As you can see in the next chart in the video, the median asking rent in our market has increased every year since 1988. Zillow just reported that renters paid an accumulated $475 billion in 2016, which is a 4% increase over 2015.

If you’re still not convinced that buying is better than renting, here are five reasons homeownership is a great financial investment:


  Mortgage payments can be fixed, while rents will only go up.
  The equity in your home can be a financial resource later on.
  You can build wealth without paying any capital gains.
  A mortgage can act as a forced savings account.
  Overall, homeowners can enjoy greater wealth and growth than any renter can ever can.


Owning a home is one of the most common ways households build long-term wealth. Instead of paying your landlord, you can pay yourself in the long run through paying down your mortgage. If you buy a house, you’re also capping your expenses. The taxes and insurance will go up a little bit, but your housing expense will remain constant.

If you or anyone you know is thinking about buying or selling a home, be sure to introduce them to me so I can help them. A great way to do this is by inviting them to our next Home Selling Shark Seminar. We’ll be holding two seminars in March—one on the 25th and one on the 28th. Both will be at the Hilton Garden Inn in Fort Washington, Pennsylvania. For more information, visit www.homesharkseminar.com.

In the meantime, if you have any questions, please feel free to give me a call. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Diane+Cardano/Suburbs+of+Philadelphia+Real+Estate-+Your+February+market+report.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Diane+Cardano/Suburbs+of+Philadelphia+Real+Estate-+Your+February+market+report.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Going forward in 2017, there are plenty of reasons both buyers and sellers should jump into the market.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Diane Cardano</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Going forward in 2017, there are plenty of reasons both buyers and sellers should jump into the market.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Montgomery County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Where Is Our Real Estate Market Headed?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/suburbs-of-philadelphia-real-estate.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Diane Cardano</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-12 17:16:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Diane+Cardano/Suburbs+of+Philadelphia+Real+Estate+Your+monthly+market+update.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Many important developments are taking place in our market as we head into 2017. Today, I want to talk about how you can take advantage of them.

Buying a home? Click here to perform a full home search
Selling a home? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Call me at 215-576-8666 for a FREE home buying or selling consultation

Welcome back to the hot real estate market! What kind of news and updates are happening out there right now?

As you know, I’ve been telling you to take advantage of the low mortgage rates we’ve seen the last few months because they would eventually rise again. Sure enough, in the last couple of weeks, they’ve risen above 4%. You shouldn’t worry too much about it, though, because that percentage is about where they began in 2016. Even if interest rates rise all the way up to 5% in 2017, that’s still nothing to fret over. I remember that during most of the 1990s they were regularly as high as 8%.

Many experts such as myself predict that by 2020, homes will increase in value between 10% and 21%. That’s a nice return on your investment. As you can see from my home price expectation survey slide in the video above, if you bought a house right now and closed next month at $250,000, in five years, that house will appreciate in value by $43,201. By January of 2022, then, it will be worth $293,201. That’s what you can expect in terms of potential growth in your family’s wealth over the next several years.

For my next slide—the state-by-state forecasted year-over-year percentage change in home price—we see that there is no state where prices are predicted to be negative. Here in Pennsylvania, we have a 4% appreciation rate, which is great.

If you can’t wait until spring to sell your home, hold that train of thought. The number of listings will increase substantially as the new year begins, including new construction homes. This will lower the demand for your house. You’re much better off putting your home on the market now.

“Don’t wait until spring to list your home.”

My next slide detailing the inventory levels of the first five months of 2016 confirms this strategy. During January and February, the number of homes on the market was very low, which meant that competition was also low. Starting in March, inventory levels started to pick up because everyone thought of spring as the perfect buying season. By April and May, they had skyrocketed. Typically, as a year gets older, more and more homes will be built. Why wait for that?

Don’t follow fake news headlines on social media or on television. Those outlets like to scare people, and they don’t understand the market as well as us experts. If you decide to list your home now, there are two points I want you to consider.

The first is to never list it with an agent who tells you a price you want to hear. Experience shows that a common mistake that sellers make is overpricing their home with an agent who is the least competent person to actually get that price. Instead, hire an agent who’s going to consult with you with integrity, negotiate for you as though it was their own home, have systems in place to organize all the details, and, most importantly, have high-tech marketing that will attract buyers before the home even goes on the market.

The second point is don’t get duped when selling your home. I get calls all the time from sellers who failed in their previous attempt at selling their house because they felt obligated to list with a friend or family member. Never do something like that with an asset as important as your house. Instead, hire and expert marketer and negotiator. Find someone who has sold hundreds of homes throughout their career rather than dozens.

Keep in mind that my next home seller seminar is coming up on Saturday, January 21st at the Hilton Garden Inn. We’re starting at 9:30 a.m., and you’re also invited to breakfast at 8:30 a.m.

For more details, visit homesharkseminar.com

If you have any questions about what’s happening in the market, please feel free to give me a call.

Also, stay tuned for my next video where I will share some awesome staging techniques to help your home sell quickly and for top dollar. Talk to you soon!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Diane+Cardano/Suburbs+of+Philadelphia+Real+Estate+Your+monthly+market+update.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Diane+Cardano/Suburbs+of+Philadelphia+Real+Estate+Your+monthly+market+update.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Many important developments are taking place in our market as we head into 2017. Today, I want to talk about how you can take advantage of them.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Diane Cardano</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Many important developments are taking place in our market as we head into 2017. Today, I want to talk about how you can take advantage of them.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Montgomery County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Looking Back at Important Stats From the 2016 Market</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/athens-real-estate-agent-looking-back.html</link>
        
          <category>Athens Real Estate Agent</category>
        
        <author>Diane Cardano</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-10 11:26:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Woodall/Athens+Real+Estate+Agent-+Looking+Back+at+2016+to+Predict+2017.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today we’re taking a look back at the Athens area market statistics from 2016 to try and get a feel for where our market is and where it might be headed in 2017.

Looking to sell a home in Athens, Georgia? Click here for a Home Price  Evaluation
Looking to buy a home in Athens, Georgia? Click here to perform a full home search

As we head into 2017, I wanted to take a moment to look back at the most important statistics from the Athens market in 2016. Now, a lot of agents can be procrastinators and haven’t yet entered all their year-end data into the MLS, so this data might not be perfect yet.

As of early January, these numbers won’t change much even as agents add in late sales data from 2016.

In Clarke County, the average sales price went up 9.8% to about $202,000. Almost 1,500 units sold in 2016, roughly 8% more homes sold than in 2015. In Oconee County, we didn’t see as many sales simply because the population is smaller. Prices rose about 6.8%, from an average of $312,000 to $333,000 in 2016.

“IF YOU’VE BEEN THINKING ABOUT MAKING A MOVE IN THE ATHENS AREA, THE TIME IS NOW.”

When you look at the Athens area as a whole, it was a good year with the average sales price rising 8.4% to $225,000. Overall, we’re seeing prices rise, and that’s a great thing. We’ve certainly needed it after being in a slump for a bit.

We’re also seeing good appreciation, so if you’re thinking about buying a house, you probably should have already done so. It’s time to stop waiting.

If you’ve thought about selling, this time is the best time in nearly the last 10 years. We hope prices will continue to rise, but we really don’t know what 2017 and 2018 will bring. As of now, things are looking up with the economy improving.

If you’ve been thinking about making a move in the Athens area, the time is now. Give us a call or send us an email today. We’d be glad to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Woodall/Athens+Real+Estate+Agent-+Looking+Back+at+2016+to+Predict+2017.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Woodall/Athens+Real+Estate+Agent-+Looking+Back+at+2016+to+Predict+2017.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today we’re taking a look back at the Athens area market statistics from 2016 to try and get a feel for where our market is and where it might be headed in 2017.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Diane Cardano</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today we’re taking a look back at the Athens area market statistics from 2016 to try and get a feel for where our market is and where it might be headed in 2017.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Montgomery County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Secret Job Opportunity You Wont Find on Any Job Boards</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/suburbs-of-philadelphia-real-estate.html</link>
        
          <category>Cardano Realtors</category>
        
        <author>Diane Cardano</author>
        <pubDate>2016-12-29 10:55:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Diane+Cardano/Suburbs+of+Philadelphia+Real+Estate+Secret+Job+Opportunity+You+Won%E2%80%99t+Find+on+Any+Job+Boards.mp4</guid>
        <description>

We have some exciting opportunities for you to join our team. Find out how we can help launch your new career.

Buying a home? Click here to perform a full home search
Selling a home? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Call me at 215-576-8666 for a FREE home buying or selling consultation

Hello raving fans! What better way is there to start the New Year than with a great opportunity? To find out all the details of our secret opportunity, watch this short video!

Right now we have hundreds of customers already committed to using our services, and due to our system of providing personalized, strategic plans, we have developed a large pool of future clients who will need to be guided through and protected from the shark-infested waters of real estate.

So what are we looking for? We’re looking for individuals who will protect our client’s real estate assets and guide them through the buying and selling process. Here at Cardano Realtors, we have the most high-tech systems, the most creative marketing, and the most up-to-date real estate tools.

If you are committed to learning our way of working real estate, want to wake up every morning excited about helping people, and earn predictable consistent income, you may be a good fit for the Cardano Realtors team.

You won’t find these opportunities on a job board. Take a look at what we offer.

Real Estate Consultants: In just 90 days, we can show you how to earn over $100,000, all while going home every night with the knowledge that you are helping and leading people with their largest asset in their financial portfolio.

You will be on the ground floor of a quietly surging real estate market, and you will learn from a well-respected company comprised of real estate experts that work with the best technology available for real estate. You’ll also have a professional team that supports you 100% while you are catering to your clients. Our unconditional support and fabulous systems will allow you to increase your income without sacrificing time away from your family and friends. Imagine that!

Additionally, here at Cardano Realtors, we don’t make cold calls. After training with us, people will look for you, as your commitment to them and their real estate assets will be unmatched.

Now, how are we going to manage all our client needs in 2017?

We need an Executive Administrative Expert. The Executive Administrative Expert will assist consultants out in the field and work directly with clients to make sure they have an outrageously good referral experience. For this position, we are looking for an experienced administrative assistant. This position is salaried with bonus potential as the business grows.

To apply go to www.CardanoJob.com

We will teach you everything we know, and we know a lot.

Thanks again for being a loyal blog listener. If you have any questions about the job opportunities or other real estate needs, please feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I can’t wait to hear from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Diane+Cardano/Suburbs+of+Philadelphia+Real+Estate+Secret+Job+Opportunity+You+Won%E2%80%99t+Find+on+Any+Job+Boards.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Diane+Cardano/Suburbs+of+Philadelphia+Real+Estate+Secret+Job+Opportunity+You+Won%E2%80%99t+Find+on+Any+Job+Boards.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

We have some exciting opportunities for you to join our team. Find out how we can help launch your new career.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Diane Cardano</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

We have some exciting opportunities for you to join our team. Find out how we can help launch your new career.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Montgomery County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Market is Hot for Home Sellers</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/whats-happening-in-our-winter-real.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Diane Cardano</author>
        <pubDate>2016-12-09 14:04:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Diane+Cardano/Suburbs+of+Philadelphia+Real+Estate+-+What%E2%80%99s+Happening+in+Our+Winter+Real+Estate+Market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

It’s winter, but the real estate market is not slowing down! Today, I’ll go over your latest market update.

Buying a home? Click here to perform a full home search
Selling a home? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Call me at 215-576-8666 for a FREE home buying or selling consultation

I’m here with your latest real estate market update!

As the weather gets colder and the holidays approach, most home sellers think, “It’s December and the market is going to slow down. I’m not even going to think about putting my home on the market.” However, that’s not a good idea.

Why? Right now, the market is actually swarming with buyers. In fact, there are so many buyers that I just sold two homes that weren’t scheduled to hit the market until April! Inventory is incredibly low, so even if you’re not planning on selling til next year, pick up the phone right now to figure out what your next steps are. Now is still a great time to be on the market, as interest rates are still low and buyers are highly motivated.

Now, first-time buyers probably think that they need to put 20% down in order to buy a home. However, the average down payment for first-time home buyers has dropped down to 6% in 2016, while repeat buyers are putting 14% down. In fact, some first-time buyers are able to get in a home for less than 4% down. You don’t need to get an FHA loan; there are other loan products out there that allow you to put 3% down.

“OUR WINTER MARKET IS SWARMING WITH MOTIVATED BUYERS.”

Right now, mortgage interest rates are at 3.5%, which is still incredibly low. Over the next 12 months, they’re expected to jump to 4.2%, which is quite a difference. Mortgage credit availability is also very good right now, so it’s easier for more people to get a mortgage.

As for what FICO score you need to buy a home, in 2016, 53% of closed loans had FICO scores between 600 and 748. In fact, 30% got a loan with a credit score under 700. This combined with low mortgage rates and increased mortgage credit availability makes now a great time to be a first-time buyer.

As for our sellers, you should know that inventory is extremely low right now. By putting your home on the market, you will be able to maximize the profits from your home sale.

That’s it for our winter market update. Keep an eye out for our next Home Selling Shark Seminar on Saturday, January 21st, 2017. We will also have a buyer conference next January. Check out HomeSellingSharks.com for more details.

In the meantime, reach out to me with any real estate questions you might have. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Diane+Cardano/Suburbs+of+Philadelphia+Real+Estate+-+What%E2%80%99s+Happening+in+Our+Winter+Real+Estate+Market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Diane+Cardano/Suburbs+of+Philadelphia+Real+Estate+-+What%E2%80%99s+Happening+in+Our+Winter+Real+Estate+Market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

It’s winter, but the real estate market is not slowing down! Today, I’ll go over your latest market update.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Diane Cardano</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

It’s winter, but the real estate market is not slowing down! Today, I’ll go over your latest market update.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Montgomery County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Secret Strategies to Making Your Real Estate Great Again</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/suburbs-of-philadelphia-real-estate-how.html</link>
        
          <category>Buyer and Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Diane Cardano</author>
        <pubDate>2016-11-10 14:35:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Diane+Cardano/Suburbs+of+Philadelphia+Real+Estate+How+to+make+your+real+estate+great+again.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Home sellers face many challenges in our current market. Luckily, I have a list of eight secret strategies that can help them sell quickly and for top dollar.

Buying a home? Click here to perform a full home search
Selling a home? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Call me at 215-576-8666 for a FREE home buying or selling consultation

One of my greatest passions as a Realtor is getting my home sellers the best possible price in the least amount of time with the least amount of hassle. In short, my biggest concern is making your real estate great again.

Today’s home seller faces many challenges in our current market. For one thing, our market is complicated. You can’t just put a sign on your lawn and expect it to sell. Currently, the average days on market is 80 days, which isn’t great. In fact, it’s bad. Taxes are also high, and they’re only getting higher. This makes it difficult for buyers to afford homes, which is causing home values to go down every single year.

Another problem is Realtors making false promises about selling your home and then using slipshod tactics like taking its listing photos with a cell phone. That’s not what a professional does! It only takes about $600 to get a license, so, unfortunately, not a lot of training goes into handling such a large asset.

How can you avoid these problems when listing your home? I’ve put together a list of eight secret strategies to help guide you through the process. You can learn these strategies by visiting 8secretstrategies.com. Whether it’s through me or another agent, this list will tell you what you should do to sell your home. In short, there are two main things that can make your real estate great again: having both a marketing expert and a negotiating expert on your team.

Why am I telling you this? Because houses today are selling quickly–for those whose house is priced right and staged properly. It’s now November, which means if you plan on selling in the spring, you need to make a plan now. Don’t make the mistake of waiting too long or not hiring an expert Realtor.

“Only houses that are priced right and staged right sell quickly.”

If you have any questions about how to make your real estate great again, please don’t hesitate to give me a call or shoot me an email. Remember, we’re having our next Home Selling Sharks seminar on January 21st at the Hilton Garden Inn. To register, all you have to do is visit homesharksseminar.com. In the meantime, I hope to hear from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Diane+Cardano/Suburbs+of+Philadelphia+Real+Estate+How+to+make+your+real+estate+great+again.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Diane+Cardano/Suburbs+of+Philadelphia+Real+Estate+How+to+make+your+real+estate+great+again.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Home sellers face many challenges in our current market. Luckily, I have a list of eight secret strategies that can help them sell quickly and for top dollar.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Diane Cardano</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Home sellers face many challenges in our current market. Luckily, I have a list of eight secret strategies that can help them sell quickly and for top dollar.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Montgomery County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Diane Cardano</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Diane Cardano</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Cardano Realtors - your professional Montgomery County Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
