<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Crystal Coast Real Estate Podcast with OK Hogan</title>
    <link>localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Star Team - your professional Crystal Coast Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>OK Hogan</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2017-12-13 16:50:42 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>OK Hogan</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Crystal Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>info@StarTeamRealEstate.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>OK Hogan</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>OK Hogan</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Crystal Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Crystal Coast Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Star Team - your professional Crystal Coast Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>Reflecting on the 2017 Real Estate Market</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/reflecting-on-2017-real-estate-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>OK Hogan</author>
        <pubDate>2017-12-07 14:57:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/OK+Hogan+(Star+Team)/Crystal+Coast+Real+Estate-+Reflecting+on+the+2017+Real+Estate+Market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

How did the 2017 real estate market do and what can you expect from our market in 2018?

Merry Christmas and happy New Year! As 2017 draws to a close, we’re looking back to see how the real estate market did this year and what to expect next year.

In our local area, the number of sales for vacant land, condos, and single-family homes increased by 17% over 2016. The average sales price is up 8%, and the total dollar amount of sales is up 26%. Inventory is down 3% compared to 2016. We simply need more properties to sell.

Despite the low inventory, pending contracts are up 18% over 2016, so this is the best market we have seen since 2005.

Looking forward to 2018, many anticipate that housing costs will go up as a result of the hurricanes in Florida and Texas and the fires in California. These natural disasters impact the whole country, and they have affected the cost of housing a little bit.

My husband is a local builder and he says that he has seen price increases from different vendors he works with in the area.

In addition, interest rates are still low right now but they may go up a little bit in the future.

Overall, the market looks good for 2018.

I want to thank my coworkers for their work in 2017 and my friends and clients for their support. 2017 was a good year, and 2018 certainly looks promising.

“2018 looks like another good year for real estate.”

If you have any questions about real estate, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you.

Have a happy holiday season!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/OK+Hogan+(Star+Team)/Crystal+Coast+Real+Estate-+Reflecting+on+the+2017+Real+Estate+Market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/OK+Hogan+(Star+Team)/Crystal+Coast+Real+Estate-+Reflecting+on+the+2017+Real+Estate+Market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

How did the 2017 real estate market do and what can you expect from our market in 2018?

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>OK Hogan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

How did the 2017 real estate market do and what can you expect from our market in 2018?

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Crystal Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Whats It Like Working With Us? Our Clients Tell the Story</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/whats-it-like-working-with-us-our.html</link>
        
          <category>Client Appreciation Event</category>
        
        <author>OK Hogan</author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-05 16:40:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/OK+Hogan+(Star+Team)/Crystal+Coast+Real+Estate-+What%E2%80%99s+it+Like+Working+With+Us-+Our+Clients+Tell+the+Story.mp4</guid>
        <description>

We want to share a few client testimonials we recorded from a viewing party of our guest feature on HGTV’s “Beachfront Bargain Hunt.”

We recently had the pleasure of working with HGTV to film an episode of “Beachfront Bargain Hunt” right here in Atlantic Beach. We had a great time filming the show, and we’d love for you to tune into episode 13 of season 15 to see us on TV.

Here are a few client testimonials from our recent viewing party of this experience:

From Bill and Fossie Latham:

“Lugean closed three properties with us in the course of about 60 days—one we bought, and two we sold. The thing I appreciated the most was, you know, whether you’re buying or selling can be a bit frustrating and emotional. I mean, there’s a lot of money involved, and Lugean, through the whole process, was very calm. She didn’t let you get too optimistic; she didn’t let you get too pessimistic. She kept everything on an even keel and things worked out wonderfully. We really appreciate what she did for us.”

From Mahilda Barbee:

“I worked with Lugean to buy my house when I was transferred here to open the state police credit union four years ago. She was so gracious to sell me a house in her neighborhood that not only did she sell me a house, but now I’m her neighbor.”

From Dale and Norma Coley:

“Lugean helped us find the absolute perfect condo in Atlantic Beach. She showed us at least 40 different condos and was very patient with us, and we ended up with the perfect condo. Lugean is the best.”

From Sharon Pietzrak:

“My husband and I met Lugean in August of 2014. She helped us buy our home, which was a foreclosure and was the first one she had done. She was just tenacious and got it done. Even after we lost it in an auction, she put in a backup bid, which we didn’t know she did, but it was a good thing because the deal fell through and she saved the day with that backup bid, and we’re so happy.”

“It was great having the support of our friends, family, and many of my clients.”

To see a few clips and photos from this viewing party, watch the video above. It was great having the support of Bluewater Real Estate, our friends, family, and many of my clients.

If you have any questions or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home here in paradise, don’t hesitate to give me a call. I’d love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/OK+Hogan+(Star+Team)/Crystal+Coast+Real+Estate-+What%E2%80%99s+it+Like+Working+With+Us-+Our+Clients+Tell+the+Story.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/OK+Hogan+(Star+Team)/Crystal+Coast+Real+Estate-+What%E2%80%99s+it+Like+Working+With+Us-+Our+Clients+Tell+the+Story.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

We want to share a few client testimonials we recorded from a viewing party of our guest feature on HGTV’s “Beachfront Bargain Hunt.”

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>OK Hogan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

We want to share a few client testimonials we recorded from a viewing party of our guest feature on HGTV’s “Beachfront Bargain Hunt.”

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Crystal Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Makes Today's Market So Great to List In?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/what-makes-todays-market-so-great-to.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>OK Hogan</author>
        <pubDate>2017-09-22 11:11:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/OK%20Hogan%20%28Star%20Team%29/Crystal%20Coast%20Real%20Estate-%20What%20Makes%20Today%2527s%20Market%20So%20Great%20to%20List%20In%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I’m bringing you a quick look at our market’s latest numbers as well as some key listing tips.

We’ve had a good hot summer this year in Crystal Coast, and the real estate market in our area is seeing that same heat.

Now that the summer has come to a close, it’s time for a market update.

First of all, it’s interesting to note that the total number of sold properties is up from last year by 217 homes. The average list price and average sold price are both also up, each having risen by $9,000.

Another factor we’re seeing is a shorter number of days on market. The average days on market has actually gone down since last year by about 47 days.

“The summer has been hot, and the real estate market in our area is seeing that same heat.”

If you’re thinking about putting your house on the market, it’s a great time to do so. Inventory is very low right now, so the market is in need of properties.

Whether you plan to list this month or a year from now, there are a few key things you can do to prepare. For one thing, upgrading your countertops is always a great idea.

Another area that buyers look at closely is flooring. I would wait to change out carpet until you’re close to listing, but vinyl and hardwood can be put in any time.

If you have any other questions, would like more information, or want more listing tips, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/OK%20Hogan%20%28Star%20Team%29/Crystal%20Coast%20Real%20Estate-%20What%20Makes%20Today%2527s%20Market%20So%20Great%20to%20List%20In%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/OK%20Hogan%20%28Star%20Team%29/Crystal%20Coast%20Real%20Estate-%20What%20Makes%20Today%2527s%20Market%20So%20Great%20to%20List%20In%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today I’m bringing you a quick look at our market’s latest numbers as well as some key listing tips.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>OK Hogan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today I’m bringing you a quick look at our market’s latest numbers as well as some key listing tips.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Crystal Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Top Tips for Hurricane Preparedness for Crystal Coast Homeowners</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/top-tips-for-hurricane-preparedness-for.html</link>
        
          <category>Buyer & Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>OK Hogan</author>
        <pubDate>2017-09-08 14:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/OK%20Hogan%20%28Star%20Team%29/Crystal%20Coast%20Real%20Estate-%20Top%20Tips%20for%20Hurricane%20Preparedness%20for%20Crystal%20Coast%20Homeowners.mp4</guid>
        <description>

We wanted to give you a quick refresher on some of the most important things you can do to prepare yourself for this hurricane.

Today I wanted to lay out a plan and offer a few tips for you to consider as Hurricane Irma continues to bear down and has us all guessing where and when it might land. This is currently a category 4 storm and potentially one of the worst storms ever recorded.

I just wanted to offer some reminders to help you get ready for anything Mother Nature might throw at us.

1. Stay tuned to the local weather station. They’re going to keep you updated on the critical info from the National Weather Service.

2. Check your disaster supply now. Your supply kit should be ready to go with a gallon of water per person, non-perishable food for three days, flashlights, batteries, and candles.

3. Remove or tie down objects in the yard. Make sure things like patio furniture are stowed away or secured so they can’t blow away or cause damage.

4. Take inventory of your property. We haven’t had a ton of hurricane wind damage in a long time here on the Crystal Coast, but we’re very susceptible to flooding. Take pictures, do a walkthrough, and write down everything. That way, if you ever have a flood or wind insurance claim to make, you’ll have something to fall back on.

5. It’s a good idea to turn the fridge and freezer all the way down. Setting the fridge and freezer to the coldest setting will help you keep it cool if the power goes out, and your food will stay fresh longer. Keep the doors closed as much as possible if you lose power.

6. Don’t forget to turn off the gas. If you have propane or other small appliances, make sure they’re turned off.

7. Keep your gasoline tank in your vehicles full. If there’s flooding and you need to get out of town, be prepared to exit with a full tank.

“Have an evacuation plan in place.”

8. Have an evacuation plan in place. This way everyone in your family will know what to do and you won’t be scrambling at the last minute.

As always, if you have any more questions, don’t hesitate to reach out to us at the Star Team. We would be happy to help you. We wish you all good luck and safety through this big storm.
</description>
        <enclosure url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/OK%20Hogan%20%28Star%20Team%29/Crystal%20Coast%20Real%20Estate-%20Top%20Tips%20for%20Hurricane%20Preparedness%20for%20Crystal%20Coast%20Homeowners.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/OK%20Hogan%20%28Star%20Team%29/Crystal%20Coast%20Real%20Estate-%20Top%20Tips%20for%20Hurricane%20Preparedness%20for%20Crystal%20Coast%20Homeowners.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

We wanted to give you a quick refresher on some of the most important things you can do to prepare yourself for this hurricane.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>OK Hogan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

We wanted to give you a quick refresher on some of the most important things you can do to prepare yourself for this hurricane.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Crystal Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Which Home Improvements Can Maximize Your Homes Value?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/which-home-improvements-can-maximize.html</link>
        
          <category>Buyer & Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>OK Hogan</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-31 10:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/OK%20Hogan%20%28Star%20Team%29/Crystal%20Coast%20Real%20Estate-%20Which%20Home%20Improvements%20Can%20Maximize%20Your%20Homes%20Value%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Here are a few repairs you can make to your home that will maximize your dollar return when it comes time to sell.

What improvements can you make to your home to increase its value when the time comes to sell it?

Countertops and bathroom fixtures are at the top of the list. If yours are dated or old, replace them. They’ll really pop if they’re brand new, and you can still enjoy them for a year or two if you don’t plan on selling right now.

“These updates will add value now and later.”

Another aspect you should focus on is flooring. Hold off on replacing any carpet until right before you list your house. You can install vinyl or wood flooring any time and it will increase your home’s value. It will not age quickly, so doing it ahead of time makes you ready once your house hits the market.

These improvements will both increase your dollar return and help market your home online. If you have any other questions about making home improvements or you’re thinking about buying or selling a home right now, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/OK%20Hogan%20%28Star%20Team%29/Crystal%20Coast%20Real%20Estate-%20Which%20Home%20Improvements%20Can%20Maximize%20Your%20Homes%20Value%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/OK%20Hogan%20%28Star%20Team%29/Crystal%20Coast%20Real%20Estate-%20Which%20Home%20Improvements%20Can%20Maximize%20Your%20Homes%20Value%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Here are a few repairs you can make to your home that will maximize your dollar return when it comes time to sell.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>OK Hogan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Here are a few repairs you can make to your home that will maximize your dollar return when it comes time to sell.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Crystal Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Cant You Trust Zillows Zestimates?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/why-cant-you-trust-zillows-zestimates.html</link>
        
          <category>Buyer & Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>OK Hogan</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-18 13:52:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/OK%20Hogan%20%28Star%20Team%29/Crystal%20Coast%20Real%20Estate-%20Why%20Cant%20You%20Trust%20Zillows%20Zestimates%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

A recent lawsuit filed against Zillow by a homeowner in Illinois demonstrates why you can’t quite trust their Zestimate tool.

Whether you’re a buyer or seller in our market, you should be wary of Zillow’s Zestimates.

In case you didn’t know, Zillow is the largest online search engine for homebuyers. The Zestimate is their version of an estimated value for a property.

A recent development in the real estate industry illustrates why you can’t quite trust Zestimates. A woman in Illinois has filed a lawsuit against Zillow, claiming that her Zestimate undervalued her house and created a roadblock for its sale. Despite Zillow’s denial that they offer appraisals, the fact that they’re promoted as a tool for potential buyers to use in assessing the market value of a property shows that the definition of an appraisal under Illinois state law was met.

The lawsuit argues that Zillow should be licensed to perform appraisals and that they should also obtain the consent of a homeowner before they go online. The Zestimate in question is for a townhome that was bought for $626,000 in 2009 and recently listed on the market for roughly what it was bought. However, the home’s most recent Zestimate was only $562,000. The homeowner is suing Zillow to either remove the Zestimate or amend it.

“Zestimates supposedly have a median error rate of 5%.”

Zillow has a different take on the situation. They don’t see their Zestimates as an appraisal, but rather as a tool that utilizes a proprietary algorithm to assess value. According to some, they have a median error rate of over 5%. That can mean a lot of money on the table. Zillow is now offering a $1 million prize to anyone who can improve their algorithm.

Until the Zestimate can be improved, my advice to you is to not allow Zillow to dictate your buying or selling choices. If you’re curious what your home is really worth, give me a call or send me an email and I’d be happy to perform a real analysis on it.

In the meantime, if you have any other questions about this or any other real estate topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. Talk to you soon!
</description>
        <enclosure url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/OK%20Hogan%20%28Star%20Team%29/Crystal%20Coast%20Real%20Estate-%20Why%20Cant%20You%20Trust%20Zillows%20Zestimates%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/OK%20Hogan%20%28Star%20Team%29/Crystal%20Coast%20Real%20Estate-%20Why%20Cant%20You%20Trust%20Zillows%20Zestimates%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

A recent lawsuit filed against Zillow by a homeowner in Illinois demonstrates why you can’t quite trust their Zestimate tool.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>OK Hogan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

A recent lawsuit filed against Zillow by a homeowner in Illinois demonstrates why you can’t quite trust their Zestimate tool.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Crystal Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Get the Biggest Return on Investment on Your Property</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-to-get-biggest-return-on-investment.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>OK Hogan</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-04 15:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/OK%20Hogan%20%28Star%20Team%29/Crystal%20Coast%20Real%20Estate-%20How%20to%20Get%20the%20Biggest%20Return%20on%20Investment%20on%20Your%20Property.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you want to maximize your ROI on your rental properties, you need to be sure that you’re charging market rate for rent to your tenants.

If you’re an investor with a rental property and have had the same tenants for a long time, I wanted to share a few things that you might want to look out for.

You always want to maximize your ROI on rental properties, and what we’re seeing currently is that there are a lot of investors who just aren’t charging market rate for rent. This is happening in commercial real estate, long-term residential rentals, and even vacation rentals.

“You always want to maximize your ROI on your rental properties.”

A classic example is an investor who bought a property many years back and continued to charge the same rental rate to his tenants year after year. He runs into a serious problem when he goes to sell the property, and his tenants are unable to afford the current market rate that the new owner will charge them.

The problem is further deepened when he realizes that they can’t leave either due to various reasons, like working in the area or being unable to afford to move anywhere else.

If you’ve dealt with investment properties in the past, then you know that getting rid of a tenant is expensive, time consuming, and often requires hiring an attorney. Many times during this period, they aren’t even paying rent.

If you have any questions about how you can maximize your ROI and avoid the pitfalls of a messy tenant removal situation, please give me a call. I’d be happy to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/OK%20Hogan%20%28Star%20Team%29/Crystal%20Coast%20Real%20Estate-%20How%20to%20Get%20the%20Biggest%20Return%20on%20Investment%20on%20Your%20Property.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/OK%20Hogan%20%28Star%20Team%29/Crystal%20Coast%20Real%20Estate-%20How%20to%20Get%20the%20Biggest%20Return%20on%20Investment%20on%20Your%20Property.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you want to maximize your ROI on your rental properties, you need to be sure that you’re charging market rate for rent to your tenants.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>OK Hogan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you want to maximize your ROI on your rental properties, you need to be sure that you’re charging market rate for rent to your tenants.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Crystal Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>These 3 Tips Will Help You Start the Downsizing Process</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/these-3-tips-will-help-you-start.html</link>
        
          <category>Buyer & Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>OK Hogan</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-20 14:48:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/OK%20Hogan%20%28Star%20Team%29/Crystal%20Coast%20Real%20Estate-%20These%203%20Tips%20Will%20Help%20You%20Start%20the%20Downsizing%20Process.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Downsizing is becoming increasingly popular in our market. If you’re thinking of downsizing, keep these three tips in mind.

Downsizing has become an increasingly popular trend in the world of real estate, and as baby boomers come of age more and more people will have it on their minds.

If you’ve thought about downsizing, these three tips will help you start the process:

1. Start with a plan: Write down what you want to keep, what you want to donate, and what needs to come with you. We can help you create those lists and then organize your possessions accordingly.

2. Start looking for your next house now: You need to know where you’re going before you put your current house on the market so that you can get a good idea of your next move. A good Realtor will help you clarify what you want and what you need in your next home and show you homes that meet your criteria. This step can also give you a taste of what your new lifestyle could be in your next neighborhood.

“Downsizing can get emotional, but it will be a positive step toward your future.”

3. Start preparing your home for sale: Downsizing can be an emotional process, but it will also be a very positive step in securing your future.

If you have any questions for us about downsizing or you’re ready to start the process, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We’d love to serve you during this important time in your life.
</description>
        <enclosure url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/OK%20Hogan%20%28Star%20Team%29/Crystal%20Coast%20Real%20Estate-%20These%203%20Tips%20Will%20Help%20You%20Start%20the%20Downsizing%20Process.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/OK%20Hogan%20%28Star%20Team%29/Crystal%20Coast%20Real%20Estate-%20These%203%20Tips%20Will%20Help%20You%20Start%20the%20Downsizing%20Process.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Downsizing is becoming increasingly popular in our market. If you’re thinking of downsizing, keep these three tips in mind.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>OK Hogan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Downsizing is becoming increasingly popular in our market. If you’re thinking of downsizing, keep these three tips in mind.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Crystal Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>6 Home Selling Mistakes to Avoid</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/6-home-selling-mistakes-to-avoid.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>OK Hogan</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-31 10:57:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/OK%20Hogan%20%28Star%20Team%29/Crystal%20Coast%20Real%20Estate-%206%20Home%20Selling%20Mistakes%20to%20Avoid.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Home selling is a complicated process. Here are six things you need to avoid doing.

Selling your home can be a stressful process, but avoiding these six common mistakes will make that process a lot easier and smoother:

1. Picking the wrong agent. It’s really easy to pick the wrong agent if you don’t do your research on them. The right agent is going to answer the phone when you call, get back to you in a timely manner, and be a market expert. They will be honest and straightforward with you rather than agreeing with everything you say and telling you what you want to hear.

2. Overpricing your home. Price is everything when marketing your home. Even a well-priced home with a bad marketing plan will sell. It will just take a little longer.

3. Failing to make simple repairs. If the dog chewed something up or there are minor dents or scratches in the paint, buyers will notice that. It’s better to get these things fixed before listing the home.

“Avoiding these mistakes will make sure your home sells for the most money possible.”

4. Neglecting the decluttering. Buyers start their home searches online these days and if the pictures of your home show off your stuff instead of the home itself, there’s a good chance buyers won’t even come out to look at the home in person. Store your excess “stuff” in the garage or a storage pod so it doesn’t get in the way.

5. Not allowing adequate access to your home. Your home should be show-ready at all times and you should be able to accommodate agents and their buyers when they want to see it. If a seller tells a buyer or their agent they can’t see a home at a certain time or they have to reschedule, most won’t come back.

6. Getting too emotional about your house. Sellers can be very attached to their homes, which is understandable. However, when you are selling your home you have to look at it as an investment, not as your home. If you get a lowball offer or someone wants to remodel a part of the home, don’t take it personally as long as they pay the price you want them to.

Avoiding these mistakes will make sure your home sells for the most amount of money possible in the least amount of time. If you have any questions in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/OK%20Hogan%20%28Star%20Team%29/Crystal%20Coast%20Real%20Estate-%206%20Home%20Selling%20Mistakes%20to%20Avoid.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/OK%20Hogan%20%28Star%20Team%29/Crystal%20Coast%20Real%20Estate-%206%20Home%20Selling%20Mistakes%20to%20Avoid.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Home selling is a complicated process. Here are six things you need to avoid doing.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>OK Hogan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Home selling is a complicated process. Here are six things you need to avoid doing.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Crystal Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Appraisals Can Affect Your Home Transaction</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-appraisals-can-affect-your-home_19.html</link>
        
          <category>Buyer & Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>OK Hogan</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-19 15:46:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/OK%20Hogan%20%28Star%20Team%29/Crystal%20Coast%20Real%20Estate-%20How%20Appraisals%20Can%20Affect%20Your%20Home%20Transaction.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What is an appraisal and why is it important? I’ll answer those questions for you today.

Appraisals have become a hot topic in today’s market. An appraisal is what the bank uses to determine what they consider the true value of a home that’s being bought and sold. It’s done by a certified home appraiser who is an independent third party in the transaction.

Essentially, the appraiser will take the property you’re buying or selling and look at homes in the area with similar amenities, features, and square footage in order to compare them. They will use that information, based on recent past sales, to validate the price of the property.

Appraisals have become more relevant recently because we have seen some appreciation in the market. However, we frequently see homes that fail to appraise at what we expect, which is not good. If an appraiser takes information from a home that sold six months ago, the home might not appraise at the price it’s listed for today.

If you’re a buyer, an appraisal is meant to protect you so you don’t overpay for a home. However, it can also have a negative effect on buyers. If you fall in love with a house and agree to a certain price, your bank will only lend you money based on the appraisal. If the home doesn’t appraise, you’d have to come up with the cash to make up the difference between the appraised value and the list price of the home or walk away if the seller won’t renegotiate.

“As a seller, if your home doesn’t appraise, you may have to lower the price or risk losing your buyer.”

As a seller, the appraisal may affect you more than anything else in the selling process. If your home doesn’t appraise, you may have to lower your price or risk your buyer walking away.

At the Star Team, we provide our friends and clients with a comprehensive market analysis, or CMA. It uses a similar approach to determining a home’s value that an appraiser does.

If you have any questions about this topic or any other real estate topics, please give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/OK%20Hogan%20%28Star%20Team%29/Crystal%20Coast%20Real%20Estate-%20How%20Appraisals%20Can%20Affect%20Your%20Home%20Transaction.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/OK%20Hogan%20%28Star%20Team%29/Crystal%20Coast%20Real%20Estate-%20How%20Appraisals%20Can%20Affect%20Your%20Home%20Transaction.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

What is an appraisal and why is it important? I’ll answer those questions for you today.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>OK Hogan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

What is an appraisal and why is it important? I’ll answer those questions for you today.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Crystal Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4 Tips for Preparing Your Home for the Spring Market </title>
        <link>localhost:4000/4-tips-for-preparing-your-home-for.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>OK Hogan</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-31 11:32:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/OK%20Hogan%20%28Star%20Team%29/Crystal%20Coast%20Real%20Estate-%204%20Tips%20for%20Preparing%20Your%20Home%20for%20the%20Spring%20Market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Large numbers of buyers have already entered the spring market to search for their dream homes. To make sure your home is ready to list, you need to do these four things.

Today I want to give you some tips on preparing your home for the spring market, which is happening right now. To ensure your home is ready, there are four things you need to do to prepare.

The first is to figure out what your home is worth. Homes sell much quicker when they are priced correctly from the start. Some people choose to get an independent appraisal done to figure out the best price for the market, but you can also consult an agent who will look at comparable homes with similar features to give you a good idea of what you should list at.

Second, you need to decide when the right time to list is. March through May is the peak time to list your home. The good news is that you don’t necessarily need to pick a specific time during peak season. It’s always prime time at the beach.

“It’s always prime time at the beach.”

Next, you need to maximize your curb appeal. 63% of buyers drop by homes they’ve seen online, which means you’ll need to make a good first impression. Get rid of signs of winter by power washing, trimming bushes, putting out pine straw or mulch, and cleaning the windows.

Finally, make sure you’re prepared for showings. This means tidying up and decluttering, along with packing away non-essentials.

If you have any questions about pricing your house or the best time to sell, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I’m always happy to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/OK%20Hogan%20%28Star%20Team%29/Crystal%20Coast%20Real%20Estate-%204%20Tips%20for%20Preparing%20Your%20Home%20for%20the%20Spring%20Market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/OK%20Hogan%20%28Star%20Team%29/Crystal%20Coast%20Real%20Estate-%204%20Tips%20for%20Preparing%20Your%20Home%20for%20the%20Spring%20Market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Large numbers of buyers have already entered the spring market to search for their dream homes. To make sure your home is ready to list, you need to do these four things.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>OK Hogan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Large numbers of buyers have already entered the spring market to search for their dream homes. To make sure your home is ready to list, you need to do these four things.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Crystal Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Can Landscaping Increase Your Homes Value?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-can-landscaping-increase-your-homes.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>OK Hogan</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-27 15:08:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/OK%20Hogan%20%28Star%20Team%29/Crystal%20Coast%20Real%20Estate-%20Jan%201.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Landscaping is one way to increase your home’s value before you sell. We have six tips to get you started today.

Whether you’re looking to sell your home or simply want to improve its appearance, you might want to consider upgrading the landscaping. Landscaping can be a real game-changer. Your home’s curb appeal will look much better if you follow these six steps.

1. Freshen your mulch. It’s only about $4 per bag for mulch or pine straw, so it’s an inexpensive way to improve your yard’s appearance.

2. Add some potted plants. Pops of color here and there can make a huge difference and make your home seem warm and welcoming.

3. Plant some shrubs. Adding shrubs in those sparse areas can give your home a lush look.

4. Spruce up your porch. Power wash the porch and consider staging it with outdoor furniture so it looks more inviting.

5. Landscape lighting. Light makes a dramatic difference at night. Not only will your home seem warmer at night with the right lighting, but lights are a great security and safety feature as well.

6. Paint your front door. A fresh coat of paint on the front door definitely boosts curb appeal.

“It’s a simple way to upgrade your home’s value.”

Landscaping can be a simple way to upgrade your home and improve value. If you have any questions or any suggestions for topics for a future video, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon!
</description>
        <enclosure url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/OK%20Hogan%20%28Star%20Team%29/Crystal%20Coast%20Real%20Estate-%20Jan%201.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/OK%20Hogan%20%28Star%20Team%29/Crystal%20Coast%20Real%20Estate-%20Jan%201.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Landscaping is one way to increase your home’s value before you sell. We have six tips to get you started today.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>OK Hogan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Landscaping is one way to increase your home’s value before you sell. We have six tips to get you started today.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Crystal Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Happy Holidays From the Star Team</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/happy-holidays-from-star-team.html</link>
        
          <category>Happy Holidays</category>
        
        <author>OK Hogan</author>
        <pubDate>2016-12-20 14:28:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

We had a wonderful year in 2016, and as it comes to a close, we wanted to wish you a merry Christmas and happy New Year. There’s a special story we’d like to share.

We’re definitely in the holiday spirit here at the Star Team, so we wanted to take a moment to deliver you a special holiday greeting as the year winds down. This year was a great one and we want to thank you for buying and selling property with us, as well as everyone who sent us referrals.

We hope to help even more families in 2017, so if you or anyone you know are looking to buy or sell a home on the Crystal Coast, we’d love to hear from you!

During the season of giving, let us take time to slow down and appreciate the job of spending time with family and friends and appreciate the true reason for the season. We hope this special time of year touches your heart in a special way. In the spirit of the season, I have a story that was recently shared with me that I wanted to pass along.

During a cold day in New York City some years ago, a lady approached a 10-year-old boy who had no shoes and was shivering in front of a shoe store window. She said “My, you’re in such deep thought staring in that window,” to which he replied, “I was asking God to give me a pair of shoes.”

The lady took this little boy by the hand and took him inside where she asked the clerk for several pairs of socks for the little boy. Then, she asked for a basin of water and a towel so she could wash and dry his feet. She put new socks on his feet and bought him a brand-new pair of shoes. She gave him the rest of the socks, patted him on the head, and said, “No doubt you will be more comfortable now.”

As she turned to leave, the boy grabbed her hand, and with tears in his eyes, he asked her, “Are you God’s wife?”

With that in mind, from our team to your family, we wish you a very merry Christmas and a prosperous, happy New , happy New Year.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

We had a wonderful year in 2016, and as it comes to a close, we wanted to wish you a merry Christmas and happy New Year. There’s a special story we’d like to share.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>OK Hogan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

We had a wonderful year in 2016, and as it comes to a close, we wanted to wish you a merry Christmas and happy New Year. There’s a special story we’d like to share.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Crystal Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Should You Know About Home Inspections?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/what-should-you-know-about-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Inspection</category>
        
        <author>OK Hogan</author>
        <pubDate>2016-12-09 14:35:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/OK%20Hogan%20%28Star%20Team%29/Crystal%20Coast%20Real%20Estate-%20Dec%201.mp4</guid>
        <description>

We’ve got some great info for you today on home inspections: what they are, who does them, and what they accomplish.

If you are getting ready to purchase a home, I always recommend a home inspection during the due diligence period, after your offer is accepted but before closing. I can recommend several reputable inspectors that I have used in the past that will do a good job for you.

Home inspections are intended to point out adverse conditions in a home, not cosmetic flaws. At the end of the inspection, you should meet with the inspector so they can review a summary of their findings in the home. There will be flaws in every home, but it’s important to pay special attention to health and safety issues.

“Home inspectors are only looking for adverse conditions.”

A home inspection report just includes the basics. During an average inspection, the inspector will consider hundreds of items in and around the interior and exterior of the home. The foundation, purchases, deck, chimney, and roof will all be inspected. So will the electrical, plumbing, heating and air, attic, and garage inside the home. Having a detailed report will help make you more comfortable with the home you’re buying.

The buyer hires and pays for the home inspection because you want the inspector to be working for you and alerting you to any potential problems in the home.

If you have any questions about home inspections or are looking to buy or sell a home, give us a call or send us an email. We would love to hear from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/OK%20Hogan%20%28Star%20Team%29/Crystal%20Coast%20Real%20Estate-%20Dec%201.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/OK%20Hogan%20%28Star%20Team%29/Crystal%20Coast%20Real%20Estate-%20Dec%201.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

We’ve got some great info for you today on home inspections: what they are, who does them, and what they accomplish.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>OK Hogan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

We’ve got some great info for you today on home inspections: what they are, who does them, and what they accomplish.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Crystal Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Sell a House with Pets</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-to-sell-house-with-pets.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>OK Hogan</author>
        <pubDate>2016-12-01 10:01:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/OK%20Hogan%20%28Star%20Team%29/What%20to%20Do%20with%20Pets%20When%20Putting%20Your%20Home%20on%20the%20Market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Selling a home when you have pets can be a bit of challenge, but these steps will make it markedly easier.

Selling a home with pets doesn’t have to be a challenge. Just make sure you take the right steps before you sell your home to ensure a smooth transaction.

First, check with your insurance. You know your pet would never hurt anyone on purpose, but you may be liable if they mistake a buyer for an intruder and attack. Next, you want to prepare your yard. Buyers will walk around the yard and you don’t want them to step in anything or roll an ankle in a hole your dog dug out. Check the lawn before each showing. If you can’t seed for new grass to cover bare patches in time, you can cover ugly patches with new sod.

Removing odors left by pets is one of the biggest challenges you need to take care of. It’s easy to store a litter box, but it’s not easy to cover up years of accidents on rugs or hardwood floors. If a bacteria-eating cleaner doesn’t help, you might want to hire a professional cleaner. If the smell persists, you may need to replace the carpet.

If you have fish tanks, make them sparkle with a daily swipe of an eraser sponge.

Next, make sure you clean all pet hair. Pet hair not only makes a home look messy, it can trigger allergies and send buyers wheezing out the door. Vacuum and dust before each showing or consider buying a Roomba vacuuming robot. If you have a pet that sheds, brush them frequently outside to avoid getting fur in the house.

Since pets—like kids—tend to accumulate lots of stuff, you want to hide evidence like leashes, toys, water bowls, and food. Store away everything you can and wash pet beds to remove odors, dirt, and hair. Only keep them out if they’re attractive.

You should also consider keeping your pets in a crate or a confined area of the house while you’re out or during showings, and make sure your agent knows where they are. Keep them busy with toys or long-lasting treats. The best option is to find a play date for your pet before a showing.

Remember that pets have emotions, too. When you do things like store their food and toys, crate them, and bring strangers into your home, some pets may get confused and anxious. Before you make any major changes in their life, talk to your vet.

“Remember, pets have emotions too.”

If you have any more questions about the best way to sell a home with pets, give us a call or send us an email soon. We’d love to help you in any way we can!
</description>
        <enclosure url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/OK%20Hogan%20%28Star%20Team%29/What%20to%20Do%20with%20Pets%20When%20Putting%20Your%20Home%20on%20the%20Market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/OK%20Hogan%20%28Star%20Team%29/What%20to%20Do%20with%20Pets%20When%20Putting%20Your%20Home%20on%20the%20Market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Selling a home when you have pets can be a bit of challenge, but these steps will make it markedly easier.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>OK Hogan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Selling a home when you have pets can be a bit of challenge, but these steps will make it markedly easier.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Crystal Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why the Fall is a Great Time to Sell your Home</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/why-fall-is-great-time-to-sell-your-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>OK Hogan</author>
        <pubDate>2016-11-03 12:24:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Sometimes, it really pays to go against the crowd.

As you probably know, spring is the season when most people put their homes on the market.

Summer is the high season, and it’s when most homes get sold.

And yet, there are a few powerful reasons why fall might actually be a better time than either spring or summer to sell your home.

It makes perfect sense when you think about it.

By the fall, the bulk of spring listings are expiring. As a result, there is less competition, particularly when you consider the NEW label and the fewer days on the market that your listing will boast.

Also, home buyers in the fall are more serious. They have been looking at listings for months, and they are eager to conclude their search and move in comfortably before the holidays.

When you put those two things together, you get that homes listed in the fall sell more quickly and often command a higher price. In fact, fall is the season with the highest percentage of sold listings, beating out summer by 1%.

Now, if you are thinking of selling your home this fall, there are a few things you have to do differently.

First, you have to prepare your home to account for the particular fall conditions.

For example, you need to check the HVAC system and replace your furnace filter so your home will be warm and smell fresh. Also, make sure to turn on all the lights; you’ve got to compensate for the shorter, cloudier days. Cleaning up the yard is also a must.

The second thing you need to do is price your home appropriately.

To get started, check out the value calculator I created that takes into
account recent sales to give you an idea of what your home is worth right now.

Enter your home address here to find out what your home is currently worth.

Once you have an idea of what your home is worth, how should you price it?

On the one hand, the fall is not a good time to start with a sky-high price. If you don’t sell right away, you might not have time to adjust the price because of the smaller number of buyers and the shorter selling period (nobody wants to move over Christmas).

On the other hand, those serious buyers I mentioned earlier might be willing to pay more simply because they’ve been looking longer and are more eager to buy.

It’s a balancing act. It’s also something I can definitely help you with.

Give me a call at 252-727-5656  if you are considering selling this fall, and I’ll give you my recommendations on how to price your home based on current conditions in the Crystal Coast.

Have a great day!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Sometimes, it really pays to go against the crowd.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>OK Hogan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Sometimes, it really pays to go against the crowd.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Crystal Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>OK Hogan</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">OK Hogan</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Star Team - your professional Crystal Coast Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
