<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hawaii Real Estate Podcast with Duke Kimhan</title>
    <link>localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from HI Pacific Property Management - your professional Hawaii Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Duke Kimhan</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2017-09-19 09:38:43 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Duke Kimhan</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Hawaii, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>info@HIPacificPM.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Duke Kimhan</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Duke Kimhan</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Hawaii, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Hawaii Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from HI Pacific Property Management - your professional Hawaii Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Do We Handle Water Leaks in Your Property?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-do-we-handle-water-leaks-in-your.html</link>
        
          <category>Hawaii Pacific Property Management</category>
        
        <author>Duke Kimhan</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-23 11:35:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Duke+Kimhan/Hawaii+Property+Management+Why+water+leaks+are+so+devastating.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Water leaks are one of the biggest pains we have in the home rental business. Here’s how you can avoid them before they even happen.

Find Out How Much Your Home Will Rent For in Today’s Market 
Learn More About Guaranteed Rent

Water leaks are probably the most menacing opponent we face in the home rental business. If you’re a homeowner/investor, I highly suggest getting additional rent loss coverage on your home for this specific purpose.

If you end up having a big leak, you’ll have to bear the full brunt of it most of the time. If we have a flooded unit, we have a tenant who can’t reside there. We will then have to immediately dry the unit out. However, that process takes three to five days to complete. During that time, you won’t be collecting any rent.

“HALF OF OUR LEAKS RESULT IN INSURANCE CLAIMS.”

About half of our leaks result in insurance claims. The sooner we can get to them, the better. If you end up having to lose rent for a month or two, it will be offset by the money you saved by having that extra insurance.

If you have any questions for us or you’re thinking about investing in real estate, give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Duke+Kimhan/Hawaii+Property+Management+Why+water+leaks+are+so+devastating.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Duke+Kimhan/Hawaii+Property+Management+Why+water+leaks+are+so+devastating.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Water leaks are one of the biggest pains we have in the home rental business. Here’s how you can avoid them before they even happen.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Duke Kimhan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Water leaks are one of the biggest pains we have in the home rental business. Here’s how you can avoid them before they even happen.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Hawaii, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Should You Allow Pets in Your Rental Home?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/should-you-allow-pets-in-your-rental.html</link>
        
          <category>Hawaii Pacific Property Management Owners</category>
        
        <author>Duke Kimhan</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-11 11:22:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Duke+Kimhan/Hawaii+Property+Management-+Fido+makes+property+owners+more+dough.mp4</guid>
        <description>

You can choose whether you want to allow pets in your rental property. Here’s what we recommend.

Find Out How Much Your Home Will Rent For in Today’s Market 
Learn More About Guaranteed Rent

One of the most common questions we get from homeowners is if they have to allow pets in their rental home. The answer is no. It’s totally up to you what kind of pets, if any, you will allow in your home.

However, keep in mind that eight out of 10 people in today’s market have pets. Especially when rent is up a little higher and families are out there looking. Most families have one or two children and one or two pets. It just comes with the territory.

If you do choose to allow pets in your home, our addendum helps protect you. We’ll go inspect the property every four months and look for pet damage, as well as any other damage. We’ll send you pictures of any damage, as well as a picture of the pet in the home.

“OUR ADDENDUM PROTECTS YOU FROM PET DAMAGE.”

We don’t take our pet policy lightly. We’re here to protect your home and put money in your account. If you don’t want to allow pets, that’s fine, but just know that you’ll be missing out on a huge part of the market and it might take us longer to find a tenant than normal.

If you have any other questions for us, don’t hesitate to reach out. We would love to hear from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Duke+Kimhan/Hawaii+Property+Management-+Fido+makes+property+owners+more+dough.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Duke+Kimhan/Hawaii+Property+Management-+Fido+makes+property+owners+more+dough.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

You can choose whether you want to allow pets in your rental property. Here’s what we recommend.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Duke Kimhan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

You can choose whether you want to allow pets in your rental property. Here’s what we recommend.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Hawaii, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Landlord or Tenant. Who Pays for Pest Control?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/who-takes-care-of-pest-control.html</link>
        
          <category>Hawaii Pacific Property Management</category>
        
        <author>Duke Kimhan</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-21 15:22:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Duke+Kimhan/Hawaii+Property+Management-+Landlord+or+tenant.+Who+pays+for+pest+control%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If a tenant leaves food out in the house and a rodent problem develops, who is responsible for pest control: the owner or the tenant?

Find Out How Much Your Home Will Rent For in Today’s Market 
Learn More About Guaranteed Rent

Pests can be a formidable adversary. Their job is to come into your house and find whatever food and water they can.

That’s why pest control is an incredibly important subject for tenants and owners.

As an owner, it is totally optional to carry pest control through the lease period of the tenants. That said, our addendum states that pest control is covered by the tenant.

Pest control includes rodent control. The owner has no control if tenants leave out food, which attracts pests—so they should not be held responsible. If rodent control is an ongoing problem mentioned in the owner’s interview, I would recommend that you continue to carry rodent control in your house.

“THE OWNER IS NOT THE ONE WHO ATTRACTED THE PESTS, SO THE OWNER DOES NOT INCUR THE COSTS OF PEST CONTROL.”

Rodents are brought in by food not being stored properly in the home. So, as I mentioned, since the tenant is the one who attracts the rodents, they are the ones responsible for the costs of rodent control.

Although pest control is important, I would say that 90% of my homes do not have a rodent problem.

If you have any other questions about pest control or would like to learn more about how we take care of your investment properties, just give me a call or send me an email. Feel free to check out our site as well. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Duke+Kimhan/Hawaii+Property+Management-+Landlord+or+tenant.+Who+pays+for+pest+control%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Duke+Kimhan/Hawaii+Property+Management-+Landlord+or+tenant.+Who+pays+for+pest+control%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If a tenant leaves food out in the house and a rodent problem develops, who is responsible for pest control: the owner or the tenant?

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Duke Kimhan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If a tenant leaves food out in the house and a rodent problem develops, who is responsible for pest control: the owner or the tenant?

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Hawaii, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Hawaii Pacific Property Management Helps Owners "Clean" Up On Rent</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-does-our-move-out-addendum-protect.html</link>
        
          <category>Hawaii Pacific Property Management</category>
        
        <author>Duke Kimhan</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-11 10:47:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Duke+Kimhan/Hawaii+Property+Management-+Hawaii+Pacific+Property+Management+Helps+Owners+-Clean-+Up+On+Rent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Our move-out addendum ensures that your property is always in good condition. Here’s how it works.

Find Out How Much Your Home Will Rent For in Today’s Market 
Learn More About Guaranteed Rent

The Hawaii Landlord-Tenant Code is a 29-page document that spells out all the expectations for owners and renters. Here at Hawaii Pacific Property Management, we add an additional 14-page addendum to our rental contract called a “move-out addendum” that we wanted to talk to you about today.

This addendum states that the tenant will get professional services to clean the home and leave it in the same condition it was when they moved in. To ensure this, we require tenants to sign the agreement up front before they move in. We also require them to provide receipts for any carpet cleaning or maid services they use. This way, there are never any questions about the condition of the property. It will look the same each time a tenant moves out.

“WE PROTECT YOUR HOME AND PUT MONEY IN YOUR ACCOUNT.”

We do two things very well: We protect your home and put money in your account. If you need help with either of those things or have any questions about real estate in general, give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Duke+Kimhan/Hawaii+Property+Management-+Hawaii+Pacific+Property+Management+Helps+Owners+-Clean-+Up+On+Rent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Duke+Kimhan/Hawaii+Property+Management-+Hawaii+Pacific+Property+Management+Helps+Owners+-Clean-+Up+On+Rent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Our move-out addendum ensures that your property is always in good condition. Here’s how it works.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Duke Kimhan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Our move-out addendum ensures that your property is always in good condition. Here’s how it works.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Hawaii, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>When Do You Get Paid for Your Investment Property?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/when-do-you-get-paid-for-your.html</link>
        
          <category>Hawaii Pacific Property Management Owners</category>
        
        <author>Duke Kimhan</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-27 16:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Duke+Kimhan/Hawaii+Property+Management-+How+you+get+the+profits+from+your+investment.mp4</guid>
        <description>As the owner of an investment property, how do you get paid? I’ll explain the process today.

Find Out How Much Your Home Will Rent For in Today’s Market 
Learn More About Guaranteed Rent

One of the most common questions we get is, “How do I get paid?”

It’s pretty simple. We collect rents on the first of every month. Hawaii has a “no grace period” law for tenants, which means that rent is definitely due on the first.

It takes a couple of days to process the payment but thanks to ACH and the magic of online banking, our owners will get paid on the fifth of the month.

We do all of the behind-the-scenes work to manage your property. However, the only thing you need to know is that we make the rent appear at no hassle to you.

“RENT IS ALWAYS COLLECTED ON THE FIRST OF EACH MONTH.”

When you work with me, you don’t have to pay any money up front. If your property needs repairs, the cost will be taken out of the rent. Don’t worry—we don’t do anything without your permission, and you will be communicated with about everything via text, email, or a phone call.

If you have any other questions about your payment or would like to learn more about how we can help you, just give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Duke+Kimhan/Hawaii+Property+Management-+How+you+get+the+profits+from+your+investment.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Duke+Kimhan/Hawaii+Property+Management-+How+you+get+the+profits+from+your+investment.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>As the owner of an investment property, how do you get paid? I’ll explain the process today.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Duke Kimhan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>As the owner of an investment property, how do you get paid? I’ll explain the process today.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Hawaii, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How We Discern Between Wear & Tear and Tenant Damage</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-we-discern-between-wear-tear-and.html</link>
        
          <category>Hawaii Pacific Property Management Tenants</category>
        
        <author>Duke Kimhan</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-09 10:06:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Duke+Kimhan/videoplayback.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Discerning the difference between normal wear and tear versus actual damage is a difficult but important part of property management. Here’s how we handle it.

Find Out How Much Your Home Will Rent For in Today’s Market 
Learn More About Guaranteed Rent

How do you discern wear and tear versus damage in a rental property? Getting a property condition form filled out correctly is one of the biggest problems I face in my business.

The standard property condition form is four pages and it’s very extensive. We require tenants to fill out this form on their way in within the first 10 days of living in a unit. We then go back in on a 10-day walkthrough to remove your lock box and collect the property condition form. During that time, we walkthrough each item on the form that’s listed as damaged or not working properly.

“GETTING A PROPERLY FILLED OUT CONDITION FORM IS ONE OF THE TOUGHEST PARTS OF PROPERTY MANAGEMENT.”

If we commit to the repairs during the 10-day walkthrough, they’ll be repaired at the owner’s cost.

Wear and tear means things like scratches and scuff marks on the stairs, walls, and bathtub, dirty mirrors, and yellowing on the toilet. We have to determine whether it’s wear and tear from living in the unit or damage from negligence by the tenant. Our job is to make that determination for our owners upon move out.

We also do a six-month walkthrough to make sure the home is cared for, four months if the unit allows pets. We provide pictures of the walkthrough, guaranteed.

If you have any questions about assessing wear and tear or damage in a unit or you’re interested in our property management services, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We’d be glad to speak with you further.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Duke+Kimhan/videoplayback.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Duke+Kimhan/videoplayback.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Discerning the difference between normal wear and tear versus actual damage is a difficult but important part of property management. Here’s how we handle it.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Duke Kimhan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Discerning the difference between normal wear and tear versus actual damage is a difficult but important part of property management. Here’s how we handle it.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Hawaii, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Does Our Rent Guarantee Work? </title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-does-our-rent-guarantee-work.html</link>
        
          <category>Rent Guarantee</category>
        
        <author>Duke Kimhan</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-22 11:16:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Duke+Kimhan/Hawaii+Property+Management-+How+our+rent+guarantee+helps+you.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What is a rent guarantee and why do we offer one? I’ll explain everything today.

Find Out How Much Your Home Will Rent For in Today’s Market 
Learn More About Guaranteed Rent

When you work with us, I guarantee that we’ll pay an agreed upon amount if we don’t rent your property in 30 days or less.

How do we do that?

First of all, very few property management companies guarantee their work. We will look at your property’s area, present you with a market rent, and guarantee your rent at a certain amount. For example, let’s say your house’s recommended rent is $3,000; we’ll guarantee your rent at $2,400 or $2,600.

There are many factors that go into renting your home. Until we actually look at the property, we don’t know how renting will go. We don’t know if the people who lived there used to bully the neighborhood, what the parking situation is, or if the house has pets.

When we arrive at the house, we will look at all of those factors to determine whether or not we can rent your home. If we can, then you sign a contract that states that we will do everything in our power to rent your home. The contract also offers a rent guarantee, an eviction guarantee, and a communication guarantee.

Many property management companies do not offer an eviction guarantee, even though they put the tenant in the property! If we have to go to eviction with a tenant, we will pay for that. We will also do a four and six-month walkthrough to make sure that your tenants are holding the line as far as your lease goes.

“WE ARE HERE TO MAKE YOU MONEY AND PROTECT YOUR PROPERTY.”

Our communication guarantee is extremely important. Many other property management companies can take a while to call you back if they call you back at all. We will give you an updated report each Monday to let you know how many people looked at the home, how many are interested in renting, and give you any feedback from the renters. You have three numbers to reach us: my number, your property manager’s number, and our 800 number that connects to all of our property managers. If you need to talk to us, someone will answer you, guaranteed.

There are two reasons why I am here: to put money into your bank account and to protect your home. We promise and guarantee that we will do both of those things. If you have any questions for us, please don’t hesitate to give us a call. We are always happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Duke+Kimhan/Hawaii+Property+Management-+How+our+rent+guarantee+helps+you.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Duke+Kimhan/Hawaii+Property+Management-+How+our+rent+guarantee+helps+you.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

What is a rent guarantee and why do we offer one? I’ll explain everything today.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Duke Kimhan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

What is a rent guarantee and why do we offer one? I’ll explain everything today.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Hawaii, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Meet Your Property Specialists - The Nurre Team ​</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/meet-your-property-specialists-nurre.html</link>
        
          <category>Hawaii Pacific Property Management</category>
        
        <author>Duke Kimhan</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-03 12:10:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Duke+Kimhan/Hawaii+Property+Management-+Meet+your+Property+Specialists+-+The+Nurre+Team.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today we want to introduce you to Ikaika and Julie Nurre, or as we call them, the Nurre Team.

Find Out How Much Your Home Will Rent For in Today’s Market 
Learn More About Guaranteed Rent

Ikaika Nurre is a property specialist who assists Julie Nurre for HI Pacific Property Management. He enjoys working our team’s sophisticated management software system because of how efficiently it allows us to serve our owners.

Julie is excited to be part of the dynamic team because of our focus on taking care of our owners. Not only do we take full care of our owners’ investment properties, we put money in the bank for them.

If you have any property management needs, don’t hesitate to reach out to us! We’d love to work with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Duke+Kimhan/Hawaii+Property+Management-+Meet+your+Property+Specialists+-+The+Nurre+Team.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Duke+Kimhan/Hawaii+Property+Management-+Meet+your+Property+Specialists+-+The+Nurre+Team.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today we want to introduce you to Ikaika and Julie Nurre, or as we call them, the Nurre Team.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Duke Kimhan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today we want to introduce you to Ikaika and Julie Nurre, or as we call them, the Nurre Team.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Hawaii, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Filet Mignon For Property Owner With Rent Loss Insurance - No Hot Dogs!</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/what-can-our-owners-and-tenants-expect.html</link>
        
          <category>Hawaii Pacific Property Management</category>
        
        <author>Duke Kimhan</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-19 11:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Adrienne+Lally/Hawaii+Property+Management-+Filet+mignon+for+property+owner+with+rent+loss+-+no+hot+dogs%2521.mp4</guid>
        <description>We recommend that our owners carry certain types of insurance coverage so they can maximize their investment property’s value.

Find Out How Much Your Home Will Rent For in Today’s Market 
Learn More About Guaranteed Rent
Free Insurance Quote

One of the questions we get asked a lot by our owners is, “How much insurance should we carry on our home while we don’t live in it?” Today I want to delve into this topic to give you an idea of what owners and tenants can expect.

The first thing you must do as an owner is notify your current insurance company that you’re not using the property as your primary residence. This is an important detail for insurance companies because that makes the property an investment property.

After that’s done, we first recommend you take out a renter’s insurance policy that covers at least $10,000 in personal property. This is primarily to cover your appliances. This sum won’t be enough to cover a disaster like a wind storm blowing off your roof, but we’ve been fortunate enough in Hawaii to mostly avoid hurricanes and other storms capable of that kind of damage in the past 100 years. Your liability coverage will be $100,000, which is in place in case an accident happens on the property.

The other thing we recommend for owners is to get loss of rent coverage. This is important because if there’s a leak or your home incurs some type of water damage, the tenants probably won’t be able to reside in it and pay rent. The loss of rent coverage makes sure you are compensated for the lost rent on your investment.

“AS AN OWNER, YOUR LIABILITY COVERAGE WILL BE $100,000.”

What do we ask on the tenant’s side? We require all tenants to carry a renter’s policy, which is a simple renter’s policy to cover a minimum of $10,000 on their property, $50,000 in liability, and more if they have a dangerous pet. If they happen to have what we consider a dangerous pet, we ask them to cover $100,000. We also ask them to have loss of rent coverage in their policy so that policy will kick in if something happens to them and prevents them from paying rent.

If your house has wood floors and experiences a water leak and the tenants can still live there but aren’t happy about it, the tenant’s coverage will take care of what they can cover, and the owner’s coverage will take care of the rest. We often see this situation happen with condos and townhouses.

Depending on the insurance company, this will cost an owner anywhere from $100 to $300 and a tenant anywhere from $100 to $200. It’s a minimal cost, and we require it of both our tenants before they move in and our owners before they have a tenant reside in their unit.

If you have any questions about this topic, please feel free to reach out to us. We look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Adrienne+Lally/Hawaii+Property+Management-+Filet+mignon+for+property+owner+with+rent+loss+-+no+hot+dogs%2521.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Adrienne+Lally/Hawaii+Property+Management-+Filet+mignon+for+property+owner+with+rent+loss+-+no+hot+dogs%2521.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>We recommend that our owners carry certain types of insurance coverage so they can maximize their investment property’s value.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Duke Kimhan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We recommend that our owners carry certain types of insurance coverage so they can maximize their investment property’s value.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Hawaii, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How We Earn Our Management Fees!</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/what-all-goes-into-services-we-offer.html</link>
        
          <category>Hawaii Pacific Property Management</category>
        
        <author>Duke Kimhan</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-22 11:02:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Duke+Kimhan/Hawaii+Property+Management-+How+we+earn+our+management+fees%2521.mp4</guid>
        <description>

How do we earn our fees as a property management company? Here are all the things we do for owners to help them protect their investments.

Find Out How Much Your Home Will Rent For in Today’s Market 
Learn More About Guaranteed Rent

This year has been great so far. Interest rates have gone up, so I commend those of you who have invested in property and chose us to help make your property more valuable. It was a smart move.

A lot of people want to know about our owner fees and how we earn them when it comes to maintenance and finding tenants. We put a lot of work into these areas so that our owners and their investments are protected.

Before we take over a property to manage, we first look at the appliances. If they need to be serviced, we take care of them. However, once the tenant gets in there, all bets on maintenance are off. People handle day-to-day living differently. Many times we’ll see a disposal overload or toilet backup.

“DOING THE HARD WORK UP FRONT ALLOWS US TO FIND GREAT TENANTS.”

Whenever something goes wrong, our property manager will contact the owner to see how they want to handle the situation. If they have a friend or family member that can take care of the maintenance, we will go to them. If not, we have our in-house vendors that we have approved and worked with in the past. We won’t repair anything for you without your permission, however.

Another area of our business where we are really strong is our marketing. We make sure to take pictures and video of our properties each time a tenant moves in or out. We also push our properties to the major websites like apartments.com, Trulia, Zillow, Craigslist, and more. Some of those sites have been very strong for us in finding good tenants.

We do background checks, credit checks, and criminal checks on all potential tenants. We believe in doing the hard work up front because once it’s done, we can foresee and chase out all the bad prospects or tenants we may get.

Once we have a tenant, we do a four- or six-month walkthrough to ensure proper maintenance in the home. If they have pets, it’s every four months. If they don’t, it’s every six.

In a nutshell, that’s how we earn our fees. We think we are more than worth our price, and many of our owners can attest to that. If you have any questions for us or you’re looking to invest in property here in Hawaii, give us a call or send us an email. We would love to hear from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Duke+Kimhan/Hawaii+Property+Management-+How+we+earn+our+management+fees%2521.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Duke+Kimhan/Hawaii+Property+Management-+How+we+earn+our+management+fees%2521.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

How do we earn our fees as a property management company? Here are all the things we do for owners to help them protect their investments.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Duke Kimhan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

How do we earn our fees as a property management company? Here are all the things we do for owners to help them protect their investments.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Hawaii, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Meet Evan Miyaki </title>
        <link>localhost:4000/meet-evan-miyaki.html</link>
        
          <category>Hawaii Pacific Property Management</category>
        
        <author>Duke Kimhan</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-09 10:12:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Duke+Kimhan/Hawaii+Property+Management-+Meet+Metro+Honolulu%2527s+property+manager.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Meet Evan Miyaki, another member of the Hawaii Pacific Property Management.

Today we’d like to introduce another member of Hawaii Pacific Property Management, Evan Miyaki.

Evan loves that our team is a high-integrity group with a commitment to communication. Evan primarily covers the metro Honolulu area.

“OUR TEAM IS COMMITTED TO COMMUNICATING WITH OUR CLIENTS.”

Another thing Evan likes about our team is our rent guarantee. Our rent guarantee states that if we don’t rent out your property in 30 days, we will pay your rent program.

If you have any questions for Evan, give him a call at 808-721-3639 or email him at Evan@HiPacificPM.com. If you have any other questions, please don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Duke+Kimhan/Hawaii+Property+Management-+Meet+Metro+Honolulu%2527s+property+manager.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Duke+Kimhan/Hawaii+Property+Management-+Meet+Metro+Honolulu%2527s+property+manager.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Meet Evan Miyaki, another member of the Hawaii Pacific Property Management.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Duke Kimhan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Meet Evan Miyaki, another member of the Hawaii Pacific Property Management.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Hawaii, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Meet Arlene Ichimura</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/meet-arlene-ichimura.html</link>
        
          <category>Hawaii Pacific Property Management</category>
        
        <author>Duke Kimhan</author>
        <pubDate>2016-12-21 11:42:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Duke+Kimhan/Hawaii+Property+Management-+Your+West+Oahu+Property+Manager.mp4</guid>
        <description>

We’re back to introduce another great member of our team. This time we’re talking to Arlene Ichimura.

It’s time again for us to introduce you to another one of the great members of our team. This time it’s Arlene Ichimura, a property manager here at Hawaii Pacific.

Arlene’s goal is to provide excellent communication and customer service to our owners and tenants. What she likes most about working with us are the efficient systems we have in place, our ongoing training, and the support we offer.

“ARLENE’S GOAL IS TO PROVIDE EXCELLENT COMMUNICATION AND CUSTOMER SERVICE.”

Arlene covers the areas of Kapolei and Ewa Beach. If you have any questions for her, give her a call at (808) 721-7990 or send her an email to Arlene@hipacificpm.com. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Duke+Kimhan/Hawaii+Property+Management-+Your+West+Oahu+Property+Manager.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Duke+Kimhan/Hawaii+Property+Management-+Your+West+Oahu+Property+Manager.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

We’re back to introduce another great member of our team. This time we’re talking to Arlene Ichimura.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Duke Kimhan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

We’re back to introduce another great member of our team. This time we’re talking to Arlene Ichimura.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Hawaii, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Our Move Out Addendum Benefits Us and Our Tenants</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-our-move-out-addendum-benefits-us.html</link>
        
          <category>Property Management Tips</category>
        
        <author>Duke Kimhan</author>
        <pubDate>2016-11-18 13:29:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Duke+Kimhan/Hawaii+Property+Management+How+Our+Move+Out+Addendum+Benefits+Us+and+Our+Tenants.mp4</guid>
        <description>

For every home we lease, we have the tenant sign a move out addendum. This ensures that the property is left in good condition for the next tenant.

Today we wanted to talk about an important part of our leasing contract: The Move Out Addendum. You see, every tenant that signs with us signs a move out addendum.

This contract is an agreement that the tenant will leave the property in the same condition that they got it, specifically with regard to ensuring that the carpet and the interior are professionally cleaned, because this is the service that we offer to them. This addendum also guarantees us in writing that if the tenant has a pet, they will get special pet treatment on their carpets and deodorize the entire home so that there is no residue.

“WE WORK TO PROTECT YOUR HOME AND PUT MONEY INTO YOUR ACCOUNT.”

In addition, this addendum gives the tenant the option of allowing us to professionally clean the home if they don’t want to do it themselves. That way, they don’t have to clean the house twice. If our tenant does choose to do their own professional cleaning and we get the receipt that things aren’t finished, however, we have the right to recall the service company, specify what they didn’t finish, and make sure the job gets done.

Remember, we only work with two goals in mind: 1) to protect your home; 2) to put money into your account.

If you have any questions about our move out addendum or anything else related to property management, please feel free to call us or shoot us an email. We look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Duke+Kimhan/Hawaii+Property+Management+How+Our+Move+Out+Addendum+Benefits+Us+and+Our+Tenants.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Duke+Kimhan/Hawaii+Property+Management+How+Our+Move+Out+Addendum+Benefits+Us+and+Our+Tenants.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

For every home we lease, we have the tenant sign a move out addendum. This ensures that the property is left in good condition for the next tenant.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Duke Kimhan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

For every home we lease, we have the tenant sign a move out addendum. This ensures that the property is left in good condition for the next tenant.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Hawaii, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Meet Our Office Manager</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/meet-our-office-manager.html</link>
        
          <category>Hawaii Pacific Property Management</category>
        
        <author>Duke Kimhan</author>
        <pubDate>2016-11-03 10:34:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Duke+Kimhan/Hawaii+Property+Management+-+Meet+Our+Office+Manager.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Priscilla Jacobo is our Office Manager. She wears a lot of hats to ensure that our business continues to thrive.

We are back to introduce another great member of our team. Priscilla Jacobo is our Office Manager here at Hawaii Pacific Property Management. She actually started out as a tenant at one of our properties. She was impressed by our genuine character and how we took care of her, so she decided that she wanted to be part of our team.

As the office manager, Priscilla handles all the bookkeeping, invoicing, and back-end tasks to ensure that we really take care of our owners and their properties. We are grateful to have Priscilla on our team.

If you have any questions for us, don’t hesitate to reach out by phone or email. We would love to hear from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Duke+Kimhan/Hawaii+Property+Management+-+Meet+Our+Office+Manager.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Duke+Kimhan/Hawaii+Property+Management+-+Meet+Our+Office+Manager.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Priscilla Jacobo is our Office Manager. She wears a lot of hats to ensure that our business continues to thrive.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Duke Kimhan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Priscilla Jacobo is our Office Manager. She wears a lot of hats to ensure that our business continues to thrive.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Hawaii, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Meet Melissa Getty</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/meet-melissa-getty.html</link>
        
          <category>Hawaii Pacific Property Management</category>
        
        <author>Duke Kimhan</author>
        <pubDate>2016-10-27 12:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Meet one of our great team members, Melissa Getty.
She is here to talk a little bit about our team today.

Today we would like to introduce you to Melissa Getty, one of the great members of our team. What she likes most about Hawaii Pacific Property Management is our transparent communication policy to all of our owners and our ability to be fast problem solvers.

The areas that Melissa serves include Mililani, Waipahu, and Waikele. If you have any questions for Melissa, don’t hesitate to give her a call at 808-445-9223 or send her an email at Melissa@HiPacificPM.com. Hope to hear from you soon!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Meet one of our great team members, Melissa Getty.
She is here to talk a little bit about our team today.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Duke Kimhan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Meet one of our great team members, Melissa Getty.
She is here to talk a little bit about our team today.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Hawaii, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What to Do if a Tenant Breaks the Lease</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/what-to-do-if-tenant-breaks-lease.html</link>
        
          <category>Property Management Tips</category>
        
        <author>Duke Kimhan</author>
        <pubDate>2016-10-18 12:07:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Duke+Kimhan/Hawaii+Property+Management+-+What+to+Do+if+a+Tenant+Breaks+the+Lease.mp4</guid>
        <description>

As a property owner, complications can arise for you if one of your tenants can’t pay rent. As a property management company, we have a system in place to alleviate this concern.

Sometimes, life happens and there’s nothing you can do about it.

As a property owner, your goal is to pick the best possible tenant by making sure that they have a great credit score, a good background check, minimal criminal history, and great references. Even if you pick the most qualified tenant for your property, though, things can go wrong.

For example, let’s say your tenant is in the military and they either get injured, have a medical discharge, or get divorced. That would mean a likely income change. If one of the spouses moved out of that house, things would also likely change dramatically. Whether that means trying to find another tenant or working with the tenant you already have, problems can arise that can complicate the rent situation.

“THE THING THAT WE DO BETTER THAN ANYONE ELSE IS FIND TENANTS FOR YOUR HOME.”

This is where we come in. We’re a property management company. The thing that we do better than anybody else is finding qualified tenants for your home. How do we do this?

We have a break lease agreement with the tenant that states they are responsible for the lease as long as the property goes vacant. As soon as we find another tenant, the Landlord-Tenant Code specifically states that we cannot charge rent to two different tenants for the same days. That’s against the law!

In the event that one of your tenants can’t pay rent, we would quickly replace them to alleviate any negative rents or mortgages that you have to pay. We would get you your rent payments by the 7th of each month in your account, while collecting rent payments on the 1st. That’s our guarantee.

If you have any further questions about property management, please don’t hesitate to contact us. Just give us a call or send us an email and we’d be happy to help in any way we can. Aloha!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Duke+Kimhan/Hawaii+Property+Management+-+What+to+Do+if+a+Tenant+Breaks+the+Lease.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Duke+Kimhan/Hawaii+Property+Management+-+What+to+Do+if+a+Tenant+Breaks+the+Lease.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

As a property owner, complications can arise for you if one of your tenants can’t pay rent. As a property management company, we have a system in place to alleviate this concern.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Duke Kimhan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

As a property owner, complications can arise for you if one of your tenants can’t pay rent. As a property management company, we have a system in place to alleviate this concern.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Hawaii, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Our Eviction Guarantee Works </title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-our-eviction-guarantee-works.html</link>
        
          <category>Property Management Tips</category>
        
        <author>Duke Kimhan</author>
        <pubDate>2016-10-03 16:07:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Duke+Kimhan/Hawaii+Property+Management+-+How+Our+Eviction+Guarantee+Works.mp4</guid>
        <description>

We offer our homeowners an eviction guarantee.
How does that work exactly? I’ll take you through each step today.

We offer our homeowners an eviction guarantee. How does this work exactly?

The Landlord-Tenant Code is very specific on the steps you are required to take when you’re going to evict someone from your property in civil court.

As soon as we realize that the rents are going to be late, the first thing we do is post a five-day
notice to terminate the lease. We then take a picture of the five-day lease (which is usually posted on the front door) and submit that photo to civil court.  At the same time, we file for an eviction notice for the tenant to appear in court. That eviction notice to appear in court will normally take 14 to 21 days to get served.

Once the eviction notice is served, we get a court date. As soon as the tenant is in court, the first question the judge will ask is, “Do you owe rent on this house and why have you not paid?” The tenants normally answer that question like this: “Judge, we do owe the money, but we have an explanation.”

I will go to the court proceedings along with my property manager for the area. We will testify that the rents are not paid. In that case, we do not take any partial rents for you; if we did, then we couldn’t file for an eviction.

Once the eviction is granted, the judge will ask how many days I will give them to vacate your unit. We will show up on the agreed-upon day with a police officer to accompany them off the property. Once we show up, they have 120 minutes to vacate your home. After they are out, we change the locks, go in with cleaners, and start the re-up process to get your home back on the market.

“WE WILL CHOOSE YOUR TENANT AND HANDLE ANY EVICTIONS AT NO CHARGE TO YOU.”

Remember now, every time we move a tenant in and out of your home, we take new pictures and videos of your property. All of those pictures and videos are date-stamped just in case we end up in court.

That is the eviction process. If you elect to use our eviction guarantee, we will choose your tenant for you. We will find a tenant with a credit score of at least 620, and we guarantee to pay for the eviction process. If you choose to select your own tenant and ignore the eviction guarantee, you will have to pay for me to go to court and evict your tenant.

Ultimately, I recommend that you let us choose your tenant. We will look at their credit, criminal, and eviction history, and then check their references from past landlords. If you have any questions about the eviction process or our eviction guarantee, please give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Duke+Kimhan/Hawaii+Property+Management+-+How+Our+Eviction+Guarantee+Works.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Duke+Kimhan/Hawaii+Property+Management+-+How+Our+Eviction+Guarantee+Works.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

We offer our homeowners an eviction guarantee.
How does that work exactly? I’ll take you through each step today.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Duke Kimhan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

We offer our homeowners an eviction guarantee.
How does that work exactly? I’ll take you through each step today.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Hawaii, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Duke Kimhan</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Duke Kimhan</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from HI Pacific Property Management - your professional Hawaii Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
