<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Don Williams - your professional Keller Williams Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Don Williams</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2018-02-05 13:04:42 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Don Williams</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://i.imgur.com/79z44Al.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Lewes, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Info@donwilliamsgroup.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Don Williams</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Don Williams</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://i.imgur.com/79z44Al.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Lewes, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Lewes, DE Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Don Williams - your professional Keller Williams Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Things a VA Loan Can Do for You</title>
        <link>http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com/5-things-a-va-loan-can-do-for-you.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Don Williams</author>
        <pubDate>2018-01-29 06:43:04 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Don+Williams/+Videos/2018/January/Don+Williams+Group-+5+Things+a+VA+Loan+Can+Do+for+You.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you are a veteran of the armed forces, you’re active duty personnel, you’re a part of the National Guard, or you’re military reserve, you can apply for a VA loan to buy a home.

There are five great advantages that come with this particular loan:

1) You don’t need a down payment. Most people consider a down payment a huge hurdle to homeownership because it sometimes requires you to put up to 20% of your overall loan amount down. With a VA loan, you get to bypass that hurdle.

2) It has more lenient requirements. For example, most people need a credit score of around 650 or 700. With a VA loan, you only need to have a credit score of 620 or above.

“There are several great reasons to apply for a VA loan if you qualify.”

3) You don’t need mortgage insurance. The only thing they require is an upfront funding fee, but that can be rolled into your payments, and it’s tax deductible.

4) It limits your closing costs.

5) It provides appraisal assistance. They can notify your agent and give you 48 hours to provide any additional information you might need to boost the appraisal value.

At the end of the day, the VA loan is our society’s way of saying thank you to all the men and women who have served our country.

If you have any more questions about how a VA loan can benefit you or you have any other real estate needs, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d be glad to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Don+Williams/+Videos/2018/January/Don+Williams+Group-+5+Things+a+VA+Loan+Can+Do+for+You.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Don+Williams/+Videos/2018/January/Don+Williams+Group-+5+Things+a+VA+Loan+Can+Do+for+You.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There are five notable advantages of using a VA loan to buy a home if you’re a member of the armed forces and you qualify for it.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Don Williams</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There are five notable advantages of using a VA loan to buy a home if you’re a member of the armed forces and you qualify for it.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Lewes, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3 Reasons to Have a Pre-Listing Home Inspection</title>
        <link>http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com/3-reasons-to-have-a-pre-listing-home-inspection.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Don Williams</author>
        <pubDate>2018-01-12 10:48:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Don+Williams/+Videos/2018/January/Don+Williams+Group-+3+Reasons+to+Have+a+Pre-Listing+Home+Inspection.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Although you are not required to get a pre-listing inspection on your home before it hits the market, there are a few advantages of doing so.

First of all, a pre-listing inspection will uncover any issues with your house before it goes up for sale. This saves you a lot of time because contracts often depend on whether or not you can repair certain items in your home.

“A pre-listing inspection will give you more credibility with future buyers.”

Getting the inspection in advance gives you a little more time to repair those things in your home and save you money in the long run. By making repairs before the home hits the market, you won’t have to worry about buyers reducing their offer price after they order an inspection on your home.

Finally, a pre-listing inspection can boost your marketability. People want transparency. They want to know what’s wrong with the house up front. Even if you don’t have the money to fix everything before you list your home, you will be able to say, “We know that there are some issues with the house, and those issues were taken into account when we created the listing price.” That will give you a lot more credibility with future homebuyers.

If you have any other questions about pre-listing inspections or selling your home, just give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Don+Williams/+Videos/2018/January/Don+Williams+Group-+3+Reasons+to+Have+a+Pre-Listing+Home+Inspection.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Don+Williams/+Videos/2018/January/Don+Williams+Group-+3+Reasons+to+Have+a+Pre-Listing+Home+Inspection.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you plan on selling your home, there are three main reasons why you should consider getting a pre-listing home inspection on your property.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Don Williams</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you plan on selling your home, there are three main reasons why you should consider getting a pre-listing home inspection on your property.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Lewes, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Do You Need a Real Estate Agent When Buying New Construction?</title>
        <link>http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com/do-you-need-a-real-estate-agent-when-buying-new-construction.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Don Williams</author>
        <pubDate>2017-12-13 04:23:54 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Don+Williams/+Videos/2017/December/Don+Williams+Group-+Do+You+Need+a+Real+Estate+Agent+When+Buying+New+Construction%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Why should you have a buyer’s advocate with you when you look at new construction homes? Why not just work with the builder’s agent? 

It’s important to remember that the agent at the new construction site is there to protect the builder’s best interests, not yours. Your buyer’s agent will have your best interests at heart. 

“A buyer’s agent will negotiate the best deal possible for you.”

A buyer’s agent will help you with any hiccups in the process. We will also negotiate the best deal possible for you. 

The best part is that we do all of this for free. You can work with a buyer’s agent at no cost to you. 

If you have any questions or need help buying a home, just give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Don+Williams/+Videos/2017/December/Don+Williams+Group-+Do+You+Need+a+Real+Estate+Agent+When+Buying+New+Construction%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Don+Williams/+Videos/2017/December/Don+Williams+Group-+Do+You+Need+a+Real+Estate+Agent+When+Buying+New+Construction%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Should you work with a buyer’s agent when purchasing a new construction home?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Don Williams</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Should you work with a buyer’s agent when purchasing a new construction home?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Lewes, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Check Out These Upcoming Holiday Events</title>
        <link>http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com/check-out-these-upcoming-holiday-events.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Don Williams</author>
        <pubDate>2017-11-28 08:44:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Don+Williams/+Videos/2017/November/Don+Williams+Group-+Check+Out+These+Upcoming+Holiday+Events.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’re in the Delaware Beach area, here’s a list of some awesome holiday events we have coming up.

Winter Wonderfest: Take pictures with San ta, visit his workshop, ice skate, and more at the Lewis Ferry Terminal Grounds on November 17 through January 1.

“Join us for some holiday fun!”

Rehoboth Beach Hometown Christmas Parade: December 5 at 6:30 p.m. Santa’s Christmas Party will take place afterward at the Rehoboth Beach fire station.

Hope to see you out there! If you have any questions about buying or selling real estate at the Delaware Beaches, please reach out to us. We’ll be happy to help you out.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Don+Williams/+Videos/2017/November/Don+Williams+Group-+Check+Out+These+Upcoming+Holiday+Events.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Don+Williams/+Videos/2017/November/Don+Williams+Group-+Check+Out+These+Upcoming+Holiday+Events.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here’s a list of some wonderful upcoming holiday events. Hope to see you out there!</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Don Williams</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here’s a list of some wonderful upcoming holiday events. Hope to see you out there!</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Lewes, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Busting the Myth That Fall Isn't a Good Time to Sell</title>
        <link>http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com/busting-the-myth-that-fall-isnt-a-good-time-to-sell.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Don Williams</author>
        <pubDate>2017-11-07 08:55:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Don+Williams/+Videos/2017/November/Don+Williams+Group-+Busting+the+Myth+That+Fall+Isn%2527t+a+Good+Time+to+Sell.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today, let’s dispel the myth that fall isn’t a good time to sell your home. It’s a common belief that couldn’t be more wrong.

A lot of people think that the best time to sell their home is in the spring or summer, and while that may be true, it’s also true that you can sell your home just as well in the fall. Let’s talk about why selling in the fall can work for you.

1.) Depending on when you close—for example, if you close before December 31—there’s a chance you could get some awesome tax breaks and write-offs for the next year.

2.) It’s a wonderful idea that you could be in a brand-new home for the holidays. There’s nothing more special than spending the holidays in the home that you’re going to live in and build memories in with your family.

“There’s nothing more special than spending the holidays in the home that you’re going to live in and build memories in with your family.”

3.) It might be the right time to get just the right price for your property because there is less competition on the market during the fall season. Your home could definitely stand out in the crowd.

4.) It’s a great time to fix up your home to sell because there are awesome holiday sales everywhere you look, Black Friday prominent among them. It’s an opportune time to fix up any areas that you’ve been wanting to tweak a little bit so that it would be even more of a great buy for someone who’s interested.

If you have any questions about how to sell your home this fall, feel free to contact our group at any time. One of our agents would be happy to call you and set up a personalized home-selling plan just for you. We look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Don+Williams/+Videos/2017/November/Don+Williams+Group-+Busting+the+Myth+That+Fall+Isn%2527t+a+Good+Time+to+Sell.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Don+Williams/+Videos/2017/November/Don+Williams+Group-+Busting+the+Myth+That+Fall+Isn%2527t+a+Good+Time+to+Sell.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re concerned about selling your home in the fall, don’t be. It’s a great time to list, for several reasons.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Don Williams</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re concerned about selling your home in the fall, don’t be. It’s a great time to list, for several reasons.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Lewes, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Is Your Home Ready for Trick-or-Treaters?</title>
        <link>http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com/is-your-home-ready-for-trick-or-treaters.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Don Williams</author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-23 05:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Don+Williams/+Videos/2017/October/Don+Williams+Group-+Is+Your+Home+Ready+for+Trick-or-Treaters%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

We’re coming to you during the scary month of October with a few tips to prepare your home for trick-or-treaters.

1. Decorate your door so that trick-or-treaters know they are welcome. There is nothing more exciting than coming up to a door that’s been decked out in Halloween decor and hoping to find candy on the other side.

2. Make sure your property is well lit to prevent any kind of injuries. Try to light up your yard so that people can safely walk from the sidewalk to your front door and back.

“Don’t forget your own costume!”

3. Try to hide valuables from your front porch or yard. We’re not worried about a robbery. This is simply about preventing any accidental damage. Someone might knock into an important valuable on the porch and, suddenly, it’s broken. Remove anything of great value until Halloween is over.

4. Stock up on candy. We also suggest getting candy for kids with allergies, and maybe even some sugar-free candy that’s friendly to everyone, no matter what kind of candy they can have.

5. Don’t forget a costume! Dressing in costume just helps seal the whole experience when you open the door decked out in your own character.

Whether you are preparing for Halloween or going to fall festivals this October, we hope you enjoy the season.

As always, if you have any real estate questions, just give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Don+Williams/+Videos/2017/October/Don+Williams+Group-+Is+Your+Home+Ready+for+Trick-or-Treaters%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Don+Williams/+Videos/2017/October/Don+Williams+Group-+Is+Your+Home+Ready+for+Trick-or-Treaters%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>October is here and Halloween is coming up soon. Today, we have five tips to help you prepare your home for trick-or-treaters.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Don Williams</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>October is here and Halloween is coming up soon. Today, we have five tips to help you prepare your home for trick-or-treaters.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Lewes, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Stage Your Home for Success</title>
        <link>http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com/how-to-stage-your-home-for-success.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Don Williams</author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-11 07:02:30 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Don+Williams/+Videos/2017/October/Don+Williams+Group-+How+to+Stage+Your+Home+for+Success.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There are a lot of things to think about when staging your home for sale. Today, I’ve got a few staging tips that can help you sell for top dollar.

First of all, you need to think about curb appeal. How does the front of your home look? A few changes here and there can really set your home apart. Consider a welcome mat to make buyers feel more at home as they enter your property.

Also, make sure that your yard is clean and well-kept, and that all of your exterior lights are in working order.

“The goal is to showcase your home’s potential.”

Another tip to consider is creating an inviting ambience in your home. This means you should think about smell, sound, and taste as well as sight. You can engage buyers beyond the visual level by leaving out cookies, playing soft, instrumental music, and having an air freshener plug-in in each room.

Next, embrace floor space to make rooms appear as large as possible. Moving furniture away from the centers of rooms, and adding mirrors to smaller spaces can really open things up.

Don’t forget to embrace any unusual or quirky parts of your property. Why not turn a smaller space into a reading nook? The goal is to showcase your home’s potential.

Finally, play up the lifestyle surrounding your home. With our area being so near the beach, we like to play up this surf and sand lifestyle by adding beach decor to a home.

If you have any other questions, would like more information, or want to know how we can offer you a professional consultation with a home stager, feel free to give me a call or send me an email.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Don+Williams/+Videos/2017/October/Don+Williams+Group-+How+to+Stage+Your+Home+for+Success.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Don+Williams/+Videos/2017/October/Don+Williams+Group-+How+to+Stage+Your+Home+for+Success.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today, I’d like to share a few key staging tips that can help you sell for top dollar. Knowing how to present your home can have a huge impact on the success of your listing.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Don Williams</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today, I’d like to share a few key staging tips that can help you sell for top dollar. Knowing how to present your home can have a huge impact on the success of your listing.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Lewes, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4 Tips for Selling Your Home This Fall</title>
        <link>http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com/4-tips-for-selling-your-home-this-fall.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Don Williams</author>
        <pubDate>2017-09-22 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Don+Williams/+Videos/2017/September/Don+Williams+Group-+4+Tips+for+Selling+Your+Home+This+Fall.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Fall is here, which means—among other things—pumpkins are everywhere! As a homeowner, it can be enticing to get into the spirit of things and do something like let your home overflow with pumpkins, but if you’re selling your home this fall, there are certain points you need to remember.

First, consider your curb appeal. Make sure your yard is free of leaves. When prospective buyers view your home, they want to see it in the best shape possible. Keep your fall decor to a minimum and don’t overdo anything because everyone has different tastes and styles.

Second, avoid any gory decorations. Not everyone celebrates Halloween with ghosts, goblins, blood, and gore. While you may think it’s fun to have zombies hanging from tree limbs, you don’t want to upset or scare any buyers when they’re looking at your house.

“If you follow these tips, we guarantee your home will be a top contender to sell this fall.”

Third, let in a lot of natural light. Our days are getting shorter, so clean your windows, pull back the shades, and do everything you can to let natural light in.

Lastly, make your space inviting. Consider placing a few plush, fall-themed pillows on the couch or a few throws on the bed. You might even consider making some homemade cookies and leaving them on the counter for buyers to see when they walk through the home.

If you follow these tips, we guarantee your home will be a top contender to sell this fall. If you have any questions or you’d be interested in letting us help you list your home, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Don+Williams/+Videos/2017/September/Don+Williams+Group-+4+Tips+for+Selling+Your+Home+This+Fall.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Don+Williams/+Videos/2017/September/Don+Williams+Group-+4+Tips+for+Selling+Your+Home+This+Fall.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re selling your home this fall, here are four important tips for you to follow.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Don Williams</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re selling your home this fall, here are four important tips for you to follow.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Lewes, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Consider a Move to Delaware?</title>
        <link>http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com/why-consider-a-move-to-delaware.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Don Williams</author>
        <pubDate>2017-09-08 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Don+Williams/+Videos/2017/September/Don+Williams+Group-+Why+Consider+a+Move+to+Delaware%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The coastal communities in Delaware have experienced unprecedented growth over the past few years. The reasons why are plain to see.

If you and your spouse are nearing retirement or are empty nesters looking to downsize, coming here to the Delaware coast is a great option.  Delaware has some of the lowest real estate taxes in the country. There’s no sales tax here, either. This is one of the primary reasons that retirees look for homes here.

“It’s plain to see why people are moving to the Delaware coast.”

If you combine the value proposition of owning a Delaware home with the fact that there are so many different affordable options, it makes perfect sense for someone who wants a coastal home with a low cost of ownership.

Our team is full of experts in Delaware real estate and we can help make your dream home a reality. If you have any questions for us, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Don+Williams/+Videos/2017/September/Don+Williams+Group-+Why+Consider+a+Move+to+Delaware%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Don+Williams/+Videos/2017/September/Don+Williams+Group-+Why+Consider+a+Move+to+Delaware%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Looking for a great coastal home with a low cost of ownership? You’ll find plenty of them in Delaware.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Don Williams</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Looking for a great coastal home with a low cost of ownership? You’ll find plenty of them in Delaware.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Lewes, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Can You Make Your Home More Energy Efficient?</title>
        <link>http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com/how-can-you-make-your-home-more-energy-efficient.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Don Williams</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-23 08:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Don+Williams/+Videos/2017/August/Don+Williams+Group-+How+Can+You+Make+Your+Home+More+Energy+Efficient%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

How can you make your home more energy efficient?

Making your home more energy efficient doesn’t have to be a difficult task. In fact, it’s easier than you might think. Also, making your home more energy efficient can add value to it.

By visiting the Delaware Division of Energy and Climate online, you’ll find a list of contractors you can use to take your first step: getting an energy audit.

These professionals will come into your home and search it for sources of wasted energy—like leaking air conditioning ducts. Leaking ducts can actually cause up to a 15% loss of your AC.

“Making your home more energy efficient can add value.”

They’ll also check your doors and windows for aging. These features, in some cases, may need to be replaced if they are causing AC or heating to leak from your home.

Your attic space may need to be updated. This could include adding insulation.

Also, while it won’t increase the value of your home, adding solar panels to your property absolutely helps your home to become more energy efficient.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Don+Williams/+Videos/2017/August/Don+Williams+Group-+How+Can+You+Make+Your+Home+More+Energy+Efficient%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Don+Williams/+Videos/2017/August/Don+Williams+Group-+How+Can+You+Make+Your+Home+More+Energy+Efficient%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’ve ever considered making your home more energy efficient, you should absolutely do so. It’s easier than you think.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Don Williams</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’ve ever considered making your home more energy efficient, you should absolutely do so. It’s easier than you think.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Lewes, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Are You Choosing a Home That's Safe?</title>
        <link>http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com/are-you-choosing-a-home-thats-safe.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Don Williams</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-30 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Don+Williams/+Videos/2017/July/Don+Williams+Group-+Are+You+Choosing+a+Home+That%2527s+Safe%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When you’re considering buying a home, it’s important to remember that there are many important factors to consider beyond the house itself.

Today, I want to bring you five specific essentials to think about when buying a home.

1. Contained pool fun. Pools are a great addition to a home and can be a huge draw, especially during the heat of summer. But as fun as pools are, they also come with a lot of safety requirements, some of which could be specific to your area. Additionally, consider whether you’ll be able to control who enters the pool. If the pool doesn’t already have features like locks or safety gates, how much money will you need to spend to get them installed?

2. Backyard fire zones. Barbeques or fire pits are great for entertaining your family and guests alike. But, once again, safety is important. When it comes to fire zones, you should be especially careful of placement. Fire zones shouldn’t be placed near play areas. Remember to make that if you have small children or grandchildren, your yard and its features are being kept kid-friendly.

“By talking to a Realtor who knows the area, you can be sure the home you choose will be safe.”

3. Aging danger zones. A deck or patio may be beautiful for a time, but without proper upkeep these features can become extremely run down over time. On these kinds of features be sure to look out for wood rot and any other aging defects.

4. Landscaping liability. As gorgeous as trees can be as a part of a home’s landscaping, they can be dangerous and costly to remove. Make sure that any trees in your yard are removed promptly and correctly if they die.

5. Curbing danger. As a potential buyer, you may only visit a given home at a time of day when traffic is at a minimum. At other points of the day, there could be much more noise and much more danger. By talking to a Realtor who knows the area, you can be sure that you are choosing a home that is safe for you and your family.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Don+Williams/+Videos/2017/July/Don+Williams+Group-+Are+You+Choosing+a+Home+That%2527s+Safe%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Don+Williams/+Videos/2017/July/Don+Williams+Group-+Are+You+Choosing+a+Home+That%2527s+Safe%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>When you are buying a home, there are a lot of things you need to consider about the property outside of the house itself.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Don Williams</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>When you are buying a home, there are a lot of things you need to consider about the property outside of the house itself.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Lewes, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3 Things All Buyers Want to See in Your Listing</title>
        <link>http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com/3-things-all-buyers-want-to-see-in-your-listing.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Don Williams</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-04 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Don+Williams/+Videos/2017/July/Don+Williams+Group-+3+Things+All+Buyers+Want+to+See+in+Your+Listing.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When selling your home, keep these three things that buyers look for in mind:

1. Curb appeal: Buyers should be impressed from the moment they pull up to the curb. Sweep the driveway and entryway, power-wash the exterior, and plant fresh flowers outside the home. You want them to be excited as soon as they step out of the car.

“Even if your home has a lot of space, you want to declutter as much as possible.”

2. Space: Get rid of all the clutter in your home even if you have a lot of space; excess clutter is one of the biggest turnoffs for buyers. You could rent a storage unit at a minimal cost. For a better return on your final sale price, get rid of all the knicknacks and make sure all countertop and floor space is available.

3. Updates: You don’t need to replace the whole kitchen, but try to upgrade things that are outdated. That could be the countertops, appliances, or hardware like the faucet and cabinet pulls.

We’ll be back soon with more tips, but if you have any questions in the meantime, you can always call or email us. We’re always happy to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Don+Williams/+Videos/2017/July/Don+Williams+Group-+3+Things+All+Buyers+Want+to+See+in+Your+Listing.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Don+Williams/+Videos/2017/July/Don+Williams+Group-+3+Things+All+Buyers+Want+to+See+in+Your+Listing.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you want to appeal your home to as many buyers as possible when you list it on the market, pay close attention to these three areas.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Don Williams</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you want to appeal your home to as many buyers as possible when you list it on the market, pay close attention to these three areas.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Lewes, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Common Mistakes That Will Ruin Your Home Sale: Part 2</title>
        <link>http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com/common-mistakes-that-will-ruin-your-home-sale-part-2.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Don Williams</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-20 10:59:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Don+Williams/Don+Williams+Group-+Communication+is+key.mp4</guid>
        <description>

We’re back with part two of our conversation about the common mistakes home sellers make and how you can avoid them. To catch up, you can watch part one here.

As you might recall us mentioning previously, when picking your agent it’s important to make sure they answer the phone when you call. It’s also important that they know your market and have done business in it. Verifying this information can be done easily by reading their testimonials on Trulia and Zillow. That will tell you whether they’re a good agent.

When putting your home on the market, make sure it stays showroom-ready, meaning you can show the house at any time. In order to sell your house, you must make it available for buyers to see it. If they can’t see it, they’ll move on and purchase something else. 80% of all Realtors won’t reschedule an appointment that’s been canceled. We don’t want to make it convenient for you—we want to make it convenient for the purchaser to come and look at your house.

Another point I want to reiterate from our previous video is not to be emotional with your house during its sale. Divorce yourself from the house as soon as you put it on the market. It’s no longer your property, so if a buyer comes in and says they’re going to repaint it, don’t get upset.

“80% of all Realtors won’t reschedule an appointment that’s been canceled.”

If you find something in the house that needs to be fixed, fix it. If the buyer finds it, it will cost four to seven times more money for you to fix it than if you would’ve found it yourself. When you’re tidying up, you also want to paint the front door. The front door gives the first impression of your house, and you want a great first impression when buyers show up at that door.

Lastly, remember to declutter the house and depersonalize it. Remove any family pictures and store any extra clutter in a storage bin if you have one. If you don’t have one, you can always rent one.

If you have any questions or you’re thinking about buying or selling a home in our market, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. If you send us a question and we use it in one of our videos, you will receive a $25 gift card. We look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Don+Williams/Don+Williams+Group-+Communication+is+key.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Don+Williams/Don+Williams+Group-+Communication+is+key.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here are some more common home selling mistakes and how you can avoid them.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Don Williams</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here are some more common home selling mistakes and how you can avoid them.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Lewes, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Common Mistakes That Will Ruin Your Home Sale</title>
        <link>http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com/common-mistakes-that-will-ruin-your-home-sale.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Don Williams</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-30 05:37:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Don+Williams/Don+Williams+Group-+Communication+is+key.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Selling a home is a long and complicated process. If you aren’t careful, you could be making major mistakes without even knowing it. We wanted to drop by today and talk about some of the most common mistakes we see from sellers in hopes that you don’t make them as well.

One of the biggest and most common mistakes for home sellers is getting too emotional about the sale. You’re always going to overvalue your home because of all the memories you’ve made in there and how much work you’ve put into it. However, overpricing your home can lead to it sitting on the market for much longer than it needs to. You should work with your agent to come up with an appropriate price, which will set your expectations at a level place and remove a lot of frustrations for you and your agent.

Another big one is ignoring small flaws throughout the home. Even though you may not have seen or even thought about that little corner of the wall that the dog chewed on, buyers will notice it right away. You want to make the best first impression possible, and taking the little bit of time and money necessary to fix those imperfections will go a long way when it comes time to sell.

“Excess clutter really turns buyers off.”

Excess clutter is another huge no-no. You want to create a blank slate for buyers with minimal furniture and decorations. Decluttering helps buyers envision themselves and their stuff in your home.

Finally, you need to avoid joining ranks with the wrong Realtor. You need someone who is passionate about selling your home, will work hard to get the job done, and have good communication with you throughout the process. If your Realtor isn’t answering your calls or texts right away, you might want to look for someone new.

If you have any questions for us about selling your home or if you want to know what we can do differently to get you the results you want, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Don+Williams/Don+Williams+Group-+Communication+is+key.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://donwilliamsgroupblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Don+Williams/Don+Williams+Group-+Communication+is+key.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Home selling mistakes are common, but easy to avoid. Here’s what to watch out for.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Don Williams</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Home selling mistakes are common, but easy to avoid. Here’s what to watch out for.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Lewes, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Don Williams</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Don Williams</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Don Williams - your professional Keller Williams Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
