<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Roanoke Real Estate Podcast with Damon Gettier</title>
    <link>http://damongettierblog.com</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://damongettierblog.com"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Damon Gettier & Associates - your professional Roanoke Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Damon Gettier</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2018-02-20 14:47:37 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Damon Gettier</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://damongettierblog.com/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Roanoke, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Damon@DamonGettier.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Damon Gettier</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Damon Gettier</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://damongettierblog.com/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Roanoke, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Roanoke Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Damon Gettier & Associates - your professional Roanoke Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>When Is the Best Time to Prepare Your Listing?</title>
        <link>http://damongettierblog.com/when-is-the-best-time-to-prepare-your-listing.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Damon Gettier</author>
        <pubDate>2018-02-15 11:51:22 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/+Videos+/2018/February/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+When+Is+the+Best+Time+to+Prepare+Your+Listing%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today, we’ll be continuing our series on things to do when preparing to sell your home. The tip I’d like to share this time is: Just do it!

There are so many things in life that we tend to put off for another day instead of taking care of them as soon as possible. I’m not going to lie to you. Putting your home on the market certainly isn’t the most fun experience. However, it is rewarding.

“Even small changes can really add up and pay off.”

Let’s take the example of selling a car for $10,000. Most people in this situation will spend $200 on getting the car detailed, having its tires filled or replaced, or getting it waxed. But when these same people sell a $200,000, they hesitate to spend even $500 on these kinds of upgrades and finishing touches.

However, little changes can really add up and pay off. Before you bring in a Realtor, start clearing out the clutter and doing everything else you can to prepare your home for the market.

Right before you’re ready to list, hire professional cleaners to make your home really shine. The time to start preparing your home for the market is today.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/+Videos+/2018/February/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+When+Is+the+Best+Time+to+Prepare+Your+Listing%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://damongettierblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/+Videos+/2018/February/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+When+Is+the+Best+Time+to+Prepare+Your+Listing%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’ve been putting off making final touches to your home before listing it on the market, there’s no better time than now to get started.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Damon Gettier</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’ve been putting off making final touches to your home before listing it on the market, there’s no better time than now to get started.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Roanoke, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Unexpected Costs of Buying a Home, Part 5: Homeowners Insurance</title>
        <link>http://damongettierblog.com/the-unexpected-costs-of-buying-a-home-part-5-homeowners-insurance.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Damon Gettier</author>
        <pubDate>2018-02-01 09:01:51 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/+Videos+/2018/February/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+Unexpected+Costs+of+Buying+a+Home%252C+Part+5-+Homeowners+Insurance.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What is homeowners insurance? Why should you consider obtaining it when purchasing a home?

Homeowners insurance is something that’s required by the lender. If you get a loan to purchase a house, the lender will require that you insure their asset.

When you obtain homeowners insurance, you want to make sure of a couple of things. First, you want to make sure it covers the structure of the house—not just what you pay for it, but what it would cost for you to rebuild it. You also need to make sure it covers the contents of the house. Just because the TV you bought four years ago is now worth $100 doesn’t mean you can replace it for $100, so make sure you get replacements costs.

“There’s nothing that will fix a flooded house if you don’t have flood insurance.”

Another thing to consider is if you’re buying in an area that requires flood insurance. Flood insurance is required in flood zone AE areas, but it’s not required in zone X areas. If you look at what happened in Houston last year and West Virginia the year before, those areas didn’t require flood insurance—they were flood zone X areas.

Living in flood zone X areas doesn’t cost nearly as much as living in flood zone AE areas, but I still recommend getting flood insurance. Remember—insurance is not for the expected. If we woke up one day and knew our car was going to crash, we wouldn’t drive it that day. We have insurance to be insured against the unexpected.

There’s nothing that will fix a flooded house if you don’t have flood insurance. Those funds will have to come out of your back pocket, and most people don’t have an extra $100,000 or $200,000 lying around to repair a house that’s been destroyed by a flood.

If you have any questions about homeowners insurance or any other unexpected costs when buying a home, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/+Videos+/2018/February/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+Unexpected+Costs+of+Buying+a+Home%252C+Part+5-+Homeowners+Insurance.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://damongettierblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/+Videos+/2018/February/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+Unexpected+Costs+of+Buying+a+Home%252C+Part+5-+Homeowners+Insurance.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you get a loan to purchase a house, the lender will require that you insure their asset with homeowners insurance, and it’s very much in your best interest to get it.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Damon Gettier</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you get a loan to purchase a house, the lender will require that you insure their asset with homeowners insurance, and it’s very much in your best interest to get it.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Roanoke, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What to Do With Excess Paper in Your Home</title>
        <link>http://damongettierblog.com/what-to-do-with-excess-paper-in-your-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Damon Gettier</author>
        <pubDate>2018-01-19 05:59:13 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/+Videos+/2018/January/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+to+Do+With+Excess+Paper+in+Your+Home.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today, I’d like to return to our series on things to do when selling your home. This time, let’s talk about paper.

For some reason, many people feel the need to save away every little piece of paper they come across. Really, there’s only a couple of things you need to keep. Tax returns, bank statements, and some bills are essentially all you need to hold onto.

Unless it’s something like a birth certificate, wedding certificate, or another important document, you only need to keep most old mail and records for about three years. After that time, it’s usually okay to throw some things away.

“Unnecessary paper can really be the Achilles’ heel of a home you’re preparing to sell.”

When you do get rid of important papers, though, don’t just toss them. Make sure you shred anything that could have your personal information on it. If you don’t own a shredder, there are many places you can have this done. You can even come down to my office if you need something shredded badly and don’t know where else to go.

The bottom line is this: get rid of unnecessary paper when you clean your home. Most of it isn’t important to keep, is a fire hazard, and is just taking up space. Paper causes a lot of clutter. It can really be the Achilles’ heel of a home you’re preparing to sell.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/+Videos+/2018/January/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+to+Do+With+Excess+Paper+in+Your+Home.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://damongettierblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/+Videos+/2018/January/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+to+Do+With+Excess+Paper+in+Your+Home.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>In today’s installment in the things you must do when selling your home, I’d like to talk about paper.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Damon Gettier</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>In today’s installment in the things you must do when selling your home, I’d like to talk about paper.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Roanoke, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Unexpected Buying Costs: Utilities</title>
        <link>http://damongettierblog.com/unexpected-buying-costs-utilities.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Damon Gettier</author>
        <pubDate>2018-01-04 08:48:15 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/+Videos+/2017/January/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Unexpected+Buying+Costs-+Utilities.mp4</guid>
        <description>

As I’ve mentioned in the past, unexpected costs can arise during any home purchase. Today, I’d like to go over one type of cost in particular: utilities.

If you were renting a property before you made your home purchase, things like your water or heat may have been included. However, as a homeowner, these costs must be accounted for.

“When submitting an offer on a home, I highly encourage buyers to ask the property’s current owners about average monthly utility costs.”

One thing I highly encourage is for buyers to ask the home’s current owners about average monthly utility costs. These numbers won’t be ironclad, but they will help you understand what you should expect.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/+Videos+/2017/January/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Unexpected+Buying+Costs-+Utilities.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://damongettierblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/+Videos+/2017/January/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Unexpected+Buying+Costs-+Utilities.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I’m back with another unexpected cost for homebuyers to factor in when making their purchase.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Damon Gettier</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I’m back with another unexpected cost for homebuyers to factor in when making their purchase.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Roanoke, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Smarter Way to Pack Up Your Belongings</title>
        <link>http://damongettierblog.com/a-smarter-way-to-pack-up-your-belongings.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Damon Gettier</author>
        <pubDate>2017-12-20 07:19:14 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/+Videos+/2017/December/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+Smarter+Way+to+Pack+Up+Your+Belongings.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I’m back with part three of our series on selling your home. Today I’d like to discuss the benefits of using clear plastic bins to store your belongings as opposed to cardboard boxes.Not only are cardboard boxes fire hazards, insect attractors, and susceptible to mice and other rodents, but you can’t see anything either. You have to unpack the whole box just to find one thing. Oftentimes, those boxes don’t get repacked and just end up making a mess.

“It will help make the selling process easier.”

The use of clear plastic bins allows you to see if something is in there right away. Then you can reach in and grab it because you know exactly where it is.Even if you only do it for a few weeks or while you’re selling your home, when you have a highly organized basement or garage with labeled bins like this, it will appear to potential buyers like you’ve been living like that the entire time. It will help make the selling process much easier and enjoyable. It will likely get you a higher price for your home, too.If you have any questions for me at all about selling your home, including where you can find these plastic bins, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/+Videos+/2017/December/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+Smarter+Way+to+Pack+Up+Your+Belongings.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://damongettierblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/+Videos+/2017/December/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+Smarter+Way+to+Pack+Up+Your+Belongings.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Instead of using cardboard boxes to pack, consider clear plastic bins. They are so much easier to use.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Damon Gettier</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Instead of using cardboard boxes to pack, consider clear plastic bins. They are so much easier to use.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Roanoke, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Unexpected Home Purchasing Costs, Part III: Taxes</title>
        <link>http://damongettierblog.com/unexpected-home-purchasing-costs-part-iii-taxes.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Damon Gettier</author>
        <pubDate>2017-12-06 09:28:33 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/+Videos+/2017/December/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Unexpected+Home+Purchasing+Costs%252C+Part+III-+Taxes.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today we’re continuing our series about the unexpected costs of homeownership with a discussion of taxes.

When you buy a house, you are responsible for the property taxes. Most of the time, that’s included in your payment unless you have an arrangement otherwise.

“If you’re not extremely responsible with money, it’s very important that you let the bank escrow your taxes so that you don’t have a huge bill come up that you won’t be able to pay.”

However, usually when you purchase your house, the bank takes money out at closing to establish an escrow account to pay your taxes.

As your taxes increase every year, the money that is required by the mortgage company will increase as well so that they can pay your taxes for you.

If you’re not extremely responsible with money, it’s very important that you let the bank escrow your taxes so that you don’t have a huge bill come up that you won’t be able to pay.

As always, if you have any questions, please feel free to contact me. I’d be glad to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/+Videos+/2017/December/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Unexpected+Home+Purchasing+Costs%252C+Part+III-+Taxes.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://damongettierblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/+Videos+/2017/December/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Unexpected+Home+Purchasing+Costs%252C+Part+III-+Taxes.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>For part three of my series about unexpected costs of homeownership, we’re discussing property taxes.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Damon Gettier</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>For part three of my series about unexpected costs of homeownership, we’re discussing property taxes.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Roanoke, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Don’t Rush When It Comes to Selling Your Home</title>
        <link>http://damongettierblog.com/dont-rush-when-it-comes-to-selling-your-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Damon Gettier</author>
        <pubDate>2017-11-17 05:41:31 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/+Videos+/2017/November/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Dont+Rush+When+It+Comes+to+Selling+Your+Home.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today we’re going to talk about giving yourself time as a seller to get everything prepared to move.

So many people call us wanting to list their house, but they want the sign in their yard the next day. Their house at the time is usually in no way, shape, or form ready to sell.

If you’re going to sell your house and it’s not an emergency—such as a death in the family, or a job change in a different city—I highly encourage you to come meet with us.

“If you’re going to sell your house and it’s not an emergency—such as a death in the family, or a job change in a different city—I highly encourage you to come meet with us.”

We do something called a coming-soon period for two to six weeks. This gives you time to get your house ready for listing. The goal is to present your house in the best possible way that we can. We can’t do that if you need to move in, say, 30 days, when you called us yesterday and expect it to be listed by tomorrow.

Your photos won’t look as good, your house won’t be staged properly, you’ll have items that need to be put into storage, your lawn/landscaping will need to be cleaned up, and so much more.

All those things and more besides will have to be done in order to present your house in its best light, which will get you the most return on the dollar. Few people want a fixer-upper; they want a house that’s move-in ready so they won’t have to do much with it. You’ll get more money for a home that is shown in optimal condition, and it will sell faster as well. Overall, it will be a much more pleasurable selling experience.

If have any questions about coming-soon periods, selling your house, or getting on the market, please feel free to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/+Videos+/2017/November/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Dont+Rush+When+It+Comes+to+Selling+Your+Home.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://damongettierblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/+Videos+/2017/November/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Dont+Rush+When+It+Comes+to+Selling+Your+Home.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Give yourself plenty of time before you list your home. You’ll need to prepare everything to list your home in its best light.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Damon Gettier</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Give yourself plenty of time before you list your home. You’ll need to prepare everything to list your home in its best light.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Roanoke, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Unexpected Home Purchasing Costs, Part II: Maintenance Costs</title>
        <link>http://damongettierblog.com/unexpected-home-purchasing-costs-part-ii-maintenance-costs.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Damon Gettier</author>
        <pubDate>2017-11-02 06:16:50 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/+Videos+/2017/October/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Unexpected+Home+Purchasing+Costs%252C+Part+II-+Maintenance+Costs.mp4</guid>
        <description>

In addition to the costs I mentioned last time, another unexpected cost you need to watch out for is the maintenance for your home.

When you rent a house, you don’t have the same external and internal maintenance duties you have when you buy a house. Of course, you don’t have the tax advantages either.

“When buying a home, budget accordingly.”

When buying a home, you really need to budget accordingly, because nothing in a home lasts forever. One reason we always encourage home warranties among our buyers is that it acts as a maintenance plan for the house.

When buying a house, look at items like the roof, the HVAC unit, and the water heater, because all of these things have expected lifespans. Make sure you plan for the replacement, upkeep, and repair for these items.

If you have any questions about the maintenance costs of purchasing a home, don’t hesitate to give me a call or shoot me an email. I’d be glad to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/+Videos+/2017/October/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Unexpected+Home+Purchasing+Costs%252C+Part+II-+Maintenance+Costs.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://damongettierblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/+Videos+/2017/October/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Unexpected+Home+Purchasing+Costs%252C+Part+II-+Maintenance+Costs.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Maintenance costs are another unexpected expense of purchasing a home that you need to be mindful of.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Damon Gettier</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Maintenance costs are another unexpected expense of purchasing a home that you need to be mindful of.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Roanoke, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What’s the First Step to Take When Selling Your Home?</title>
        <link>http://damongettierblog.com/whats-the-first-step-to-take-when-selling-your-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Damon Gettier</author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-19 10:17:35 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/+Videos+/2017/October/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Whats+the+First+Step+to+Take+When+Selling+Your+Home%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The first task I want to talk about when it comes to things you must do when selling your home is sorting, or how to simplify your moving experience.

There are a couple ways you can do this. One way is to sort stuff into piles. This includes stuff you want to donate, stuff you want to trash, and stuff you want to keep. I generally suggest another way, though, and that way is something I call the “one-year rule.”

The one-year rule goes as follows: If you haven’t used it in the last year and you’re not going to use it in the next year, sell it or get rid of it because it’s cluttering your life. From there, get rid of anything you consider trash. Take it to the dumpster or the landfill. Don’t let your kids or your spouse look at what it is—just get rid of it.

Most people who move are moving up, so if that’s the case for you, then your current house is too small. If your house is too small for you and appears to be too small for you, then it will appear to be too small for the next person, too.

“Renting a storage unit will go a long way in getting your home sold.”

That’s why my second tip is to rent a storage unit and store everything that’s not essential to your day-to-day life inside it. This means removing all your extra clothes from your closets so they look big and roomy, all the storage boxes lying around in the basement or attic, and other stuff like that so there’s plenty of room in the house. Storage units aren’t cheap, but what they can do in terms of getting your home sold is incredible.

I don’t advise getting a pod instead of a storage unit. A pod just tells everyone you ran out of room in the house and what’s leftover is sitting in your driveway.

If you have any questions about getting your house ready to sell, whether that involves staging, sorting, or throwing things away, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/+Videos+/2017/October/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Whats+the+First+Step+to+Take+When+Selling+Your+Home%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://damongettierblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/+Videos+/2017/October/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Whats+the+First+Step+to+Take+When+Selling+Your+Home%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Sorting the things inside your home will start your home sale off right by simplifying your moving experience.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Damon Gettier</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Sorting the things inside your home will start your home sale off right by simplifying your moving experience.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Roanoke, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Unexpected Costs Could Leave You Reeling</title>
        <link>http://damongettierblog.com/unexpected-costs-could-leave-you-reeling.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Damon Gettier</author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-05 15:54:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/+Videos+/2017/October/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Unexpected+Costs+Could+Leave+You+Reeling.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Don’t go into a transaction unprepared. There is a difference between closing costs and the total cost to close, and it could be thousands of dollars.

Want to Sell Your Home? Get the Value of Your Central or Southwest Virginia Home
Looking to Buy a Home? Search All Homes on the MLS

Today we’re going to discuss some of the unexpected costs you may run into when purchasing a home, specifically regarding closing costs.

Closing costs are different from the cost to close. A lot of people think closing costs are everything they’ll need to close on a home.

“THE DIFFERENCE BETWEEN SPECIFIC CLOSING COSTS AND THE TOTAL COST TO CLOSE COULD BE THOUSANDS OF DOLLARS.”

In our area, however, closing costs are strictly defined in the contract, so the difference between specific closing costs and the total cost to close could be thousands of dollars.

Your annual homeowners insurance is not a closing cost—it is a cost to close, as are property taxes. Things like that can run up your cost to close very quickly, so when you’re getting a quote for closing costs, make sure it’s not just for closing costs, but how much money you will actually need in total to be able to close on the home.

If you need any information about this or other topics, please feel free to contact us.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/+Videos+/2017/October/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Unexpected+Costs+Could+Leave+You+Reeling.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://damongettierblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/+Videos+/2017/October/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Unexpected+Costs+Could+Leave+You+Reeling.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Don’t go into a transaction unprepared. There is a difference between closing costs and the total cost to close, and it could be thousands of dollars.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Damon Gettier</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Don’t go into a transaction unprepared. There is a difference between closing costs and the total cost to close, and it could be thousands of dollars.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Roanoke, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Do Speedy Visits Spell Disinterest for Your House?</title>
        <link>http://damongettierblog.com/do-speedy-visits-spell-disinterest-for.html</link>
        
          <category>Tips for Sellers</category>
        
        <author>Damon Gettier</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-09 14:04:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/+Videos+/2017/August/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Do+Speedy+Visits+Spell+Disinterest+for+Your+House%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If a buyer makes a speedy visit to your house, they’re probably not interested in it. Here’s why.

Want to Sell Your Home? Get the Value of Your Central or Southwest Virginia Home
Looking to Buy a Home? Search All Homes on the MLS

If a prospective buyer zips in and out of your house, they’re probably not a serious buyer—at least not for your house.

There are a variety of reasons why a buyer would make a speedy visit. Maybe when they drove up to your home, they didn’t like the landscaping, the exterior, or just the neighborhood in general. Perhaps when they walked into the house there was a smell or odor they didn’t like. Maybe it just wasn’t the right house for them.

“A SPEEDY VISIT MEANS THAT BUYER PROBABLY ISN’T INTERESTED IN YOUR HOUSE.”

A serious buyer, on the other hand, will stop and envision themselves in your house. They’ll take the time to imagine where their furniture would go and mentally pick out rooms for their children.

It’s very rare that a buyer zips in and out of your house and then comes back to make an offer on it. If they make a speedy visit, you pretty much have your answer whether they’re interested in your house or not.

If you have any questions about speedy visits or you’re thinking of buying or selling a house in our Roanoke market, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to work with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/+Videos+/2017/August/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Do+Speedy+Visits+Spell+Disinterest+for+Your+House%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://damongettierblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/+Videos+/2017/August/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Do+Speedy+Visits+Spell+Disinterest+for+Your+House%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If a buyer makes a speedy visit to your house, they’re probably not interested in it. Here’s why.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Damon Gettier</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If a buyer makes a speedy visit to your house, they’re probably not interested in it. Here’s why.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Roanoke, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Type of Loans Exist for Renovations?</title>
        <link>http://damongettierblog.com/what-type-of-loans-exist-for-renovations.html</link>
        
          <category>Renovations</category>
        
        <author>Damon Gettier</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-09 14:04:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/+Videos+/2017/August/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+Type+of+Loans+Exist+for+Renovations%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Are there any loan options for home renovations out there? There are two, but one is better than the other.

Want to Sell Your Home? Get the Value of Your Central or Southwest Virginia Home
Looking to Buy a Home? Search All Homes on the MLS

There are two types of loans that you can get to help fund your renovation project: the FHA loan and conventional loan.

The conventional loan is the more difficult of the two to get approved for. You need more money down than the other one, and we don’t use that one very often for renovation projects.

The FHA 203K loan has two different options, depending on the size of your renovation project. There’s a streamlined loan that is for repairs that are $30,000 or less and a full FHA 203k that is for as much as you need, as long as the house appraises as repaired.

“ON A FULL FHA LOAN, YOU CAN DO WHATEVER YOU WOULD LIKE TO THE HOME, AS LONG AS IT APPRAISES.”

When you apply for the loan, you need to have two separate contractors come out to the house and write a bid for the repairs that they see that need to be done. These two bids need to match—not on the dollar amount but on what needs to be done to the home. Those bids are then sent to the lender so they can approach for the requested amount.

For the streamlined FHA loan, those repairs can only go up to $30,000 and can’t be on anything structural, so no walls can be knocked out or rooms added. On a full FHA loan, you can do whatever you would like to the home—add or take out walls, add a new master bedroom or bathroom—as long as the house appraises with those items included and it’s under the lending limit, which in our area is $271,000.

If you have any questions about renovation loans, feel free to give me a call. I’d be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/+Videos+/2017/August/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+Type+of+Loans+Exist+for+Renovations%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://damongettierblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/+Videos+/2017/August/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+Type+of+Loans+Exist+for+Renovations%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Are there any loan options for home renovations out there? There are two, but one is better than the other.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Damon Gettier</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Are there any loan options for home renovations out there? There are two, but one is better than the other.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Roanoke, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Do Open Houses Really Work?</title>
        <link>http://damongettierblog.com/do-open-houses-really-work.html</link>
        
          <category>Open House</category>
        
        <author>Damon Gettier</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-25 11:39:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/+Videos+/2017/July/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Do+Open+Houses+Really+Work%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There are a few things you need to know about open houses, and whether they are truly worth it.

Want to Sell Your Home? Get the Value of Your Central or Southwest Virginia Home
Looking to Buy a Home? Search All Homes on the MLS

A question my team and I often get is, “What happens when my agent meets a buyer at my open house?”

The first thing to know is that nationally, less than 7% of open houses sell. In fact, the purpose of an open house is not typically to sell. The point is to acquire buyers.

To tell the truth, open houses don’t work as well now as they used to for one simple reason: the internet. Most people find a large portion of their information about a given home online.

With things like the floor plan, 3D images, and videos available, physically visiting the home often doesn’t come until the point where a buyer is fairly serious about making an offer.

“DON’T PUT TOO MUCH STOCK IN THE BUYERS WHO SHOW UP TO AN OPEN HOUSE.”

But where they lack in successful selling power, open houses are still effective in attracting buyers.

Along with those buyers, though, an open house can also draw out a lot of nosy neighbors.

So if your agent does do an open house, don’t put too much stock in the buyers who show up there.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/+Videos+/2017/July/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Do+Open+Houses+Really+Work%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://damongettierblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/+Videos+/2017/July/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Do+Open+Houses+Really+Work%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

There are a few things you need to know about open houses, and whether they are truly worth it.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Damon Gettier</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

There are a few things you need to know about open houses, and whether they are truly worth it.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Roanoke, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Should You Bring an Architect in on a Home Inspection?</title>
        <link>http://damongettierblog.com/should-you-bring-architect-in-on-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Inspections</category>
        
        <author>Damon Gettier</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-05 15:11:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Can you bring an architect or engineer with you to a home inspection? When should you do that?

Want to Sell Your Home? Get the Value of Your Central or Southwest Virginia Home
Looking to Buy a Home? Search All Homes on the MLS

Lately, a lot of homebuyers have asked me, “Can I bring an architect or engineer with me on a home inspection? Should I make the house purchase subject to an architectural review or have an engineer look at it?”

If you really want to talk to an engineer or architect, the only way you can ask is to write it into the contract. Make the offer subject to an architect or engineer reviewing the home plans. Your agent will help you with the exact language.

“IF YOU PLAN ON DOING A HUGE REMODEL, IT’S A GOOD IDEA TO BRING IN AN ENGINEER.”

You don’t always need an engineer to look at a home before you buy it. If you are buying a house and you want to blow out the walls and open up the floor plan, then it would be a good idea to have an architect or engineer check the property. They will let you know which walls are load-bearing, and then you can make an educated buying decision.

The worst thing you can do is buy a house, blow out the wrong wall, and have the house implode on you.

If you have any other questions about buying a home or the home inspection process, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://damongettierblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Can you bring an architect or engineer with you to a home inspection? When should you do that?

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Damon Gettier</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Can you bring an architect or engineer with you to a home inspection? When should you do that?

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Roanoke, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>When to Take a Buyer Seriously in This Market</title>
        <link>http://damongettierblog.com/when-to-take-buyer-seriously-in-this.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Damon Gettier</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-16 15:33:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+spot+a+strong+buyer.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When someone says they are just beginning their home search, they could mean a number of different things. Here’s a better question to ask a buyer.

Want to Sell Your Home? Get the Value of Your Central or Southwest Virginia Home
Looking to Buy a Home? Search All Homes on the MLS

What does it mean when someone says they are “just starting” their home search? Well, it can mean a lot of things. Your home may actually be the first home they have looked at, or it could be the 50th. There’s a better way to tell if a buyer is serious about buying a home or not.

If the buyer you talk to is pre-approved for a mortgage and working with a real estate agent, I would take them very seriously. They could give you your highest offer and if nothing else, they will give you good feedback about your home so you can improve it for the next buyer who comes through.

“SERIOUS BUYERS WORK WITH AN AGENT.”

If the buyer you talk to isn’t working with an agent, doesn’t have a pre-approval, and is just beginning their search, I wouldn’t take them as seriously. It’s likely they wouldn’t be able to make a strong offer anyway.

If you have any questions for me about selling your home or anything else related to real estate, give me a call or send me an email. We look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+spot+a+strong+buyer.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://damongettierblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+spot+a+strong+buyer.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

When someone says they are just beginning their home search, they could mean a number of different things. Here’s a better question to ask a buyer.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Damon Gettier</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

When someone says they are just beginning their home search, they could mean a number of different things. Here’s a better question to ask a buyer.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Roanoke, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Should You Get an Inspection Before Making Renovations?</title>
        <link>http://damongettierblog.com/should-you-get-inspection-before-making.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Damon Gettier</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-30 13:08:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Do+renovations+warrant+a+home+inspection%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Getting a home inspection offers many benefits if you’re thinking of buying an as-is property and making renovations to it.

Want to Sell Your Home? Get the Value of Your Central or Southwest Virginia Home
Looking to Buy a Home? Search All Homes on the MLS

If you’re thinking about buying an as-is property and making some renovations, do you need an inspection?

Absolutely. We always suggest getting a home inspection, especially if you plan on doing a renovation. It gives you a starting point of things you need to fix. Otherwise you might ask your contractor to make certain fixes without even knowing about other fixes that could be huge issues if left unresolved.

“A HOME INSPECTION GIVES YOU A STARTING POINT FOR YOUR RENOVATIONS.”

Getting a home inspection also means you can give it to your contractor and include both your ‘have-to’ fixes and your ‘want-to’ fixes’ so when you get a bid, you get a complete bid.

If you have any more questions about renovations, home improvements, contractors, or anything else of that nature, feel free to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Do+renovations+warrant+a+home+inspection%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://damongettierblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Do+renovations+warrant+a+home+inspection%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Getting a home inspection offers many benefits if you’re thinking of buying an as-is property and making renovations to it.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Damon Gettier</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Getting a home inspection offers many benefits if you’re thinking of buying an as-is property and making renovations to it.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Roanoke, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Should You Be Wary of Solo Buyers?</title>
        <link>http://damongettierblog.com/why-should-you-be-wary-of-solo-buyers.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Damon Gettier</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-16 11:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+solo+buyer+is+almost+unheard+of.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Beware of solo buyers. If they don’t have an agent representing them, they probably don’t know what they’re doing.

Want to Sell Your Home? Get the Value of Your Central or Southwest Virginia Home
Looking to Buy a Home? Search All Homes on the MLS

Why should you be hesitant to trust a solo buyer? There are a number of different reasons, but let me start with this. A solo buyer could be anyone. You don’t know whether they are qualified, whether they want to buy now or later, or whether they can even afford what they’re looking at.

If someone is actually serious about buying a home in this market, they will hire an agent. I can’t ever recall seeing a serious or committed buyer who hasn’t worked with one. It’s like treating yourself instead of letting a doctor do it.

“SERIOUS BUYERS HIRE AN AGENT.”

Whenever a buyer who isn’t working with an agent comes to your house, don’t take it too seriously. They probably aren’t a serious buyer.

If you have any questions for me about real estate or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home, give me a call or send me an email today. I would love to hear from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+solo+buyer+is+almost+unheard+of.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://damongettierblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+solo+buyer+is+almost+unheard+of.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Beware of solo buyers. If they don’t have an agent representing them, they probably don’t know what they’re doing.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Damon Gettier</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Beware of solo buyers. If they don’t have an agent representing them, they probably don’t know what they’re doing.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Roanoke, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>When Is the Right Time to Renovate Your Home?</title>
        <link>http://damongettierblog.com/when-is-right-time-to-renovate-your-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Damon Gettier</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-21 14:58:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+When+is+the+right+time+to+renovate%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’re thinking about renovating, when should you do it? Here’s what we recommend.

Want to Sell Your Home? Get the Value of Your Central or Southwest Virginia Home
Looking to Buy a Home? Search All Homes on the MLS

Many people think they need to renovate their house. How do you know if that’s the right choice or when the right time to do it is?

My suggestion is that if you are going to renovate, do it when you buy the house. Contrary to what you see on TV or read in magazines, you don’t get your $10,000 you spend on the kitchen back. You might get it back five or 10 years from now as the house appreciates, but renovations won’t bring you an instant dollar-for-dollar return.

“RENOVATING EARLY MAKES YOUR HOME MORE SELLABLE.”

We also recommend renovating when you move in rather than when you move out because you at least get to enjoy your renovations. It also makes the house much more sellable for a Realtor when the time comes.

If you have any questions about renovations or homes in general here in the Roanoke market, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I’d be happy to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+When+is+the+right+time+to+renovate%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://damongettierblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+When+is+the+right+time+to+renovate%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you’re thinking about renovating, when should you do it? Here’s what we recommend.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Damon Gettier</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you’re thinking about renovating, when should you do it? Here’s what we recommend.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Roanoke, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Need to Give a Spare Room a Purpose?</title>
        <link>http://damongettierblog.com/need-to-give-spare-room-purpose-put-bed.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Damon Gettier</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-03 13:06:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Real+Estate/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Got+a+useless+room%253F+Heres+your+solution.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I’m going to tell you the best way to give an empty room a purpose when selling your home.

Want to Sell Your Home? Get the Value of Your Central or Southwest Virginia Home
Looking to Buy a Home? Search All Homes on the MLS

When selling your home, the last thing you want to show is a room that appears to have no use. I have the perfect solution to share with you today.

So what can you do with a spare room? Put a bed in it. It’s that simple. Putting a bed in a spare room will make it look occupied and lived in. It doesn’t matter what floor the spare room is on or if it has windows. Put a bed in it. That’s the best way to give an empty room a purpose and you’ll have the use of a guest room in the meantime.

“PUT A BED IN IT. IT’S THAT SIMPLE”

Questions about staging? Reach out to me. I can answer any questions you may have about preparing to show your home. If you have any other questions, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Real+Estate/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Got+a+useless+room%253F+Heres+your+solution.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://damongettierblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Real+Estate/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Got+a+useless+room%253F+Heres+your+solution.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today I’m going to tell you the best way to give an empty room a purpose when selling your home.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Damon Gettier</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today I’m going to tell you the best way to give an empty room a purpose when selling your home.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Roanoke, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Is the Home Inspector Really Working for You? </title>
        <link>http://damongettierblog.com/is-home-inspector-really-working-for-you.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Damon Gettier</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-13 16:10:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Can+you+trust+the+home+inspector%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Do home inspectors work for the buyer or the seller? The answer really depends on one simple thing.

Want to Sell Your Home? Get the Value of Your Central or Southwest Virginia Home
Looking to Buy a Home? Search All Homes on the MLS

Who does the home inspector work for, the homebuyer or the seller?

The answer is really very simple. The home inspector works for whoever pays them.

So, if you negotiate for the seller to pay for the home inspection, then the home inspector will work for the seller and look out for their needs. It all boils down to who writes the check for the home inspector.

When you buy a home, I highly recommend that you hire the home inspector, radon inspector, water test company, and termite inspector. After all, once you own the home, you are responsible for any issues.

“PAY EXTRA ATTENTION TO THE TERMITE INSPECTION.”

You should pay extra attention to the termite inspection. Remember, not all termite inspectors are created equal. If you buy a house, do you want any termite inspector or the best termite inspector? We recommend Brad Killinger from Killinger Pest Inspections. He is an honest inspector, which is exactly what you want: someone who will honestly tell you about any problems in the home.

If you need any recommendations for other home inspections or if you have any real estate questions, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Can+you+trust+the+home+inspector%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://damongettierblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Can+you+trust+the+home+inspector%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Do home inspectors work for the buyer or the seller? The answer really depends on one simple thing.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Damon Gettier</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Do home inspectors work for the buyer or the seller? The answer really depends on one simple thing.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Roanoke, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Does Refreshing Your Linens Help Sell Your Home? </title>
        <link>http://damongettierblog.com/how-does-refreshing-your-linens-help.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Damon Gettier</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-28 15:26:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Make+sure+you+refresh+your+linens.mp4</guid>
        <description>

In order to sell your home faster and for more money, make sure you take care of one simple thing: refreshing the linens.

Want to Sell Your Home? Get the Value of Your Central or Southwest Virginia Home
Looking to Buy a Home? Search All Homes on the MLS

If you are thinking of selling your home, I recommend that you refresh your linens. Why?

The simple reason is that old linens do not show well. If you have an old, worn bedspread that has a burned spot from an old ironing accident, buyers will think that you can’t take care of your home.

In fact, I walked into a house the other day where the drapes matched the wallpaper, which matched the bedspread, which matched the throw rugs. The entire room looked like one big ivy vine because every surface was covered with the same print.

“YOU NEED TO HAVE CLASSY, FRESH LINENS IN YOUR HOME.”

You need to have classy, clean, fresh linens in your home. If you don’t want to get rid of your old, comfortable bedspread, simply put the new one on top of it when you prepare to sell your home. Doing so will position your house to sell faster and for more money.

You want people to feel like they could live in your house. They need to be comfortable in your house and every room needs to be fresh and clean.

If you have any other questions about staging your home or about real estate in general, give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Make+sure+you+refresh+your+linens.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://damongettierblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Make+sure+you+refresh+your+linens.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

In order to sell your home faster and for more money, make sure you take care of one simple thing: refreshing the linens.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Damon Gettier</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

In order to sell your home faster and for more money, make sure you take care of one simple thing: refreshing the linens.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Roanoke, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Choose the Right Home Inspector </title>
        <link>http://damongettierblog.com/how-to-choose-right-home-inspector.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Damon Gettier</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-10 13:21:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Real+Estate/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+You+Should+Always+Price+to+Sell.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you need to order a home inspection, it’s important you pick the right home inspector. Here’s how.

Want to Sell Your Home? Get the Value of Your Central or Southwest Virginia Home
Looking to Buy a Home? Search All Homes on the MLS

A home inspection is an essential part of any home sale, so I want to go over some things you should be aware of when ordering one.

Many people are curious as to who chooses the home inspector. The answer is you. I would recommend, before hiring the inspector, that you call them and ask them questions about what they check and what their process is like when inspecting a home.

“NOT ALL HOME INSPECTORS ARE CREATED EQUAL.”

Do they actually get on the roof? Do they have a septic or sewer camera? Do they do thermal imaging? If there is anything that you are concerned about or want to know if they can do, you need to ask them if they do it. Never just assume they can and will do something for you.

Not all home inspectors are created equal. Just make sure you pick the one that works best for you.

If you have any questions please feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I’m always happy to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Real+Estate/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+You+Should+Always+Price+to+Sell.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://damongettierblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Real+Estate/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+You+Should+Always+Price+to+Sell.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you need to order a home inspection, it’s important you pick the right home inspector. Here’s how.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Damon Gettier</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you need to order a home inspection, it’s important you pick the right home inspector. Here’s how.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Roanoke, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Focus on the Bed When Selling Your Home?</title>
        <link>http://damongettierblog.com/why-focus-on-bed-when-selling-your-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Damon Gettier</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-26 13:48:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Beware+of+big+beds+in+small+rooms.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Bedrooms are one of the most important rooms for potential buyers to see. Here’s a tip to stage your bedroom properly.

Want to Sell Your Home? Get the Value of Your Central or Southwest Virginia Home
Looking to Buy a Home? Search All Homes on the MLS

The two things people look at first in a home are the kitchen and bedrooms. So how can you make your bedroom look more appealing to potential buyers?

If you’re selling, the most important thing to remember about your bedrooms is to have the proper size bed in them. Oftentimes, we go into a house with a regular sized bedroom that has a king bed in it. Frankly, I don’t even know how they got it in there. It may be how you want to live, but you don’t want the buyer to think that the room is too small. That’s what an oversized bed does.

“IN MOST HOUSES, A QUEEN BED IS THE LARGEST YOU SHOULD GO.”

In most standard houses, a queen bed is usually as large as you should go. If you can’t walk on either side of the bed comfortably, you probably don’t need a king bed in there. If you have a trunk or bench at the end of your bed for storage, make sure that’s an appropriate size as well.

If you have any questions for us about staging bedrooms or anything else related to real estate, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Beware+of+big+beds+in+small+rooms.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://damongettierblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Beware+of+big+beds+in+small+rooms.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Bedrooms are one of the most important rooms for potential buyers to see. Here’s a tip to stage your bedroom properly.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Damon Gettier</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Bedrooms are one of the most important rooms for potential buyers to see. Here’s a tip to stage your bedroom properly.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Roanoke, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Do You Actually Get from a Home Inspection?</title>
        <link>http://damongettierblog.com/what-do-you-actually-get-from-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buying Tips</category>
        
        <author>Damon Gettier</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-09 14:19:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Real+Estate/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+do+you+really+get+with+an+inspection%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Not many home buyers seem to truly understand what you get with a home inspection, so today, I wanted to clarify the possible outcomes of such inspections.

Want to Sell Your Home? Get the Value of Your Central or Southwest Virginia Home
Looking to Buy a Home? Search All Homes on the MLS

When it comes to home inspections, one of the most common misconceptions is that they cover only a basic inspection.

Home inspections are designed to give you a report card on your house. In the grand scheme of things, it outlines everything a home inspector can find during a three- to four-hour window. They won’t find everything, but they will find more than just the basics.

An inspector will look at the systems, appliances, and HVAC, to name a few. Their job is to give you a good report card of your house, because not all these items will be covered by the contract, and not all these things will be repaired by the contract. Instead, you’ll get a good list of things to work on in the house. Remember, when you buy a house, you buy a used house; it’s going to have issues.

“THE INSPECTOR’S JOB IS TO GIVE YOU A GOOD REPORT CARD OF YOUR HOUSE.”

The good news is that you’ll get a really good report up front to know what’s wrong with it.

If you have any questions about home inspections and what you get from them, or you’re ready to buy or sell a home in the Roanoke market, give me a call or send me an email. I’d be happy to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Real+Estate/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+do+you+really+get+with+an+inspection%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://damongettierblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Real+Estate/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+do+you+really+get+with+an+inspection%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Not many home buyers seem to truly understand what you get with a home inspection, so today, I wanted to clarify the possible outcomes of such inspections.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Damon Gettier</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Not many home buyers seem to truly understand what you get with a home inspection, so today, I wanted to clarify the possible outcomes of such inspections.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Roanoke, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Keep Your Rooms Simple When Selling</title>
        <link>http://damongettierblog.com/why-should-you-ditch-multi-purpose-room.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Damon Gettier</author>
        <pubDate>2016-12-16 12:32:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+tip+for+properly+staging+your+home.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When you are getting ready to sell, staging is an important step. One thing you should do is turn that home gym back into a bedroom.

Want to Sell Your Home? Get the Value of Your Central or Southwest Virginia Home
Looking to Buy a Home? Search All Homes on the MLS

When you sell your home, there are a lot of important things to keep in mind. One of these is keeping your rooms single-use.

Let’s say you have an extra bedroom that you put an exercise bike and TV in. That’s perfectly fine to do when living in the home if you have the room. However, you don’t want the buyer to think there’s not enough space for them.

So take the exercise bike and TV out of that bedroom. Open it up and make it more inviting. If you have a room that has a desk that you work from home on, get that out of there too. To buyers, it looks like you don’t have enough room in your house.

“HOME INSPECTIONS ARE THERE TO INVESTIGATE ANY MAJOR ISSUES IN THE HOUSE.”

I really like to stress keeping rooms for their desired intention. A kitchen is a kitchen, a bathroom is a bathroom, and a bedroom is a bedroom. We like to keep things singular in purpose.

If you have any questions for us about staging a home or anything else relating to real estate or selling a home, give me a call or send me an email. I would love to hear from you soon!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+tip+for+properly+staging+your+home.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://damongettierblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+tip+for+properly+staging+your+home.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

When you are getting ready to sell, staging is an important step. One thing you should do is turn that home gym back into a bedroom.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Damon Gettier</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

When you are getting ready to sell, staging is an important step. One thing you should do is turn that home gym back into a bedroom.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Roanoke, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Should You Look for in a Home Inspection?</title>
        <link>http://damongettierblog.com/what-should-you-look-for-in-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buying Tips</category>
        
        <author>Damon Gettier</author>
        <pubDate>2016-12-01 13:55:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Whats+the+deal+with+home+inspections%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

As a buyer, there are only certain things you can ask for in a home inspection and only certain issues a home inspection is supposed to investigate.

Want to Sell Your Home? Get the Value of Your Central or Southwest Virginia Home
Looking to Buy a Home? Search All Homes on the MLS

When people ask us about home inspections, they usually want to know two things:


  What does an inspector look for in a home inspection?
  What can I ask for in a home inspection?


As to what you can ask for in a home inspection, in our contract, a home inspection limits you to asking for material defects. A material defect is defined as “something that would’ve caused a normal buyer not to purchase the home had they known it was there.”.

“HOME INSPECTIONS ARE THERE TO INVESTIGATE ANY MAJOR ISSUES IN THE HOUSE.”

What an inspector looks for during a home inspection is major issues within the house. They’re not looking for any cosmetic issues such as the paint or the wall coverings. If you’re worried about those types of issues, they should be taken care of in the contract. During a home inspection, the key is to look for issues like a leaky roof, any type of plumbing system or electrical setup that’s not safe and functional, and any overarching structural issues.

If you have any more questions about home inspections, feel free to reach out to us by phone or email. We look forward to helping you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Whats+the+deal+with+home+inspections%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://damongettierblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Whats+the+deal+with+home+inspections%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

As a buyer, there are only certain things you can ask for in a home inspection and only certain issues a home inspection is supposed to investigate.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Damon Gettier</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

As a buyer, there are only certain things you can ask for in a home inspection and only certain issues a home inspection is supposed to investigate.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Roanoke, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Can Landscaping Do for the Value of Your Property?</title>
        <link>http://damongettierblog.com/what-can-landscaping-do-for-value-of.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Damon Gettier</author>
        <pubDate>2016-11-03 10:46:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Real+Estate/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Can+landscaping+add+value+to+your+property%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you want to get your house sold quickly and for top dollar, you need to invest in it by focusing on the landscaping.

Want to Sell Your Home? Get the Value of Your Central or Southwest Virginia Home
Looking to Buy a Home? Search All Homes on the MLS

Does landscaping increase your home’s value? Absolutely.

Let’s say someone wants to sell their $6,000 used car. The first thing they’re going to do is get it detailed, right? It’s perfectly conceivable that they’ll spend as much as $300 for that detail. That’s 5% of the car’s overall value.

Unfortunately, people who are trying to sell their house don’t carry this same mindset when it comes to landscaping, even though their house might be worth hundreds of thousands of dollars. You need to invest in your home to get it sold for top dollar. How do you do that? You do that by giving it instant curb appeal.

“YOU NEED TO INVEST IN YOUR HOME TO GET IT SOLD FOR TOP DOLLAR.”

Houses generate more offers and sell faster when the curb appeal is there. When looking at a property, not many people get excited about the prospect of needing to spend $4,000 or $5,000 over the course of two or three years just to get the front yard looking right.

If you want to sell your house for its maximum value, you need to position it properly. Spend some money on the landscaping to upgrade the curb appeal so it makes the right impression on potential buyers. That way, they’ll be more eager to move forward. You may even get multiple offers.

If you have any questions about increasing your home’s value or about the Roanoke market, give me a call or send me an email. I’d be happy to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Real+Estate/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Can+landscaping+add+value+to+your+property%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://damongettierblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Real+Estate/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Can+landscaping+add+value+to+your+property%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you want to get your house sold quickly and for top dollar, you need to invest in it by focusing on the landscaping.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Damon Gettier</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you want to get your house sold quickly and for top dollar, you need to invest in it by focusing on the landscaping.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Roanoke, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What You Need to Know About Inspections</title>
        <link>http://damongettierblog.com/what-you-need-to-know-about-inspections.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buying Tips</category>
        
        <author>Damon Gettier</author>
        <pubDate>2016-10-21 14:28:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+pick+an+inspector+when+the+time+comes.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’re buying a home at any point, you’ll have to deal with a home inspection. So who chooses the inspector? What do they look for? How do you know if they’re right for you?

Want to Sell Your Home? Get the Value of Your Central or Southwest Virginia Home
Looking to Buy a Home? Search All Homes on the MLS

There are some important things you need to know about a home inspection. If you’ve ever bought or sold a home or you plan on buying a home at any point in the future, you’ll deal with an inspector at some point.

So who chooses the home inspector? It’s simple–you do. I highly suggest that before choosing one, you call them and ask them some questions. You want to ask what they will check, whether they will actually get on your roof and check it, whether they have a septic or sewer camera, whether they do thermal imaging, etc. You need to ask them whether they will look at something you’re concerned about; don’t just assume they’ll do it.

“DON’T JUST ASSUME THEY’LL INSPECT EVERYTHING YOU’RE WORRIED ABOUT.”

Not all home inspectors are created equal, just like not all real estate agents are created equal. Since it’s your right to pick your home inspector, you need to pick the one that’s right for you.

If you have any other questions about home inspectors or how to choose the right one for your specific situation, give me a call. I’d be happy to walk you through it.

Additionally, if you or anyone you know is thinking about buying or selling a home in the Roanoke area, give me a call or send me an email. I’d love to work with you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+pick+an+inspector+when+the+time+comes.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://damongettierblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+pick+an+inspector+when+the+time+comes.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you’re buying a home at any point, you’ll have to deal with a home inspection. So who chooses the inspector? What do they look for? How do you know if they’re right for you?

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Damon Gettier</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you’re buying a home at any point, you’ll have to deal with a home inspection. So who chooses the inspector? What do they look for? How do you know if they’re right for you?

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Roanoke, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Damon Gettier</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Damon Gettier</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Damon Gettier & Associates - your professional Roanoke Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
