<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Becky Ivins Movers Real Estate Podcast</title>
    <link>http://beckyivinsblog.com</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://beckyivinsblog.com"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Beck Ivins Movers Real Estate - your professional Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Beck Ivins</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2018-01-16 12:31:05 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Beck Ivins</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://i.imgur.com/9EiKtTI.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Oklahoma City, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>becky@beckyivins.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Beck Ivins</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Beck Ivins</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://i.imgur.com/9EiKtTI.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Oklahoma City, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Oklahoma City Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Beck Ivins Movers Real Estate - your professional Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tracking Buyer Activity for Your Home</title>
        <link>http://beckyivinsblog.com/tracking-buyer-activity-for-your-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Beck Ivins</author>
        <pubDate>2017-12-29 07:21:50 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

How do you know whether or not your house is getting enough activity while it’s on the market?

There are many different types of activity. As your real estate professional, it’s important to me to track the different kinds of activity on your home. I am basically the marketing firm for your property, and I will tell you about the activity on your home.

For example, if I’m seeing good activity on your house on different websites, then I need to tell you about that. I may say, “Your home was viewed 36 times on Trulia this week, and seven of them stayed on and looked at every single picture.” A good real estate agent will give you that information.

Another important activity marker is the number of buyers who drive by to look at your property. This number can be a little harder to judge, but we keep track by placing a brochure in front of the home. If someone is interested in your home, they’ll pick up a brochure. Then we can judge how many people are driving by your home based on the number of brochures that are missing.

We also have an 800 number on those property brochures in order to track the number of times someone calls to listen to the recording for that property. We can see how many calls we got, and how many of those calls for the same number. Someone might call a number of times to share the description of the house they want to make an appointment for with their spouse or family members.

“We will tell you what buyers say about your property after each showing.”

Having advertised sources of activity and knowing where the activity is coming from is extremely important to me as the marketer of your home, and that information should be relayed to you as the consumer.

You need to know whether or not your house is being marketed properly.

Another way to track buyer activity is through showings. Sometimes, people schedule showing appointments and don’t show up. It’s rude, but it happens. Sometimes buyers find the house of their dreams right before they come to look at your property; it’s nothing personal.We will call you after each showing to tell you if they showed up and what they liked or disliked about the home. They may say something like, “I love this house, but it really smells like cat pee,” or “The house is great, but that backyard will be too much of a hassle to mow.”

We will take that feedback and use it to prepare for your next showing. You may not be able to change the backyard, but you can deep-clean your carpets or even replace them to get rid of unwanted smells.

Your real estate agent should tell you all of the things that other Realtors and buyers say about your house at each showing. A good real estate agent will make sure that happens.

If you have any other questions about selling your home, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://beckyivinsblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>How do you know if your home is getting any activity from prospective buyers? There are a few different ways your agent can track activity.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Beck Ivins</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>How do you know if your home is getting any activity from prospective buyers? There are a few different ways your agent can track activity.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Oklahoma City, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Are You Obligated to Disclose When Selling Your Home?</title>
        <link>http://beckyivinsblog.com/what-are-you-obligated-to-disclose-when-selling-your-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Beck Ivins</author>
        <pubDate>2017-11-27 05:46:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Becky+Ivins/Videos/December/Oklahoma+City+Metro+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Increase+Your+Value.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When you sell a home, what information are you obligated to disclose about your property?

People often seem confused about disclosures in the marketplace, but there is a clear statute that you follow. There is a set form of three pages for every residential property. All you have to do is answer the questions on that list.

Basically, you will confirm whether or not everything is in working order, and whether or not certain items exist on the property.

For example, if you have a swimming pool, you will have to say whether or not it’s in working order. If you don’t have a pool, all you have to do is say you don’t have one. The same is true for natural gas supply. Does natural gas come to the property, or is it a total electric home? Is there an underground storage tank?

There are a number of things on the disclosure list, but it’s not left up to your imagination. It’s a defined list that the state requires all sellers of residential properties to fill out.Additionally, if your home was built before 1978, you will have to fill out another disclosure. The lead-based paint disclosure is required by HUD, by the state, and by the EPA. This form is very simple to fill out. You either have lead-based paint and you know it, or you’re unaware of any lead-based paint in the home.

“The seller disclosure is a defined list of questions about residential properties.”

If your home has never been tested for lead-based paint, then you have no records to disclose.

The seller, the buyer, and the Realtors must all sign the lead-based paint disclosure.

As a qualified real estate professional, I like to go over the forms with the seller as they fill them out. Sometimes, I’ll ask a question and the seller will look uncertain, so I’ll do more research on that.

Other than the seller, your real estate agent should be the most knowledgeable person about the property. I should know whether or not it’s total electric, whether the soft water system is leased or owned, and whether or not the property has any easements other than utility easements.

As the seller, if you have any questions about an item on the form, I always recommend that you err on the side of caution. You want the buyer to know everything about the property that they are entitled to. If the buyer isn’t going to buy your home because there’s been water in the heating and air conditioning ducts, let’s not sell it to that buyer. Let’s find a buyer who knows that you corrected the situation and won’t be afraid to buy your home.

If you have any other questions about seller disclosures or the selling process in general, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Becky+Ivins/Videos/December/Oklahoma+City+Metro+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Increase+Your+Value.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://beckyivinsblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Becky+Ivins/Videos/December/Oklahoma+City+Metro+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Increase+Your+Value.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>As a seller, what information do you have to disclose to potential buyers? I’ll clear up all the confusion around seller disclosures today.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Beck Ivins</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>As a seller, what information do you have to disclose to potential buyers? I’ll clear up all the confusion around seller disclosures today.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Oklahoma City, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>You've Given Us Your Business, So We're Giving You Free Pie</title>
        <link>http://beckyivinsblog.com/youve-given-us-your-business-so-were-giving-you-free-pie.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Beck Ivins</author>
        <pubDate>2017-11-09 05:55:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Becky+Ivins/Videos/NOV/Oklahoma+City+Metro+Real+Estate+Agent-+Let+Us+Provide+the+Pie+This+Thanksgiving.mp4</guid>
        <description>

With Thanksgiving just around the corner, I want to take a moment to let all of my clients know how much my team and I appreciate you. Thanks to your support, referrals, and loyalty, we’ve been able to sell thousands of homes over the past three years.

Now, it’s our time to give back. This Thanksgiving, the pie is on us. That right: we’re giving away free pies.

“This Thanksgiving, the pie is on us.”

All you need to do is fill out the form linked below to order your choice of either apple, pumpkin, or pecan pie by Sunday, November 19th and show up at our office to pick it up between 2pm and 6pm on Tuesday, November 21st. Our office is located at 6905 NW 122nd Street Oklahoma City, OK 73142.

You can place your order here.

Now, my husband Jim graciously offered to bake each and every pie himself. But, to do that, he would’ve needed to start a long time ago. That’s why we’re using a bakery.

If you want to see his attempt, however, you can check out the video above.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Becky+Ivins/Videos/NOV/Oklahoma+City+Metro+Real+Estate+Agent-+Let+Us+Provide+the+Pie+This+Thanksgiving.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://beckyivinsblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Becky+Ivins/Videos/NOV/Oklahoma+City+Metro+Real+Estate+Agent-+Let+Us+Provide+the+Pie+This+Thanksgiving.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>With Thanksgiving just around the corner, I want to take a moment to let all of my clients know how much my team and I appreciate you. To show you we mean it, we’re giving away some free pies.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Beck Ivins</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>With Thanksgiving just around the corner, I want to take a moment to let all of my clients know how much my team and I appreciate you. To show you we mean it, we’re giving away some free pies.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Oklahoma City, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Can You Increase the Value of Your Home?</title>
        <link>http://beckyivinsblog.com/how-can-you-increase-the-value-of-your-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Beck Ivins</author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-12 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

I’ve got a few tips to share with you today that will help you increase your home’s value whether you plan on selling now or at a later date. They include:1. Making a good first impression. Curb appeal matters to buyers. If you have dirty flowerbeds or a broken light fixture on your porch, make sure you get it fixed. You want them to have a great feeling as they are walking up to the door.2. Good smell. A good smell is no smell at all. Nobody likes to be overwhelmed by flowery scents. People always think sellers are hiding something when they do that. No smell is the smell you want to go for. If you have a pet, there are pet odors present that you don’t smell. You’ll want to get those cleaned too. We know the best carpet cleaners around and can refer you to them.

“The best smell is no smell.”

3. Small improvements. The best improvement you can make is one of the cheapest. Fresh paint. Get rid of any scuffs or marks on the wall too, as well as any family pictures. Make sure your home is uncluttered and clean.These are the best ways to get the maximum value out of your home. If you have any questions about this subject or anything else relating to real estate in OKC, give me a call or send me an email. I’m here to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://beckyivinsblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>You can increase your home’s value</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Beck Ivins</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>You can increase your home’s value</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Oklahoma City, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Do You Need Professional Photos to Sell Your Home?</title>
        <link>http://beckyivinsblog.com/do-you-need-professional-photos-to-sell-your-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Beck Ivins</author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-09 19:02:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Becky+Ivins/Videos/Oklahoma+City+Metro+Real+Estate+Agent-+Do+Professional+Photos+Matter%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When listing your home, it’s very important that you use professional photography.

Listed homes that use professional photography typically attract more attention, sell faster, and sell for a higher price than those that don’t. I have a few studies I want to show you that prove this fact.

The first comes from IMOTO, a company that creates professional real estate photography. IMOTO did a study of 350 homes that used professional photography and 350 homes that didn’t, all 700 of which were located in the same zip code. They found that homes that had professional photography sold 50% faster and 39% closer to their original listing price.

The second comes from Latter &amp; Blum Inc., a New Orleans-based real estate agency. They conducted a study that found that homes that used professional photography attracted 118% more views online than comparable listings that didn’t use professional photography.

The last one is an in-house study we conducted right here in our office. I studied the back end of different websites we advertise on because it matters how long someone stays on your listing and reads everything that’s written about it. You can’t sell a home that’s not marketed, and you can’t set an appointment with someone who hasn’t seen your home’s photos. We found that properties on Realtor.com within our zip code that used professional photos were viewed 16x longer than homes that didn’t.

“Photography matters.”

In case you’re wondering, we absolutely use professional photography for our listings.We use three different professional photographers who each specialize in a different style of photography. After all, different-sized properties require different photographs. If you’re listing an acreage with a lake, for example, you need a drone. If you’re listing a smaller property, you’ll need an extremely wide-angle lens to capture its dimensions accurately.

We also use professional photography for a different reason than you might think. We use it to set a showing appointment—not necessarily to sell the house. This is because our goal is to get someone to want to see your house.

Additionally, we recently added something super cool to our arsenal of marketing tools: 3-D imaging. We have a 3-D photographer who creates a virtual floor plan of houses which you can then view them through the same way you’d use Google Maps. This allows you to get an in-depth look at how the property is arranged, and it’s helped us sell a lot of homes.

Lastly, outside photography is also extremely important. You don’t want to set a showing appointment for a property you think is a nice, big brick home only to find out that the front is a facade and the back is made up of rotting wood.

If you have any questions as to how we can show your house in its best light or you have another real estate topic in mind you’d like to discuss with us, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We’d be happy to speak with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Becky+Ivins/Videos/Oklahoma+City+Metro+Real+Estate+Agent-+Do+Professional+Photos+Matter%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://beckyivinsblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Becky+Ivins/Videos/Oklahoma+City+Metro+Real+Estate+Agent-+Do+Professional+Photos+Matter%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Listed homes that use professional photography typically attract more attention, sell faster, and sell for a higher price than those that don’t.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Beck Ivins</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Listed homes that use professional photography typically attract more attention, sell faster, and sell for a higher price than those that don’t.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Oklahoma City, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Win in a Multiple Offer Situation</title>
        <link>http://beckyivinsblog.com/how-to-win-in-a-multiple-offer-situation.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Beck Ivins</author>
        <pubDate>2017-09-07 06:28:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Becky+Ivins/Videos/Oklahoma+City+Metro+Real+Estate+Agent-+Getting+Your+Offer+Accepted.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Not everybody is a competitor. Sometimes in a multiple offer situation, you’ll have people pull out just because they don’t want to compete. If buyers back out, you may not end up in a multiple offer position in the end. But how do you get your offer accepted?

The first thing to do is to look at the value of the property you’re interested in and figure out the highest price you are willing to pay for that property. You want to make sure that you put down a substantial amount of earnest money.

Price rules—and not just your purchase price. Your price at the bottom line rules as well. If you can afford to pay your closing costs instead of asking the seller to pay them, then do that. It’ll put you ahead of other offers that ask for those closing costs to be paid.

“Price rules, but not just the purchase price.”

Closing dates are pretty important. It may not matter to you when your closing is, but it might matter to the seller. If you can, indicate in your offer that the seller can choose the closing date at their convenience.

Make it easy on the seller if you can, but do not eliminate anything that is truly important to you in the purchase agreement.

A truly experienced Realtor can look at your offer and help you make sure that what you’re submitting to the seller is the highest and best offer that you can give them. Many times buyers don’t realize that the demands that they are putting into the contract are taking money away from the seller’s bottom line, and could hurt their chances of getting their offer accepted.

If you have any questions or you’re looking to buy or sell a home in our area, give me a call. I’d be happy to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Becky+Ivins/Videos/Oklahoma+City+Metro+Real+Estate+Agent-+Getting+Your+Offer+Accepted.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://beckyivinsblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Becky+Ivins/Videos/Oklahoma+City+Metro+Real+Estate+Agent-+Getting+Your+Offer+Accepted.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I wanted to give you some tips on how to get your offer accepted.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Beck Ivins</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I wanted to give you some tips on how to get your offer accepted.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Oklahoma City, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Are Appraisals and How Do They Work?</title>
        <link>http://beckyivinsblog.com/what-are-appraisals-and-how-do-they-work.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Beck Ivins</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-09 09:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Becky+Ivins/Videos/Oklahoma+City+Metro+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+Appraisals+Do+Other+Than+Determine+Value.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today, we’re going to be covering a subject that is important to any real estate transaction: appraisals.

First of all, what is an appraisal? Well, an appraisal is a value placed on a property by a licensed appraiser. This is different than a market analysis done by a real estate agent.

Appraisals are much more in depth, and are based upon the values of similar properties within a certain, tight geographic area.

This value is adjusted even further according to several factors. Things like square footage, the size of the lot, the age of the property, and the number of bedrooms and bathrooms are all important to the appraisal.

Even in the past few years, the appraisal process has changed quite a bit. Previously, real estate agents had the ability to choose who appraised the property.

However, regulations now typically require a third-party appraisal company to be hired by the lender. This is to make sure that there is no unnecessary pressure put on the appraiser.

“Outside of simply determining value, appraisals can also impact the transaction.”

So what exactly does the appraisal do? Well, outside of simply determining value, it can also impact the transaction. If the appraisal is lower than the amount offered by the buyer and accepted by the seller, the buyer may not be able to borrow as much as they may need for the mortgage.

This is why it’s so important that your Realtor’s market value is very thorough before you even order an appraisal.

The seller can also be affected. Even though a seller may price a property however they want, regardless of an appraisal, it would be difficult to find a cash buyer willing to pay any amount.

This isn’t often the case. In most cases, buyers need mortgages, and as I mentioned earlier, an appraisal must be of sufficient value to support the purchase price.

If an appraiser can’t justify a value, the seller will often have to reduce the value or the buyer will need to supplement the price with cash. Situations like these, if not handled correctly, can lead to a broken deal.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email, I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Becky+Ivins/Videos/Oklahoma+City+Metro+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+Appraisals+Do+Other+Than+Determine+Value.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://beckyivinsblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Becky+Ivins/Videos/Oklahoma+City+Metro+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+Appraisals+Do+Other+Than+Determine+Value.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Appraisals are an integral part of any real estate transaction. Today, I’ll explain what exactly they are and how they work.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Beck Ivins</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Appraisals are an integral part of any real estate transaction. Today, I’ll explain what exactly they are and how they work.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Oklahoma City, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Handle Multiple-Offer Situations</title>
        <link>http://beckyivinsblog.com/how-to-handle-multiple-offer-situations.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Beck Ivins</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-13 11:21:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Becky+Ivins/Videos/Oklahoma+City+Metro+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Handle+Multiple+Offers.mp4</guid>
        <description>
In any market, a property can receive multiple offers. We deal with this in our office on a near-daily basis. What that typically means is that folks may like a certain property and that property receives several different offers.

When you have a multiple offer situation, there are several different ways to handle it. The first thing to remember is that it’s not the agent’s prerogative as to how to handle the multiple offer, and many agents are confused about that. Our real estate commission rules and regulations state that you must follow the instructions of the seller. My job as a real estate agent is to tell the seller what the options are and allow them to choose.

If the property gets multiple offers, the seller has the option to look at just the first offer that comes in, or look at all offers that come in. Then you have an option as to how exactly to deal with those.

Sometimes a seller will choose to look at all the offers, which is my recommendation as a real estate agent, and then we can issue what is considered in the industry to be a “highest and best.” This is a notice to all the agents involved that they can have the buyers issue a different offer on the property. They can change the price, the terms, or even the closing date—anything to make that offer more desirable to the seller.

When we have a deadline for these offers to come in and they are received, I will then present all the updated offers to the seller for consideration.
“The highest offer isn’t necessarily the best offer.”
What makes it the best offer for the seller? It really depends on what the seller considers is the best offer for their property. Sometimes it depends on the closing date, especially if the seller is on a deadline and needs to close on or before a certain date. Other times, it’s all about the purchase price.

The highest offer isn’t necessarily the best offer—it’s more about the bottom line and how much the seller can net for their property. It also needs to fall within the range of value that I have determined for the property. A price higher than the appraised value of the home can cause problems.

Is a cash offer better than a financed offer? The cash offer is better if you have a big earnest money check. The buyer can take a walk through the property on the day of closing and drop the deal. If the check is small, then they don’t lose a lot of money by walking away.

How can you as a qualified professional help the seller find the right offer? Before you even take a listing, you should know what the seller needs. Those needs should be realistic.They need a certain bottom line, closing date, and make sure that they have a qualified buyer. Knowing this information will help you find the right offer for your client.

If you have any other questions about this topic or you’re looking to buy or sell a home, give me a call. I’d be happy to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Becky+Ivins/Videos/Oklahoma+City+Metro+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Handle+Multiple+Offers.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://beckyivinsblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Becky+Ivins/Videos/Oklahoma+City+Metro+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Handle+Multiple+Offers.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What happens when you’re presented with multiple offers on your home? Today I want to walk you through the process.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Beck Ivins</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What happens when you’re presented with multiple offers on your home? Today I want to walk you through the process.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Oklahoma City, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Latest From the Oklahoma City Market</title>
        <link>http://beckyivinsblog.com/the-latest-from-the-oklahoma-city-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Beck Ivins</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-08 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Becky+Ivins/Videos/Oklahoma+City+Metro+Real+Estate+Agent-+OKC+Metro+Area+Market+Update+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>
People often ask me if the Oklahoma City metro area is a buyer’s market or a seller’s market, but there are actually two different answers.

Because of the energy sector being out of work as long as they have been, it’s truly a buyer’s market in the upper end of homes, or those priced $350,000 and up. In the normal price ranges where average folks buy, you’ll find that it’s basically a seller’s market. However, nine times out of 10, sellers still pay the buyer’s closing costs.

You’ve probably heard about low housing inventory in the national news, and it’s the same here. We just don’t have many homes for sale in the price ranges where most people shop; about $100,000 to $300,000. However, inventory in the upper end is plentiful, which has actually driven prices down.
 “Low interest rates mean you have a lot of buying power.”
Mortgage interest rates, which affect your buying power, are still really good. They’re hovering just above or below the 4% mark right now, and it’s pretty easy to get a mortgage these days if you have a job and a down payment.

So what does this all mean for you?

The next few months will be a great time to buy a home thanks to the buying power you’ll have with interest rates so low. Prices are also steady since we never really go way up or way down here in the metro. You won’t have as many options, so when you find a home you like, you need to strike quick.

If you have any questions about the market or you’re ready to buy or sell a home, give me a call or send me an email soon. I’d be happy to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Becky+Ivins/Videos/Oklahoma+City+Metro+Real+Estate+Agent-+OKC+Metro+Area+Market+Update+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://beckyivinsblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Becky+Ivins/Videos/Oklahoma+City+Metro+Real+Estate+Agent-+OKC+Metro+Area+Market+Update+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What's going on in the Oklahoma City metro area market? Depending on which segment of the market you're looking in, you'll get a different answer.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Beck Ivins</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What's going on in the Oklahoma City metro area market? Depending on which segment of the market you're looking in, you'll get a different answer.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Oklahoma City, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Can You Really Trust Zillow’s Zestimate Tool?</title>
        <link>http://beckyivinsblog.com/can-you-really-trust-zillows-zestimate-tool.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Beck Ivins</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-01 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Becky+Ivins/Videos/Oklahoma+City+Metro+Real+Estate+Agent-+Zillow%2527s+Zestimate+Goes+to+Court.mp4</guid>
        <description>
I get a lot of questions about whether or not Zillow’s Zestimate can nail down the true value of a property. It turns out that a woman in Illinois has actually filed a lawsuit against Zillow, stating that their Zestimate is not the true value of her property.

My friend, Barbara Corcoran from “Shark Tank,” recently did an interview on “Good Morning America” about the lawsuit.

Basically, the woman in Illinois said that Zillow’s inaccurate Zestimate hurt her ability to sell her home. Barbara says that it makes sense in this case. “The woman felt her home was worth $626,000 and the Zestimate came back at $562,00. That’s a $64,000 difference,” says Barbara. “If a typical buyer checks her Zestimate, then they’ll think her home is worth less than what she’s saying.”

Barbara adds, “Her home was put in with a basket of other homes that have no bearing on the value of her home.”

“One in 10 homes get a Zestimate that is 20% under its actual market value.”

Zillow has since released a statement saying that their Zestimate is a good starting point for homeowners and buyers, but it’s not an official appraisal.

Barbara agrees, noting that the company has been very forthcoming about the fact that the Zestimate is not a real appraisal. However, the problem is that the buyer does not realize that Zestimates have a fault factor of 5% and that one in 10 homes get a Zestimate that’s 20% less than its true market value.

“They say it’s a starting point, but it’s not reliable,” says Barbara. “Every consumer out there knows about the Zestimate. They know to check it, and they use it as though it’s an appraisal. That’s the basis of the lawsuit.”

If you want to know the real value of your home, hire a real estate professional to compare your home to similar properties. The other way to figure out your home’s value is to pay for an appraisal. You can’t just rely on Zillow’s algorithm.

If you have any questions about your Zestimate or would like to learn more about home values in your specific neighborhood, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Becky+Ivins/Videos/Oklahoma+City+Metro+Real+Estate+Agent-+Zillow%2527s+Zestimate+Goes+to+Court.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://beckyivinsblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Becky+Ivins/Videos/Oklahoma+City+Metro+Real+Estate+Agent-+Zillow%2527s+Zestimate+Goes+to+Court.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Zillow’s Zestimates are under scrutiny thanks to a lawsuit filed by one Illinois homeowner. Can you really trust them to figure out your home value?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Beck Ivins</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Zillow’s Zestimates are under scrutiny thanks to a lawsuit filed by one Illinois homeowner. Can you really trust them to figure out your home value?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Oklahoma City, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Beck Ivins</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Beck Ivins</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Beck Ivins Movers Real Estate - your professional Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
