<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Las Vegas Real Estate Podcast with Mike Misak Chobanian</title>
    <link>http://www.myvegasrealestateinfo.com</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://www.myvegasrealestateinfo.com"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Vegas Capital Realty - your professional Las Vegas Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Mike Misak Chobanian</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2018-03-19 13:28:01 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Mike Misak Chobanian</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://www.myvegasrealestateinfo.com/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Las Vegas, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>info@VegasCapital.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Mike Misak Chobanian</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Mike Misak Chobanian</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://www.myvegasrealestateinfo.com/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Las Vegas, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Las Vegas Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Vegas Capital Realty - your professional Las Vegas Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Is Driving Las Vegas’ Rapid Growth?</title>
        <link>http://www.myvegasrealestateinfo.com/what-is-driving-las-vegas-rapid-growth.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Mike Misak Chobanian</author>
        <pubDate>2018-03-12 15:49:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+Tchobanian/Las+Vegas+Real+Estate+Why+is+Las+Vegas+growing.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What is driving the massive growth in Las Vegas? Today, I have three reasons that contribute.

&nbsp;

Forbes magazine just recently announced America’s fastest-growing cities in 2018. Las Vegas was one of the top cities in the country in terms of projected aggressive growth.

What is driving this growth?


  One of the reasons that Las Vegas’ cost of living is still very low compared to the rest of the country is that real estate prices are still 25% to 30% below the peak of where they once were. This has caused an influx of people moving to the area.
  Many people who once lived in Vegas unfortunately lost their houses due to foreclosure short sale bankruptcy when the market collapsed. Those people are back on the market now that they’ve fixed their credit, so they’re ready to buy again. This means there’s been an increase in demand from buyers that were renting at one point. This also encourages a lot of new home construction.
  Additionally, there are a lot of jobs that are being created by the construction field. Recently, a new Raiders stadium began construction, as well as a practice facility that will be built in Henderson. There are also a couple major casinos that will begin construction soon.


“There are a lot of jobs that are being created by the construction field.”

If you have any questions about what Las Vegas’ recent growth means for you or you are looking to buy or sell real estate, feel free to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+Tchobanian/Las+Vegas+Real+Estate+Why+is+Las+Vegas+growing.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.myvegasrealestateinfo.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+Tchobanian/Las+Vegas+Real+Estate+Why+is+Las+Vegas+growing.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What is driving the massive growth in Las Vegas? Today, I have three reasons that contribute.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mike Misak Chobanian</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What is driving the massive growth in Las Vegas? Today, I have three reasons that contribute.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Las Vegas, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>When Is the Best Time for Homeownership? </title>
        <link>http://www.myvegasrealestateinfo.com/the-real-cost-of-renting.html</link>
        
          <category>Las Vegas Real Estate Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mike Misak Chobanian</author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-09 10:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+Tchobanian/Las%2520Vegas%2520Real%2520Estate-%2520When%2520is%2520the%2520best%2520time%2520to%2520buy%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Waiting around for a market correction is rarely a good reason to keep renting. The longer you wait, the more money you are putting toward someone else’s mortgage instead of your own.

Want to sell your home? Get a FREE home value report.
Want to buy a home? Search all homes for sale.

Is it better to buy right away or rent until there’s a market correction? The truth is that it depends on your circumstances.

To help you determine what’s right for you, there are a couple of things you should ask yourself. First, how long are you looking to rent for? If the period of time is short, it’s a good idea to rent. This is especially true if you are only looking for temporary housing.

If you’re only looking to rent because you want to wait for prices to correct themselves in the market, there are a few statistics you should be aware of.

The average rent of a small home is $1,500. If you pay this amount each month for a full year, this would amount to $18,000.

“THE LONGER YOU WAIT, THE LONGER YOU’RE PUTTING OFF HAVING A PAID-OFF HOME OF YOUR OWN.”

If you’re waiting around for the market to correct itself, you are throwing away a lot of money. Over the course of three years, a monthly rent of $1,500 would amount to $54,000. Why help someone else pay off their mortgage when the money could go towards your own?

A typical mortgage will be paid off within 30 years. The longer you wait, the longer you’re putting off having a paid-off home of your own.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+Tchobanian/Las%2520Vegas%2520Real%2520Estate-%2520When%2520is%2520the%2520best%2520time%2520to%2520buy%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.myvegasrealestateinfo.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+Tchobanian/Las%2520Vegas%2520Real%2520Estate-%2520When%2520is%2520the%2520best%2520time%2520to%2520buy%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Waiting around for a market correction is rarely a good reason to keep renting. The longer you wait, the more money you are putting toward someone else’s mortgage instead of your own.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mike Misak Chobanian</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Waiting around for a market correction is rarely a good reason to keep renting. The longer you wait, the more money you are putting toward someone else’s mortgage instead of your own.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Las Vegas, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Think You Need 20% Down? Not With These Assistance Programs</title>
        <link>http://www.myvegasrealestateinfo.com/you-could-be-able-to-afford-home-sooner.html</link>
        
          <category>Las Vegas Real Estate Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mike Misak Chobanian</author>
        <pubDate>2017-09-05 12:13:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+Tchobanian/Las%2520Vegas%2520Real%2520Estate-%2520The%2520secret%2520to%2520putting%2520less%2520down%2520on%2520a%2520home.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Many people believe that it takes a lot of money down to be able to afford a home. With the help of down payment assistance programs, this isn’t always the case.

Want to sell your home? Get a FREE home value report.
Want to buy a home? Search all homes for sale.

Today I’ve got some exciting news. If you’ve been renting because you believe you don’t have enough money for a down payment, you should know that you actually have some options.

It is a common misconception that to buy a home you need to come up with a large sum for the down payment. This is not always the case.

There are a number of programs out there allow you to purchase a home for very little money down.

To discuss this, I recently sat down with one of the top loan officers in Las Vegas: Monica Aldana from Cross Country Mortgage.

With a conventional loan, you can put just 3%, 4%, or 5% down so long as your credit score is above 640.

You also never have to repay the money you receive from this assistance program. However, there is a fee of approximately $700 for down payment assistance.

“THERE ARE A NUMBER OF PROGRAMS OUT THERE ALLOW YOU TO PURCHASE A HOME FOR VERY LITTLE MONEY DOWN.”

If you have credit score of at least 660 and are using the FHA loan, you can qualify to put down 4% through that program. Typically, though, buyers can qualify for just 3.5% down using an FHA loan. This means that money saved on the down payment could go toward closing costs.

Programs like these open up a lot of opportunities. However, there are some things you should be aware of.

It’s also important to remember that interest rates are higher for these programs than what is found on the standard market. However, these interest rates are not FICO-driven.

This means that if you have a low FICO score, you could get a lower interest rate by using a down payment assistance program.

If you’ve got any questions for Monica about this, you can reach her by calling (702) 339-8221.

Also, if you would like more information or have any other questions for me, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+Tchobanian/Las%2520Vegas%2520Real%2520Estate-%2520The%2520secret%2520to%2520putting%2520less%2520down%2520on%2520a%2520home.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.myvegasrealestateinfo.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+Tchobanian/Las%2520Vegas%2520Real%2520Estate-%2520The%2520secret%2520to%2520putting%2520less%2520down%2520on%2520a%2520home.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Many people believe that it takes a lot of money down to be able to afford a home. With the help of down payment assistance programs, this isn’t always the case.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mike Misak Chobanian</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Many people believe that it takes a lot of money down to be able to afford a home. With the help of down payment assistance programs, this isn’t always the case.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Las Vegas, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Should You Sell Now or Wait?</title>
        <link>http://www.myvegasrealestateinfo.com/should-you-sell-now-or-wait.html</link>
        
          <category>Las Vegas Real Estate Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mike Misak Chobanian</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-14 13:49:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+Tchobanian/Las%2520Vegas%2520Real%2520Estate-%2520This%2520is%2520a%2520tough%2520decision%2520to%2520make(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>

Should you sell now or wait to see where our market is headed?

Want to sell your home? Get a FREE home value report.
Want to buy a home? Search all homes for sale.

In real estate, timing can be a critical factor to any transaction.

Something on the minds of many people who are thinking about listing is whether they should do so now or wait to see what happens in our market.

Because the market is currently appreciating, this can be a tough question to answer. In fact, there is no one-size-fits-all answer.

The answer to this question depends on your personal circumstances. To determine what is right for you, you should consider two main factors.

“THERE IS NO ONE-SIZE-FITS-ALL ANSWER.”

First of all, think about your own motivation and need to sell. Why do you want to sell? Do you need to sell first to buy another property?

Next, consider price. Pricing a home correctly is absolutely critical to getting top dollar. Future appreciation aside, you can still get a great price now if you understand how to properly price your home.

Another thing you might want to consider is the option of renting your property out. If you’re waiting to see where the market goes, why not rent out the property and make some money in the meantime?

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+Tchobanian/Las%2520Vegas%2520Real%2520Estate-%2520This%2520is%2520a%2520tough%2520decision%2520to%2520make(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.myvegasrealestateinfo.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+Tchobanian/Las%2520Vegas%2520Real%2520Estate-%2520This%2520is%2520a%2520tough%2520decision%2520to%2520make(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Should you sell now or wait to see where our market is headed?

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mike Misak Chobanian</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Should you sell now or wait to see where our market is headed?

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Las Vegas, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Few Tips if Youre Looking to Get a Mortgage</title>
        <link>http://www.myvegasrealestateinfo.com/a-few-tips-if-youre-looking-to-get.html</link>
        
          <category>Las Vegas Real Estate Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mike Misak Chobanian</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-31 12:39:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+Tchobanian/Las%2520Vegas%2520Real%2520Estate-%2520One%2520way%2520to%2520set%2520yourself%2520apart.mp4</guid>
        <description>

How can you stand out in this competitive market? We have the answer.

Want to sell your home? Get a FREE home value report.
Want to buy a home? Search all homes for sale.

We’re lucky enough to be joined today by Monica with CrossCountry Mortgage. She is here to give us some more information about what’s going on in this crazy market.

As you’re probably already aware, Las Vegas is a strong seller’s market right now. With many more buyers than sellers, what’s the best way for a buyer to prepare to get the home they want? According to Monica, it’s getting a pre-approval. Don’t settle for a quick pre-qualification. A fully underwritten approval with verified income and assets is what you’re looking for. It only takes a few days, and then you can go home shopping with confidence.

“A FULLY UNDERWRITTEN PRE-APPROVAL IS KEY.”

If you’re a seller in this market, Monica says not to accept an offer from a buyer who doesn’t have a fully underwritten approval because they might not actually be able to buy your home. Their income and assets should be verified as well.

If you have any questions for Monica, you can give her a call at (702) 339-8221. If you have any other questions for us, you can always give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+Tchobanian/Las%2520Vegas%2520Real%2520Estate-%2520One%2520way%2520to%2520set%2520yourself%2520apart.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.myvegasrealestateinfo.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+Tchobanian/Las%2520Vegas%2520Real%2520Estate-%2520One%2520way%2520to%2520set%2520yourself%2520apart.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

How can you stand out in this competitive market? We have the answer.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mike Misak Chobanian</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

How can you stand out in this competitive market? We have the answer.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Las Vegas, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Stand out to Sellers in the Las Vegas Market: Part 2</title>
        <link>http://www.myvegasrealestateinfo.com/how-to-stand-out-to-sellers-in-las.html</link>
        
          <category>Las Vegas Real Estate Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mike Misak Chobanian</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-09 09:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+Tchobanian/Las%2520Vegas%2520Real%2520Estate-%2520How%2520to%2520win%2520the%2520home%2520you%2520want%2520in%2520our%2520market-%2520part%25202.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you want to buy a home here in the Las Vegas market, it won’t be easy. You can help yourself with these three tips.

Want to sell your home? Get a FREE home value report.
Want to buy a home? Search all homes for sale.

We’re back to continue our conversation about how to get your offer accepted as a buyer in the crazy seller’s market we’re experiencing in Las Vegas. If you missed the first part of our discussion, you can see it here.

Inventory is low across the country and Las Vegas is no different. We have just 4,917 single-family houses for sale in the Las Vegas area. That might not sound like a shortage, but compared to the nearly 8,000 houses we had for sale at this time last year, you can see how drastically inventory has shrunk.

There are also just 366 condominiums and 305 townhomes for sale in our market. When you buy a home in our market, you need to be aggressive. You can win in this low inventory market by following a few key tips:

1. Don’t overanalyze the process: Be aggressive and don’t take too long looking for options because you just won’t have many options.

2. Be prepared for a bidding war: There will be a lot of buyers looking for homes that are priced right and in good condition, so put your best foot forward.

“YOU DON’T HAVE THE LUXURY OF TIME IF YOU FIND A HOME YOU LIKE.”

3. Listen to your agent: Learn from other buyers’ mistakes. An experienced agent can help you through the whole process, so trust them and be prepared.

If you’re looking to buy a home or sell your current house, give me a call or send me an email. I’d love to use my experience to help you get the best outcome in our market.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+Tchobanian/Las%2520Vegas%2520Real%2520Estate-%2520How%2520to%2520win%2520the%2520home%2520you%2520want%2520in%2520our%2520market-%2520part%25202.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.myvegasrealestateinfo.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+Tchobanian/Las%2520Vegas%2520Real%2520Estate-%2520How%2520to%2520win%2520the%2520home%2520you%2520want%2520in%2520our%2520market-%2520part%25202.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you want to buy a home here in the Las Vegas market, it won’t be easy. You can help yourself with these three tips.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mike Misak Chobanian</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you want to buy a home here in the Las Vegas market, it won’t be easy. You can help yourself with these three tips.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Las Vegas, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title> How to Stand out to Sellers in the Las Vegas Market</title>
        <link>http://www.myvegasrealestateinfo.com/how-to-stand-out-to-sellers-in-las.html</link>
        
          <category>Las Vegas Real Estate Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mike Misak Chobanian</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-24 14:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+Tchobanian/Las%2520Vegas%2520Real%2520Estate-%2520How%2520to%2520win%2520the%2520home%2520you%2520want%2520in%2520our%2520market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When you want to buy a home here in the hot Las Vegas market, there are a few certain things you can do to make yourself stand out amongst the competition.

Want to sell your home? Get a FREE home value report.
Want to buy a home? Search all homes for sale.

If you want to buy a Las Vegas home, there are a few specific things you can do to get the home you want for a great deal.

1. Choose an experienced agent: You want a full-time agent who knows what they’re doing. They should be patient and willing to show you properties. It’s also not just about finding your house, you want an agent who can negotiate and be aggressive to get your offer accepted.

2. Be aggressive with your offer: When you find the right property in the right area that fits your criteria (size, price, budget, etc.) don’t sit there and over-analyze things.

“EVEN THOUGH IT’S A SELLER’S MARKET, THERE ARE CERTAIN THINGS YOU CAN DO TO MAXIMIZE YOUR PROFIT.”

3. Have your full financing approval ready: Make sure you have a copy before you even start shopping for homes. Not having your approval ready would be like going hunting without a gun. Even if you find the perfect home, if you haven’t been approved for financing yet, it could take a lot of time and cause you to lose out on the house.

Stay tuned for our next video where I’ll reveal the last three things you can do as a homebuyer to set yourself up to win the home you want. In the meantime, give me a call or send me an email with any questions you have. I’d be glad to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+Tchobanian/Las%2520Vegas%2520Real%2520Estate-%2520How%2520to%2520win%2520the%2520home%2520you%2520want%2520in%2520our%2520market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.myvegasrealestateinfo.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+Tchobanian/Las%2520Vegas%2520Real%2520Estate-%2520How%2520to%2520win%2520the%2520home%2520you%2520want%2520in%2520our%2520market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

When you want to buy a home here in the hot Las Vegas market, there are a few certain things you can do to make yourself stand out amongst the competition.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mike Misak Chobanian</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

When you want to buy a home here in the hot Las Vegas market, there are a few certain things you can do to make yourself stand out amongst the competition.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Las Vegas, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Las Vegas and Henderson Market Update </title>
        <link>http://www.myvegasrealestateinfo.com/las-vegas-and-henderson-market-update.html</link>
        
          <category>Las Vegas Real Estate Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Mike Misak Chobanian</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-09 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+Tchobanian/Las+Vegas+Real+Estate-+Mother%2527s+Day+market+update.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I’m bringing you the latest numbers in the Las Vegas and Henderson area market and wishing all the mothers out there a very Happy Mother’s Day.

Want to sell your home? Get a FREE home value report.
Want to buy a home? Search all homes for sale.

Before I get started with your newest market update, I want to take a moment to wish all the mothers out there a Happy Mother’s Day! Make it a great weekend and enjoy your time with your families. You deserve it!

Currently, we have a little more than 5,000 single family homes, approximately 400 condos, and around 300 townhomes for sale. Last month in April, there were 2,800 homes sold. Based on those numbers, we have a very low inventory. In fact, if no new houses came on the market, it would only take 45 days to sell everything currently for sale.

“EVEN THOUGH IT’S A SELLER’S MARKET, THERE ARE CERTAIN THINGS YOU CAN DO TO MAXIMIZE YOUR PROFIT.”

Those numbers put us in a very strong seller’s market. There are more buyers than there are homes for sale, so prices are going to continue to rise. If you are thinking about selling, make sure you contact the right agent to help you strategize. Even though it’s a seller’s market, there are certain things you can do to maximize your profit.

If you have any questions about the market conditions or are looking to buy or sell a home, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I’m more than happy to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+Tchobanian/Las+Vegas+Real+Estate-+Mother%2527s+Day+market+update.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.myvegasrealestateinfo.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+Tchobanian/Las+Vegas+Real+Estate-+Mother%2527s+Day+market+update.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today I’m bringing you the latest numbers in the Las Vegas and Henderson area market and wishing all the mothers out there a very Happy Mother’s Day.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mike Misak Chobanian</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today I’m bringing you the latest numbers in the Las Vegas and Henderson area market and wishing all the mothers out there a very Happy Mother’s Day.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Las Vegas, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 Listing Mistakes to Avoid in the Las Vegas Market </title>
        <link>http://www.myvegasrealestateinfo.com/5-listing-mistakes-to-avoid-in-las.html</link>
        
          <category>Las Vegas Real Estate Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mike Misak Chobanian</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-17 11:29:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+Tchobanian/Las+Vegas+Real+Estate-+5+listing+mistakes+to+avoid+at+all+costs.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When you sell your house in the spring market, you want to avoid these five mistakes at all costs.

Want to sell your home? Get a FREE home value report.
Want to buy a home? Search all homes for sale.

If you’re getting ready to sell your house in the upcoming spring or summer months, there are five mistakes you want to avoid making:

1. Do not overprice your home: Even in this appreciating market, it could cost you in the long run.

2. Don’t leave minor repairs undone: Minor repairs are part of getting your house ready to list on the market.

3. Don’t overimprove: Don’t think that spending a ton of money on improvements will all come back in your bottom line. Consult with your Realtor about which upgrades will make you your money back when you sell.

4. Don’t make it hard for buyers to see your property: With low inventory in our market, we have a lot of motivated buyers. A lot of people will want to see your house in the first two weeks it’s on the market, so make it as easy as possible for them.

“OVERPRICING YOUR HOME COULD ACTUALLY COST YOU MONEY IN THE END.”

5. Don’t try to sell on your own: You might think you’ll save money on real estate commission, but in this appreciating market, it will cost you more than if you sell with a professional real estate agent.

If you have any questions or you’re thinking about making a move in the Las Vegas market, give me a call or send me an email. I’m always happy to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+Tchobanian/Las+Vegas+Real+Estate-+5+listing+mistakes+to+avoid+at+all+costs.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.myvegasrealestateinfo.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+Tchobanian/Las+Vegas+Real+Estate-+5+listing+mistakes+to+avoid+at+all+costs.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

When you sell your house in the spring market, you want to avoid these five mistakes at all costs.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mike Misak Chobanian</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

When you sell your house in the spring market, you want to avoid these five mistakes at all costs.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Las Vegas, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4 Tech Features That Improve a Homes Value</title>
        <link>http://www.myvegasrealestateinfo.com/4-tech-features-that-improve-homes-value.html</link>
        
          <category>Las Vegas Real Estate Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mike Misak Chobanian</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-03 10:37:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+Tchobanian/Las+Vegas+Real+Estate-+Buyers+love+seeing+these+in+homes.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Smart home technology has improved a lot over the years. Here’s what buyers are looking for in today’s market.

Want to sell your home? Get a FREE home value report.
Want to buy a home? Search all homes for sale.

Having the latest technology in your home will help it get more attention from buyers, both online and in-person. Here are four tech upgrades you can make in your home to maximize its value when the time comes to sell:

1. Smart thermostat. They keep your home at the temperature you like when you are home, and keep it at an energy-efficient temperature when you’re away. These thermostats can help bring energy bills way down.

2. Surveillance cameras. Nowadays, they are pretty inexpensive. There is even a doorbell that comes with its own webcam. You want something newer that is compatible with smart technology.

3. Smart culinary equipment. No-touch faucets are great for keeping germs off faucets, and a fridge that tells you when you’re running low on milk or Coors Light is an added bonus for buyers.

“SMART THERMOSTATS HELP LOWER ENERGY BILLS.”

4. Updated surround sound. Whether you have a theater room or not, buyers love seeing high-end sound systems when it comes to entertainment areas.

If you have any questions for us about selling your home or what else you can do to help it stand out, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+Tchobanian/Las+Vegas+Real+Estate-+Buyers+love+seeing+these+in+homes.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.myvegasrealestateinfo.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+Tchobanian/Las+Vegas+Real+Estate-+Buyers+love+seeing+these+in+homes.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Smart home technology has improved a lot over the years. Here’s what buyers are looking for in today’s market.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mike Misak Chobanian</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Smart home technology has improved a lot over the years. Here’s what buyers are looking for in today’s market.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Las Vegas, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Whats Happening in the Last Vegas Real Estate Market?</title>
        <link>http://www.myvegasrealestateinfo.com/whats-happening-in-last-vegas-real.html</link>
        
          <category>Las Vegas Real Estate Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Mike Misak Chobanian</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-13 13:43:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+Tchobanian/Las+Vegas+Real+Estate-+A+perfect+storm+for+Las+Vegas+homeowners.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The Las Vegas market is as active as ever. We have less than two months of inventory and a high level of demand from buyers.

Want to sell your home? Get a FREE home value report.
Want to buy a home? Search all homes for sale.

The Las Vegas real estate market has been extremely active as of late. With low inventory and high demand from buyers, we are seeing homes fly off the market. I wanted to drop by and give you a quick rundown of all the important numbers we’ve been keeping an eye on.

Right now, the current inventory for single-family homes is 5,571. We also have 474 condos and 338 townhomes on the market. In the month of February, we sold 2,737 homes. Based on those numbers, we have less than a two-month supply of available homes on the market. With such a low level of inventory, we expect home prices to continue to increase throughout the spring and summer, even though demand is higher during those times of year.

“LOW INVENTORY IS GOOD NEWS FOR SELLERS.”

If you have been thinking of selling your home, now is an excellent time. Buyers will be able to overlook a lot more imperfections than they would if there were more homes available to purchase. Now is also a great time to consider buying as a long-term investment. With interest rates and home prices expected to rise in the next year (prices rose 10% in just the last year), locking in a purchase now will save you thousands of dollars over the life of your loan.

If you have any questions for me about the Las Vegas market or if you’re considering making a move, give me a call or send me an email. I would love to hear from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+Tchobanian/Las+Vegas+Real+Estate-+A+perfect+storm+for+Las+Vegas+homeowners.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.myvegasrealestateinfo.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+Tchobanian/Las+Vegas+Real+Estate-+A+perfect+storm+for+Las+Vegas+homeowners.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

The Las Vegas market is as active as ever. We have less than two months of inventory and a high level of demand from buyers.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mike Misak Chobanian</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

The Las Vegas market is as active as ever. We have less than two months of inventory and a high level of demand from buyers.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Las Vegas, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Hire the Right Listing Agent </title>
        <link>http://www.myvegasrealestateinfo.com/how-to-hire-right-listing-agent.html</link>
        
          <category>Las Vegas Real Estate Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mike Misak Chobanian</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-23 11:51:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+Tchobanian/Las+Vegas+Real+Estate-+4+tips+for+hiring+a+listing+agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Hiring the right real estate agent to sell your house is absolutely crucial. Here are four tips to help you choose the best agent for the job.

Want to sell your home? Get a FREE home value report.
Want to buy a home? Search all homes for sale.

When you plan on selling your house, it is crucial to hire the right agent. How do you know which agent is the best one for the job? Here are a few tips:

1. Work with an agent who specializes in selling houses. Don’t work with a buyer’s agent. Listing agents are experienced in negotiating with buyers. They know what to do to sell your home and will give you the best advice to help you move forward, avoid surprises, and net the most money.

2. You should hire an active agent. Over 80% of agents only sell four properties a year. They are not actively working in the real estate industry every day to sell homes.

“HIRE A LISTING AGENT WHO IS ACTIVE IN THE MARKET EVERY DAY.”

3. Ask how much experience they have. You need an experienced agent who has seen both the peak and the lowest point of the market. They will know how to handle every situation that may arise during the transaction. Keep in mind that some experienced agents only do four deals a year, so ask how many transactions they do as well.

4. Ask for references. Ask the agent for three or four references. Check their past sales on Zillow and other review sites to make sure that you hire a good listing agent.

Keep these four things in mind when hiring a listing agent and you will hire the right one for the job. If you have any other questions about selling your house, give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+Tchobanian/Las+Vegas+Real+Estate-+4+tips+for+hiring+a+listing+agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.myvegasrealestateinfo.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+Tchobanian/Las+Vegas+Real+Estate-+4+tips+for+hiring+a+listing+agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Hiring the right real estate agent to sell your house is absolutely crucial. Here are four tips to help you choose the best agent for the job.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mike Misak Chobanian</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Hiring the right real estate agent to sell your house is absolutely crucial. Here are four tips to help you choose the best agent for the job.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Las Vegas, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Happens When the Appraisal Is Lower Than Sale Price?</title>
        <link>http://www.myvegasrealestateinfo.com/what-happens-when-appraisal-is-lower.html</link>
        
          <category>Las Vegas Real Estate Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mike Misak Chobanian</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-09 12:24:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+Tchobanian/Las+Vegas+Real+Estate-+What+happens+if+your+appraisal+comes+in+low.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What happens if you’re selling your house and the appraised value comes in lower than the purchase price? You can choose from one of these three courses of action.

Want to sell your home? Get a FREE home value report.
Want to buy a home? Search all homes for sale.

If you’re selling your home and the appraised value comes in lower than the purchase price, what should you do?

This is common in the Las Vegas market because of how much home values have appreciated. Appraisers don’t take our low supply, high demand, and appreciation into consideration when appraising a home’s value. They only look at the most recent sales within the area.

“IF YOUR HOME’S APPRAISAL COMES IN LOW, YOU HAVE THREE OPTIONS.”

As a home seller, you have three options:

1. We ask the buyer to come up with the difference in cash out of pocket. This is ideal for the seller because it keeps the deal together and gets you the same amount of money as you expected from the beginning.

2. The seller can lower the sales price to the appraised value. In this case, you will net less money, but if you’re really motivated to keep a deal together and move, this might be the best solution.

3. We can renegotiate the deal and meet the buyer halfway. Meeting halfway means the buyer will come up with some cash for the difference and the seller brings the sales price down a bit. We can also renegotiate to have the buyer pay some or all of the closing costs.

If you’re thinking about selling your house and you’d like to know what it’s worth in today’s market, give me a call or send me an email. I’d be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+Tchobanian/Las+Vegas+Real+Estate-+What+happens+if+your+appraisal+comes+in+low.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.myvegasrealestateinfo.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+Tchobanian/Las+Vegas+Real+Estate-+What+happens+if+your+appraisal+comes+in+low.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

What happens if you’re selling your house and the appraised value comes in lower than the purchase price? You can choose from one of these three courses of action.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mike Misak Chobanian</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

What happens if you’re selling your house and the appraised value comes in lower than the purchase price? You can choose from one of these three courses of action.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Las Vegas, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Will the Las Vegas Market Look Like in 2017?</title>
        <link>http://www.myvegasrealestateinfo.com/what-will-las-vegas-market-look-like-in.html</link>
        
          <category>Las Vegas Real Estate Market Prediction</category>
        
        <author>Mike Misak Chobanian</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-20 15:06:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+Tchobanian/Las+Vegas+Real+Estate-+What+to+expect+from+our+market+in+2017.mp4</guid>
        <description>

After five years of appreciation, our market should see a bit of a slowdown. That slowdown should affect different price brackets in different ways.

Want to sell your home? Get a FREE home value report.
Want to buy a home? Search all homes for sale.

What can you expect from the Las Vegas real estate market going into 2017?

Over the past five years, our market has been steadily appreciating. Looking back at the history of real estate in our country, though, five-year growth periods tend to be followed by a market correction or slowdown. I don’t expect our market to depreciate, but I do expect some kind of slowdown based on the supply and demand.

Houses listed above the $300,000 to $400,000 range should be the price bracket most directly affected by this slowdown. As the number of buyers in this area decreases, the number of sellers should increase because of the overall appreciation and a better opportunity to sell those kinds of homes. There aren’t a lot of buyers out there who can qualify for that kind of loan, so if you’re selling your home above this price bracket, I would be very aggressive with pricing it before the competition increases.

“OVERALL, THINGS ARE LOOKING POSITIVE.”

If your house is worth less than $280,000, that’s a great place to be, because that’s the maximum mortgage amount the majority of home buyers can qualify for here in Las Vegas. If you’re buying a house under $280,000, I would get very aggressive when submitting an offer, because the competition is far greater in this price bracket.

Overall, things are looking positive. As our population continues to grow, so will our real estate market. If you have any questions or are interested in buying or selling a house in this market, feel free to give me a call. I’d be happy to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+Tchobanian/Las+Vegas+Real+Estate-+What+to+expect+from+our+market+in+2017.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.myvegasrealestateinfo.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+Tchobanian/Las+Vegas+Real+Estate-+What+to+expect+from+our+market+in+2017.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

After five years of appreciation, our market should see a bit of a slowdown. That slowdown should affect different price brackets in different ways.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mike Misak Chobanian</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

After five years of appreciation, our market should see a bit of a slowdown. That slowdown should affect different price brackets in different ways.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Las Vegas, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Thanks for Your Support in 2016</title>
        <link>http://www.myvegasrealestateinfo.com/thanks-for-your-support-in-2016.html</link>
        
          <category>Client Appreciation</category>
        
        <author>Mike Misak Chobanian</author>
        <pubDate>2016-12-20 12:41:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+Tchobanian/Las+Vegas+Real+Estate-+Happy+holidays+from+our+team.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I wanted to take a moment to say thanks to everyone who helped us make 2016 great.

Want to sell your home? Get a FREE home value report.
Want to buy a home? Search all homes for sale.

Today I just wanted to take a moment to thank everyone that we did business with in 2016.

May you and your family have a merry Christmas and a safe, happy new year as we head into 2017.

“WE HOPE YOU HAVE A SAFE, HAPPY, AND HEALTHY HOLIDAY SEASON.”

We’re always here to help you or anyone you know who is looking to buy or sell a home in Las Vegas in 2017 and beyond. Just give me a call!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+Tchobanian/Las+Vegas+Real+Estate-+Happy+holidays+from+our+team.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.myvegasrealestateinfo.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+Tchobanian/Las+Vegas+Real+Estate-+Happy+holidays+from+our+team.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today I wanted to take a moment to say thanks to everyone who helped us make 2016 great.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mike Misak Chobanian</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today I wanted to take a moment to say thanks to everyone who helped us make 2016 great.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Las Vegas, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 Huge Benefits to Selling Your Home During the Holidays</title>
        <link>http://www.myvegasrealestateinfo.com/5-huge-benefits-to-selling-your-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Las Vegas Real Estate Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mike Misak Chobanian</author>
        <pubDate>2016-12-07 13:47:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

As a home seller, listing your property during the holidays affords you more advantages than you would see at any other time of year.

Want to sell your home? Get a FREE home value report.
Want to buy a home? Search all homes for sale.

Thinking of selling your home this holiday season? Don’t hesitate. There are five big advantages to home sellers when it comes to listing your home during the holidays:

“A MORE EMOTIONAL BUYER IS A QUICKER BUYER.”


  Buyers who are looking to buy a property during the holidays are far more serious about making a purchase. They won’t waste a minute of your time, and they won’t hesitate to pull the trigger if they like your home.
  Buyers have more time to search for homes. All the time off they get from work will give them more hours in the day to peruse the market.
  The number of listing increases dramatically after the holidays. This means if you follow suit, your house might be swallowed up by the competition.
  Houses always show better during the holidays. All houses look better when they’re decorated for the holidays.
  The season makes buyers more emotional. A more emotional buyer is a quicker buyer.


If you have any questions or are thinking about buying or selling, please feel free to contact me so we can set up a free consultation. I look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.myvegasrealestateinfo.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

As a home seller, listing your property during the holidays affords you more advantages than you would see at any other time of year.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mike Misak Chobanian</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

As a home seller, listing your property during the holidays affords you more advantages than you would see at any other time of year.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Las Vegas, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Mike Misak Chobanian</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Mike Misak Chobanian</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Vegas Capital Realty - your professional Las Vegas Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
