<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Valencia Real Estate Video Blog with Randy Plaice</title>
    <link>http://randyplaiceandassociatesblog.com</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://randyplaiceandassociatesblog.com"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Randy Plaice &amp; Associates - your professional Valencia Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Randy Plaice</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2017-05-30 11:47:43 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Randy Plaice</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://randyplaiceandassociatesblog.com/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valencia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">News &amp; Politics</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>salesteam@randyplaice.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Randy Plaice</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Randy Plaice</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://randyplaiceandassociatesblog.com/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valencia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Valencia Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Randy Plaice &amp; Associates - your professional Valencia Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="News &amp; Politics"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>Is New Home Construction Worth It?</title>
        <link>http://randyplaiceandassociatesblog.com/is-new-home-construction-worth-it.html</link>
        
          <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Randy Plaice</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-18 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Randy+Plaice/Videos/2017/Is+New+Home+Construction+Worth+It%253F+-+Santa+Clarita+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I’ve touched on new construction in the past, but this time I want to dive deeper into the topic and talk about some of the pros and cons of buying a brand new home and what you can expect throughout the process.

New construction purchases have many advantages over traditional resale purchases. For one, you can see the different models, layouts, and features before you even start building. You can pick a lot of the features out in your home, from the floor to the kitchen backsplash and even the light positions. If it’s early on in the process, you can make this a really special and unique home. You also get to be the first person to live in the space.

“Builders want you to be unrepresented, but you shouldn’t be.”

Builders will sometimes even offer you incentives like design center credits to update your home to sweeten the deal. However, in an ideal world, you would come to them as an unrepresented buyer. That would be a mistake on your part. 

When you work with an agent in buying a new home, it doesn’t cost you a thing. In return, you get the knowledge and expertise of a real estate professional who is on your side throughout the transaction. Having someone who can negotiate on behalf of you and your best interests is invaluable when buying a new home. 

Overall, new construction is a great opportunity for homebuyers. These homes can be a little more expensive and take a little longer to build, but the sooner you can get in there and figure out your options, the better.

If you have any questions for me about new construction or anything else relating to real estate, give me a call or send me an email. I would love to hear from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Randy+Plaice/Videos/2017/Is+New+Home+Construction+Worth+It%253F+-+Santa+Clarita+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://randyplaiceandassociatesblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Randy+Plaice/Videos/2017/Is+New+Home+Construction+Worth+It%253F+-+Santa+Clarita+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Buying a new home offers many benefits and only a few drawbacks. Here’s what you should know.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Randy Plaice</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Buying a new home offers many benefits and only a few drawbacks. Here’s what you should know.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valencia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Risks & Rewards of Airbnb With Investment Properties</title>
        <link>http://randyplaiceandassociatesblog.com/the-risks-rewards-of-airbnb-with-investment-properties.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Randy Plaice</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-04 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Randy+Plaice/Videos/2017/What%2527s+Up+With+Airbnb%253F+-+Santa+Clarita+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Airbnb has become increasingly popular with homeowners who like the idea of renting out their place and making some income without having a tenant for a full month or year. You get flexibility with renting and can still use the property.

The simplicity of it is one of the biggest benefits, too. It’s app-driven, so it’s easy for renters to come to you. All you have to do is post pictures of your place and they’ll come find you. 

“You don’t just want to think about the rental income, but also the appreciation of an area in terms of real estate value.”

There are a lot of investment properties that I as a real estate agent can situate you with to create the best investment opportunity for you. Here in the Santa Clarita market, you want to consider the proximity to the areas where people are likely to use Airbnb, but also how you can situate yourself to make the most money possible on an ongoing basis. 

You don’t just want to think about the rental income, but also the appreciation of an area in terms of real estate value.

Finally, you need to be aware of all the restrictions with Airbnb. Many community CC&amp;Rs will regulate against this type of rental, so you really want to make sure you know about any restrictions before buying a property. Otherwise, you could end up in some real hot water because a community board won’t allow Airbnb properties. 

Make sure you do your due diligence and can legally have an Airbnb rental without any issues. If you have any questions about investment properties and the opportunities with Airbnb, give me a call or send me an email. I’d love to speak with you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Randy+Plaice/Videos/2017/What%2527s+Up+With+Airbnb%253F+-+Santa+Clarita+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://randyplaiceandassociatesblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Randy+Plaice/Videos/2017/What%2527s+Up+With+Airbnb%253F+-+Santa+Clarita+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Have you heard about using Airbnb as a rental investment opportunity? It can be a great rental income opportunity if the conditions are right.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Randy Plaice</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Have you heard about using Airbnb as a rental investment opportunity? It can be a great rental income opportunity if the conditions are right.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valencia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Get Excited for the Spring Real Estate Market</title>
        <link>http://randyplaiceandassociatesblog.com/get-excited-for-the-spring-real-estate-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Randy Plaice</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-12 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Randy+Plaice/Videos/2017/Get+Excited+for+the+Spring+Real+Estate+Market+-+Santa+Clarita+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The spring market is coming very quickly and there are a lot of positive changes happening in the world of real estate.

This has been a very strong year for both buyers and sellers. It’s been a good year for buyers because interest rates are still low. Now, they are starting to go up a little bit but overall, they are still really favorable and people are starting to realize that. Talk to a local lender to see what interest rate you qualify for in the current market before rates go up further.

If you plan on selling your home, now is also a great time to get in the market. More and more buyers are coming into the market because of those low interest rates. Consumer confidence is also up this spring, as more people are eager to buy a home. Plus, buyers want to make a purchase now before interest rates go up, so as a seller, you have a really great advantage in this market.

“Your home looks incredible in the spring.”

There are other advantages to selling in the spring. For one, your home looks incredible in the spring. Flowers start to bloom and your home feels nicer; it’s not as cold and gloomy as it can be during the winter. In spring, your home can be more lively and beautiful. Spring is also a great time to photograph your home, so introduce it to the market and capitalize on all of those buyers who are waiting to buy your home.

Of course, real estate is hyperlocal, so every neighborhood’s market is slightly different. If you are curious about your specific neighborhood or if you have any other questions about the spring market in general, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Randy+Plaice/Videos/2017/Get+Excited+for+the+Spring+Real+Estate+Market+-+Santa+Clarita+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://randyplaiceandassociatesblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Randy+Plaice/Videos/2017/Get+Excited+for+the+Spring+Real+Estate+Market+-+Santa+Clarita+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>As the spring market approaches, there are a lot of positive changes happening in the real estate market that impact both buyers and sellers.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Randy Plaice</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>As the spring market approaches, there are a lot of positive changes happening in the real estate market that impact both buyers and sellers.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valencia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why We Charge You the Standard 6% Commission</title>
        <link>http://randyplaiceandassociatesblog.com/why-we-charge-you-the-standard-6-commission.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Randy Plaice</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-24 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Randy+Plaice/Videos/2017/Why+We+Charge+You+the+Standard+6%2525+Commission+-+Santa+Clarita+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’re selling your house, it might be tempting, but you don’t want to discount the amount of commission you will ultimately pay your broker. Allow me to explain why.

Doing this will not actually serve your cause; on the contrary, it could actually hurt you. Of course, you want to sell your house for as much as you can and you want to save as much as possible in costs and fees. Selling a home isn’t cheap and there’s a lot that goes into it, so it can be tempting to want to pay your Realtor/broker 3% or 4% rather than the standard 6%.

“The $5,000 you save by hiring that guy from Craigslist will actually hurt your bottom line.”

However, the reality is that when you start doing this, it comes with certain trade-offs. If you pay less, you trade off things like time, marketing, and exposure that your home should get. We don’t want to discount our services to such a level where we limit our ability to serve you at the highest level. We do things at a high level, like using the best photographers and the most comprehensive marketing, because that’s what will get your home sold at the highest possible price here in the Santa Clarita market.

If you hire that guy you found on Craigslist, you might think you’ll save $5,000. However, the money you’re ‘saving’ actually hurts you because you won’t make as much as you could due to the lack of marketing and exposure for your home. We, on the other hand, will do things the right way at a high level to get you to the best quality offers and the highest possible sales price.

If you have any questions about how we can accomplish this, I’d love to explain a little more about what we do differently than the other teams. Just give me a call or send me an email soon—I look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Randy+Plaice/Videos/2017/Why+We+Charge+You+the+Standard+6%2525+Commission+-+Santa+Clarita+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://randyplaiceandassociatesblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Randy+Plaice/Videos/2017/Why+We+Charge+You+the+Standard+6%2525+Commission+-+Santa+Clarita+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What do you really get when you work with a real estate agent who agrees to work for a commission lower than the standard amount? Time is money, and your home sale will suffer in the end.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Randy Plaice</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What do you really get when you work with a real estate agent who agrees to work for a commission lower than the standard amount? Time is money, and your home sale will suffer in the end.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valencia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Should You Consider a Move to Santa Clarita?</title>
        <link>http://randyplaiceandassociatesblog.com/why-should-you-consider-a-move-to-santa-clarita.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Randy Plaice</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-09 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Randy+Plaice/Videos/2017/Why+Should+You+Consider+a+Move+to+Santa+Clarita%253F+-+Santa+Clarita+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Santa Clarita is a great place to live. How do I know? I’ve lived here for years and there are a ton of great benefits to owning a home in this area. 

The main reason I moved here was for my kids. I wanted them to grow up in a safe environment with a great school district. That was my No. 1 concern, a concern I share with a lot of people that choose to move here. 

In terms of home value, you get a lot of bang for your buck in Santa Clarita. It’s an affordable place to live, which is always near the top of homebuyers’ lists. 

“I can get to the Staples Center in 40 minutes.”

A lot of people think that Santa Clarita is way off the beaten path, but it’s really not. I have season tickets to the Lakers and I’m able to get to the Staples Center in around 40 minutes. There are also a lot of great shops and restaurants here, so you aren’t really missing out on anything in the city. If you feel like you are, the good news is that you are still close enough to enjoy everything LA has to offer.

If you have any questions about Santa Clarita or are interested in buying or selling a home here, give us a call or send us an email. We would love to hear from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Randy+Plaice/Videos/2017/Why+Should+You+Consider+a+Move+to+Santa+Clarita%253F+-+Santa+Clarita+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://randyplaiceandassociatesblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Randy+Plaice/Videos/2017/Why+Should+You+Consider+a+Move+to+Santa+Clarita%253F+-+Santa+Clarita+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Santa Clarita is a great place to raise a family in Southern California. I know from experience.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Randy Plaice</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Santa Clarita is a great place to raise a family in Southern California. I know from experience.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valencia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Real Estate Teams vs. Individual Agents</title>
        <link>http://randyplaiceandassociatesblog.com/real-estate-teams-vs-individual-agents.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Randy Plaice</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-20 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Randy+Plaice/Videos/2017/Real+Estate+Teams+vs.+Individual+Agents+-+Santa+Clarita+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I often get asked why I started a real estate team. What is the benefit of hiring a real estate team instead of working with a solo agent?

I started out as an individual agent, like most people do. I tried to do everything. As you know, our business covers a lot of territory; there are legal aspects, documents, negotiation, finding and searching for homes, marketing, and more.

While we always try to get better and improve, there are some areas of the business that you will be naturally good at and other areas that you will struggle in. I decided to assemble a team of real estate agents to counterbalance my strengths and offset my weaknesses. In other words, we are specialists instead of generalists.

“You can hire eight people for the price of one when you hire a team.”

Basically, I focus on negotiations. It’s an area that I love and that I’m very good at. I also focus on marketing because that’s what I studied in school.

In terms of finding homes or overseeing the documents that are part of a deal, I’m still a part of it to make sure that things are done correctly and comprehensively. However, we have specialists who oversee those aspects so that you are served at the highest level.

The other huge benefit is that hiring a real estate team costs the same.Instead of paying for an individual agent who will do a great job at some parts of the transactions, you can pay eight specialists to handle your transaction for the price of one.

If you have any other questions about real estate teams versus individual agents, just give us a call or send us an email. My team and I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Randy+Plaice/Videos/2017/Real+Estate+Teams+vs.+Individual+Agents+-+Santa+Clarita+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://randyplaiceandassociatesblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Randy+Plaice/Videos/2017/Real+Estate+Teams+vs.+Individual+Agents+-+Santa+Clarita+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What is the benefit of working with a real estate team rather than an individual agent? The main reason to hire a real estate team is you will have a team of specialists working on your behalf.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Randy Plaice</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What is the benefit of working with a real estate team rather than an individual agent? The main reason to hire a real estate team is you will have a team of specialists working on your behalf.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valencia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Waiting to Buy May Cost You a Home</title>
        <link>http://randyplaiceandassociatesblog.com/waiting-to-buy-may-cost-you-a-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Randy Plaice</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-03 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Randy+Plaice/Videos/2017/Waiting+to+Buy+May+Cost+You+-+Santa+Clarita+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

A lot of people have been asking us lately how they should time their move. They want to know if they should take action now and buy or wait for even better conditions. Because rates are so low right now, it really makes sense to take advantage of them right now by buying a home. The cost of buying a home is way more affordable right now than it will be a year from now most likely. 

That means you can afford a larger home now for the same price than you will be able to when rates go up. You could also get a home in a better location. You have a ton of options right now, so we recommend you start exploring them. Come to the office, let’s talk about your wants and needs in a home, and we can even talk about what a home purchase will cost you now versus what it would cost you if rates went up. 

“Come to the office, let’s talk about what your wants and needs are.”

As your consultant, that’s our job. We want to inform you in a way that will help you win and help you get in the best situation possible. 

If you have any questions for us, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Randy+Plaice/Videos/2017/Waiting+to+Buy+May+Cost+You+-+Santa+Clarita+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://randyplaiceandassociatesblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Randy+Plaice/Videos/2017/Waiting+to+Buy+May+Cost+You+-+Santa+Clarita+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Waiting to buy could really cost you. Not only will you be able to afford less of a home when interest rates inevitably go up, you will have to pay more for it.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Randy Plaice</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Waiting to buy could really cost you. Not only will you be able to afford less of a home when interest rates inevitably go up, you will have to pay more for it.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valencia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Is it Smart to Buy or Sell in Winter?</title>
        <link>http://randyplaiceandassociatesblog.com/why-is-it-smart-to-buy-or-sell-in-winter.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
          <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Randy Plaice</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-10 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Randy+Plaice/Videos/2017/Make+It+Happen+This+Winter+-+Santa+Clarita+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Conventional wisdom says that the spring is the ideal time to be in the real estate market because it’s when activity is the highest. While that may be a valid argument in certain instances, the fact of the matter is that there are still buyers and sellers out in the market during the winter.

The main difference between buyers in the spring and summer and buyers in the winter is that the winter buyers are much more motivated. They are out in the cold and willing to hunt for the right home. Usually, their offers are more appealing and they are a little more excited to get a deal done.

“Interest rates are creeping up”

Interest rates are starting to adjust, and not for the better. They’re going up a bit, which is ultimately going to make homes more expensive for buyers. We want to make sure we are listing homes now to capitalize on interest from buyers while rates are still favorable. When they go up in the spring, buyers won’t be able to afford as much.

One of the great value adds you have by deciding to list now is that it’s a beautiful time of year to show a home. The festive atmosphere gives a great sense of community to your home, and it’s also great for photography and video. People connect with homes differently this time of year, and they can develop that sense of connection easier.

If you have any questions about buying or selling during the winter, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Randy+Plaice/Videos/2017/Make+It+Happen+This+Winter+-+Santa+Clarita+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://randyplaiceandassociatesblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Randy+Plaice/Videos/2017/Make+It+Happen+This+Winter+-+Santa+Clarita+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>The winter is a great time to buy or sell a home. There are a number of advantages you won’t get in the spring or summer.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Randy Plaice</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>The winter is a great time to buy or sell a home. There are a number of advantages you won’t get in the spring or summer.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valencia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Randy Plaice</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Randy Plaice</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Randy Plaice &amp; Associates - your professional Valencia Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
