<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Florida's Emerald Coast Real Estate Podcast with Nathan Abbott</title>
    <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://ownemeraldcoast.com"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Nathan Abbott Team - your professional Florida's Emerald Coast Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Nathan Abbott</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2018-03-07 15:41:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Nathan Abbott</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://ownemeraldcoast.com/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Florida's Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">News &amp; Politics</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Nathan@NathanAbbottTeam.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Nathan Abbott</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Nathan Abbott</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://ownemeraldcoast.com/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Florida's Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Florida's Emerald Coast Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Nathan Abbott Team - your professional Florida's Emerald Coast Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="News &amp; Politics"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Recap of Our Amazing Retreat in Port St. Joe</title>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/a-recap-of-our-amazing-retreat-in-port-st-joe.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Nathan Abbott</author>
        <pubDate>2018-03-01 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/2018/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+We+Deliver+Expert+Local+Advice+Throughout+Our+Coastline.mp4</guid>
        <description>

We’re currently in Port St. Joe, Florida, which is also known as “Florida’s forgotten coast.” A lot of our clams and oysters are harvested out of this bay. There’s so much untouched beauty here, and I love visiting.

My recent trip out here was a special one because it was with my team.As a team, it’s great to get out of the office setting, spend some quality time with each other, and then come back and serve our customers on a much higher level because we work together better.

“This was great for our team to spend some quality time together.”

We are natives to Northwest Florida and live a coastal lifestyle, and we can deliver expert local advice for our customers in order to deliver the ultimate results that they desire.

If you have any questions for us about the real estate market, buying or selling a home, or anything else, give us a call or send us an email today. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/2018/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+We+Deliver+Expert+Local+Advice+Throughout+Our+Coastline.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://ownemeraldcoast.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/2018/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+We+Deliver+Expert+Local+Advice+Throughout+Our+Coastline.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>My team and I recently had a retreat in Port St. Joe. Here’s a look at what we did.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nathan Abbott</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>My team and I recently had a retreat in Port St. Joe. Here’s a look at what we did.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Florida's Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Making Memories Through Real Estate</title>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/making-memories-through-real-estate.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Nathan Abbott</author>
        <pubDate>2018-02-06 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Making+Memories+Through+Real+Estate.mp4</guid>
        <description>

One of the greatest things about being in real estate is the people that you meet along the way and the memories you share with the people that you serve.

I recently got back from one of the most amazing vacations. I’ve been snowboarding since I was a kid, and I’ve always been really into the outdoors.

I just got back from Bella Coola in British Columbia. Bella Coola is one of the most remote mountain regions in the world. There are 2.5 million acres of terrain. You have to take a prop plane, a two-day boat ride, or drive through the mountains for 12 hours to get to civilization, a.k.a. Vancouver.

“I was able to share this amazing experience with three different people I’ve served in real estate transactions.”

I was able to share this amazing experience with three different people that I’ve served in real estate transactions. They all had a passion for skiing or snowboarding like I did. I put the trip together on a whim, and we just got back with some great memories that we will share for the rest of our lives.

Check out the video above for a short film of our skiing adventure. I hope to create some great memories with you as well.

If you have any real estate questions, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Making+Memories+Through+Real+Estate.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://ownemeraldcoast.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Making+Memories+Through+Real+Estate.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>One of the best things about working in real estate is the people I meet and the memories we share. I took three past clients to Bella Coola, and we had a great time!</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nathan Abbott</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>One of the best things about working in real estate is the people I meet and the memories we share. I took three past clients to Bella Coola, and we had a great time!</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Florida's Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Prepare for Unexpected Costs After Closing</title>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/how-to-prepare-for-unexpected-costs-after-closing.html</link>
        
          <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Nathan Abbott</author>
        <pubDate>2017-12-22 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Budget+for+these+costs+after+closing.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Buying a new real estate property is exciting, but they often come along with some unexpected expenses right after closing.

People commonly forget about these expenses and they can certainly add up. Here are just a few examples:


  Moving expenses.
  New furniture.
  Window treatments.
  Dishes and cutlery.
  Shower curtains.


“I was amazed when I bought my first home to see just how lengthy and expensive a process it was.”

There are many more beyond what I’ve listed. I was amazed when I bought my first home to see just how lengthy and expensive a process it was to fully furnish and decorate the home. Between shelving, appliances, paper goods, and more, fine details can really add up.

For that reason, it’s important to do some budgeting beforehand. Compile a list of the things you’ll need when you move in so that you aren’t surprised at the additional costs associated with your new home. However, don’t buy these items prior to closing. This can have a negative impact on your loan.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Budget+for+these+costs+after+closing.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://ownemeraldcoast.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Budget+for+these+costs+after+closing.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Buying a new real estate property is exciting, but they often come along with some unexpected expenses right after closing.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nathan Abbott</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Buying a new real estate property is exciting, but they often come along with some unexpected expenses right after closing.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Florida's Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Paradise in Northwest Florida</title>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/paradise-in-northwest-florida.html</link>
        
          <category>Outdoor Entertainment</category>
        
        <author>Nathan Abbott</author>
        <pubDate>2017-12-13 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Explore+Defuniak+Springs+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>

We’re doing a little bit of exploring today.

Defuniak Springs is a beautiful area with tons of countryside, and it’s only an hour north of the beach.

There are a lot of great places to explore in Northwest Florida and Defuniak is definitely one of those areas. Downtown Defuniak Springs has a charming, small-town feel, and was recently rated one of the best small towns in the Southeast.

“See the beauty that Defuniak Springs has to offer.”

I highly recommend that you get out, explore a bit, and see the beauty that Northwest Florida has to offer.

Check out the video above to see more of Defuniak Springs.

If you have any real estate questions, I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Explore+Defuniak+Springs+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://ownemeraldcoast.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Explore+Defuniak+Springs+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>We’re doing a little bit of exploring today.   Defuniak Springs is a beautiful area with tons of countryside, and it’s only an hour north of the beach.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nathan Abbott</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We’re doing a little bit of exploring today.   Defuniak Springs is a beautiful area with tons of countryside, and it’s only an hour north of the beach.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Florida's Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Experience Florida at Deer Lake State Park</title>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/experience-florida-at-deer-lake-state-park.html</link>
        
          <category>Outdoor Entertainment</category>
        
        <author>Nathan Abbott</author>
        <pubDate>2017-12-01 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Video+tour+of+Deer+Lake+State+Park.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Located in Seagrove Beach, Deer Lake State Park provides a great opportunity for people to explore Florida in it’s natural state. The park is nestled between the Watersound community to the immediate east and Deer Lake Dunes and Seclusion Dunes to the west. Between the beautiful scenery and the beach, which is accessible by way of the boardwalk, a visit to Deer Lake State Park is a great experience. To see the full tour, watch this short video.

“A visit to Deer Lake State Park is a great experience.”
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Video+tour+of+Deer+Lake+State+Park.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://ownemeraldcoast.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Video+tour+of+Deer+Lake+State+Park.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Located in Seagrove Beach, Deer Lake State Park provides a great opportunity for people to explore Florida in it’s natural state.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nathan Abbott</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Located in Seagrove Beach, Deer Lake State Park provides a great opportunity for people to explore Florida in it’s natural state.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Florida's Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Sitting Down With Mike Ragsdale of 30A.com</title>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/sitting-down-with-mike-ragsdale-of-30a-com.html</link>
        
          <category>Outdoor Entertainment</category>
        
        <author>Nathan Abbott</author>
        <pubDate>2017-11-08 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+An+interview+with+Mike+Ragsdale+of+30A.com.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Mike Ragsdale, owner and founder of 30A.com, has an amazing story behind the foundation of the 30A brand, and I’m proud to be able to interview him and share that story with you.

Mike business background started at the University of Alabama, where he graduated with a master’s degree in advertising and public relations. “Despite how clever and educated I thought I was, I couldn’t get a job,” Mike recalls. He then bought a computer and forced himself to start a graphic design business. He ran that company successfully for seven years, and it grew in size to about 60 or 70 employees. After that, though, he had a long string of business failures. Those failures, however, led him to move to the Emerald Coast and start 30A.

Mike had been vacationing in this area for years, and he always felt that it was a special place. “The natural beauty is just unparalleled, and it felt like the perfect place to raise a family,” he says. When he arrived at the Emerald Coast, the area didn’t have a cohesive brand. 30A was not used to the degree that it is today—a company in Texas actually owned the URL. Every individual community in the Emerald Coast had its own brand, but the one thing that tied all of them together was Highway 30A.

“Today, we really don’t view it as a location—we view it as a lifestyle.” What he means when he says that is scenic 30A here in South Walton is just one of four 30A roads. State Road 30 runs from the Alabama state line to Perry, Florida, and there are four alternate routes (hence the “A”) that branch off that old state highway. 30A isn’t just here—there’s also a 30A in Bay County and two 30As in Franklin County. To him, the 30A idea evokes small-town America and “old” Florida.

“It’s a lifestyle brand, not a tourism brand.”

Mike originally moved here to become a writer, so he initially bought the 30A.com domain name to be a blog. He had no intention of turning it into a business, but after several years of developing the URL, people started asking him if they could advertise on the site, and he agreed. He describes this evolution as “very organic and unintentional.”

Today, 30A.com has three different divisions: the digital division, the retail division, and licensing division.The digital division includes their radio station, mobile app, Facebook page, and their websites. Their retail division includes their four 30A stores, but their apparel can be found in over 100 locations nationwide. “Think of it as Patagonia,” he explains. “Patagonia is a place, but you don’t have to go to Argentina to wear Patagonia apparel.” Their licensing division takes first-class products and licenses their brand to the companies that produce them.

Mike was surprised by how fast his company grew, but as an entrepreneur, he always has an eye for growth and business. Having 900,000 Facebook fans is something he never really anticipated, but he thinks they’re just getting started, and they’re now focused on taking the brand national. Not the tourism brand—the lifestyle brand.

“I tell people it’s small-town America at the beach, and that’s what we’re trying to capture in everything that we do.”

As to where 30A.com ranks online, it’s difficult to say and depends on a few different metrics. To them, though, the goal isn’t about online rankings. They view their website as a way to share stories. Everything they do in their company comes down to four words: “We love the beach.” That could mean loving it in ways that include music, cocktails, food, and lifestyle, and also loving it in ways that mean preserving and protecting the beach itself. That’s where they feel the company is going as much as the digital side.

What’s next for 30A.com? They’re about to launch their 30A Sessions concert, and they have Lady Antebellum as their first opening act. They also have several shows coming up next year featuring big names and world-class talent which will be captured for broadcasts on major networks.

30A is a blessing for our area, and we’re glad they’re here. We all look forward to seeing what’s next for them. If you have any questions about this interview, feel free to reach out to me. I’d be happy to chat with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+An+interview+with+Mike+Ragsdale+of+30A.com.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://ownemeraldcoast.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+An+interview+with+Mike+Ragsdale+of+30A.com.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Mike Ragsdale, owner and founder of 30A.com, has an amazing story behind the foundation of the 30A brand, and I’m proud to be able to interview him and share that story with you.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nathan Abbott</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Mike Ragsdale, owner and founder of 30A.com, has an amazing story behind the foundation of the 30A brand, and I’m proud to be able to interview him and share that story with you.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Florida's Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Fall 2017 Northwest Florida Housing Update</title>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/fall-2017-northwest-florida-housing-update.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Nathan Abbott</author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-26 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Fall is upon us, and with it the end of the high season for real estate.However, if you’re thinking you’ve missed your chance to sell your home, let me reassure you.This autumn actually presents a fantastic moment to sell. Here’s why.First off, housing inventory is still pretty low along the Emerald Coast.In fact, according to data from the Census Bureau and the National Association of Realtors, inventory remains well below historic averages, and is 50% less than the peak in 2006.Second, while mortgage rates also remain very low, recent announcements by the Federal Reserve might cause them to finally start rising.This would make mortgages less affordable and might turn away a significant number of potential buyers.This is even more of a concern when you consider the continuing growth of home prices—6.9% in the last year alone.Third, contrary to conventional wisdom, fall is generally a great time to list your home.Buyers in the fall are likely to be more serious because they have probably been searching for months without success.Also, because fewer homes are listed in the fall, this means there’s even less competition than we’ve seen due to the general low inventory.So what do you get when you put all those things together?Well, if you were to list your home right now, chances are good that you would be able to sell it and for a solid price.On the other hand, if you decide to wait, the situation might not be as favorable because mortgage rates might rise or because new construction might pick up.That means the time to list your home is now.You can get started with this home value calculator on my website, which takes into account recent Northwest Florida sales:Enter your home address to find out what your home is currently worth.This calculator will give you a good idea of what your home is worth.And if you would like a more precise estimate of what your home could sell for this fall, or if you have any other questions about the current Destin real estate situation, give me a call at 850.632.0136. I’m here to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://ownemeraldcoast.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Fall is upon us, and with it the end of the high season for real estate.However, if you’re thinking you’ve missed your chance to sell your home, let me reassure you.This autumn actually presents a fantastic moment to sell. Here’s why.First off, housing inventory is still pretty low along the Emerald Coast.In fact, according to data from the Census Bureau and the National Association of Realtors, inventory remains well below historic averages, and is 50% less than the peak in 2006.Second, while mortgage rates also remain very low, recent announcements by the Federal Reserve might cause them to finally start rising.This would make mortgages less affordable and might turn away a significant number of potential buyers.This is even more of a concern when you consider the continuing growth of home prices—6.9% in the last year alone.Third, contrary to conventional wisdom, fall is generally a great time to list your home.Buyers in the fall are likely to be more serious because they have probably been searching for months without success.Also, because fewer homes are listed in the fall, this means there’s even less competition than we’ve seen due to the general low inventory.So what do you get when you put all those things together?Well, if you were to list your home right now, chances are good that you would be able to sell it and for a solid price.On the other hand, if you decide to wait, the situation might not be as favorable because mortgage rates might rise or because new construction might pick up.That means the time to list your home is now.You can get started with this home value calculator on my website, which takes into account recent Northwest Florida sales:Enter your home address to find out what your home is currently worth.This calculator will give you a good idea of what your home is worth.And if you would like a more precise estimate of what your home could sell for this fall, or if you have any other questions about the current Destin real estate situation, give me a call at 850.632.0136. I’m here to help.
</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nathan Abbott</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Fall is upon us, and with it the end of the high season for real estate.However, if you’re thinking you’ve missed your chance to sell your home, let me reassure you.This autumn actually presents a fantastic moment to sell. Here’s why.First off, housing inventory is still pretty low along the Emerald Coast.In fact, according to data from the Census Bureau and the National Association of Realtors, inventory remains well below historic averages, and is 50% less than the peak in 2006.Second, while mortgage rates also remain very low, recent announcements by the Federal Reserve might cause them to finally start rising.This would make mortgages less affordable and might turn away a significant number of potential buyers.This is even more of a concern when you consider the continuing growth of home prices—6.9% in the last year alone.Third, contrary to conventional wisdom, fall is generally a great time to list your home.Buyers in the fall are likely to be more serious because they have probably been searching for months without success.Also, because fewer homes are listed in the fall, this means there’s even less competition than we’ve seen due to the general low inventory.So what do you get when you put all those things together?Well, if you were to list your home right now, chances are good that you would be able to sell it and for a solid price.On the other hand, if you decide to wait, the situation might not be as favorable because mortgage rates might rise or because new construction might pick up.That means the time to list your home is now.You can get started with this home value calculator on my website, which takes into account recent Northwest Florida sales:Enter your home address to find out what your home is currently worth.This calculator will give you a good idea of what your home is worth.And if you would like a more precise estimate of what your home could sell for this fall, or if you have any other questions about the current Destin real estate situation, give me a call at 850.632.0136. I’m here to help.
</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Florida's Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Can the Tortoise Clinic Do for You?</title>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/what-can-the-tortoise-clinic-do-for-you.html</link>
        
          <category>Venue Reviews</category>
        
        <author>Nathan Abbott</author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-18 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+What+can+acupuncture+really+do%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I’m super excited to bring you a look at a place my family and I have been visiting for years: the Tortoise Clinic. The acupuncture and herbal medicine they provide here are both absolutely amazing.

To help me explain what the clinic does, I spoke with medical director Drew Smith. Drew first got involved in acupuncture fairly early in life. In middle school, he developed an interest in martial arts and in Eastern culture in general.

It was specifically his junior year in high school when Drew says he first stumbled across the subject of Eastern medicine. He was browsing the shelves at a bookstore when he came across some material on the subject and was immediately fascinated.

After graduating, Drew went on to graduate school at Florida State University. There, he met his future wife. When she had to return home to Japan, he knew he had to do whatever it took to follow her there.

He received a scholarship from the Japanese government, allowing him to pick any university and course of study. On his second day of classes, he met a neighbor who happened to be a scholar of Chinese medicine The two began to practice tai chi together in the parks on campus.

Drew briefly returned to FSU, but then returned to Japan. He had sustained some injuries from judo, and found that Eastern medical treatments worked very well for them. From then on, he knew he wanted to study this kind of medicine. So, he found a school in Maryland and has been working in related fields since

“The possibilities for what Eastern medicine can achieve are as broad as the field itself.”

With all of that traveling, I wondered why Drew returned specifically to the Emerald Coast. He told me that since he grew up in Florida, he had always known and thought of our area as the state’s “sweet spot.” He didn’t originally have plans of returning to Florida, but ultimately wanted to fully pursue acupuncture and Eastern healing.

Having previously worked in a chiropractic clinic, he knew it was time to pursue his passion. It was actually when he saw an ad for an acupuncture business online that he decided to reply and see what would happen. That’s when he found the Tortoise Clinic. Next thing Drew knew, he and his wife moved to the area and have been here for nearly 10 years.

As far as the benefits of acupuncture and eastern medicine, Drew believes the possibilities are as broad as the field itself.  He says you could spend a lifetime studying the use of plants as medicine, and there would still be more to learn. In order to do this for a living, he believes you have to be able to help every pain there is.

Personally, he enjoys helping people boost their fertility. He also says that acupuncture can benefit people emotionally and digestively. Eastern medicine has been around for so long and is largely about your body healing itself through stimulation from acupuncture and herbal medicine.

If you’d like to learn more about the Tortoise Clinic, you can visit their website at www.TheTortoiseClinic.com. To drop by in person, simply go to 2441 US Highway 98 W Unit 111, Santa Rosa Beach. Their phone number is (850) 267-5611. I highly recommend checking them out.

Also, for all of your real estate needs, call The Nathan Abbott Team at (850) 632-0136. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+What+can+acupuncture+really+do%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://ownemeraldcoast.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+What+can+acupuncture+really+do%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I’m super excited to bring you a look at a place my family and I have been visiting for years: the Tortoise Clinic. The acupuncture and herbal medicine they provide here are both absolutely amazing.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nathan Abbott</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I’m super excited to bring you a look at a place my family and I have been visiting for years: the Tortoise Clinic. The acupuncture and herbal medicine they provide here are both absolutely amazing.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Florida's Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Have You Been to the Sunset Bay Cafe?</title>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/have-you-been-to-the-sunset-bay-cafe.html</link>
        
          <category>Venue Reviews</category>
        
        <author>Nathan Abbott</author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-05 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Have+you+been+to+Sunset+Bay+Cafe%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

We’re here today at the Sunset Bay Cafe with owner Bryce Jarvis. He’s here to talk a little bit about his restaurant and why you will love it the next time you stop in for a bite.

Back in high school, Bryce worked in banquet setup with Abbott Resorts. He turned that experience into over 20 years of working in restaurants. Now, he has one of his own.

When Bryce was looking for a location for his restaurant, he wanted something unique. He found that at Sandestin Resort, where Sunset Bay Cafe is located. There’s plenty of parking and space inside the restaurant and out on the patio. The vision was to put together a nice, family-friendly restaurant that you could come to for any occasion. That vision has clearly been realized.

“The menu is as diverse as it is delicious.”

The menu is as diverse as it is delicious. For breakfast, Bryce recommends the Hillbilly Benedict. It consists of a fried gouda grit cake, topped with a fried chicken breast, a poached egg, and hollandaise. For lunch, their shrimp and grits is the way to go. Gouda grits, blackened shrimp, and a delicious red-eye gravy to top it off.It’s fantastic.

Sunset Bay Cafe is located right on the Sandestin Golf and Beach Resort inside of the Linkside Conference Center at 158 Sandestin Boulevard N. You can learn plenty more about them at www.sunsetbaycafesandestin.com.

In the meantime, if you have any real estate needs we can help fulfill or any questions at all, don’t hesitate to reach out and give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Have+you+been+to+Sunset+Bay+Cafe%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://ownemeraldcoast.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Have+you+been+to+Sunset+Bay+Cafe%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>We’re here today at the Sunset Bay Cafe with owner Bryce Jarvis. He’s here to talk a little bit about his restaurant and why you will love it the next time you stop in for a bite.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nathan Abbott</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We’re here today at the Sunset Bay Cafe with owner Bryce Jarvis. He’s here to talk a little bit about his restaurant and why you will love it the next time you stop in for a bite.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Florida's Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Here Are a Few Examples of the Beautiful Homes in Paradise Cove</title>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/here-are-a-few-examples-of-the-beautiful-homes-in-paradise-cove.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Nathan Abbott</author>
        <pubDate>2017-09-20 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Lovely+Paradise+Cove+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>

Boswell Builders have been building amazing custom homes along the Emerald Coast for over 40 years and bring an incredible level of expertise to our marketplace. You’ll see it in the level of interior detail they have in the model homes shown above.

Boswell filled an immediate need for high-quality new construction homes at an affordable price. This is how Paradise Cove was created. The homes here are priced starting at $350,000 and you’ll certainly be proud of whichever home you choose.

The Pineview floorplan is a 4-bedroom, 3.5-bathroom with 2,441 sq ft. There are a lot of great custom features in here and it’s in a great price point for this community. It also has a great open floor plan that transitions from living room, to dining room, to kitchen.

“Most builders charge extra for these features.”

In addition to the great kitchen, here are a few other amenities you’ll find in these Boswell homes:


  Self-closing drawers
  Stainless steel appliances
  Granite countertops in the kitchen and bathrooms
  Full chef’s kitchen


A lot of builders charge extra for features like these, but they’re automatically included in all of these homes. The master bedroom in this floorplan is great as well. It lets in a lot of natural light and has a spacious closet and bathroom.

As you can see, these homes in Paradise Cove have all the elements that you’d be proud of at your primary residence. To learn more about the community and the homes within it, visit the Paradise Cove website here.

If you have any questions for us or you’d like to tour one of these beautiful homes, give us a call or send us an email. We are open seven days a week and would love to hear from you today.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Lovely+Paradise+Cove+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://ownemeraldcoast.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Lovely+Paradise+Cove+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Boswell Builders have been building amazing custom homes along the Emerald Coast for over 40 years and bring an incredible level of expertise to our marketplace. You’ll see it in the level of interior detail they have in the model homes shown above.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nathan Abbott</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Boswell Builders have been building amazing custom homes along the Emerald Coast for over 40 years and bring an incredible level of expertise to our marketplace. You’ll see it in the level of interior detail they have in the model homes shown above.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Florida's Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Have You Tried Cuvée Kitchen and Wine Bar?</title>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/have-you-tried-cuv%C3%A9e-kitchen-and-wine-bar.html</link>
        
          <category>Venue Reviews</category>
        
        <author>Nathan Abbott</author>
        <pubDate>2017-09-06 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Have+you+tried+this+unique+local+restaurant%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I’m excited to feature a great local restaurant that is sure to impress: Cuvée Kitchen and Wine Bar.

The owners, Chris Ruyan and Tyler Jarvis, are both experienced restaurateurs here on the Emerald Coast. On top of Cuvée Kitchen, they also own Jackacudas and Brotula’s Seafood House and Steamer.

Since I had the opportunity to sit down with Chris and Tyler, I decided to ask them a few questions.

First, I wanted to know how the inspiration for Cuvée Kitchen came to light. According to Chris, it was an evolution of their shared vision for restaurants they enjoyed. Chris and Tyler wanted to create a great menu as well as an amazing atmosphere. From the beginning, they wanted Cuvée Kitchen to be a place where people could gather to enjoy food, drink, and company.

Staying true to this vision is something that has always been important to them—even now following their recent relaunch of the restaurant. The space has been opened up and the format of the dining experience has been changed, as well.

“Cuvée Kitchen is a place where people can gather to enjoy food, drink, and company.”

Social interaction through intimate spacing, small plates, and craft-style cocktails are all key features that Chris and Tyler have tried to bring with this relaunch. They wanted to create a fun and interactive experience instead of the more quiet atmosphere that is usually associated with upscale dining.

Also, because they use fresh ingredients, the cuisine at Cuvée Kitchen is always unique. The chefs have a lot of freedom to create different items on a daily basis. Recently, Chris and Tyler have begun to think about implementing a rotation-style menu that would change four times a year depending on the season.

But the food isn’t all that makes Cuvée Kitchen unique. The restaurant also offers a wide variety of cocktails. Cuvée Kitchen carries a lot of different craft cocktails that aren’t typically found in the area, as well as some imported spirits.

The “Corrupt Bargain” cocktail is Tyler’s personal favorite. A spin on a traditional Manhattan, the Corrupt Bargain is a blend of single barrel and rye whiskey complemented with Carpano Antica and vermouth. Finally, the drink also has a flamed orange peel, which provides a unique and delicious smokiness.

Food and drink aren’t the only things Cuvée Kitchen has to offer. Each week from Monday through Saturday between 5 p.m. and 7 p.m., the restaurant hosts a social hour. From 9 p.m. to close on those same days, you can experience the reverse social hour.

Each of these hours will feature small bites, sushi, local fish beignets, cocktails, and more.

To learn more about Cuvée Kitchen, you can visit their website: www.CuveeKitchen.com. Also, if you’re interested in dropping by to experience it for yourself, you can find the restaurant in downtown Destin at 26120 Emerald Coast Parkway.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Have+you+tried+this+unique+local+restaurant%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://ownemeraldcoast.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Have+you+tried+this+unique+local+restaurant%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I’m excited to feature a great local restaurant that is sure to impress: Cuvée Kitchen and Wine Bar.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nathan Abbott</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I’m excited to feature a great local restaurant that is sure to impress: Cuvée Kitchen and Wine Bar.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Florida's Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring Northwest Florida With the Surfing Realtor</title>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/exploring-northwest-florida-with-the-surfing-realtor.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Nathan Abbott</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-15 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Meet+the+Surfing+Realtor.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Recently, my sister Amanda Abbott was featured on Wyndham’s website. Amanda is a fantastic real estate agent who enjoys exploring all that Northwest Florida has to offer.

Our dad and our uncle started one of the first real estate companies in the area—Abbott Realty. I jumped into the real estate business soon after college, but Amanda explored a little before returning home and becoming an agent in her own right.

Somebody once called her “the Surfing Realtor,” which is a good fit. “My favorite thing is to be in the water,” says Amanda. “That’s when I feel most at peace.”

“Amanda encourages others to find a balance between hard work and taking time for yourself.”

If you grew up in Northwest Florida like we did, it can be easy to take the beauty around us for granted. However, Amanda is constantly exploring. She surfs, paddleboards, and motorbikes all around the area. “I’ve traveled all over the world, and I still think it’s one of the nicest places to be,” she says.

Amanda really believes in finding a balance between working hard and taking time for herself. She tries to encourage everyone else to do that, as well. She also does a great job helping her clients find amazing homes that encourage a wonderful lifestyle.

You can see a little of how Amanda spends her days in the video above. Congratulations on such a wonderful spotlight, Amanda!

As always, if you have any real estate questions, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you.


  Nathan Abbott

</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Meet+the+Surfing+Realtor.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://ownemeraldcoast.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Meet+the+Surfing+Realtor.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Recently, my sister Amanda Abbott was featured on Wyndham's website. Amanda is a fantastic real estate agent who enjoys exploring all that Northwest Florida has to offer.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nathan Abbott</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Recently, my sister Amanda Abbott was featured on Wyndham's website. Amanda is a fantastic real estate agent who enjoys exploring all that Northwest Florida has to offer.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Florida's Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Explore Grayton Beach State Park for Free Before Labor Day</title>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/explore-grayton-beach-state-park-for-free-before-labor-day.html</link>
        
          <category>Outdoor Entertainment</category>
        
        <author>Nathan Abbott</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-26 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Have+you+explored+Grayton+Beach%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Instead of talking about Northwest Florida real estate, today I want to bring you along on a tour of Grayton Beach State Park.

We locals often don’t take advantage of the number of stunning state parks around the Emerald Coast. We tend to forget how special these places are. A lot of tourists may not even know about these places.

Grayton Beach is a great way to really escape and enjoy Florida’s stunning natural landscape.

This park is just north of Watercolor and there is a beautiful, natural beach right near a great coastal lake that you can see in the video above.

Western Lake is also the perfect place to paddleboard or kayak. It’s a 100-acre coastal dune lake located right in the park.

“Grayton Beach is a great place to escape and enjoy the beauty of Florida.”

I highly recommend this park. The Florida State Parks are all fantastic, and Grayton Beach will be open to the public for free through Labor Day. It really is a great place to take your family and just explore.

For more details about Grayton Beach, check out this website. I hope you take some time to get out there and roam through this beautiful state park.

In the meantime, if you have any real estate questions, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Have+you+explored+Grayton+Beach%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://ownemeraldcoast.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Have+you+explored+Grayton+Beach%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Instead of talking about Northwest Florida real estate, today I want to bring you along on a tour of Grayton Beach State Park.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nathan Abbott</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Instead of talking about Northwest Florida real estate, today I want to bring you along on a tour of Grayton Beach State Park.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Florida's Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Have You Visited The HUB at 30A?</title>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/have-you-visited-the-hub-at-30a.html</link>
        
          <category>Outdoor Entertainment</category>
        
        <author>Nathan Abbott</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-17 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Video+tour+of+The+HUB+at+30A.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Recently, I took some time to visit The HUB at 30A.

This amazing outdoor venue has a lot of covered areas and about 10 different dining options as well as several bars. Additionally, there’s a shopping pavilion outside of the amphitheater.

The complex also holds a lot of events, typically as often as four nights each week.

This includes live music, movie nights, and football games shown on the big screen on Sundays—both of which really pack the venue in the evenings.

“The complex also holds a lot of events, typically as often as four nights each week.”

With as many options as there are for food and drink, including a nice wrap-around bar, it’s a great place to visit.

On top of everything, the venue is very conveniently located—right outside of Watersound just down from Rosemary. It’s centered within the Prominence subdivision that offers new homes and townhomes on the market. You don’t have to leave to entertain. Check out The HUB and Prominence today.

If you have any questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Video+tour+of+The+HUB+at+30A.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://ownemeraldcoast.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Video+tour+of+The+HUB+at+30A.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Recently, I took some time to visit The HUB at 30A.  This amazing outdoor venue has a lot of covered areas...</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nathan Abbott</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Recently, I took some time to visit The HUB at 30A.  This amazing outdoor venue has a lot of covered areas...</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Florida's Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The 10 Commandments of Buying a Home and Applying for a Mortgage</title>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/the-10-commandments-of-buying-a-home-and-applying-for-a-mortgage.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Nathan Abbott</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-06 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+The+10+commandments+of+closing+on+a+home.mp4</guid>
        <description>

We give our customers a buyer’s guide that shares the 10 commandments of things you should never do when going through the process. Today I’ve listed those ten things below:

1. Thou shalt not change your job or quit your job during the mortgage approval period. Even if you’ve been awarded a promotion or offered a chance to change your environment, you don’t want to make these changes during the loan process. Lenders like consistency, not change.

2. Thou shalt not buy furniture or decor for your home before you buy it.Sometimes people use their funds that they have set aside for the closing and buy furniture or home decor. It’s easy to get excited, but you don’t even own the home yet! Focus on the mortgage first and then when you close, you can start looking at furniture for your home.

3. Thou shalt not use credit cards excessively and miss your payment due dates. Little dings can affect your credit and you’d be surprised at how much that can put you in jeopardy of not being approved for your home loan. Keep that spending at a minimum and make your payments on time.

4. Thou shalt not buy a car, boat, truck, or any large item.It’s not a good idea to get a loan on that item, and even if you’re paying cash, it’s better to wait to make that purchase until your mortgage process is complete.

5. Thou shalt not omit debts from your credit application. A lot of times folks want to make themselves look good on paper and leave stuff off their loan application. Omitting any items could get you in trouble and jeopardize your loan process if any of those things come up.

“Lenders like consistency, not change.”

6. Thou shalt not stop paying rent or your current mortgage payment during the loan process. This can greatly affect your credit if you miss payments, and you can lose your loan approval for your new home.

7. Thou shalt not originate any inquiries to your credit during the mortgage process. Lenders don’t like a lot of change. Don’t make a lot of inquiries to your credit and keep things neutral during that process.

8. Thou shalt not cosign for someone else’s loan. You may want to help a friend or family, and they may make the payments on time, but it could affect your ability to get your loan approved so it’s best to hold off while you’re going through this process.

9. Thou shalt not make large deposits into your account without letting your lender know first. These deposits have to be verified at the source that they come from and you can get some advice from your lender about which accounts to deposit the funds into.

10. Thou shalt not change bank accounts or make a lot of transfers from one bank account to the other. You don’t want to make a lot of changes while you’re going through the mortgage process, so keep those funds where they’re at as much as possible.

If you have any questions about this topic, or you’re looking to buy or sell a home, give us a call. We’d be happy to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+The+10+commandments+of+closing+on+a+home.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://ownemeraldcoast.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+The+10+commandments+of+closing+on+a+home.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>We give our customers a buyer’s guide that shares the 10 commandments of things you should never do when going through the process. Today I’ve listed those ten things.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nathan Abbott</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We give our customers a buyer’s guide that shares the 10 commandments of things you should never do when going through the process. Today I’ve listed those ten things.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Florida's Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring the Beautiful Waterways of the Emerald Coast</title>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/exploring-the-beautiful-waterways-of-the-emerald-coast.html</link>
        
          <category>Outdoor Entertainment</category>
        
        <author>Nathan Abbott</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-14 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Cruising+the+Emerald+Coast+waterways.mp4</guid>
        <description>

One of the first things people think of when they visit the Destin area is our white sand beaches and the Gulf of Mexico, but this is also a boater’s dream with plenty of places to explore throughout all of our coastal waterways. There are so many wonderful places to explore by water to create memories that last forever.

Recently I visited the Fort Walton Beach sound on the west side of Mary Esther to do a little boating on the adjoining intercoastal waterway and along the Destin harbor. There are many beaches like the one I’m standing on in the video above scattered up and down the coastline, and we’re fortunate to live in such a beautiful area.

“We’d be honored to give you a private tour of waterfront properties if you want.”

Destin’s original tag line was “The World’s Luckiest Fishing Village” due to our vast variety of fish, but we’re now also recognized as one of the top coastal vacation destinations in the country.

We live this lifestyle and if you ever want to explore waterfront real estate opportunities by boat, we would be honored to give you a private tour. Looking at real estate and our area by water gives you a much different perspective than by land.

If you have any questions or you think you might like to take a ride to look at some waterfront properties, don’t hesitate to give me a call. You don’t have to twist my arm to get me out of the office.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Cruising+the+Emerald+Coast+waterways.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://ownemeraldcoast.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Cruising+the+Emerald+Coast+waterways.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>One of the first things people think of when they visit the Destin area is our white sand beaches and the Gulf of Mexico, but this is also a boater's dream with plenty of places to explore throughout all of our coastal waterways.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nathan Abbott</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>One of the first things people think of when they visit the Destin area is our white sand beaches and the Gulf of Mexico, but this is also a boater's dream with plenty of places to explore throughout all of our coastal waterways.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Florida's Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Should You Seek Out Low Condo Association Fees?</title>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/should-you-seek-out-low-condo-association-fees.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Nathan Abbott</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-15 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+The+pros+and+cons+of+condo+association+fees.mp4</guid>
        <description>

More often than not, whenever we have people looking for a resort condominium project to buy, the first thing they desire is low condo association fees. Is it a good idea to seek out low condo association fees, though?

No, it’s not. This is the wrong mentality to have because it could negatively affect you in the long run. When these fees are too low, the property typically isn’t being properly maintained, no reserves are being built for future replacements or improvements, and there’s not enough staff to properly run the HOA. Without these things, the building usually falls into disarray and ages much quicker.

I prefer to see a see a building that has great financials in place, whose budget is being met, and for which a constant reserve is being built for future improvements of the building. When a reserve isn’t being built, that’s when you get popped with an unexpected fee that’s a much larger amount in one bulk fee versus one that’s dispersed over time.

“You can see the difference between a building that’s being properly funded and one that isn’t.”

Condo association fees also cover a lot of items in the building. They cover all of your utilities except for the electric and all of your exterior insurance—the only other insurance policy you’ll usually have to get is a contents policy, which costs about $1,200 a year. They also cover liability insurance for the common areas and the maintenance for the common areas. You can really see the difference in a building that’s being properly funded and one whose fees are too low.

If you consider what those fees are compared to an individual home’s costs, it’s usually a wash. When it comes to an individual home, you pay your fees in smaller increments. For instance, if you pay an $800 per month fee for a condo as part of the association, think about what you’d pay in a home at times. You might need to shell out $150 for the landscaping, $150 for the pool maintenance, and pay for all the exterior maintenance and insurance to boot. These costs can amount to more than the condo fee itself. Condos are more convenient because they charge a flat fee and you don’t have to keep up with all the bills.

Condos also offer a great way of life down here. They allow you to be closer to the Gulf or right on the beach at an affordable price. Overall, there’s less maintenance and you can come and go as you please.

We’re extremely knowledgeable on every condominium from Fort Walton beach to Panama City Beach and everything in between, so if you’re looking for a condominium or you have any other questions, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love the opportunity to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+The+pros+and+cons+of+condo+association+fees.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://ownemeraldcoast.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+The+pros+and+cons+of+condo+association+fees.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>More often than not, whenever we have people looking for a resort condominium project to buy, the first thing they desire is low condo association fees. Is it a good idea to seek out low condo association fees, though?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nathan Abbott</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>More often than not, whenever we have people looking for a resort condominium project to buy, the first thing they desire is low condo association fees. Is it a good idea to seek out low condo association fees, though?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Florida's Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Taste Some Great Wine & Food at Vin’tij Wine Boutique & Bistro</title>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/taste-some-great-wine-food-at-vintij-wine-boutique-bistro.html</link>
        
          <category>Venue Reviews</category>
        
        <author>Nathan Abbott</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-10 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Find+great+wine+and+food+at+VinTij.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Have you been to Vin’tij Wine Boutique &amp; Bistro yet? We recently sat down with owner Todd Reber to give you a taste of what you’re missing in our latest local venue spotlight.

Todd got started in the restaurant industry through a series of jobs he held in college. That experience led him to decide that the marriage of food and wine seemed like a great lifestyle. He gravitated toward it because he enjoyed the camaraderie of restaurant tours and the crowds that came through. When he graduated from Florida State, he discovered he actually made more money in the restaurant industry than he could in a professional field. He decided to challenge himself and open up Vin’tij.

“It’s been a good run for the last 17 years,” Todd says.

He chose Destin as his location because Miramar Beach was close to his home and it was a big destination for outlet stores, which allowed him to use that synergy to test out his concept. 15 years ago, all of the fine wines were earmarked for restaurants. According to Todd, if you wanted a fine wine to take home and enjoy with your friends, you had very few choices. His idea was to find boutique wines and offer them at a reasonable price that you could either enjoy at the restaurant or take home with you.

“We always feel welcome at Vin’tij, and the food is superb.”

In his opinion, the people make Vin’tij stand apart from the competition. He also noted Chef John and his fare, which is fresh and consistently good, and the employees that work there, who are all lifers and have helped to create a family atmosphere.

“We try to welcome everybody that walks in the door,” he says. “We know we’ve got only this moment to make it well and make it right, and that’s what we focus on. We don’t focus on what happened yesterday or what’s going to happen tomorrow—we’re in the now.”

He prefers guests’ experience to be simple. He knows they’re there to have a great meal, and their goal is to help them do so.

This is a place our team loves to go to, and it’s one of the top-rated restaurants in town. We always feel welcome there, the food is always superb, and they support the local residents. We highly recommend you try the experience for yourself.

We want to thank Todd for sitting down to talk with us. If you’d like to know more about Vin’tij, visit their website at www.Vintij.com.

If you have any other questions for us, feel free to give us a call or shoot us an email. We’d be happy to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Find+great+wine+and+food+at+VinTij.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://ownemeraldcoast.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Find+great+wine+and+food+at+VinTij.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Have you been to Vin’tij Wine Boutique & Bistro yet? We recently sat down with owner Todd Reber to give you a taste of what you’re missing in our latest local venue spotlight.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nathan Abbott</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Have you been to Vin’tij Wine Boutique & Bistro yet? We recently sat down with owner Todd Reber to give you a taste of what you’re missing in our latest local venue spotlight.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Florida's Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Pedego Bikes</title>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/pedego-bikes.html</link>
        
          <category>Venue Reviews</category>
        
        <author>Nathan Abbott</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-09 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Have+You+Been+to+Pedego+Bikes%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

We’re at Pedego Bikes, one of my favorite spots. They rent and sell electric bikes here, and I actually bought one for Christmas. It’s been a ton of fun for me and my family. It lets us explore 30A without having to pedal up any steep hills.

We were delighted to be joined by Pedego Bikes owner Jason Medina. He recently retired from the Coast Guard after 22 years and created this store in part to get through some of the congestion and parking issues he faced. Jason says electric bikes are the best way to get around 30A, and I agree. They offer sales and rentals to get the whole family out there cruising around.

“Electric bikes are the best way to get around 30A.”

They are located at 174 Watercolor Way in Santa Rosa, right next door to Publix and the UPS Store. I encourage you to come check out some of these bikes and take one for a test drive yourself.

If you have any questions for me about Pedego or about real estate, give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Have+You+Been+to+Pedego+Bikes%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://ownemeraldcoast.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Have+You+Been+to+Pedego+Bikes%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>We’re at Pedego Bikes, one of my favorite spots. They rent and sell electric bikes here, and I actually bought one for Christmas.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nathan Abbott</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We’re at Pedego Bikes, one of my favorite spots. They rent and sell electric bikes here, and I actually bought one for Christmas.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Florida's Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Lulu's</title>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/lulus.html</link>
        
          <category>Venue Reviews</category>
        
        <author>Nathan Abbott</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-09 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+A+Beachside+Retreat+Fit+for+a+Feast.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I’m here today to talk to you about one of my favorite places in the area that you may not know about. We’re visiting today, and I’m excited to show you around.

This is Lulu’s, a restaurant in Destin right by the Mid-Bay Bridge. They have a big outdoor beach, lots of great seating, and all kinds of activities and events for kids. It has beautiful views of the ocean with both outdoor and indoor seating.

If you have any questions for me about Lulu’s or about real estate, give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+A+Beachside+Retreat+Fit+for+a+Feast.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://ownemeraldcoast.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+A+Beachside+Retreat+Fit+for+a+Feast.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>I’m here today to talk to you about one of my favorite places in the area that you may not know about. We're visiting today, and I’m excited to show you around.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nathan Abbott</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>I’m here today to talk to you about one of my favorite places in the area that you may not know about. We're visiting today, and I’m excited to show you around.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Florida's Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Take a Look at This Beautiful Coastal Park</title>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/take-a-look-at-this-beautiful-coastal-park.html</link>
        
          <category>Outdoor Entertainment</category>
        
        <author>Nathan Abbott</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-17 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/videoplayback.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I’m coming to you from the beautiful Emerald Coast. My son and I are at Topsail State Park, one of our favorite state parks in Florida. It has the most beautiful trails and it really sets your mind free to be here. It’s a spot to really think about the important things in life.

Topsail State Park is just one of the many parks throughout 30a, and we can help you discover all of the great parks Florida has to offer.

If you have any questions, please feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!

Get directions to or learn more about Topsail Gulf Front State Park.


</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/videoplayback.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://ownemeraldcoast.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/videoplayback.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I’m coming to you from the beautiful Emerald Coast.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nathan Abbott</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I’m coming to you from the beautiful Emerald Coast.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Florida's Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Find What You’re Looking for at Not Too Shabby Boutique</title>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/find-what-youre-looking-for-at-not-too-shabby-boutique.html</link>
        
          <category>Venue Reviews</category>
        
        <author>Nathan Abbott</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-07 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Find+unique+items+at+Not+Too+Shabby+Boutique.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I’m here at the Not Too Shabby Boutique, owned by Tony and Marisol Gullo. Marisol was recently chosen as the 2017 Artist of the Year! You can find Marisol’s artwork at the boutique along with many unique pieces.

“We are a one-stop shop,” says Tony. Tony and Marisol make custom pieces that you can’t get anywhere else. They use reclaimed wood for their pieces and sell upholstery by Four Seasons. You can also find Bella Notte Linens, pieces by Regina Andrew, and more from Aidan Gray Home.

“Not Too Shabby is a one-stop shop.”

Although Not Too Shabby has been around for 17 years, they moved into this plaza five years ago. You can find the Not Too Shabby Boutique at 3906 Hwy 98 West.

If you need to furnish your new home or if you need furniture for a rental property, make sure you check out Not Too Shabby. You will be amazed at the variety of furniture and art pieces here that you can use to create a unique look.

If you have any questions for Tony or Marisol, you can contact them here. As always, if you have any real estate questions, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Find+unique+items+at+Not+Too+Shabby+Boutique.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://ownemeraldcoast.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Find+unique+items+at+Not+Too+Shabby+Boutique.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I’m here at the Not Too Shabby Boutique, owned by Tony and Marisol Gullo. Marisol was recently chosen as the 2017 Artist of the Year! You can find Marisol’s artwork at the boutique along with many unique pieces.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nathan Abbott</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I’m here at the Not Too Shabby Boutique, owned by Tony and Marisol Gullo. Marisol was recently chosen as the 2017 Artist of the Year! You can find Marisol’s artwork at the boutique along with many unique pieces.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Florida's Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Top 5 Tips for Scoring a Great Deal on Your Dream Property</title>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/top-5-tips-for-scoring-a-great-deal-on-your-dream-property.html</link>
        
          <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Nathan Abbott</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-23 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+5+tips+to+get+a+great+deal+on+your+dream+home.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Here are five creative tips that will help you get a great deal on the perfect property.

1. Be very specific about what you want. The more you share with us, the easier it will be to find that dream property. Don’t be afraid to let us know what you would be uncomfortable with spending, either. Everything you tell us will help us find the right pool of options that perfectly align with your needs.

2. Be financially well documented. If you’re taking out a loan, make sure you are pre-approved and have that pre-approval letter before you start looking at homes. If you’re a cash buyer, you’ll still want to have some form of financial verification to present to the seller. Having that paperwork presents you as a serious buyer. We’ll align you with the best lender for your needs that is already familiar with properties in our area.

“The more you share with us, the easier it will be to find that dream property.”

3. Act quickly. We’ll be sending you properties as soon as they hit the market, so when you see one that checks off all the boxes, be ready to see it and possibly make an offer. Chances are, you’ll be one of six or seven people also looking at that same home, so be prepared to pounce.

4. Come in with a market-appropriate offer. Don’t try to undercut the sellers. A low offer could cause the seller to reach out to other interested parties, creating a bidding war and ultimately driving up the price. If you present a great offer right off the bat, the seller will only be focused on yours so you can avoid that competition.

5. Minimize contingencies. If you write in a bunch of ways in which you can get out of or cancel a contract, a seller isn’t going to take you very seriously. You want to include some contingencies to make sure you’re protected, but limit the amount to show you are serious about closing on that property.

If you have any questions or need any help buying or selling your home, please don’t hesitate to give us a call. We’re here to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+5+tips+to+get+a+great+deal+on+your+dream+home.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://ownemeraldcoast.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+5+tips+to+get+a+great+deal+on+your+dream+home.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I want to give you some creative buyer tips to get a great deal on the perfect property.  1. Be very specific about what you want. The more you share with us, the easier it will be to find that dream property.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nathan Abbott</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I want to give you some creative buyer tips to get a great deal on the perfect property.  1. Be very specific about what you want. The more you share with us, the easier it will be to find that dream property.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Florida's Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>If You Try Sushimoto, I Guarantee You'll Be Back</title>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/if-you-try-sushimoto-i-guarantee-youll-be-back.html</link>
        
          <category>Venue Reviews</category>
        
        <author>Nathan Abbott</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-09 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Best+sushi+in+town.mp4</guid>
        <description>

This week I’m honored to feature Sushimoto, one of our favorite local restaurants here on the Emerald Coast.

My wife and I absolutely love coming here for sushi that’s extremely fresh and hot dishes that are great. In fact, Emeril Lagasse himself recently featured Sushimoto as one of his favorite restaurants! Owners Andy and Sophia are great people and good friends that provide the best customer service.

“If you mention the Nathan Abbott Team, you’ll get a hot sake on the house.”

Andy wanted a way to feature local seafood and our beautiful beaches drew him here. He loves having a local spot and seeing so many new faces come try his food.

If you mention the Nathan Abbott Team, they’ll even give you a hot sake on the house.

I encourage you to check out Sushimoto because if you come once, I’m sure you’ll be back. You won’t be disappointed!

Until then, give me a call or send me an email with any questions about our local real estate market. I’d be happy to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Best+sushi+in+town.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://ownemeraldcoast.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Best+sushi+in+town.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>This week I'm honored to feature Sushimoto, one of our favorite local restaurants here on the Emerald Coast.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nathan Abbott</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>This week I'm honored to feature Sushimoto, one of our favorite local restaurants here on the Emerald Coast.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Florida's Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Prepare Your Home for the Market</title>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/prepare-your-home-for-the-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Nathan Abbott</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-06 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+How+to+prepare+your+home+for+the+market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

As a home seller, what can you do to get your home ready for the photo shoot, the market, and for buyer showings?

When potential buyers pull up to your house, the outside needs to be just as inviting as the inside. This means having your bushes trimmed back, your driveway and home pressure washed, fresh light bulbs, and maybe some fresh cut flowers. If the exterior of your home is in disarray, that buyer may just keep driving because they got a bad first impression of your home.

As they walk through your front door, it’s important to have all of your carpets vacuumed and your home smelling clean and fresh.

You should also make sure that your home is free of all personal items. Take down family photos and make sure that there aren’t any books stacked on the counter or above cabinets. You want the buyer to feel like this can be their home, and if your personal stuff is lying around everywhere, they will feel like they are intruding in someone else’s home.

“A few small fixes can go a long way.”

It’s important to have all of the smaller items in your home functioning correctly. Check on cabinet hinges, sliding glass doors, and more.

During the showing, we recommend that you have jazz music playing or cookies baking. Doing so will show buyers that you have pride in homeownership. We provide a professional stager to all of our clients. The stager will come in and let you know what you need to do to make showings fantastic. Sometimes just switching out the comforters on the beds or adding a new lamp makes all the difference. Little changes go a long way; you don’t have to spend a lot of money to make your home more appealing to buyers.

Hopefully some of these tips will help you sell your home faster and maximize your price. It’s all about the little touches and the experience the buyer has from the moment they pull up in front of your home. If you have any questions, give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+How+to+prepare+your+home+for+the+market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://ownemeraldcoast.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+How+to+prepare+your+home+for+the+market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Now is the time to prepare your home for the spring real estate market. I’ll give you a few tips on how to create an enjoyable showing experience for potential buyers.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nathan Abbott</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Now is the time to prepare your home for the spring real estate market. I’ll give you a few tips on how to create an enjoyable showing experience for potential buyers.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Florida's Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Where Is the Emerald Coast Real Estate Market Trending?</title>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/where-is-the-emerald-coast-real-estate-market-trending.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Nathan Abbott</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-03 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Hows+the+Emerald+Coast+housing+market+doing%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What’s happening in our local real estate market?

As a whole, our market is very healthy right now. There are indications that it’s converting into a buyer’s market but some of that is due to December being a traditionally slow month for a vacation market, such as ours.

We are in one of the fastest-growing areas in the country for primary residents, and we’re being discovered on a national level. Growing up in this area, I can tell you that, historically, most of our real estate traffic has come from the Southeast region. Now, though, we have residents coming from as far away as California.

“Our area is being discovered on a national level.”

In the past, whenever we had a rise or fall in the market, there was so much speculation in our area that a lot of people who bought properties didn’t have the holding power to keep them and shouldn’t have been buying those properties on the level that they were. Today, there isn’t nearly as much speculation. The activity in our market now is based more on our exposure and people wanting to live in our area.

If you get a loan, lenders are very strict right now about who they’re lending to. There is a lot of cash entering our market, and that’s a strong indication of longevity. Another indicator I always look at in gauging market strength is how the commercial growth is happening in that area, and our commercial growth has been great lately. We have a brand-new 5-star hotel, a new Whole Foods, and plenty of new shopping centers up and down Highway 98. These property developments are all signs of a strengthening market.

Shopping and Entertainment, Brand New and Expansions:

Destin Commons

Pier Park

Pier Park North

The HUB

30 Avenue

New Hotels:

The Henderson (5 star)

The Pearl of Rosemary

The Hampton Inn

If you have any questions about our market or if there’s anything I can assist you with, please feel free to give me a ring or shoot me an email. I would love the opportunity to serve you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Hows+the+Emerald+Coast+housing+market+doing%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://ownemeraldcoast.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Hows+the+Emerald+Coast+housing+market+doing%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Thanks to a growing national exposure and a windfall of commercial development, our real estate market is very healthy.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nathan Abbott</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Thanks to a growing national exposure and a windfall of commercial development, our real estate market is very healthy.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Florida's Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Nathan Abbott</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Nathan Abbott</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Nathan Abbott Team - your professional Florida's Emerald Coast Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
