<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Frisco Real Estate Podcast with Troy Copeland</title>
    <link>troycopeland.com</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="troycopeland.com"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Troy Copeland Real Estate - your professional Frisco Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Troy Copeland</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2017-07-13 15:17:13 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Troy Copeland</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://i.imgur.com/KQw936a.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Frisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">News &amp; Politics</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>info@troycopeland.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Troy Copeland</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Troy Copeland</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://i.imgur.com/KQw936a.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Frisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Frisco Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Troy Copeland Real Estate - your professional Frisco Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="News &amp; Politics"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Common Mistakes Many Home Sellers Make</title>
        <link>troycopeland.com/5-common-mistakes-many-home-sellers-make.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Troy Copeland</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-13 05:31:37 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Troy+Copeland/2017/Troy+Copeland+Real+Estate-+Top+5+Seller+Mistakes.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When selling your home, there are five costly mistakes you should try to avoid:

“Buyers want to be able to picture themselves living in your home.”


  Mispricing your home: This is common because everybody thinks their house is more valuable than their neighbor’s. If you price too low, you can leave money on the table and if you price too high, you won’t get any offers. Then, as buyers look at other homes, they’ll start thinking there’s something wrong with yours. Price is the most critical point in presenting your home.
  Not doing necessary repairs before listing: Most people just want to move on without investing in their home, but if you want to get the most value, it’s better to do these repairs first. Buyers don’t want to have to buy a house and then put in the sweat equity themselves; they don’t see the future value.
  Not presenting the home correctly: This means not staging it or not depersonalizing your home. Think of the buyer–they want to imagine living there, not see all your clutter. Make your home open so buyers can see themselves living there.
  Not having professional photos: This is a critical aspect of presenting your home because 90% to 95% of people now start their home search on the Internet by looking at photos. If you don’t have professional photos, your house will not stand out. Hiring a professional will pay itself off in the long run.
  Not hiring a real estate professional: Hiring a professional can be expensive, yes, but they will take care of all the little things I’ve mentioned like getting professional photos and marketing your home. They’ll also have a team behind them to help you through this stressful process.


If you have any questions about the home selling process or you’re thinking of putting your home on the market, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to answer any questions you have.

</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Troy+Copeland/2017/Troy+Copeland+Real+Estate-+Top+5+Seller+Mistakes.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="troycopeland.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Troy+Copeland/2017/Troy+Copeland+Real+Estate-+Top+5+Seller+Mistakes.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>When the time comes to sell you home, there's a lot of room for error. I've found that there are common mistakes that sellers make over and over, but five stand out to me as the most common. The first and biggest mistake I see sellers make is mispricing their home. Pricing either too high or too low almost always ends up costing you money in the end. To learn how to avoid all five of these common mistakes when selling your house, watch my latest video.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Troy Copeland</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>When the time comes to sell you home, there's a lot of room for error. I've found that there are common mistakes that sellers make over and over, but five stand out to me as the most common. The first and biggest mistake I see sellers make is mispricing their home. Pricing either too high or too low almost always ends up costing you money in the end. To learn how to avoid all five of these common mistakes when selling your house, watch my latest video.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Frisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Top 5 Home Design Trends of 2017</title>
        <link>troycopeland.com/the-top-5-home-design-trends-of-2017.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Troy Copeland</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-01 06:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Troy+Copeland/2017/Troy+Copeland+Real+Estate-+The+Top+5+Home+Design+Trends+of+2017.mp4</guid>
        <description>

We are delighted to be joined today by Angie McCoy of Evergreen Staging and Design, who is going to be talking with us about the top five home design trends in real estate for 2017. Without further ado, let’s take it away.

1. New paint colors. Paint is a wonderful way to update your home because it’s inexpensive and creates an upbeat look. Sherwin Williams has come out with their color of the year for 2017, Poised Taupe. It’s a mix of gray and brown that fits perfectly in any room. The color experts, Pantone, also picked several colors that they think are going to be big this year, including purple and grape shades that people love.

2. Rich materials. These include things like reclaimed wood on fireplaces and metal mixes of silvers, golds, pewters, and bronzes. It also includes furry textures on throw rugs and pillows.
“Great kitchens are selling homes in this market.”
3. Going green. Basically, make the home more energy efficient. People want to feel like they are helping the environment and they can do that in many ways like updating windows, adding solar panels, and getting tankless water heaters.

4. A functional home office. More and more people are working from home these days, and they want a designated space to do that. Turning a third bedroom into a home office is a good way to find that space.

5. Splurging on kitchen renovations. Kitchens are almost single-handedly selling homes in this market. The kitchen is the heart of the home, where most people begin and end their day. Small updates like changing the backsplash or upgrading appliances are great ways to add value and increase the functionality of your kitchen.

If you want to improve the look and feel of your interior, give Angie a call at (214)-984-4233 or send her an email at info@evergreenstaging.com.

If you have any other real estate questions, we are always here to answer them. Just reach out. We look forward to hearing from you soon!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Troy+Copeland/2017/Troy+Copeland+Real+Estate-+The+Top+5+Home+Design+Trends+of+2017.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="troycopeland.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Troy+Copeland/2017/Troy+Copeland+Real+Estate-+The+Top+5+Home+Design+Trends+of+2017.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What design trends should you be aware of in 2017? Angie McCoy of Evergreen Staging and Design is here to give us the answer.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Troy Copeland</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What design trends should you be aware of in 2017? Angie McCoy of Evergreen Staging and Design is here to give us the answer.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Frisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Latest News in Frisco Real Estate</title>
        <link>troycopeland.com/the-latest-news-in-frisco-real-estate.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Troy Copeland</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-04 11:08:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Troy+Copeland/2017/Troy+Copeland+Real+Estate-+Frisco+Market+Update.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’ve been paying attention to the real estate market lately, none of this should be a surprise to you. However, if you haven’t, here are the biggest changes I’ve been seeing in the Frisco market this year as compared to last year. 

Inventory increased by almost 8% in March to about 8,300 homes. However, we continue to have a lower supply of homes on the market that we have seen in the past seven years.

Demand has stayed strong, with about 40,000 people moving to the area each month. With new companies moving to the area, excellent public schools, and no state taxes, north Texas remains one of the most sought-after areas in the nation for homebuyers. 

With a high level of demand and a low level of supply, home prices are going to continue to rise. In fact, right now, we are seeing the highest average sale price in our history. It’s up 12% to an astonishing $377,000.

“North Texas remains one of the most sought-after areas in the nation”

What does this mean for buyers? With limited options, you need a good real estate professional on your side who can find the home for you and find it quickly. I’m talking as soon as it comes on the market. You must also expect to pay at least list price, if not more, to get the home you want in this competitive market.

For sellers, it’s all about preparation. Your home is going to sell quickly if you have an agent who can help you prepare your home, price it correctly, and present it to buyers in its best light. You also need to make sure you have your home purchase plans in place before you even put your home on the market. If you price correctly with a professional who knows what they’re doing, chances are that you will have a lot of showings and a lot of competing bids for your home. 

If you have any other questions about the current state of the market or you want to take advantage of the current conditions as a buyer or seller, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Troy+Copeland/2017/Troy+Copeland+Real+Estate-+Frisco+Market+Update.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="troycopeland.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Troy+Copeland/2017/Troy+Copeland+Real+Estate-+Frisco+Market+Update.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>North Texas is still one of the most sought after areas in the country for homebuyers. Here’s why.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Troy Copeland</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>North Texas is still one of the most sought after areas in the country for homebuyers. Here’s why.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Frisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Is Your Home Worth in the Spring Market?</title>
        <link>troycopeland.com/what-is-your-home-worth-in-the-spring-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Troy Copeland</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-12 10:26:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Troy+Copeland/2017/Troy+Copeland+Real+Estate-+Pricing+Your+Home.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you are thinking of listing your home during the selling season, then you need to find out what your home is worth. There are four ways to do just that:

1. Find out what your X factors are. Knowing which homes have sold in your neighborhood is a great starting point, but you must also figure in which features your home has that could increase its value.

2. Remember the three C’s of pricing: consumption, condition, and competition. Consumption is the number of homes sold in your particular neighborhood. You also need to compare the condition of your home to other homes on the market; evaluate your home as if you were a picky buyer. Finally, it’s important to know who your competition is. How many homes in your area are on the market? How many of those homes are in your price range?

3. Hire an appraiser. Now, appraisals can cost $400 to $500 but if you get varied results from different agents, then it may be a good idea to bring in an appraiser to give you a better range.

“Hire a professional real estate agent and ask for a CMA.”

4. Hire a real estate professional and ask for a comparative market analysis, or CMA, to get a more accurate value of your home. If you are interested in one, click here.

If you have any other questions about your home value or if you would like to know more about another real estate topic, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Troy+Copeland/2017/Troy+Copeland+Real+Estate-+Pricing+Your+Home.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="troycopeland.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Troy+Copeland/2017/Troy+Copeland+Real+Estate-+Pricing+Your+Home.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you want to know what your home is worth in the current market, there are four things that you can do.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Troy Copeland</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you want to know what your home is worth in the current market, there are four things that you can do.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Frisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Questions Do You Have About Real Estate?</title>
        <link>troycopeland.com/what-questions-do-you-have-about-real-estate.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Troy Copeland</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-03 09:22:55 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Troy+Copeland/2017/Troy+Copeland+Welcome+To+Blog+edit.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I’m excited to announce my new real estate video blog!

I’ll be sending you two educational videos a month that have to do with all things real estate. They will feature tips on the local real estate market and answers to any questions you may have about home buying, home selling, or investing in real estate.

“This video blog is a resource for you.”

I’ll also touch on what’s going on in the lending and title world as well.

However, this new blog is a resource for you, so I want to know what questions you would like me to answer in these videos. Are you curious about the market in your particular area? Are there any topics you would like me touch on, or terms in real estate that you are unfamiliar with? Let me know what you would like to learn about and I will be happy to answer any and all of your real estate questions.

I can’t wait to start answering your questions in my video blog, but in the meantime, if you have any questions, please feel free to give me a call or shoot me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Troy+Copeland/2017/Troy+Copeland+Welcome+To+Blog+edit.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="troycopeland.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Troy+Copeland/2017/Troy+Copeland+Welcome+To+Blog+edit.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>I have some exciting news to share with you! I have decided to start a real estate video blog to answer any and all of your real estate questions. I’ll be sending out two videos a month answering your questions about buying or selling a home, investing in real estate, or anything else you want to learn more about. I want this blog to be a resource for you, so please let me know what you would like to find out about the market. To get a sneak peek of what your new real estate resource can do for you, watch this short video.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Troy Copeland</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>I have some exciting news to share with you! I have decided to start a real estate video blog to answer any and all of your real estate questions. I’ll be sending out two videos a month answering your questions about buying or selling a home, investing in real estate, or anything else you want to learn more about. I want this blog to be a resource for you, so please let me know what you would like to find out about the market. To get a sneak peek of what your new real estate resource can do for you, watch this short video.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Frisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Troy Copeland</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Troy Copeland</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Troy Copeland Real Estate - your professional Frisco Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
