<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Greater Denver Area Real Estate Podcast with Rex Jarnagin</title>
    <link>http://denverrealestatetips.com</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://denverrealestatetips.com"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Rex Jarnagin - your professional Real Estate Agent.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Rex Jarnagin</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2017-09-01 14:28:49 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Rex Jarnagin</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Colorado, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>elitehometeam@outlook.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Rex Jarnagin</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Rex Jarnagin</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Colorado, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Colorado Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Rex Jarnagin - your professional Real Estate Agent.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>Should You List Your Home or Buy a New One First?</title>
        <link>http://denverrealestatetips.com/should-you-list-your-home-or-buy-a-new-one-first.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Rex Jarnagin</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-25 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Rex+Jarnagin/Videos/2017/August/Elite+Home+Team-+Should+You+List+Your+Home+or+Buy+a+New+One+First%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

A question that’s come up quite a few times in the last few weeks deals with buying and selling at the same time. Which comes first? Do you list your current home or buy your new home first?

In most cases, you really have to list first, and here’s why.

If you consider the current market, many sellers are getting multiple offers on their homes. Most homeowners won’t even consider an offer where a buyer has to list and sell their home first. This is especially true if the buyer hasn’t even put their home on the market yet.

If the house is already listed or under contract, it really changes the offer in the seller’s eyes. If you find a home and then wait to put an offer on it so that you can list your own home, that property will be gone. The seller will have accepted an offer from a buyer who’s ready to move in.

There’s really no other way around it: you have to list your home first.

We understand that this is a really stressful situation for you. We do this type of transaction every day, and we help people through this scenario all the time. We’ve found over the years that there are three key things that we can do to put you into the best position.

“There’s really no other way around it: You have to list your home first.”

The first thing we do is pre-market your home for several days before showings. While you’re looking for the home you want to buy, we’ll get the marketing set up. We’ll get the listing written, get all the paperwork together, and let other agents know that your home is coming for sale.

The second thing we do is let buyers know that you’re selling and looking to buy. We can get you as much time as you need to search for your home if we’re up front about your situation.

Finally, if an offer comes in then we can negotiate how much time you will need in order to make a smooth transition into your new home.

If you’d like to discuss this topic more in detail or you’re looking to buy or sell a home in our area, give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to helping you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Rex+Jarnagin/Videos/2017/August/Elite+Home+Team-+Should+You+List+Your+Home+or+Buy+a+New+One+First%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://denverrealestatetips.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Rex+Jarnagin/Videos/2017/August/Elite+Home+Team-+Should+You+List+Your+Home+or+Buy+a+New+One+First%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Should you list your home or buy a new one first? I’ve laid out the best strategy to tackle this type of scenario below.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Rex Jarnagin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Should you list your home or buy a new one first? I’ve laid out the best strategy to tackle this type of scenario below.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Colorado, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4 Hidden Costs That Can Sneak Up on You When Listing Your Home</title>
        <link>http://denverrealestatetips.com/4-hidden-costs-that-can-sneak-up-on-you-when-listing-your-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Rex Jarnagin</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-10 05:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Rex+Jarnagin/Videos/2017/August/Elite+Home+Team-+4+Hidden+Costs+That+Can+Sneak+Up+on+You+When+Listing+Your+Home.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What does it really cost to sell your home today?

There are a few hidden costs most sellers don’t anticipate, and some Realtors don’t do a good job making sure their clients know all of these costs, so I want to make sure you know what they are.

What we do for our own clients to mediate these costs is provide a net sheet at the very beginning of the listing process. This is a detailed breakdown of all the closing costs involved in selling a home. We bring this information to the very first meeting and as we get offers, we provide this information again. I don’t want our clients to get any surprises

For now, though, here are four hidden costs you may incur during the selling process:

1. Commission costs: Sometimes agents don’t communicate well with their seller and they fail to understand exactly what type of commission structure will be charged on the successful close of the property. Sellers generally pay for the buyer’s agent’s commission as well as the listing agent’s. Make sure you understand how that works and how you’re being charged.

“Don’t go under contract on your new home until you’ve listed and begun selling your old one.”

2. Closing costs:This is where our net sheet comes in handy. Take title insurance, for example. This is usually the seller’s responsibility to pay to ensure the title is free and clear. Another closing cost is the HOA status transfer fee. Both of these costs can be substantial, and there are quite a few smaller costs that come with the contract, so make sure you know what they are.

3. Moving expenses: Sometimes sellers just don’t consider what it will cost them to move. There will be moving expenses whether you’re hiring a moving company or doing it yourself. Get an estimate so you’re aware of what your moving expenses will be.

4. Multiple mortgages: If a client moves prior to selling their home, they’ll have to carry two mortgages and make two payments. This is why we usually recommend to our clients not to go under contract on their new home until they’ve listed and begun selling their old home. I did a previous video titled “Should I Sell My House Before I Find a House?” that addresses this topic that you can watch here. Make sure the agent you hire has a lot of experience navigating this process. You should be able to do both simultaneously without a hitch.

If you have any additional questions about hidden home selling costs or any other real estate topic, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I’d be happy to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Rex+Jarnagin/Videos/2017/August/Elite+Home+Team-+4+Hidden+Costs+That+Can+Sneak+Up+on+You+When+Listing+Your+Home.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://denverrealestatetips.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Rex+Jarnagin/Videos/2017/August/Elite+Home+Team-+4+Hidden+Costs+That+Can+Sneak+Up+on+You+When+Listing+Your+Home.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There are four hidden costs that you should be mindful of when selling your home. Here’s how you can mediate them.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Rex Jarnagin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There are four hidden costs that you should be mindful of when selling your home. Here’s how you can mediate them.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Colorado, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>When Is the Best Time to Sell?</title>
        <link>http://denverrealestatetips.com/when-is-the-best-time-to-sell.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Rex Jarnagin</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-26 08:40:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Rex+Jarnagin/Videos/2017/July/Elite+Home+Team-+When+Is+the+Best+Time+to+Sell%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When it comes to selling your home, when is the best time to do it? Should you wait, or should you make your move? What time of year is best?

When people ask this kind of question, they’re already a step closer to the truth than they might think. They already understand that timing is the most important factor in selling.

Lately, the Denver metro area has been one of the biggest selling hotspots in the nation. With several instances of multiple offers, consistently rising home prices, and record sales, this definitely seems to be the case.

A number of things affect the market, including economic growth, population growth, and interest rates. When looking at the right time to sell, all of these factors are significant.

Right now, these factors have created a perfect storm for sellers. As demand continues to climb, this climate is likely to persist.

However, waiting around based on predictions may not be a good idea. A lot of things affect the local market, and with interest rates expected to increase in the near future, there is no time better to sell than now.

“If you are motivated to do so, it’s always the right time to sell.”

We simply don’t know what the future of the housing market will look like. What we do know is that right now is a great time to be a seller. In fact, this is one of the best-selling markets in our history.

But regardless of other factors, the time of year does consistently have an impact on the market. Spring and summer are typically the busiest times of year in real estate, while fall and winter tend to be less so.

However, with lower inventory and less competition in the fall and winter, buyers may want to consider looking during those times instead of when the market is hot.

Ultimately, there are benefits to any time of year. So when it comes to timing your sale, it’s best to look at other statistics, like days on market, absorption rates, and months of inventory. Knowing the competition is another key factor.

With all of that said, the only real way to determine if now is the right time to sell is to ask yourself, “What works best for me?” If you have good reason and you are motivated to do so, it’s always the right time to sell.

If this is true for you, you should definitely take advantage of today’s incredible seller’s market. We can never know how long it will last—so don’t wait.

If you have any other questions or want more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Rex+Jarnagin/Videos/2017/July/Elite+Home+Team-+When+Is+the+Best+Time+to+Sell%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://denverrealestatetips.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Rex+Jarnagin/Videos/2017/July/Elite+Home+Team-+When+Is+the+Best+Time+to+Sell%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>In our area right now, we’re seeing an incredible seller’s market. There are a few things to consider when asking yourself if now is the right time to sell.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Rex Jarnagin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>In our area right now, we’re seeing an incredible seller’s market. There are a few things to consider when asking yourself if now is the right time to sell.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Colorado, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>8 Reasons Why Your Home Isn't Selling</title>
        <link>http://denverrealestatetips.com/8-reasons-why-your-home-isnt-selling.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Rex Jarnagin</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-21 08:58:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Rex+Jarnagin/Elite%2520Home%2520Team-%2520Reasons%2520your%2520home%2520wont%2520sell.mp4</guid>
        <description>

As you know, we are in a really busy seller’s market, but would it surprise you to know that 15%-20% of homes that are listed don’t sell? Why does that happen? I’ve broken down eight reasons that homes don’t sell.

8. The condition and cleanliness of the home can have a huge impact on how the buyers view the home. From the curb appeal to the inside, if your home doesn’t outshine the competition, it won’t sell.

7. Timing. You must be prepared to move at the speed of the market. If you wait until your home is perfectly ready, you may miss the best time to sell.

6. Photography. You only get one chance to make a first impression. These days your first showing is on the Internet, and if you don’t use professional, high-quality photos, you may not get another showing from potential buyers.

“You only get one chance to make a first impression.”

5. Marketing. Some houses don’t sell because the agent doesn’t have a marketing plan or budget. Your agent should have a strategy designed for your property.

4. Commissions. There are some companies that have reduced commissions for the agents they employ. If you use one of these agents, you may run the risk of losing out on potential buyers who see that reduced commission as a red flag.

3. Availability. Many times serious buyers skip homes that aren’t easy to see. You should be flexible with your showings so the most people can see your house.

2. The agent you’re using could be a huge factor in why your home isn’t selling. Many times it’s because a homeowner used a discount company or an inexperienced agent that their home didn’t sell.

1. The price. Your home should be accurately priced. Overpriced homes get passed by and they sit on the market for too long.

If you have any questions about this or any other real estate topics, or you’re looking to buy or sell your home, give me a call. I’d be happy to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Rex+Jarnagin/Elite%2520Home%2520Team-%2520Reasons%2520your%2520home%2520wont%2520sell.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://denverrealestatetips.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Rex+Jarnagin/Elite%2520Home%2520Team-%2520Reasons%2520your%2520home%2520wont%2520sell.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Are you wondering why your home isn’t selling? I’ve compiled a list of eight reasons below.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Rex Jarnagin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Are you wondering why your home isn’t selling? I’ve compiled a list of eight reasons below.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Colorado, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why It’s Such a Great Time to Sell Your Denver House</title>
        <link>http://denverrealestatetips.com/why-its-such-a-great-time-to-sell-your-denver-house.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Rex Jarnagin</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-08 09:17:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Rex+Jarnagin/Elite+Home+Team-+A+closer+look+at+the+market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Our market is pretty insane right now. It’s a great time to sell your house if you’ve been thinking about it. Truthfully, this is the best market Denver has ever seen. We have the lowest interest rates and the lowest competition levels we’ve ever seen.

However, there is one thing to be wary of in this market: failed transactions. The number of deals falling out of contract nearly doubled last month. The Denver Post wrote that 23% of all transactions fell out last month.

One problem that’s causing this is how complicated the market is. With record low inventory, most agents don’t have the experience or the expertise to navigate this market. Most agents only close between four and 12 deals per year, so they simply don’t have enough experience to get deals done the right way.

“Low appraisals have become a big problem.”

Another big problem for sellers is appraisals. Homes are selling for much higher prices than they are actually appraising for. This isn’t a problem for cash buyers, but it is for the overwhelming majority of buyers who have financing. If a home doesn’t appraise as high as its sale price, the deal is more likely to fall apart if you’re not working with an experienced agent.

Finally, a lot of buyers are having to make offers they aren’t fully comfortable with. They get sick of getting outbid and making a high offer, only to get cold feet after they go under contract. Most of the time, the monthly payment is just more than they are comfortable paying.

This is a difficult market to be in, but it can be a very lucrative market if you have the right help. Having a good agent to keep your deal from falling apart is an invaluable tool in this market. For the record, we didn’t have any deals fall apart last month because we make them every day and we know how to get them done.

If you have any questions or need any help or advice about how to attack this market, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Rex+Jarnagin/Elite+Home+Team-+A+closer+look+at+the+market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://denverrealestatetips.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Rex+Jarnagin/Elite+Home+Team-+A+closer+look+at+the+market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>The Denver market is about as good as it ever has been. There are a few key reasons why.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Rex Jarnagin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>The Denver market is about as good as it ever has been. There are a few key reasons why.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Colorado, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Rex Jarnagin</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Rex Jarnagin</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Rex Jarnagin - your professional Real Estate Agent.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
