<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Florida's Emerald Coast Real Estate Podcast with Nathan Abbott</title>
    <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://ownemeraldcoast.com"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Nathan Abbott Team - your professional Florida's Emerald Coast Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Nathan Abbott</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2017-03-09 13:40:31 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Nathan Abbott</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://ownemeraldcoast.com/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Florida's Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">News &amp; Politics</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Nathan@NathanAbbottTeam.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Nathan Abbott</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Nathan Abbott</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://ownemeraldcoast.com/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Florida's Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Florida's Emerald Coast Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Nathan Abbott Team - your professional Florida's Emerald Coast Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="News &amp; Politics"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>If You Try Sushimoto, I Guarantee You'll Be Back</title>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/if-you-try-sushimoto-i-guarantee-youll-be-back.html</link>
        
          <category>Venue Reviews</category>
        
        <author>Nathan Abbott</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-09 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

This week I’m honored to feature Sushimoto, one of our favorite local restaurants here on the Emerald Coast.

My wife and I absolutely love coming here for sushi that’s extremely fresh and hot dishes that are great. In fact, Emeril Lagasse himself recently featured Sushimoto as one of his favorite restaurants! Owners Andy and Sophia are great people and good friends that provide the best customer service.

“If you mention the Nathan Abbott Team, you’ll get a hot sake on the house.”

Andy wanted a way to feature local seafood and our beautiful beaches drew him here. He loves having a local spot and seeing so many new faces come try his food.

If you mention the Nathan Abbott Team, they’ll even give you a hot sake on the house.

I encourage you to check out Sushimoto because if you come once, I’m sure you’ll be back. You won’t be disappointed!

Until then, give me a call or send me an email with any questions about our local real estate market. I’d be happy to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://ownemeraldcoast.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>This week I'm honored to feature Sushimoto, one of our favorite local restaurants here on the Emerald Coast.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nathan Abbott</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>This week I'm honored to feature Sushimoto, one of our favorite local restaurants here on the Emerald Coast.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Florida's Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Few of My Favorite Spots Around Destin</title>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/a-few-of-my-favorite-spots-around-destin.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Nathan Abbott</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-22 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+A+few+great+places+for+you+to+check+out.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I’m here today to talk to you about some of my favorite places in the area that you may not know about. We’re visiting two of them today, and I’m excited to talk about them.

First up is Lulu’s, a restaurant in Destin right by the Mid-Bay Bridge. They have a big outdoor beach, lots of great seating, and all kinds of activities and events for kids. It has beautiful views of the ocean with both outdoor and indoor seating.

Next, we’re headed to Pedego Bikes, one of my favorite spots. They rent and sell electric bikes here, and I actually bought one for Christmas. It’s been a ton of fun for me and my family. It lets us explore 30A without having to pedal up any steep hills.

“Lulu’s has such a gorgeous ocean view.”

We were delighted to be joined by Pedego Bikes owner Jason Medina. He recently retired from the Coast Guard after 22 years and created this store in part to get through some of the congestion and parking issues he faced. Jason says electric bikes are the best way to get around 30A, and I agree. They offer sales and rentals to get the whole family out there cruising around.

They are located at 174 Watercolor Way in Santa Rosa, right next door to Publix and the UPS Store. I encourage you to come check out some of these bikes and take one for a test drive yourself.

If you have any questions for me about either of these places or about real estate, give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+A+few+great+places+for+you+to+check+out.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://ownemeraldcoast.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+A+few+great+places+for+you+to+check+out.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>I want to take you to a couple of my favorite spots in the area today. First up is Lulu’s.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nathan Abbott</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>I want to take you to a couple of my favorite spots in the area today. First up is Lulu’s.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Florida's Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Prepare Your Home for the Market</title>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/prepare-your-home-for-the-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Nathan Abbott</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-06 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+How+to+prepare+your+home+for+the+market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

As a home seller, what can you do to get your home ready for the photo shoot, the market, and for buyer showings?

When potential buyers pull up to your house, the outside needs to be just as inviting as the inside. This means having your bushes trimmed back, your driveway and home pressure washed, fresh light bulbs, and maybe some fresh cut flowers. If the exterior of your home is in disarray, that buyer may just keep driving because they got a bad first impression of your home.

As they walk through your front door, it’s important to have all of your carpets vacuumed and your home smelling clean and fresh.

You should also make sure that your home is free of all personal items. Take down family photos and make sure that there aren’t any books stacked on the counter or above cabinets. You want the buyer to feel like this can be their home, and if your personal stuff is lying around everywhere, they will feel like they are intruding in someone else’s home.

“A few small fixes can go a long way.”

It’s important to have all of the smaller items in your home functioning correctly. Check on cabinet hinges, sliding glass doors, and more.

During the showing, we recommend that you have jazz music playing or cookies baking. Doing so will show buyers that you have pride in homeownership. We provide a professional stager to all of our clients. The stager will come in and let you know what you need to do to make showings fantastic. Sometimes just switching out the comforters on the beds or adding a new lamp makes all the difference. Little changes go a long way; you don’t have to spend a lot of money to make your home more appealing to buyers.

Hopefully some of these tips will help you sell your home faster and maximize your price. It’s all about the little touches and the experience the buyer has from the moment they pull up in front of your home. If you have any questions, give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+How+to+prepare+your+home+for+the+market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://ownemeraldcoast.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+How+to+prepare+your+home+for+the+market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Now is the time to prepare your home for the spring real estate market. I’ll give you a few tips on how to create an enjoyable showing experience for potential buyers.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nathan Abbott</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Now is the time to prepare your home for the spring real estate market. I’ll give you a few tips on how to create an enjoyable showing experience for potential buyers.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Florida's Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Where Is the Emerald Coast Real Estate Market Trending?</title>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/where-is-the-emerald-coast-real-estate-market-trending.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Nathan Abbott</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-03 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Hows+the+Emerald+Coast+housing+market+doing%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What’s happening in our local real estate market?

As a whole, our market is very healthy right now. There are indications that it’s converting into a buyer’s market but some of that is due to December being a traditionally slow month for a vacation market, such as ours.

We are in one of the fastest-growing areas in the country for primary residents, and we’re being discovered on a national level. Growing up in this area, I can tell you that, historically, most of our real estate traffic has come from the Southeast region. Now, though, we have residents coming from as far away as California.

“Our area is being discovered on a national level.”

In the past, whenever we had a rise or fall in the market, there was so much speculation in our area that a lot of people who bought properties didn’t have the holding power to keep them and shouldn’t have been buying those properties on the level that they were. Today, there isn’t nearly as much speculation. The activity in our market now is based more on our exposure and people wanting to live in our area.

If you get a loan, lenders are very strict right now about who they’re lending to. There is a lot of cash entering our market, and that’s a strong indication of longevity. Another indicator I always look at in gauging market strength is how the commercial growth is happening in that area, and our commercial growth has been great lately. We have a brand-new 5-star hotel, a new Whole Foods, and plenty of new shopping centers up and down Highway 98. These property developments are all signs of a strengthening market.

Shopping and Entertainment, Brand New and Expansions:

Destin Commons

Pier Park

Pier Park North

The HUB

30 Avenue

New Hotels:

The Henderson (5 star)

The Pearl of Rosemary

The Hampton Inn

If you have any questions about our market or if there’s anything I can assist you with, please feel free to give me a ring or shoot me an email. I would love the opportunity to serve you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Hows+the+Emerald+Coast+housing+market+doing%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://ownemeraldcoast.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Hows+the+Emerald+Coast+housing+market+doing%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Thanks to a growing national exposure and a windfall of commercial development, our real estate market is very healthy.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nathan Abbott</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Thanks to a growing national exposure and a windfall of commercial development, our real estate market is very healthy.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Florida's Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Nathan Abbott</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Nathan Abbott</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Nathan Abbott Team - your professional Florida's Emerald Coast Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
