<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Andrey Bustamante Team Real Estate Podcast</title>
    <link>localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Andrey Bustamante Team - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Andrey Bustamante</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2017-03-08 15:35:27 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Andrey Bustamante</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000/img/podcast.png"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">News &amp; Politics</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>info@andreybustamante.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Andrey Bustamante</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Andrey Bustamante</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="localhost:4000/img/podcast.png"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the  Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Andrey Bustamante Team - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="News &amp; Politics"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Latest Scoop on Orlando Real Estate</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/the-latest-scoop-on-orlando-real-estate.html</link>
        
        <author>Andrey Bustamante</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-03 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Andrey%20Bustamante/Jan%201%20%283%29.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Some of you know already, but we have recently relocated our corporate headquarters to downtown Orlando. We’re very excited about the opportunity to host you and your family in our new state-of-the-art office. I get lots of questions about the Orlando market, so I want to address one of them now. Are we in a buyer’s or seller’s market?

It depends on the price point more than anything else. In the lower price points, we have more of a seller’s market. There isn’t as much inventory and there are first-time buyers and investors all fighting for the same type of property.

The current inventory as a whole is rather short. There is a shortage of houses on the market, particularly in the lower price points. As you get higher in price point, there is a lot more inventory. In those basic price points, however, there is definitely a shortage of homes.

“Some homes are even selling over list price.”

This affects home values. The higher-priced homes are seeing a lot of price reductions to help them move. They are selling for about 90% to 93% of their list price on average. The homes in the lower price range are selling closer to 100% of their list price—some are even selling for more than that.

Interest rates have gone up recently and they are expected to continue to climb even further. A few months ago they were hovering around 3.25%, and now they are upwards of 4.2%.

What does this mean to you as a buyer or seller? The general market conditions are still very good. Buyers are buying houses on a daily basis. As a matter of fact, 2,654 homes were sold in the last month. The median price of these sales is right around $205,000. The market is extremely healthy right now and should continue to be healthy in the coming months. It’s a great time to buy and sell.

If you have any questions, comments, or concerns for us, we would love to hear from you. Just give us a call or send us an email. We would also love to help out if you or someone you know is looking to make a move. We look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Andrey%20Bustamante/Jan%201%20%283%29.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Andrey%20Bustamante/Jan%201%20%283%29.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>The Orlando market looks great. Here’s what you should know.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Andrey Bustamante</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>The Orlando market looks great. Here’s what you should know.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Andrey Bustamante</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Andrey Bustamante</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Andrey Bustamante Team - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
