<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Govig and Associates Podcast</title>
    <link>http://govigblog.com</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://govigblog.com"/>
    <description>Govig &amp; Associates is one of the largest privately held firms in the Executive Search industry. With more than three decades in staffing and recruiting, we have the knowledge, the network and the speed to provide unparalleled service to our clients.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Govig and Associates</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2017-06-15 11:02:23 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Govig and Associates</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://govigblog.com/img/govig_podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>recruiter, executive recruiter, executive search, executive search firms, executive headhunters, top executive recruiters, recruitment firm, management recruiter</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">News &amp; Politics</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email></itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Govig and Associates</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Govig and Associates</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://govigblog.com/img/govig_podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>recruiter, executive recruiter, executive search, executive search firms, executive headhunters, top executive recruiters, recruitment firm, management recruiter</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle></itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>Govig &amp; Associates is one of the largest privately held firms in the Executive Search industry. With more than three decades in staffing and recruiting, we have the knowledge, the network and the speed to provide unparalleled service to our clients.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="News &amp; Politics"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>These 3 Traits Make a Great Team Player</title>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/these-3-traits-make-a-great-team-player.html</link>
        
          <category>Health Care</category>
        
        <author>Govig and Associates</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-13 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Healthcare/Videos/2017/These+3+Traits+Make+a+Great+Team+Player+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>

What does the ideal team player look like?

I recently read a book by Patrick Lencioni called “The Ideal Team Player,” and the premise of this book is that when the author hires for his team or assesses his team, he hones in on three main traits: humble, hungry, and smart.

“Humble” is pretty self-explanatory because you don’t want a team member who is arrogant or egocentric. Someone who is humble and plays well with others will put the team before themselves. Herb Brooks said it best in “Miracle,” the name on the front of the jersey should always be more important than the name on the back.

Someone who is hungry will want more responsibility, will want to learn more, and be self-motivated. They won’t need to be micromanaged.

“Someone who is hungry will want more responsibility, to learn more, and be self-motivated.”

Finally, when he says someone is “smart,” it’s not the first thing you think of when it comes to intelligence. In this context, it refers more to being socially smart. A smart team member knows how to read people, knows how they’re perceived, and is aware of their social presence in a conversation.

With these traits, there are also three extremes to be aware of as well. Someone who is too humble could be afraid to contribute or speak up when it could benefit their team. Someone who is too hungry can be a steamroller, rolling over anyone at any cost to succeed. Someone who is too socially smart might be considered a schmoozer who tells you everything you want to hear, even when it might not be the truth.

If you’d like to talk further about how these traits affect a team dynamic or you’d like to talk more about your career, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I’d love to hear from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Healthcare/Videos/2017/These+3+Traits+Make+a+Great+Team+Player+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://govigblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Healthcare/Videos/2017/These+3+Traits+Make+a+Great+Team+Player+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>When it comes to team dynamics, there are three traits we like to look for that we've borrowed from the book "The Ideal Team Player."</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Govig and Associates</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>When it comes to team dynamics, there are three traits we like to look for that we've borrowed from the book "The Ideal Team Player."</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>recruiter, executive recruiter, executive search, executive search firms, executive headhunters, top executive recruiters, recruitment firm, management recruiter</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Conflict Resolution in the Workplace</title>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/conflict-resolution-in-the-workplace.html</link>
        
          <category>Bio Pharma</category>
        
        <author>Govig and Associates</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-12 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/BioPharma/Videos/2017/Conflict+Resolution+in+the+Workplace.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What are the top leadership skills? There are really quite a few skills we’d like to cover, so this video is the first of a bimonthly series on this topic. The first skill I wanted to focus on is how to navigate relationships in the workplace, or conflict resolution.

Conflict resolution is not a topic that most people are eager to discuss. However, fundamentally, it is one of the most important things you can learn how to do and learn how to be effective at. This is because everything is team-oriented today. We rarely see business environments that don’t have people somehow involved in a team. Plus, it’s a management skill; how do you create teams that are effective, efficient, and that have good communication?

“Everything is team-oriented today.”

Patrick Lencioni’s book “The Five Dysfunctions of a Team” helped me significantly in learning and mastering this particular leadership skill and I recommend it highly for anyone who is interested. The process of conflict resolution is:

1. Identify the problem and decide what the end goal will be and why that outcome will be beneficial.
2. Craft your language with an objective third party.
3. Have a meeting with the person you have a concern with. Be straightforward with the issue right away.
4. Compliment the person on their good aspects to diffuse any kind of defensiveness they may have as you discuss the issue.
5. Move on to what your concern is, what your end goal is, and why that would be beneficial to both that person and the team as a whole.
6. Ask for feedback.

It sounds simple, but you need to practice this tactic. It is fundamental to not only leadership within a group, but also how effectively you can manage and navigate relationships as you progress to management.

In our next video, we’ll talk more about leadership skills. If you have any questions about this or any other topic we’ve covered, please don’t hesitate to reach out. We’d be happy to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/BioPharma/Videos/2017/Conflict+Resolution+in+the+Workplace.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://govigblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/BioPharma/Videos/2017/Conflict+Resolution+in+the+Workplace.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>I’m always asked what some of the top leadership skills are. Today I wanted to talk to you about conflict resolution in the workplace.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Govig and Associates</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>I’m always asked what some of the top leadership skills are. Today I wanted to talk to you about conflict resolution in the workplace.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>recruiter, executive recruiter, executive search, executive search firms, executive headhunters, top executive recruiters, recruitment firm, management recruiter</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Must Companies Constantly Reinvent Themselves?</title>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/why-must-companies-constantly-reinvent-themselves.html</link>
        
          <category>Futurity</category>
        
        <author>Govig and Associates</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-05 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Futurity/Videos/2017/Why+Must+Companies+Constantly+Reinvent+Themselves%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

To keep pace with constant changes in the market and in the world at large, businesses must learn how to adapt and continually reinvent themselves in order to secure a future. Why do companies need to do this, though? It reminds me of the Winchester Mansion project. Let me tell you why.

Sarah Winchester was an heir to the Winchester Rifle fortune. Unfortunately, after her husband died she became convinced that she was cursed by all the victims that had lost their lives to Winchester rifles.

She decided to build a sprawling mansion and she never stopped. She built stairways to ceilings, doorways in floors, and all sorts of hidden passageways and secret rooms. What appeared to be beautiful from the outside was actually very chaotic and confusing on the inside

“Many factors can lead to chaos.”

An evolving business can be like that. When you think about the technology advancement, market shorts, organic growth, and new leadership all playing a part in a company’s future, what can appear to be calm on the outside is often chaotic from the inside.

When you’re living in a business day in and day out, you don’t necessarily see what’s going on. So take a step back and be objective when looking at your organization and how it needs to adapt in order to continue its success in the future. What was relevant yesterday just might not be relevant today.

If you’d like to talk more about your business or how you can ensure it’s as efficient and effective as possible, give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Futurity/Videos/2017/Why+Must+Companies+Constantly+Reinvent+Themselves%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://govigblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Futurity/Videos/2017/Why+Must+Companies+Constantly+Reinvent+Themselves%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Businesses must constantly reinvent themselves these days. It’s how they stay relevant and compete with new companies.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Govig and Associates</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Businesses must constantly reinvent themselves these days. It’s how they stay relevant and compete with new companies.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>recruiter, executive recruiter, executive search, executive search firms, executive headhunters, top executive recruiters, recruitment firm, management recruiter</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Telephone and Virtual Interview Tips</title>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/telephone-and-virtual-interview-tips.html</link>
        
          <category>Bio Pharma</category>
        
        <author>Govig and Associates</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-22 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/BioPharma/Videos/2017/Telephone+and+Virtual+Interview+Tips.mp4</guid>
        <description>

We recently had a question about how to better handle telephone interviews or virtual (Skype) interviews. I am going to elaborate a little bit on this topic today.

In both of these instances, you want to make sure you’re prepared and know your skills, your accomplishments, and how those things benefit the person you’re interviewing with. Secondly, you want to make sure you’ve done your research on the hiring authority, their background, and their accomplishments. Finally, you’ve got to do your research on the company. The more prepared you are, the more confident you will be.

“In either instance, you want to be prepared.”

For telephone interviews, the best tip I have for you is to stand up. By standing up, you will have more energy in your voice and in terms of how you bring across the information that is relevant in the interview.

When you’re doing a Skype interview, it’s not as simple. You typically have to sit down in that situation, so standing up can be difficult. The big thing to remember is to keep distractions at a minimum. That means making sure everything shown on camera is neat and anyone else in the house with you knows to keep loud noises at a minimum for the duration of your interview.

If you have any questions about this topic or want to learn more interview tips, give me a call or send me an email. I would be glad to discuss this topic further with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/BioPharma/Videos/2017/Telephone+and+Virtual+Interview+Tips.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://govigblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/BioPharma/Videos/2017/Telephone+and+Virtual+Interview+Tips.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Are you interviewing via skype or over the telephone sometime soon? If so, I’ve got a few tips to share with you.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Govig and Associates</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Are you interviewing via skype or over the telephone sometime soon? If so, I’ve got a few tips to share with you.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>recruiter, executive recruiter, executive search, executive search firms, executive headhunters, top executive recruiters, recruitment firm, management recruiter</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Few Outside the Box Hiring Tips</title>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/a-few-outside-the-box-hiring-tips.html</link>
        
          <category>Building Products</category>
        
        <author>Govig and Associates</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-22 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Building+Products/Videos/2017/A+Few+Outside+the+Box+Hiring+Tips.mp4</guid>
        <description>

How do companies in this industry grow faster than the industry average? The common denominator is that they think outside the box when bringing new people on board.

When you think about it, every company is basically looking to fill their roles by looking at the same criteria. You want someone with product experience, selling experience, and a proven track record. The only thing that separates the top companies from the average ones is the culture of the organization. In fact, a recent USA Today study concluded that 85% of the people that were hired only had 65% of the actual criteria they were looking for.

Companies are hiring people who fit their culture as opposed to people who have the exact skill sets they are looking for. They are thinking outside the box about what skills could be transferrable from a similar industry just by teaching the product. 

“We’ve had success recruiting pharmaceutical reps”

When we look for A&amp;D reps, we certainly would love to find someone with that experience, but we also have had a tremendous amount of success actually recruiting pharmaceutical reps. A&amp;D reps update libraries, work with a designer to influence them to specify their product on a particular project, and they do lunch and learns. Pharmaceutical reps have a very similar transactions with their doctors. They influence the doctor to write the scripts, work with the office in updating samples, and do lunch and learns. As you can see, those skills are very transferrable and this strategy has been very successful for the companies we have worked with.

When you’re thinking about hiring, thinking outside the box is important. Don’t go down that normal track because you have the same people always cycling through the industry, just with a different business card. Be different and be bold.

If you have any questions for me, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Building+Products/Videos/2017/A+Few+Outside+the+Box+Hiring+Tips.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://govigblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Building+Products/Videos/2017/A+Few+Outside+the+Box+Hiring+Tips.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What do the top companies in this industry have in common? They think outside the box when hiring.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Govig and Associates</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What do the top companies in this industry have in common? They think outside the box when hiring.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>recruiter, executive recruiter, executive search, executive search firms, executive headhunters, top executive recruiters, recruitment firm, management recruiter</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3 Questions That Lead to the Perfect Hire</title>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/3-questions-that-lead-to-the-perfect-hire.html</link>
        
          <category>Health Care</category>
        
        <author>Govig and Associates</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-18 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Healthcare/Videos/2017/3+Questions+That+Lead+to+the+Perfect+Hire.mp4</guid>
        <description>
Making a better hiring decision boils down to three questions you should ask yourself when interviewing any candidate for your organization.

First, can do they do the job? Do they have the mental ability, skill set, and personality to do the job well? If they don’t have the skill set to do the job well, do you have the ability to train them and teach them the required skills to get them up to speed quickly to give you a return on investment for that hire?

“The best candidate is not always the right candidate.”

Second, can they do the job long term? Do they have the aspirations to be at the job long term? If they don’t, do you have a timeline that aligns with theirs or can you give them additional responsibilities or a promotion to keep them engaged in your organization in the long term?

Finally, are they the right fit for the team? The best candidate is not always the right candidate. The team culture is very important, so they need to fit the mold and fit to the culture while also performing.

If you have any questions about this topic, please feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Healthcare/Videos/2017/3+Questions+That+Lead+to+the+Perfect+Hire.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://govigblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Healthcare/Videos/2017/3+Questions+That+Lead+to+the+Perfect+Hire.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you want to make a better hiring decision, ask yourself these three questions when interviewing candidates.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Govig and Associates</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you want to make a better hiring decision, ask yourself these three questions when interviewing candidates.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>recruiter, executive recruiter, executive search, executive search firms, executive headhunters, top executive recruiters, recruitment firm, management recruiter</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Jumpstart Your Post-College Career</title>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/how-to-jumpstart-your-post-college-career.html</link>
        
          <category>Careers</category>
        
        <author>Govig and Associates</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-05 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Careers/Videos/2017/How+to+Jumpstart+Your+Post-College+Career.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you just finished college but you aren’t sure what you want to do or how to enter the business world, then you’re not alone. If you want a successful career, there are two things that you need to understand. 

First of all, you need to be aware of the latest demographic trends and how they will affect your career. Baby boomers are retiring at a rate of 10,000 people a day. There simply aren’t enough experienced people to replace the baby boomers, which creates an opportunity for up and comers. 

Secondly, I recommend that you read “Outliers” by Malcolm Gladwell. This is a great book and its fundamental thesis is that it takes 10,000 hours for you to become really good at any skill set. From athletics to music to software programming, you need 10,000 hours of experience to fully understand the skills needed for the job. 

“Choose a job that you can develop a passion for and stick with it.”

As a recent college graduate, you need to figure out how you can combine the demographic trends with the 10,000 hour rule. 

Rather than following what appears to be the millennial career path of having 16 different jobs with 20 different companies in three years, find something that you can develop a passion for over time. The problem with frequently changing jobs is that you are never in one place long enough to get really good at one particular job. If you spend 10,000 hours—which roughly equals five years—in one career, then you will be extremely knowledgeable about that particular area.   

It takes awhile to understand the common knowledge of the domain, and it takes even longer to know the uncommon knowledge that gives the top 1% their competitive edge. That uncommon knowledge is not a secret; you just don’t have enough knowledge to really execute the job properly until you have been there long enough to know the common knowledge. 

So, you need to go into an area where you can develop some passion for the job and learn all about it. Since baby boomers are retiring in droves, there will be plenty of opportunities for you down the line. By spending all your time on one career path, you will have a leg up on other millennials who have had a few different jobs and aren’t especially good at any one thing. 

Companies are dying to hire people who know their space and can bring value to the table. To be successful in your career, you need to become that person. 

If you have any other questions about entering the real world of business, give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Careers/Videos/2017/How+to+Jumpstart+Your+Post-College+Career.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://govigblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Careers/Videos/2017/How+to+Jumpstart+Your+Post-College+Career.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you are a recent college graduate, don’t just start bouncing from one job to the next. There are a couple of things you can do to launch a successful career.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Govig and Associates</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you are a recent college graduate, don’t just start bouncing from one job to the next. There are a couple of things you can do to launch a successful career.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>recruiter, executive recruiter, executive search, executive search firms, executive headhunters, top executive recruiters, recruitment firm, management recruiter</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Leading a Hockey Team Is Like Leading a Business</title>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/how-leading-a-hockey-team-is-like-leading-a-business.html</link>
        
          <category>Futurity</category>
        
        <author>Govig and Associates</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-04 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Futurity/Videos/2017/How+Leading+a+Hockey+Team+Is+Like+Leading+a+Business.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What can business leaders learn from hockey? 

In hockey, players are taught to skate not to where the puck is, but where it’s going next. To win the game, you have to be able to effectively anticipate your next move.

In N. Dean Meyer’s book, “Structural Cybernetics,” he actually talks about five different organizational systems. The first is culture, which is how we treat one another. The second is structure, which is work charts and workflows. Then, there is the internal economy, which is how money moves throughout the organization. The fourth is methods and tools, and the last is metrics and reward, which is incentives and accountability. 

Here’s a really good example of how anticipation works in business. In a company, you could have a people problem, which ultimately could be a structural problem or a culture problem. Or, simply put, it could simply be that you need to change out an existing tool.

For companies, not knowing how to anticipate the difference or the end result of your actions can mean fixing one problem only to cause two more. 

Companies need to think like hockey players so they can effectively anticipate their next move.

“Winning is all about the ability to anticipate the next move.”

In the movie Miracle on Ice, there’s a saying that comes up over and over, ‘the legs feed the wolf.’ The coach anticipated that in order for this team to go all the way to the Olympics, they would need one thing, and that was to be able to have the strongest legs on the ice. So he trained his players to not only have the strongest legs but also have the greatest amount of endurance. His ability to anticipate what his team needed from beginning to end was why they won the gold.

If you have any further questions about the power of anticipation in business, we’d be happy to answer them. We hope to hear from you soon!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Futurity/Videos/2017/How+Leading+a+Hockey+Team+Is+Like+Leading+a+Business.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://govigblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Futurity/Videos/2017/How+Leading+a+Hockey+Team+Is+Like+Leading+a+Business.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What can leaders in the business world learn from hockey? Getting ahead is all about anticipation.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Govig and Associates</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What can leaders in the business world learn from hockey? Getting ahead is all about anticipation.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>recruiter, executive recruiter, executive search, executive search firms, executive headhunters, top executive recruiters, recruitment firm, management recruiter</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How the Affordable Care Act Affects the Nursing Home Industry</title>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/how-the-affordable-care-act-affects-the-nursing-home-industry.html</link>
        
          <category>Health Care</category>
        
        <author>Govig and Associates</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-27 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Healthcare/Videos/2017/How+the+Affordable+Care+Act+Affects+the+Nursing+Home+Industry.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The Affordable Care Act was designed to provide health care coverage for those who didn’t have insurance, so how is it affecting the nursing home industry?

Within the nursing home industry, most residents do have some form of coverage whether it’s Medicare, Medicaid, or an HMO, so the thought was that the impact the Affordable Care Act would have on the nursing home industry would be small, if any.

The unforeseen consequence is that it really exacerbates the shortage and the demand for physicians. It adds strain on the number of medical professionals available. In fact, by the year 2025, there will be a shortage of 52,000 primary care physicians for a few reasons. The first is that very few study nursing home care while in medical school. Second, regulations are often very high, and third, the pay is often lower for that type of role.

“By the year 2025, there will be a shortage of 52,000 primary care physicians.”

There are, however, a few things that management of nursing home facilities can do to make sure they are aligned strongly with a physician for their community.

First, take an executive approach to make sure your administrator and the director of nursing build a good rapport with physicians in your marketplace. If the medical community hires a new physician, your administrator should invite them out to get a feel for your community and introduce them to the care you provide.

Again, physicians want to have a rapport built with key executives, like the administrator and director of nursing. Ensuring that rapport is built will have you on your way to having a physician in your corner.

If you have any questions, please feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Healthcare/Videos/2017/How+the+Affordable+Care+Act+Affects+the+Nursing+Home+Industry.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://govigblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Healthcare/Videos/2017/How+the+Affordable+Care+Act+Affects+the+Nursing+Home+Industry.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>How does the Affordable Care Act affect the nursing home industry? I’ll answer that for you today.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Govig and Associates</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>How does the Affordable Care Act affect the nursing home industry? I’ll answer that for you today.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>recruiter, executive recruiter, executive search, executive search firms, executive headhunters, top executive recruiters, recruitment firm, management recruiter</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Best Ways to Differentiate Your Company in Today’s Market</title>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/the-best-ways-to-differentiate-your-company-in-todays-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Building Products</category>
        
        <author>Govig and Associates</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-26 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Building+Products/Videos/2017/The+Best+Ways+to+Differentiate+Your+Company+in+Todays+Market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What really differentiates companies in today’s marketplace? The two biggest ways companies can set themselves apart are through thought leadership and online presence. 

Now, 2017 is going to be a big year for manufacturers in the building products industry. As a whole, the industry is projected to grow, but that also means there will be a lot of competition. The manufacturers who stay ahead of the curve with their sales and marketing efforts will continue to create competitive advantages as the industry continues to rebound. 

In many ways, though, the building and design industry is still old school. Jobs are won and lost through relationships and connections, and products are chosen for similar reasons. Even though manufacturers understand that their online presence is important, they haven’t gone the extra step to truly differentiate themselves from the competition. The “follow the leader” mentality is still a prevailing force in the industry, and even the companies who invest in their online presence tend to have similar online profiles. 

“Use articles, blogs, and videos to produce thought leadership.”

As online usage continues to grow, your online presence needs to measure up. Consumers want the manufacturers to solve their problems, so manufacturers are realizing that just pushing their product isn’t enough to get their audience’s attention anymore. You really have to produce thought leadership through articles, blogs, videos, and other online content that really helps solve that everyday business problem. 

Ultimately, great marketing helps the audience solve the issues that matter to them. Remember, people are not buying products; they are buying solutions. 

If you have any questions, please don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Building+Products/Videos/2017/The+Best+Ways+to+Differentiate+Your+Company+in+Todays+Market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://govigblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Building+Products/Videos/2017/The+Best+Ways+to+Differentiate+Your+Company+in+Todays+Market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What really differentiates companies in today’s marketplace? You need to focus on thought leadership and your online presence.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Govig and Associates</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What really differentiates companies in today’s marketplace? You need to focus on thought leadership and your online presence.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>recruiter, executive recruiter, executive search, executive search firms, executive headhunters, top executive recruiters, recruitment firm, management recruiter</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Is a Sales Driven Company Right for You?</title>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/is-a-sales-driven-company-right-for-you.html</link>
        
          <category>Careers</category>
        
        <author>Govig and Associates</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-12 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Careers/Videos/2017/Is+a+Sales+Driven+Company+Right+for+You%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I recently got asked a great question by a friend of mine whose son was graduating from college and looking to go into a sales career. So, today I’m answering the question, “What should you look for in a company when looking for a career in sales?”

The number No. 1 I would look for in a company when seeking a sales career is if the company is sales driven. Companies can be marketing driven, research driven, or distribution driven, but you want to make sure you’re with a sales driven company.

For example, a marketing driven company would be Visa. They are great at marketing and have great brand identity across the world. A research company would be a company like 3M, which is phenomenal with their research and development which leads to them producing fantastic products.

“If you want a lasting career in sales, make sure the company is sales driven.”

A sales driven company is a company that places a high value on salespeople, and as a result they are compensated accordingly. One question I would ask the president or CEO to find out if a company is a sales driven company is, “What do you do when your top sales rep makes more money than you?” A company that would see that as a problem is not a sales driven company, whereas a company that says they would send them on a trip, buy them a watch, reward them, or ask them to teach other reps is a sales driven company.

If you want to have a career in sales, your best earning potential and long-term potential is going to be with a company that understands and respects sales and rewards people accordingly.

If you have any questions, please feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I’m always happy to help!

</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Careers/Videos/2017/Is+a+Sales+Driven+Company+Right+for+You%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://govigblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Careers/Videos/2017/Is+a+Sales+Driven+Company+Right+for+You%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Making sure a company is sales driven is key when setting up a long-lasting sales career. Here’s why.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Govig and Associates</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Making sure a company is sales driven is key when setting up a long-lasting sales career. Here’s why.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>recruiter, executive recruiter, executive search, executive search firms, executive headhunters, top executive recruiters, recruitment firm, management recruiter</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Your Hiring Process Impacts the Brand of Your Company</title>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/how-your-hiring-process-impacts-the-brand-of-your-company.html</link>
        
          <category>Building Products</category>
        
        <author>Govig and Associates</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-07 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Building+Products/Videos/2017/How+Your+Hiring+Process+Impacts+the+Brand+of+Your+Company.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Request a Consultation - Hire Us to Fill Your Job Openings

Does your hiring process impact the brand of your company? The simple answer is yes.

Companies create marketing experiences for customers in order to drive positive engagement. They are now realizing that they need to do the same thing for the candidates that come through to interview.

Given that the candidate-driven market continues to be a reality for the executive, managerial, and professional labor levels, employers should give more consideration to the lasting impression that they leave.

Companies should really think about the interview process as a critical part of the strategy in communicating their brand and organizational culture. After all, applicants will communicate their interview experience in the marketplace through social media or conversations with their peers.

“Make sure that you have an efficient interview process.”

To make sure that your company’s hiring process is in line with its mission, values, and business goals, I recommend avoiding these two simple contradictions:

1. Having an inefficient interview process when the company claims to be cutting edge. It’s very important that when someone comes in for an interview, they know exactly who they will be interviewing with, why they are interviewing with that person, and how long the interview will take. The more buttoned-up that process is, the better impression your company will have on the candidate. The candidate will believe that the company has strong communication skills, knows what they are looking for, and has the ability to get things done in a timely manner.

2. Taking too long to hire candidates when the company claims to value speed. When a company has people in the hiring process and cannot give them feedback or takes too long to get the candidate through the process, then the candidate thinks the company may not know how to make a decision. That can scare candidates away from a company because they want to know that when they are hired, it will be easy to get things done.

These two things seem very simple but can become very difficult to execute, especially if your company is bigger. Regardless of the size of your company, just remember that your hiring process can impact your company’s brand.

If you have any questions, please don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Building+Products/Videos/2017/How+Your+Hiring+Process+Impacts+the+Brand+of+Your+Company.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://govigblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Building+Products/Videos/2017/How+Your+Hiring+Process+Impacts+the+Brand+of+Your+Company.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Your hiring process impacts your company’s brand. What can you do to create a positive experience for job candidates?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Govig and Associates</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Your hiring process impacts your company’s brand. What can you do to create a positive experience for job candidates?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>recruiter, executive recruiter, executive search, executive search firms, executive headhunters, top executive recruiters, recruitment firm, management recruiter</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Employer Brand Attracts Talent. Here's How to Improve Yours</title>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/employer-brand-attracts-talent-heres-how-to-improve-yours.html</link>
        
          <category>Health Care</category>
        
        <author>Govig and Associates</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-06 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Healthcare/Videos/2017/Employer+Brand+Attracts+Talent.+Here%2527s+How+to+Improve+Yours.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Your employer brand is just as important (if not more important) than the product and the services you provide as an organization. Companies that attract top talent are the ones that have a proactive approach to strengthening their employer brand.

There are three specific tools you can use to strengthen your brand as an employer to attract top talent:

1. Glassdoor.com: This is a community where current employees can rate their employer. They can rate the CEO, the interview process, the CEO’s vision for the company, and the company as a whole. Good, bad, right, or wrong, employees can leave feedback, and as a prospect, this is one of the first places you want to look to see if it’s an organization you want to work for. Companies who do this well take a proactive approach to commenting on this feedback. Commenting on feedback shows that you care as an organization and that you take this feedback seriously and want to improve.

2. Utilize social media:Most companies have a website to showcase themselves as employers, but companies that do very well with branding have other avenues. To attract top talent, organizations should have a company Facebook page, Twitter handle, and YouTube channel to give updates and showcase the culture. This could include awards you’ve won or fun things going on.

3. A company LinkedIn page: This falls under social media as well, but it’s also where a lot of talent is and where they spend a lot of time. Your company LinkedIn page should always be up to date with current openings as well as company news. Keep it relevant to stay ahead of the curve.

If you have any other questions about how to boost your employer brand, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to hear from you.

</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Healthcare/Videos/2017/Employer+Brand+Attracts+Talent.+Here%2527s+How+to+Improve+Yours.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://govigblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Healthcare/Videos/2017/Employer+Brand+Attracts+Talent.+Here%2527s+How+to+Improve+Yours.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Employer brand can be just as important as your product or services. Here are few ways to improve that brand to help attract top talent.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Govig and Associates</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Employer brand can be just as important as your product or services. Here are few ways to improve that brand to help attract top talent.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>recruiter, executive recruiter, executive search, executive search firms, executive headhunters, top executive recruiters, recruitment firm, management recruiter</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Futurity Assessment Got the Name</title>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/how-futurity-assessment-got-the-name.html</link>
        
          <category>Futurity</category>
        
        <author>Govig and Associates</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-31 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Futurity/Videos/2017/How+Futurity+Assessment+Got+the+Name.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Do you know how Futurity Assessment got its name or what our process is?

A couple years ago, I was visiting a client in Chicago and having a conversation with their CEO. The conversation took a unique shift.

We were talking about how important it was that the company focused on how they would prepare for the future and not just on how they were performing today. At that point, the CEO told me that no one was actually speaking to him about the future readiness of his organization, and if that’s what I wanted to talk about, he’d actually stand up and listen.

Obviously, this conversation was very impactful to me. When I got home from the trip, I knew I had to find a name that really defines future readiness. Just like everyone, I hopped online to start and I found the word ‘futurity.’ Oddly enough, ‘futurity’ is actually a horse show in which young horses are judged on what their future abilities look like.

“We aim to bring a company’s future into the present.”

We took that premise and designed it for companies.

So, the company Futurity Assessment is a process or tool that companies can use to benchmark themselves against what their future abilities look like.We focus on four key areas:

Employment branding - what’s the value proposition the company has for its employees and how does it relate to retention?

Leadership potential - who can the company groom for leadership roles in the future and what is their succession plan?

Putting together development and growth strategies - we actually design a future organization chart for the company.

Process mapping - this is where the organization can uncover where they need to be more efficient in their processes.

The goal of our company is to bring the future into the present so that companies can design the future they want instead of experiencing unwanted consequences they didn’t prepare for.

If you have any questions about our company or you’re interested in working with us, please reach out to us soon. We’d love to start an impactful conversation about your company’s future.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Futurity/Videos/2017/How+Futurity+Assessment+Got+the+Name.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://govigblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Futurity/Videos/2017/How+Futurity+Assessment+Got+the+Name.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>How did Futurity Assessment get that name? Explaining this story will help you understand exactly how we can bring you value.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Govig and Associates</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>How did Futurity Assessment get that name? Explaining this story will help you understand exactly how we can bring you value.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>recruiter, executive recruiter, executive search, executive search firms, executive headhunters, top executive recruiters, recruitment firm, management recruiter</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Do Telecommuters Affect a Workforce?</title>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/how-do-telecommuters-affect-a-workforce.html</link>
        
          <category>Building Products</category>
        
        <author>Govig and Associates</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-17 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Building+Products/Videos/2017/The+Power+Of+Telecommuters.mp4</guid>
        <description>

How do telecommuters affect a workforce?

Telecommuters who work from home are healthier, happier, more loyal, and have a much better work-life balance. The regular, work-at-home, non-self-employed population has grown 103% in the last 10 years. While there is no real census bureau or government data, global workplace analytics research shows that 50% of the U.S. workforce is already compatible to work remotely. 

Furthermore, 80% to 90% of the workforce would love to do it. Their preference would be to work this way part-time (meaning generally two to three days a week), which they feel would give them a great balance of concentrative work at home and collaborative work at the office. 

Fortune 1,000 companies have already started revamping their offices globally to support the people that already work mobile. Within every company, studies have shown that employees are only at their desk 50% to 60% of the time. I know companies are worried about whether people actually work when they work from home, but we’ve found that 76% of telecommuters say they actually put in more work and work harder when companies support their position. They are also more loyal to that organization. 

On average, work-from-home programs for businesses save $2,000 per person, per year. They’ve also reduced the turnover rate by 50%. We all know that when turnover is reduced, it saves a company exponential amounts of money.

“The companies that are growing the fastest are the ones embracing telecommuters.”

This move toward telecommuting can be either a blessing or a curse to the office furniture industry. I think companies that have perfected or are moving toward being able to sell 1,000 home workstations in the same amount of time that they’re selling 1,000 workstations for an office space are going to have tremendous opportunities in the future.

The bottom line is companies who are growing the most aggressively are the ones able to make the shift and have the ability to support telecommuters. Keep in mind, though, that you still have to hire the right person with the right mindset and the right capability to work remotely and still be effective. It’s still an adjustment for many people.

If you have any questions about the emergence of telecommuters in the workforce, please don’t hesitate to give us a call. We’d be happy to speak with you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Building+Products/Videos/2017/The+Power+Of+Telecommuters.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://govigblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Building+Products/Videos/2017/The+Power+Of+Telecommuters.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Telecommuting can be either a blessing or a curse to the office furniture industry, but here’s why I believe the future is brighter for companies who embrace telecommuters.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Govig and Associates</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Telecommuting can be either a blessing or a curse to the office furniture industry, but here’s why I believe the future is brighter for companies who embrace telecommuters.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>recruiter, executive recruiter, executive search, executive search firms, executive headhunters, top executive recruiters, recruitment firm, management recruiter</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Can You Compete in the Top 1% in Your Industry?</title>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/how-can-you-compete-in-the-top-1-in-your-industry.html</link>
        
          <category>Bio Pharma</category>
        
        <author>Govig and Associates</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-15 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/BioPharma/Videos/2017/How+Can+You+Compete+in+the+Top+1%2525+in+Your+Industry%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What’s the number one thing you can do to compete in the top 1% in terms of career progression? It’s really simple, but it takes commitment. There’s a simple saying I’d like to share in that regard: There is no such thing as luck—it’s only preparation meeting opportunity.

What do you think that means? How does that apply to you?

First, ask yourself three questions:


  Are you disciplined?
  Are you willing to commit one hour a week?
  Are you willing to do it for the rest of your career?


If the answer is yes and if you think you can compete in the top 1%, then follow these suggestions.

First, read for an hour a week. Pick 10 to 12 publications and sift through them rapidly within that hour. These publications should cover all aspects of the world and relate to whatever industry you’re focused in, whether that’s politics, economics, and/or technology. You can pick many ways to get this information—digital, hard copy, newspaper, magazines, etc. It really doesn’t matter. What matters is that you’re getting a wide range of information and getting it fast.

“There is no such thing as luck—it’s only preparation meeting opportunity.”

Next, ‘pulse-read’ through that information. What do I mean by that? Pulse reading means going through any magazine, looking at each topic, and deciding whether it’s relevant to the topic you’re interested in. If not, read only the first paragraph and move on. If the next topic you pick is of deeper interest, you might read the first paragraph, then the second paragraph, and only the last paragraph before moving on. You’ll do this with any publication you subscribe to.

In the end, after months of months (or years and years) of doing this, you’ll have a repertoire of information you can draw on that will allow you to make decisions in an expert manner because you’ll have a wealth of subject matter relevant to those decisions.

The most successful people I’ve known over the years—over a wide range of industries—have always been avid readers. If you have any questions about this topic, please feel free to reach out to us. We’d be happy to speak with you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/BioPharma/Videos/2017/How+Can+You+Compete+in+the+Top+1%2525+in+Your+Industry%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://govigblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/BioPharma/Videos/2017/How+Can+You+Compete+in+the+Top+1%2525+in+Your+Industry%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>The key to competing in the top 1% in terms of career progression involves reading the right material and doing it over and over again. Here’s what I mean.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Govig and Associates</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>The key to competing in the top 1% in terms of career progression involves reading the right material and doing it over and over again. Here’s what I mean.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>recruiter, executive recruiter, executive search, executive search firms, executive headhunters, top executive recruiters, recruitment firm, management recruiter</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Formatting an Effective Resume</title>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/formatting-an-effective-resume.html</link>
        
          <category>Health Care</category>
        
        <author>Govig and Associates</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-15 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Healthcare/Videos/2017/4+Ways+to+Spruce+Up+Your+Resume.mp4</guid>
        <description>

How can you format a resume to make it the most effective?

The first piece is the most basic but often overlooked, which is making sure all of your contact information is up to date. Make sure you don’t have an outdated email address or cell phone number on your resume.

Next, you need to keep it consistent.You might update your resume with your most recent positions, which is fine, but make sure the font size, type, and color, are the same as the rest of the resume. Also, make sure bullet points are the same size and things that need to be italicized are italicized. It needs to look uniform throughout.

“Make sure all of your contact information is up to date.”

Make sure you don’t come across as a job hopper. If you have moved up in a company or have held multiple positions, put all those under the one company header.

Finally, you need to showcase your achievements, especially in terms of numbers. Anytime you can show accomplishments using numbers on a resume is fantastic.

If you have any other questions, feel free to email us or give us a call. We look forward to hearing from you.

</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Healthcare/Videos/2017/4+Ways+to+Spruce+Up+Your+Resume.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://govigblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Healthcare/Videos/2017/4+Ways+to+Spruce+Up+Your+Resume.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I want to take you through a few steps that will ensure your resume is the most effective.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Govig and Associates</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I want to take you through a few steps that will ensure your resume is the most effective.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>recruiter, executive recruiter, executive search, executive search firms, executive headhunters, top executive recruiters, recruitment firm, management recruiter</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Find Great DON Candidates</title>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/how-to-find-great-don-candidates.html</link>
        
          <category>Health Care</category>
        
        <author>Govig and Associates</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-27 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Healthcare/Videos/2017/How+to+Find+Great+DON+Candidates.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When I started here eight years ago, we were able to find qualified director of nursing candidates within 72 hours, generally, but times have changed. In January of 2017 alone, there were 7,500 postings for director of nursing candidates and only 1,200 active candidates, which shows the scarcity of these candidates out there. New York, Los Angeles, and Chicago were hit the hardest. 

So how can you combat this? There are a couple things you can do.

The first is to develop your bench strength. Look at your RNs, your MDS coordinators, your ADONs, and really put in the time and energy to mold them into someone who can step into that director of nursing role if needed. Generally speaking, the best hires you can make are people who know the organization, the culture, the leadership, and the vision of the company. 

Secondly, when you conduct interviews, interview for potential rather than just experience. I think the days of interviewing a director of nursing with 25 years of experience are coming to a close. Look at a candidate’s potential—can they step into that role two or three positions into their career? Do they have the potential to be molded and trained to be a director of nursing?

“Interview for potential rather than just experience.”

Finally, make sure that your director of nursing is engaged. As a search firm, the number one reason we hear candidates want to leave is that they’re not being supported by the subordinates that report to them, the leadership, or both. Make sure you touch base with that director of nursing periodically and that they’re engaged and happy in the role. We all know that the relationship between an administrator and director of nursing is vital, so they need to make sure they feel supported and have everything they need to feel supported.

If you have a vacancy, there a couple things you can do. 

For one, you can engage the staff you already have. Ask anybody in a clinical role who they’ve worked with in the past and respect who would be a great director of nursing. Some of the best referrals you can get come from employees you already have in the building. If you have exhausted all your resources, I really recommend engaging a search firm for the position. If you have 7,500 postings out there and only 1,200 active candidates, finding that needle in a haystack can be difficult.

If you have any other questions about this topic, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I’d be glad to help!
 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Healthcare/Videos/2017/How+to+Find+Great+DON+Candidates.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://govigblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Healthcare/Videos/2017/How+to+Find+Great+DON+Candidates.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What does it take to recruit a great candidate for a director of nursing? Today I'll go over the resources you can look to for finding a great candidate.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Govig and Associates</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What does it take to recruit a great candidate for a director of nursing? Today I'll go over the resources you can look to for finding a great candidate.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>recruiter, executive recruiter, executive search, executive search firms, executive headhunters, top executive recruiters, recruitment firm, management recruiter</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Best Way to Figure Out Who You Want to Hire</title>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/the-best-way-to-figure-out-who-you-want-to-hire.html</link>
        
          <category>Building Products</category>
        
        <author>Govig and Associates</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-23 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Building+Products/Videos/2017/The+Best+Way+to+Figure+Out+Who+You+Want+to+Hire.mp4</guid>
        <description>

How do you define the profile of a person you are looking to hire?

Defining the type of person you want to hire may seem difficult to do. However, whenever we ask someone who they don’t want to hire, the answer comes very easily to them.

So, if you are really struggling to figure out how you want to hire, we recommend that you sit down and figure out who you don’t want to hire first. Think about the skills that you don’t need the candidate to have or personality traits that won’t align with your core values.

“Your top three qualities are non-negotiable.”

After you figure that out, you should be able to have some clarity on who you want to hire. Once that clarity hits, you need to write down your do’s and don’ts for the ideal candidate. Then, you need to highlight the top three qualities that your ideal candidate would have.

Those three qualities are non-negotiable. No candidate is perfect. Just make sure that your candidate matches with your top three, non-negotiable qualities. Those qualities should fit into where you see your company going in the future. You need to make sure that the candidate can grow with your organization, both through their role and through the culture of the company.

I hope this helps you define the right type of person that you want to hire. If you need any help in the future, please don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Building+Products/Videos/2017/The+Best+Way+to+Figure+Out+Who+You+Want+to+Hire.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://govigblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Building+Products/Videos/2017/The+Best+Way+to+Figure+Out+Who+You+Want+to+Hire.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>How can defining the type of candidate you don’t want to hire give you clarity on what the ideal candidate looks like?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Govig and Associates</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>How can defining the type of candidate you don’t want to hire give you clarity on what the ideal candidate looks like?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>recruiter, executive recruiter, executive search, executive search firms, executive headhunters, top executive recruiters, recruitment firm, management recruiter</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Best Ways to Prepare for an Interview</title>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/the-best-ways-to-prepare-for-an-interview.html</link>
        
          <category>Bio Pharma</category>
        
        <author>Govig and Associates</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-21 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/BioPharma/Videos/2017/The+Best+Ways+to+Prepare+for+an+Interview.mp4</guid>
        <description>

How do you effectively interview? How can you prepare for an interview?

Whether you are a two-year or 15-year veteran, most people are not good at interviewing for two reasons. First of all, socially, we are not really allowed to talk highly about ourselves or brag about ourselves, so we’re very bad at it.

Secondly, most people don’t prepare properly for an interview, which is really kind of silly. If you were going to present to a group of executives, you would prepare. You would practice and know exactly what you’re going to say.

Here are two ways to effectively prepare for an interview:

First, open up a Word document and then, stream of consciousness style, put together words or phrases that describe your best attributes and characteristics. You may write something like sales leadership or communication skills. Leave a space between each skill that you write down so you can go back and effectively, concisely write an example of that specific skill.

“It’s absolutely crucial to prepare for an interview.”

Using two to three sentences at the most, leave them with the idea that you absolutely can perform that skill effectively. For example, you may say that over the last five years, you’ve built two teams from scratch. You hired, fired, and trained all of the top people that worked for your team and made them some of the top 10 contenders in your business. Your team brought in $2 million of new business.

That is very concise and direct, and shows how you can impact that particular company.

Next, when you begin to interview, you don’t know what they’re going to ask you about. On your list, have 10 to 15 different skill sets prepared. As early in the interview as you can, you should say, “Tell me what you want me to accomplish for you.” They will outline that for you so you get a chance to speak directly to what they want you to do.

In a 30-minute interview, you need to speak concisely about five to 15 years of business experience and how that experience applies to the job you are being considered for. These two tips will help you do just that.

If you have any other questions about the interview process, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/BioPharma/Videos/2017/The+Best+Ways+to+Prepare+for+an+Interview.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://govigblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/BioPharma/Videos/2017/The+Best+Ways+to+Prepare+for+an+Interview.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Most people have difficulty interviewing effectively. Today, we’ll go over two tips to help you prepare for an interview.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Govig and Associates</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Most people have difficulty interviewing effectively. Today, we’ll go over two tips to help you prepare for an interview.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>recruiter, executive recruiter, executive search, executive search firms, executive headhunters, top executive recruiters, recruitment firm, management recruiter</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Benefits Are Wooing Candidates?</title>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/what-benefits-are-wooing-candidates.html</link>
        
          <category>Health Care</category>
        
        <author>Govig and Associates</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-09 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Healthcare/Videos/2017/What+Benefits+Are+Wooing+Candidates%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today we are here to answer a question from Jennie, an HR manager in the Twin Cities who asked, “What are candidates honing in on right now when choosing an employer?”

The first big thing we are hearing from candidates is that they want to join a company that is in growth mode. Career growth for the company means career growth for the employee as well. Candidates are honing in on these growing companies so that they can create an upward trajectory for their career as well.

Benefits are a hot button topic right now as well. The cost of benefits is going up a lot, especially for families. The cost is going to be higher at your position than it was in the past as well. Can you find another way to compensate an employee, maybe in the form of a little higher salary? Being flexible like this is the key to getting the best hires.

“Focus on the person, not the title.”

Another big thing to remember about hiring is that you want to focus the search on a specific person instead of a title. If you find an exceptional candidate, but you can’t offer them as much vacation as they are already getting, I encourage you to try and find ways around the black and white HR handbook you adhere to. It’s a small sacrifice to make in order to find the perfect fit for a role.

Finally, candidates are really concerned about who they are working for. There has got to be a good rapport there. Consider bringing the hiring authority in on the process from the beginning to get candidates excited about taking a position with you.

If you have any other questions for us about hiring, career growth, retention, or anything else, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Healthcare/Videos/2017/What+Benefits+Are+Wooing+Candidates%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://govigblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Healthcare/Videos/2017/What+Benefits+Are+Wooing+Candidates%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>We are back to answer another great question about hiring in the healthcare world. Jennie, an HR manager from the Twin Cities, wants to know what candidates are looking for in an employer right now.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Govig and Associates</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We are back to answer another great question about hiring in the healthcare world. Jennie, an HR manager from the Twin Cities, wants to know what candidates are looking for in an employer right now.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>recruiter, executive recruiter, executive search, executive search firms, executive headhunters, top executive recruiters, recruitment firm, management recruiter</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Never Put These 5 Things on Your Resume</title>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/never-put-these-5-things-on-your-resume.html</link>
        
          <category>Building Products</category>
        
        <author>Govig and Associates</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-09 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Building+Products/Videos/2017/Never+Put+These+5+Things+on+Your+Resume.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Request a Consultation - Hire Us to Fill Your Job Openings

As you already know, there are a ton of resources available out there that show how to write a great resume. In turn, we’re often asked what not to put on a resume. So today, we wanted to provide you with a list of the top five things you shouldn’t put on your resume.

You want to make sure your resume is a reflection of yourself. A lot of people put canned things on their resume to make themselves look good, but they’re ultimately not comfortable with them.

1. Do not put your picture on your resume. There are a ton of social media sites where someone can look you up. A picture is still not appropriate to have on your resume and we don’t like to see them on there.

2. Keep the format simple. Some people like to spruce up their resume by having different fonts, colors, or margins, but remember, people will often look at your resume on their phone or a number of different programs. Extra fonts and colors can not only be distracting, they can get jumbled up when being looked at on different devices or programs. Keep it simple with clean lines, right indentation, and one font that can be bolded or italicized in certain areas.

3. No paragraphs. People in HR or recruiting look at a ton of resumes every day, so you want to make sure it’s easy to read. Use bullet points, but make sure they have quantifiable achievements. Don’t use the same bullet points for every role that you’ve had; they want to make sure that you have put some thought into it and listed exactly what you’ve done in that role even if the responsibilities were similar.

“Recruiters and HR people look at a ton of resumes every day, so make yours easy to read.”

4. Don’t use an objective. You’ll get many opinions on this since it may seem normal to put an objective on your resume, but the problem is that it becomes very canned. We all know that your objective is to get a position with a stable, well-branded company and such. It’s better to leave it off and use that space to highlight your successes or talents, or dive right into things regarding your most recent position. Don’t fill it just for the sake of filling it.

5. Keep it to two pages. Obviously, the more experience you have, the harder it is to do this. However, it’s OK to use bullets for your last two to three positions and then just summarize the positions you’ve held before that, especially if it was more than 10 years ago. Once you get up to three, four, or even five pages, nobody will read it anyway. Remember that this is a marketing brochure; it’s not going to tell the whole story. You want people to want to read it and be attracted to your resume.

I hope you found this information helpful if you’re updating your resume or getting ready to send it out. If you have any questions at all, just give us a call or send us an email. We’d be happy to answer them for you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Building+Products/Videos/2017/Never+Put+These+5+Things+on+Your+Resume.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://govigblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Building+Products/Videos/2017/Never+Put+These+5+Things+on+Your+Resume.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today we've got five tips for things you should absolutely not include on your resume.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Govig and Associates</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today we've got five tips for things you should absolutely not include on your resume.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>recruiter, executive recruiter, executive search, executive search firms, executive headhunters, top executive recruiters, recruitment firm, management recruiter</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Effectively Negotiate Your Salary</title>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/how-to-effectively-negotiate-your-salary.html</link>
        
          <category>Bio Pharma</category>
        
        <author>Govig and Associates</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-01 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/BioPharma/Videos/2017/How+to+Effectively+Negotiate+Your+Salary+-+Dianna+LoDolce.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The question of how to be effective at salary negotiation is a common one for us, so we wanted to cover it for all of you who have been asking the same question. As we discuss salary negotiations, there are three main topics I want to cover. Although they might sound simple at first glance, most people don’t do them. Following their lead could cost you, so here are three things you should know heading into salary negotiations:

1. Know how much compensation you are currently taking home on an annual basis. Consider your base salary in addition to any bonuses, incentives, stock benefits, or other monetary value you take home. When you understand that critically, you can make a decision on what your bottom line number is and what your ideal number is.

“Figure out what your yearly compensation is first.”

2. Look at the new opportunity you are interviewing for. You have to make the decision of if this is the right career choice for you. In the end, you want to be able to ask yourself if the job has enough challenge, opportunity, and experience. If you can see yourself making the same amount of money while also enjoying the new job more, you’re on the right track.

3. Actually negotiate the salary. There are two methods that are common in the marketplace and I like them both. The first is to present a hiring manager with what you are making now and what you would like to make in the future. Give them a mid-range and a high-range number. The other option you have is to not present any numbers at all. Just tell the person that you are very interested in the role and are confident in receiving a fair offer. This gives the hiring manager the opportunity to give you their best offer.

I hope this information has helped you out. If you have any other questions for us, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We would love to hear from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/BioPharma/Videos/2017/How+to+Effectively+Negotiate+Your+Salary+-+Dianna+LoDolce.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://govigblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/BioPharma/Videos/2017/How+to+Effectively+Negotiate+Your+Salary+-+Dianna+LoDolce.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Negotiating a salary isn’t an easy process. However, these three tips should help.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Govig and Associates</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Negotiating a salary isn’t an easy process. However, these three tips should help.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>recruiter, executive recruiter, executive search, executive search firms, executive headhunters, top executive recruiters, recruitment firm, management recruiter</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What’s the Top Trait We Look for in a Recruiter?</title>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/whats-the-top-trait-we-look-for-in-a-recruiter.html</link>
        
          <category>Careers</category>
        
        <author>Govig and Associates</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-26 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Careers/Videos/2017/Whats+the+Top+Trait+We+Look+for+in+a+Recruiter%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What’s the number one trait we look for in a recruiter?

We look for risk takers. How do we identify risk takers? We find that the risk taking trait manifests itself in recruiters in three different ways.

The first way is how they tend to want to be paid for performance instead of having a set salary that’s oftentimes based more on tenure than anything else. Risk takers are people who want to work hard, log extra hours, spend extra energy, and are compensated accordingly.

The second way is in their relationships with people. The best recruiters tend to be themselves in the recruiting process—they don’t try to replicate somebody else’s style. They put their own personality into the process, and as a result, they’re very sincere and authentic and come across as trustworthy.

“Be yourself, but be louder.”

The third way is by being comfortable in a sales process where you don’t control everything. Our business is unlike a process that simply allows you to sell a specific product that has certain traits, features, and benefits that you can market. With our process, we’re selling a service that matches a candidate with a hiring authority. Both sides are represented by people who don’t always know exactly what they want until they see it. This means there’s a lot of human psychology involved, and our job can mimic that of a marriage broker—we help manage two people come to a conclusion to solve mutual needs and requirements.

If you have any questions about this topic, please feel free to reach out to us. We look forward to talking with you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Careers/Videos/2017/Whats+the+Top+Trait+We+Look+for+in+a+Recruiter%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://govigblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Careers/Videos/2017/Whats+the+Top+Trait+We+Look+for+in+a+Recruiter%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Risk-taking tends to manifest itself in three separate ways in our business. Here’s how we identify risk-takers.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Govig and Associates</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Risk-taking tends to manifest itself in three separate ways in our business. Here’s how we identify risk-takers.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>recruiter, executive recruiter, executive search, executive search firms, executive headhunters, top executive recruiters, recruitment firm, management recruiter</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>When Is the Right Time for a Retained Search?</title>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/when-is-the-right-time-for-a-retained-search.html</link>
        
          <category>Health Care</category>
        
        <author>Govig and Associates</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-23 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Healthcare/Videos/2017/When+Is+the+Right+Time+for+a+Retained+Search%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I wanted to answer some questions I get when it comes to the difference between a retained and contingent search. When should you use each one?

The answer we hear from many other recruiters is to only use a retained search for high-level executive positions. Frankly, I’ve found that this is not always the case.

I believe you want to look at using a retained search anytime you want to exhaust a search.It’s a position that’s tough to fill and it’s imperative that you find the right person for that role, so a retained search is probably the best way to go. With our retained searches, we tap into the 21 recruiters we have working specifically in healthcare. We do a full nationwide search that allow us to identify several candidates to present.

Having an investment from our client up front allows us the time and resources to perform a strong and exhaustive search.

Another question we often get is whether candidates are better on a retained search versus a contingent search. At the end of the day, it’s the same candidates out there, but with a retained search, you will find that the candidates are vetted much better. With a retained search, you can really take the time to make sure you’re exhausting the search and identifying the candidates.

“Retained searches usually provide a more exhaustive search.”

In a contingent model, usually, the first candidate to raise his or her hand is the first candidate presented. When a contingent recruiter is working on several searches, you’ll find that they find one candidate, then move on to the next. You really don’t get an exhaustive approach.

Finally, another one of the most common questions we’re asked by candidates is whether it truly matters to them (as a candidate) if the recruiter is working on a contingent or retained search. My answer would be yes. The candidate is much more vested in presenting that candidate to their client. They want to be sure they’re doing it in all the appropriate ways.

We put together a file for a candidate, as well as perform psychometric testing, which gives you a much fuller story than a black and white resume. That way, when you meet with that client, they know who you are and have a better idea of how you can be an asset to their team. You’ll also be given much more information by the recruiter.

Hopefully that gives you a better idea of some answers to common questions regarding retained and contingent searches. If you have any questions for us about retention, hiring, or career development, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Healthcare/Videos/2017/When+Is+the+Right+Time+for+a+Retained+Search%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://govigblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Healthcare/Videos/2017/When+Is+the+Right+Time+for+a+Retained+Search%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today we're answering some questions we receive about the difference between contingent and retained searches, as well as how they affect both the client and the candidates.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Govig and Associates</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today we're answering some questions we receive about the difference between contingent and retained searches, as well as how they affect both the client and the candidates.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>recruiter, executive recruiter, executive search, executive search firms, executive headhunters, top executive recruiters, recruitment firm, management recruiter</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Big of a Raise Should Make You Consider Moving?</title>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/how-big-of-a-raise-should-make-you-consider-moving.html</link>
        
          <category>Building Products</category>
        
        <author>Govig and Associates</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-18 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Building+Products/Videos/2017/How+Big+of+a+Raise+Should+Make+You+Consider+Moving%253F+-+Jennifer+Meyer.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Back in the mid 90s and early 2000s, making a move was much more profitable than it is now. Back then, prospects were getting anywhere from a 15% to 20% increase in pay to make a move. During the market crash, that increase dropped to 3%. People were making a move to stay employed at that point, not for the money.

Lately, there has been an uptick in the raises that those making a move to a new company are getting.These are people who are already employed and doing well, but they are also making anywhere from 5% to 10% more to make a move.

“A 5% increase is a pretty good benchmark.”

A 5% increase in overall pay is a pretty good benchmark to have if you’re considering making a move.Moving forward, I don’t think many places will be looking at giving away more than that. We are no longer in the era where people will incentive people to make a move.

My suggestion for you or anyone you know who is looking to make a move is to look at that opportunity as a whole, not just at the money. If you like the opportunity and can also get that 5% to 10% increase in compensation, it’s something you should seriously consider.

If you have any questions for us or want to learn more about the building product industry, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We would love to hear from you.

</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Building+Products/Videos/2017/How+Big+of+a+Raise+Should+Make+You+Consider+Moving%253F+-+Jennifer+Meyer.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://govigblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Govig/Building+Products/Videos/2017/How+Big+of+a+Raise+Should+Make+You+Consider+Moving%253F+-+Jennifer+Meyer.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>The days of making 15% to 20% more in a new position are over. What kind of raise should you look for when a new opportunity presents itself?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Govig and Associates</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>The days of making 15% to 20% more in a new position are over. What kind of raise should you look for when a new opportunity presents itself?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>recruiter, executive recruiter, executive search, executive search firms, executive headhunters, top executive recruiters, recruitment firm, management recruiter</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Can You Create a Good Corporate Culture?</title>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/how-can-you-create-a-good-corporate-culture.html</link>
        
          <category>Bio Pharma</category>
        
        <author>Govig and Associates</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-05 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/GoVig/BioPharma/Videos/2017/How+Can+You+Create+a+Good+Corporate+Culture%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Request a Consultation - Hire Us to Fill Your Job Openings

What do people really mean when they ask about corporate culture? 

It’s nice to be able to take your dog to work or have an office softball team. Those kinds of things are important in cultivating a company’s culture. Really, though, there are only three core things people think about anytime they consider a job change:


  Transparency
  Will this new company have my back?
  Will they allow me to grow?


What is transparency? Transparency simply means that you’re open, direct, and your employees know what to do to meet or exceed expectations internally and that you’ll tell them when they are not. If there are changes, transparency means you will speak to them directly and openly. 

How can you have their back? Everybody makes mistakes; it’s part of being human. Employees need to know how you’re going to respond to that. Any employee that is allowed more autonomy and allowed to take more risks is going to be more creative and likely achieve a higher rate of production. If they make a mistake, will you use that as a coaching opportunity and help them work through their error so they can use it as a learning experience? This is critical, because employees will chafe in their role if you don’t let them make mistakes. 

How can you allow them to grow? By supporting learning by experience. Everybody wants to progress in their jobs and see variety in their day-to-day tasks. If you don’t allow those things, that employee will grow stale and be looking over their shoulder wondering whether or not this is the right opportunity for them. You need to be able to show them that you can give them the challenges and opportunities they need to grow and be willing to help them do that. 

As a hiring manager, you need to be able to know whether you have existing examples that will allow your future employees to be able to see that you can give them these three things. Can you speak to these examples clearly so that they’re willing to leave the job that they have and join your company? If you can, you’re going to do a much better job overall of attracting top talent. 

If you have any questions about how to attract and facilitate talent, please don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We look forward to speaking with you! 

“Can you present challenges to your employees and help them grow?”
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/GoVig/BioPharma/Videos/2017/How+Can+You+Create+a+Good+Corporate+Culture%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://govigblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/GoVig/BioPharma/Videos/2017/How+Can+You+Create+a+Good+Corporate+Culture%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>In attracting top talent to your company, you need to foster transparency, present challenges to your employees, and be willing to help them grow in their roles.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Govig and Associates</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>In attracting top talent to your company, you need to foster transparency, present challenges to your employees, and be willing to help them grow in their roles.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>recruiter, executive recruiter, executive search, executive search firms, executive headhunters, top executive recruiters, recruitment firm, management recruiter</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4 Tips to Impress a Client During an Interview</title>
        <link>http://govigblog.com/4-tips-to-impress-a-client-during-an-interview.html</link>
        
          <category>Health Care</category>
        
        <author>Govig and Associates</author>
        <pubDate>2016-12-27 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/GoVig/Healthcare/Videos/Hadley+Gayles+%252812-5-2016%2529+Interviewing.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Request a Consultation - Hire Us to Fill Your Job Openings

If you’re a job candidate, what can do to make sure that you impress the hiring authorities in your interview?

First off, make a great first impression. 90% of hiring authorities make their decision within the first two minutes and spend the rest of the time justifying that decision. Being on time, being polished, and being presentable can greatly improve your odds to strike the right chord within that crucial timeframe.

Secondly, bring multiple copies of your resume. When you show up, you want to have at least three copies of your resume—one for the person interviewing you, and others for whoever else may be involved with the interview. With the resume, you want to be able to speak to each change you’ve made in your career and any quantifiable achievements you’ve made. These are the things you think would really make you shine as a candidate.

“Always ask questions.”

Third, be prepared with questions. At the end of the interview, clients always ask their candidates if they have any questions for them. The worst thing you can do at that moment is not have any. The best kinds of questions to ask are the ones that pertain to the client themselves, how they got into the business, what’s kept them there, and what their future plans are.

Lastly, close the interview. When you leave the interviewer, let them know that you want the job. Furthermore, ask them if there’s anything about your background that they still have concerns about. Tell them that you’re really interested in the next step and that you’re curious what that step looks like.

If you have any questions regarding hiring or retention, please feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We’d be happy to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/GoVig/Healthcare/Videos/Hadley+Gayles+%252812-5-2016%2529+Interviewing.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://govigblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/GoVig/Healthcare/Videos/Hadley+Gayles+%252812-5-2016%2529+Interviewing.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re interviewing for a job, the way to impress the hiring authorities is to be prepared and be punctual. Today I have four tips to achieve each of these objectives.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Govig and Associates</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re interviewing for a job, the way to impress the hiring authorities is to be prepared and be punctual. Today I have four tips to achieve each of these objectives.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>recruiter, executive recruiter, executive search, executive search firms, executive headhunters, top executive recruiters, recruitment firm, management recruiter</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Govig and Associates</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Govig and Associates</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">Govig &amp; Associates is one of the largest privately held firms in the Executive Search industry. With more than three decades in staffing and recruiting, we have the knowledge, the network and the speed to provide unparalleled service to our clients.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
