<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Central PA Real Estate Podcast with Heather Neidlinger</title>
    <link>http://centralparealtorsblog.com</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://centralparealtorsblog.com"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Heather Neidlinger Team - your professional Central PA Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Heather Neidlinger</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2018-02-16 14:53:32 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Heather Neidlinger</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://centralparealtorsblog.com/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Central PA, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>listwithheather@homesale.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Heather Neidlinger</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Heather Neidlinger</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://centralparealtorsblog.com/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Central PA, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Central PA Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Heather Neidlinger Team - your professional Central PA Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Can You Expect From Our Market in 2018?</title>
        <link>http://centralparealtorsblog.com/what-can-you-expect-from-our-market-in-2018.html</link>
        
        <author>Heather Neidlinger</author>
        <pubDate>2018-02-16 08:40:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Heather+Neidlinger/2018/Central+Pennsylvania+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+to+Expect+from+Market+2018.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What are the latest buying and selling trends in our housing market in 2018?

To get an idea, let’s look back to 2017. According to Darrell Morgan of Berkshire Hathaway, our market did great overall last year. There was tremendous growth, with more and more ready and willing buyers looking at homes. Because there were so many buyers flooding the market and so little inventory, we saw a lot of multiple offer situations.

On the flip side, properties listed on the market sold faster and for higher prices due to this influx. Mortgage lenders were also able to close loans within 30 to 45 das on a regular basis. On our team, our listings were on the market for roughly half of the time that there were in previous years. In many cases, multiple offer situations resulted in higher sale prices for our sellers.

“Our listings were on the market for roughly half of the time that there were in previous years.”

Where are clients finding Realtors in 2018? In Darrell’s experience, many clients base their picks on reputation. Word of mouth from past clients is huge in this business. The internet is also one of the main resources, which means online reviews are extremely important.

If you or anyone you know is thinking about buying or selling a home in our market, don’t hesitate to reach out to us for a free consultation. We’re here to help with all of your real estate needs.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Heather+Neidlinger/2018/Central+Pennsylvania+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+to+Expect+from+Market+2018.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://centralparealtorsblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Heather+Neidlinger/2018/Central+Pennsylvania+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+to+Expect+from+Market+2018.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Recently, I’ve been getting a lot of questions from buyers and sellers about what we can expect from the housing market in 2018. While I can’t predict the future, I can tell you that looking at the trends from 2017 will give us some insight into what will happen this year. Today I’m joined by Darrell Morgan, the Berkshire Hathaway director of operations for our area, to provide you the latest update for our market. Last year, we experienced tremendous growth. To find out more about last year’s impact on our 2018 market, watch our latest video.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Heather Neidlinger</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Recently, I’ve been getting a lot of questions from buyers and sellers about what we can expect from the housing market in 2018. While I can’t predict the future, I can tell you that looking at the trends from 2017 will give us some insight into what will happen this year. Today I’m joined by Darrell Morgan, the Berkshire Hathaway director of operations for our area, to provide you the latest update for our market. Last year, we experienced tremendous growth. To find out more about last year’s impact on our 2018 market, watch our latest video.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Central PA, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Have Questions About Mortgage Application? We’ve Got Answers</title>
        <link>http://centralparealtorsblog.com/have-questions-about-mortgage-application-weve-got-answers.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Heather Neidlinger</author>
        <pubDate>2018-01-22 06:57:56 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Heather+Neidlinger/2018/Central+Pennsylvania+Real+Estate+Agent-+FAQs+About+Applying+for+a+Mortgage.mp4</guid>
        <description>

In this business, we work with a lot of mortgage lenders and banks, but there are only a few lenders who I consider my go-to guys. Chris Fratelli from Union Home Mortgage is one of those guys, and he’s joining me today to answer some frequently asked questions about the lending process.

Is the mortgage process difficult?

It can be, but it really depends on the loan officer themselves. A loan officer is the one who sets expectations upon your group. If the officer tells the client specifically what they need to provide, what time they should have it by, and also explains the process from start to finish, then it’s actually a breeze. It’s about setting the proper expectations.

Does it cost anything to apply for a mortgage?

It doesn’t. It really just costs your time, which is about 15 minutes for the application. You don’t have to wait months or even hours; you’ll know within 15 to 20 minutes whether or not you’re qualified. If I can’t get you approved, then I’ll create a roadmap for you to figure out what you need to do for approval.

Is it easier to get qualified at a local bank?

The only thing a local bank can offer you that I can’t is the ability to provide your bank statements. Local banks and direct lenders play by the same rules; we’ll ask you for the same documentation. In some cases, banks may require more documentation.

“It only costs about 15 minutes of your time to apply for a loan.”

What are interest rates doing in 2018?

They are moving up, so I believe that we’ll be seeing some rate hikes this year. Buy now rather than later.

If I don’t have any money to put down toward the house, can I still buy?

You can, but it’s quite specific now. There are a lot of programs and grants out there that offer clients the ability to buy with no money down. If a client doesn’t have money for a down payment and they don’t qualify for those programs and grants, we can discuss how they might be able to get the money through other avenues.

After going under contract, how long does it take to get to closing?

Thirty days is the industry standard, but you really want to give the seller the appropriate amount of time to handle everything they need, such as moving out of the home.

Do you have a favorite loan program?

I love working with vets. I appreciate the sacrifices they made for our country. It’s always an exciting time to get to close, but especially for a vet who’s buying a home for the first time. The VA loan program is actually a very underutilized program. You’d be surprised at how many veterans out there don’t understand the benefits they can enjoy. It’s one of the most lenient programs available, with no money down required.

How do I apply?

The best way is for your agent to give me your contact information so I can reach out to you and set up an appointment to start your application.

If you would like to contact Chris to set up an appointment or to address any questions about the lending process you may have, give him a call at (717) 712-4739. For other real estate questions, feel free to reach out to the Heather Neidlinger Team by phone or email. I look forward to representing your next real estate deal.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Heather+Neidlinger/2018/Central+Pennsylvania+Real+Estate+Agent-+FAQs+About+Applying+for+a+Mortgage.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://centralparealtorsblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Heather+Neidlinger/2018/Central+Pennsylvania+Real+Estate+Agent-+FAQs+About+Applying+for+a+Mortgage.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Are you unsure about the specifics of the loan application process? Chris Fratelli from Union Home Mortgage is here to answer your questions.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Heather Neidlinger</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Are you unsure about the specifics of the loan application process? Chris Fratelli from Union Home Mortgage is here to answer your questions.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Central PA, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Waiting Until Spring Can Cost You</title>
        <link>http://centralparealtorsblog.com/waiting-until-spring-can-cost-you.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Heather Neidlinger</author>
        <pubDate>2018-01-09 10:14:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Heather+Neidlinger/2018/Central+Pennsylvania+Real+Estate+Agent-+Waiting+Until+Spring+Can+Cost+You.mp4</guid>
        <description>

In our opinion, waiting until spring to buy or sell a home is not the best decision. Our Director of Operations, Teri Bowermaster, is here with me today to explain why.

If you’re a prospective home seller and are waiting for the spring market to list, all you’re doing is opening yourself up to a whole lot more competition. Everyone else who is thinking about selling their home in your town and in your neighborhood is waiting until spring. Listing now is smart because there are a handful of serious buyers out there and their selection is limited.

“There is less competition out there for buyers and sellers.”

At the same time, the spring market starts a race of buyers to new listings. This is the type of market where we have competing offers and buyers end up paying more than list price. If you get in the market now, you won’t have to put yourself up against the wall and compete against multiple offers. There’s still a decent selection out there that you can take advantage of. Less competition is a great reason to start your home search.

If you have any questions for us about this market or about buying or selling a home, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Heather+Neidlinger/2018/Central+Pennsylvania+Real+Estate+Agent-+Waiting+Until+Spring+Can+Cost+You.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://centralparealtorsblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Heather+Neidlinger/2018/Central+Pennsylvania+Real+Estate+Agent-+Waiting+Until+Spring+Can+Cost+You.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Thinking about waiting until spring to list? It’s not something we advise to do.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Heather Neidlinger</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Thinking about waiting until spring to list? It’s not something we advise to do.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Central PA, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Can My Team and I Do For You?</title>
        <link>http://centralparealtorsblog.com/what-can-my-team-and-i-do-for-you.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Heather Neidlinger</author>
        <pubDate>2017-11-30 05:21:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Heather+Neidlinger/2017/Central+Pennsylvania+Real+Estate+Agent-+Heather+Neidlinger+Intro.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I want to tell you a little bit about myself, which is never an easy thing to do. However, I can tell you that I sell real estate, and I’ve done so here in Carlisle, Pennsylvania since the early 2000s.

Even after all that time, I still absolutely love this job. Being born and raised here in Central PA, I’ve chosen to live my life and raise my family right here in Carlisle. Fully knowing my area and living in it helps me to be a dedicated and successful real estate agent.

“I truly love my job and helping people succeed with all their real estate dreams.”

Why is that? It’s because I truly love my job and and helping people succeed with all their real estate dreams.

I’m Heather Neidlinger, and my team and I would love to work with you.

If you have any questions or want to hear more about what my team and I can do for you, please feel free to give us a call or send an email. We would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Heather+Neidlinger/2017/Central+Pennsylvania+Real+Estate+Agent-+Heather+Neidlinger+Intro.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://centralparealtorsblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Heather+Neidlinger/2017/Central+Pennsylvania+Real+Estate+Agent-+Heather+Neidlinger+Intro.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Knowing the area has helped me stay dedicated and be successful as a real estate agent.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Heather Neidlinger</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Knowing the area has helped me stay dedicated and be successful as a real estate agent.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Central PA, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Heather Neidlinger</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Heather Neidlinger</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Heather Neidlinger Team - your professional Central PA Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
