<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Atlas Premier Realty Real Estate Podcast</title>
    <link>http://baltimorerealestateupdate.com</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://baltimorerealestateupdate.com"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Campbell &amp; Kellar Team - your professional Baltimore &amp; Carroll Counties Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Nick Kellar</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2017-02-21 12:15:22 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Nick Kellar</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://baltimorerealestateupdate.com/img/Kellar_podcast.png"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Baltimore &amp; Carroll Counties, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">News &amp; Politics</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Nick@AtlasPremierRealty.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Nick Kellar</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Nick Kellar</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://baltimorerealestateupdate.com/img/Kellar_podcast.png"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Baltimore &amp; Carroll Counties, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Baltimore &amp; Carroll Counties Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Campbell &amp; Kellar Team - your professional Baltimore &amp; Carroll Counties Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="News &amp; Politics"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Are Some Unexpected Costs When Buying a Home?</title>
        <link>http://baltimorerealestateupdate.com/what-are-some-unexpected-costs-when-buying-a-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Nick Kellar</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-12 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nick+Kellar/CarrollCounty+Real+Estate+Unexpected+Costs.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Purchasing a home is the American Dream for many people. However, it doesn’t come cheap. There are some unexpected costs you should be aware of when buying a home.

The first cost you have to consider is the down payment. However, the down payment is more of an investment than an expense, which has to do with the loan type. The most prevalent loan type out there is an FHA loan because the down payment is usually only around 3.5%. 

There are also VA and USDA loans, which require no money down. However, you need certain memberships or to meet certain income requirements to qualify for those. For a USDA loan, the property you want to purchase has to qualify as well. 

Outside of those loans, conventional financing is also an option. Conventional financing usually requires 20% for a down payment, but you avoid private mortgage insurance with that option, potentially saving you hundreds of dollars a month. However, there are programs that can assist you with conventional loans, reducing the down payment to 5% or even 3%. 

You also have to take closing costs into account when purchasing a home. Closing costs vary by state and area, but in Maryland, closing costs are usually 3% to 4% of the purchase price. Lender fees, title fees, transfer taxes, and other miscellaneous fees are covered with closing costs. 

“Always expect the unexpected when purchasing a home, and be financially prepared.”

Unlike the down payment, if you negotiate well, closing costs can be covered by the seller. There is a good chance you might get some if not all your closing costs taken care of. 

You also need to budget for any inspection costs. These costs will depend on the size of the house, whether the house needs a septic inspection or pest inspection, and other factors, so be sure you set aside a good amount to get those inspections done. 

Although it’s a common one, don’t forget about the cost of moving. Obviously, moving to a different state will cost more than moving across town, but it’s still wise to budget exactly what those costs will be. 

Always expect the unexpected when purchasing a house. A good strategy is to have an emergency fund. My advice is to have at least three months of living expenses set aside. Also, plan on having 1% to 2% of the purchase price of your home set aside for maintenance. Keep in mind that if you are purchasing an older home, it might require more upkeep, so you should maybe put aside a bit more. 

One way to offset that is to make sure you are taking good care of your home. You should also consider purchasing a home warranty to offset costs as well. 

If you have any questions, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help! 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nick+Kellar/CarrollCounty+Real+Estate+Unexpected+Costs.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://baltimorerealestateupdate.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nick+Kellar/CarrollCounty+Real+Estate+Unexpected+Costs.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There is more to purchasing a home than the sticker price. Here are some costs to look out for when buying a home.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nick Kellar</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There is more to purchasing a home than the sticker price. Here are some costs to look out for when buying a home.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Baltimore &amp; Carroll Counties, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What’s Happening in the Baltimore & Carroll County Markets?</title>
        <link>http://baltimorerealestateupdate.com/whats-happening-in-the-baltimore-carroll-county-markets.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Nick Kellar</author>
        <pubDate>2016-12-29 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nick+Kellar/Email+Assets/CarrollCounty+Real+Estate+What%E2%80%99s+happening+in+our+market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Now that the election is finally over, a lot of people have been asking how the market is performing. Are we in a buyer’s market or a seller’s market?

First of all, it’s really important to understand that our market is impacted by the seasons. In the spring, the market has more of a frenetic pace and is definitely considered a seller’s market. Starting in mid-summer, the market starts to slow down, and we usually have more of a buyer’s market in the third and fourth quarters.

So, what’s going on with inventory? There is not a lot of new inventory coming on the market right now. If you are a buyer, you have probably noticed that there aren’t many new options to choose from. Homes that are currently on the market are sitting a little longer and aren’t getting the same amount of activity they were before the election, so some of those listings are starting to go stale.

How do we measure whether or not a listing is getting stale? We use something called the absorption rate, which looks at the current sales pace versus the amount of active inventory. In short, if no other new homes came on the market, how long would it take to sell all of our current inventory?

According to industry standards, four to six months of inventory is a balanced market. Anything less than three months is considered a seller’s market, and anything more than six months is a buyer’s market. In a seller’s market, homes sell quickly because there is low inventory and high demand. In a buyer’s market, homes aren’t selling as fast as new homes come on the market.

“We are creeping towards a buyer’s market.”

Right now, we still have between four and six months of inventory. However, things are creeping closer to that six month mark, so we are approaching a buyer’s market.

What’s happening with interest rates? They have jumped up since the election, and it looks like they will continue to rise. There is no sugarcoating it — rising interest rates have definitely impacted affordability. If you have been in the market searching and rates have jumped up on you, you need to check in with your lender because that increase does impact your monthly mortgage payments.

If you are selling your home, keep in mind that as more and more buyers are affected by interest rate increases, home prices may need to come down to keep up with demand. Some buyers may even be pushed out of the market entirely as interest rates go up.

That said, it’s still a great time to buy and sell. Ultimately, the decision to enter the real estate market revolves around your own goals and needs. If you have any other questions about our current market, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nick+Kellar/Email+Assets/CarrollCounty+Real+Estate+What%E2%80%99s+happening+in+our+market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://baltimorerealestateupdate.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nick+Kellar/Email+Assets/CarrollCounty+Real+Estate+What%E2%80%99s+happening+in+our+market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>How is our real estate market performing? Are we in a buyer’s or seller’s market? I’ll tell you everything you need to know today.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nick Kellar</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>How is our real estate market performing? Are we in a buyer’s or seller’s market? I’ll tell you everything you need to know today.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Baltimore &amp; Carroll Counties, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why You Can’t Trust Zillow’s Zestimate Feature</title>
        <link>http://baltimorerealestateupdate.com/why-you-cant-trust-zillows-zestimate-feature.html</link>
        
          <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Nick Kellar</author>
        <pubDate>2016-12-14 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nick+Kellar/CarrollCounty+Real+Estate+Zestimates.mp4</guid>
        <description>

How much stock should you put into Zillow’s Zestimates?

First, let me explain what a Zestimate is. Per Zillow’s website, it’s an automated algorithm to give you a general idea of a home’s value that uses physical attributes, tax assessments, and recent sales data. I call this “surface data.” While this data is important, I think that if you’re looking for true market value, you have to really look under the hood.

The first things you need to look at to evaluate a home’s value are amenities and cosmetic improvements you’ve made to the house like granite countertops, hardwood floors, or structural things like a roof, siding, or new windows. You also need to consider the layout and flow of the home. The location of the bathrooms and the bedrooms impact home value.

You also need to analyze the overall market and its current climate. Is the market a buyer’s or seller’s market? You must also factor in the condition of your home. Showability absolutely matters when it comes to value. Is your house very plain or has it been improved? An automated estimate can’t account for these things.

“You need to analyze the market and its overall climate.”

In fact, Zillow actually says to do more research to find an accurate value for your home. This could be a professional agent performing an analysis or you could have an appraisal done. 

Finally, I wanted to give you some examples of Zestimates and how they compare to real home sales. 

Recently, we had two cases of Zestimates that were higher than what we sold the house for by about 12% to 16%. If you were to rely on these Zestimates and overprice your home, it would accumulate all these days on market. You might even end up selling for less than you could have if you had just started with a thorough market analysis. We also recently had a home sell for 3% higher than the Zestimate. While 3% doesn’t sound significant, think about the fact that it equated to $12,000.

If you have any other questions about home values or you have a real estate topic you’d like to learn more about, don’t hesitate to reach out. We’d be glad to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nick+Kellar/CarrollCounty+Real+Estate+Zestimates.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://baltimorerealestateupdate.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nick+Kellar/CarrollCounty+Real+Estate+Zestimates.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you're selling a home, how much can you rely on Zillow's Zestimates for home value? Not much. I'll explain exactly why today.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nick Kellar</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you're selling a home, how much can you rely on Zillow's Zestimates for home value? Not much. I'll explain exactly why today.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Baltimore &amp; Carroll Counties, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Avoid These 7 Home Improvements</title>
        <link>http://baltimorerealestateupdate.com/avoid-these-7-home-improvements.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Nick Kellar</author>
        <pubDate>2016-11-08 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nick+Kellar/CarrollCounty+Real+Estate+7+Home+Improvements+to+Avoid.mp4</guid>
        <description>

A lot of the time when people ask me about home renovations, they want to know what they can do to improve their market value. However, today I wanted to talk about a few renovations that you should avoid, as they can actually take value away from your home.


  
    Too much wallpaper: One of the latest trends in new construction homes is to add a little bit of wallpaper here and there to accent certain rooms. However, too much wallpaper will scare buyers away, so don’t wallpaper entire rooms and definitely avoid outdated wallpaper.
  
  
    Lavish light fixtures: Replace gaudy brass fixtures with the subtle, brushed bronze or the brushed nickel look. Flashy, over-the-top light fixtures draw the eye and distract buyers from the rest of the room.
  
  
    Textured walls and ceilings: These are very difficult to paint over and don’t look great, either. Avoid textured walls and ceilings as much as possible.
  
  
    Too many different kinds of flooring: If you go into a house and see carpet in one room, hardwood in another, tile in another, and then a different kind of hardwood, the home seems disjointed. You don’t need to replace all of the flooring; in fact, you will get the best ROI by just replacing some of the flooring in order to create a better flow from one room to the next.
  
  
    Too much carpeting: These days, people prefer hardwood because it is easier to clean up, doesn’t trap as much dirt, and is more allergy-sensitive than carpeting.
  
  
    Bold wall colors: You have probably heard this on HGTV, but you need to stay away from bold colors. Red, deep blue, or purple might work with your home decor but it won’t appeal to a lot of buyers, so stick to soft earth tones such as greens, tans, and grays accented with white trim.
  
  
    Hot tubs or swimming pools: In certain price points and on certain lot sizes, a pool or hot tub can be an advantage. However, if the pool is crammed into the corner of a small yard, it can be detrimental to your property value. Before you install a hot tub or swimming pool, make sure you consult with a professional.
  


“Hardwood flooring is extremely popular with today’s buyers.”

These are just a few renovations that you may want to avoid if you are trying to add value to your home. If you have any other questions about home improvements or preparing your home for the market, give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nick+Kellar/CarrollCounty+Real+Estate+7+Home+Improvements+to+Avoid.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://baltimorerealestateupdate.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nick+Kellar/CarrollCounty+Real+Estate+7+Home+Improvements+to+Avoid.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Some home improvements add more value to your property than others. Today, I’ll go over the top seven home renovations you should avoid.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nick Kellar</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Some home improvements add more value to your property than others. Today, I’ll go over the top seven home renovations you should avoid.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Baltimore &amp; Carroll Counties, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What’s Happening in the Baltimore & Carroll County Real Estate Markets?</title>
        <link>http://baltimorerealestateupdate.com/whats-happening-in-the-baltimore-carroll-county-real-estate-markets.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Nick Kellar</author>
        <pubDate>2016-10-20 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nick+Kellar/The+CK+Team+Market+Update.mp4</guid>
        <description>

People ask me all the time whether we’re in a buyer’s or seller’s market. In our industry, the answer usually depends on the season.

In the spring, we typically see more of a seller’s market, and that was the case this year. Right around the beginning of July it started to slip, and we started to see the days on market creep up. Houses were sitting on the market a little longer and they weren’t selling for the same prices that we saw in the spring.

That trend has continued into the fall. How do we know this? We use what’s called the ‘absorption rate.’ The absorption rate measures the sales pace versus the current active inventory. An absorption rate of four to six months is considered a balanced market. Anything less than four months is considered a seller’s market. Anything longer than six months is considered a buyer’s market. Right now, we’re seeing things push a little bit closer to that six-month mark. That would currently make our area a buyer’s market.

How does that impact property values? The longer things stay on the market, the less they stand to make. As far as the current inventory goes, there aren’t a lot of new homes coming on the market, but there isn’t a whole lot of activity on what’s being listed. I’ve also discovered that here in Baltimore and Carroll County, there’s typically a 5% correction in the price from the spring market (2nd quarter) to the fall market (3rd quarter).

“Inventory is down, and interest rates are extraordinarily low.”

Interest rates are extraordinary right now, and this has created huge buying opportunities for anyone looking to purchase a home. The Fed has left them untouched, but they’re rumored to be hiking them up in the 4th quarter.

What does all this mean for buyers and sellers? It depends on your particular situation and what your goals are. If you’re a seller, there aren’t a lot of new homes coming on the market. There are opportunities out there, you just have to be more strategic about pursuing them. If you’re a buyer, now is a great opportunity to act due to the combination of low interest rates and the seasonal decline in prices.

If you have any more questions about the current market, please don’t hesitate to reach out to us. Just give us a call or send us an email, and we’d be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nick+Kellar/The+CK+Team+Market+Update.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://baltimorerealestateupdate.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nick+Kellar/The+CK+Team+Market+Update.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>We will update this channel regularly with great seller tips, buyer tips, and real estate market updates for our area.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nick Kellar</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We will update this channel regularly with great seller tips, buyer tips, and real estate market updates for our area.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Baltimore &amp; Carroll Counties, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Introducing the Campbell &amp; Kellar Team YouTube Channel</title>
        <link>http://baltimorerealestateupdate.com/introducing-the-campbell-kellar-team-youtube-channel.html</link>
        
        <author>Nick Kellar</author>
        <pubDate>2016-10-20 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nick+Kellar/The+CK+Team+YouTube+Intro.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Welcome to the new YouTube channel for the Campbell &amp; Kellar Team! We will update this channel regularly with great seller tips, buyer tips, and real estate market updates for our area. Take a look around, discover topics that interest you, and if there are topics that you’d like to learn more about, reach out to us and we just might answer your question with a video. To learn more about our new channel, watch this short video. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nick+Kellar/The+CK+Team+YouTube+Intro.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://baltimorerealestateupdate.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nick+Kellar/The+CK+Team+YouTube+Intro.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>We will update this channel regularly with great seller tips, buyer tips, and real estate market updates for our area.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nick Kellar</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We will update this channel regularly with great seller tips, buyer tips, and real estate market updates for our area.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Baltimore &amp; Carroll Counties, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Nick Kellar</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Nick Kellar</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Campbell &amp; Kellar Team - your professional Baltimore &amp; Carroll Counties Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
