<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>North Jersey Real Estate Podcast with Brett Sikora</title>
    <link>localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Sikora Group - your professional North Jersey Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Brett Sikora</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2017-10-13 14:54:14 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Brett Sikora</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in North Jersey, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Brett@SellWithSikora.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Brett Sikora</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Brett Sikora</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in North Jersey, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the North Jersey Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Sikora Group - your professional North Jersey Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Costs That Shock First-Time Homebuyers</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/5-costs-that-shock-first-time-homebuyers.html</link>
        
          <category>North Jersey Real Estate Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brett Sikora</author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-03 10:49:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+5+Costs+That+Shock+First-Time+Homebuyers.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Your mortgage isn’t the only thing you’ll have to pay when you buy a home. Here are five unexpected costs.

Want to sell your home? Get a FREE home value report.
Want to buy a home? Search all homes for sale.

If you’re thinking about buying a home, you need to be aware of all of the costs associated before you decide to take the leap. Here are five expenses that typically shock and/or creep up on first-time buyers.

1. Closing costs. These include mortgage taxes, lender application fees, attorney fees, and more. They vary from state to state and lending company to lending company, so make sure you get an accurate estimate of what yours will be.

2. Home improvements. According to a study by the Harvard University Joint Center on housing studies, the average home maintenance is 1% to 2% of the value of the home per year. For a $300,000 home, that’s around $3,000 per year. A condo will have slightly lower maintenance costs.

**3. Property taxes. They vary from town to town and tend to go up most years. However, if you feel like what you’re paying is too high, you can appeal your property taxes on your own or with the help of an attorney.

“Closing costs vary from state to state.”

4. Utilities. These also vary based on the climate and the city you’re living in. In Atlanta, utilities are around $2,600 per year. In Portland, they are closer to $3,800.

5. Homeowners insurance. If you’re getting a mortgage, you’re going to be required to have homeowners insurance regardless. The annual premium is around $1,132 per year.

If you have any questions for us about any of these costs or anything else relating to real estate, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+5+Costs+That+Shock+First-Time+Homebuyers.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+5+Costs+That+Shock+First-Time+Homebuyers.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Your mortgage isn’t the only thing you’ll have to pay when you buy a home. Here are five unexpected costs.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Sikora</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Your mortgage isn’t the only thing you’ll have to pay when you buy a home. Here are five unexpected costs.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in North Jersey, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 Questions to Ask Before Looking at Homes</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/5-questions-to-ask-before-looking-at.html</link>
        
          <category>North Jersey real estate buyer tips</category>
        
        <author>Brett Sikora</author>
        <pubDate>2017-09-18 11:21:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+5+Questions+to+Ask+Before+Looking+at+Homes.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The first step in buying a home isn’t looking online for properties. It’s answering these five questions about your financial situation.

Want to sell your home? Get a FREE home value report.
Want to buy a home? Search all homes for sale.

If you’re thinking about buying a home, here are five questions that you should ask yourself before you even start the first step of the process:

1. Do you have a steady source of income? If you’ve been employed on a regular basis with a steady level of income, that’s a good start.

2. Do you have a good record of paying bills? This will affect your credit and will also tell a lender whether you’re responsible enough to handle a mortgage payment.

3. Do you have enough money for a down payment? You only need 3.5% with an FHA loan, but a majority of people put down 20% to avoid paying private mortgage insurance.

“A steady source of income is essential.”

4. Do you have any outstanding debts? Any kind of monthly payment you have could affect your debt-to-income ratio.

5. Can you pay the mortgage each month with additional costs? When you pay rent, that’s typically all the money you have to worry about (save utilities and cable). When you own a home, there are a lot of extra costs that come up. Whether you have to replace an appliance or fix a hole in the wall, you’ll need to have enough money to do that.

If you can answer yes to all of these questions, it might be time to give us a call and get a buyer consultation set up. Then we can get you pre-approved with our preferred lender and begin your search.

If you have any questions, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+5+Questions+to+Ask+Before+Looking+at+Homes.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+5+Questions+to+Ask+Before+Looking+at+Homes.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

The first step in buying a home isn’t looking online for properties. It’s answering these five questions about your financial situation.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Sikora</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

The first step in buying a home isn’t looking online for properties. It’s answering these five questions about your financial situation.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in North Jersey, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Should You Think About Before You Sell?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/what-should-you-think-about-before-you.html</link>
        
          <category>North Jersey Real Estate Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brett Sikora</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-17 13:57:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+What+Should+You+Think+About+Before+You+Sell%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’re a seller, what are a some ways you can maximize your opportunity? Today, I’ve got two methods to share.

Want to sell your home? Get a FREE home value report.
Want to buy a home? Search all homes for sale.

How can you maximize your opportunity as a seller?

Today, I’ve got a few tips to share on how to do just that.

First of all, remember to schedule around holidays. Avoid timing sales within the two weeks prior to a holiday or within the last two weeks of August.

Inventory and conditions overall will tend to pick up outside of those times.

“Don’t miss out by waiting for the next best thing.”

Next, try not to be overly selective about offers. In today’s economy, getting an offer in general is a win. You don’t want to pass over a good thing in the hope that something even better will come along.

Don’t let yourself miss out by waiting for the next best thing.

Accepting offers, even ones that are lower, doesn’t mean you have to stop showing the property until you’re under contract.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+What+Should+You+Think+About+Before+You+Sell%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+What+Should+You+Think+About+Before+You+Sell%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you’re a seller, what are a some ways you can maximize your opportunity? Today, I’ve got two methods to share.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Sikora</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you’re a seller, what are a some ways you can maximize your opportunity? Today, I’ve got two methods to share.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in North Jersey, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why You Need to Start With a Strong Offer</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/why-you-need-to-start-with-strong-offer.html</link>
        
          <category>North Jersey Real Estate Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brett Sikora</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-03 11:06:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+Why+You+Need+to+Start+With+a+Strong+Offer.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When you make your first offer on a home, it needs to be a strong one. There are a couple of main reasons why.

Want to sell your home? Get a FREE home value report.
Want to buy a home? Search all homes for sale.

When you make your first offer on a home, you need to make sure that it’s a strong offer. Why?

First of all, there’s the matter of etiquette to the seller.

For example, let’s say that a seller lists their property at $800,000. It just hit the market and you see it over the weekend for the first time. You make an offer at $750,000.

Now, the seller hasn’t been on the market long enough to accept that offer. They might counter offer and they may even accept your offer at $760,000. However, they will continue to show that property to other buyers. They will also look for every chance to kill that deal.

“Don’t give someone else the chance to make a better offer than yours.”

The other thing to keep in mind is that once another buyer knows that you’ve already made an offer on the property, they will go in with a stronger offer than yours. Don’t give another buyer a chance to steal your dream home away.

Go in with a strong offer, get in and out of attorney review, and try to get to the closing table as soon as possible.

If you have any other questions about buying a home in today’s market, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+Why+You+Need+to+Start+With+a+Strong+Offer.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+Why+You+Need+to+Start+With+a+Strong+Offer.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

When you make your first offer on a home, it needs to be a strong one. There are a couple of main reasons why.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Sikora</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

When you make your first offer on a home, it needs to be a strong one. There are a couple of main reasons why.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in North Jersey, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Is Your Home Ready for the Spring Market?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/is-your-home-ready-for-spring-market.html</link>
        
          <category>North Jersey Real Estate Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brett Sikora</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-27 14:20:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+3+tips+to+prepare+for+the+spring+market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Is your home ready for the spring selling season? If not, here are three simple things you can do now to make your home more appealing to buyers.

Want to sell your home? Get a FREE home value report.
Want to buy a home? Search all homes for sale.

The spring market is just around the corner, and there are three simple things that you can do to prepare your home to sell for top dollar:

1. Deep clean your home. Hire a professional cleaning crew and have them clean the windows and regrout the tubs. People do not like to see the mildew in the bathroom, so this is an easy way to make your home more appealing to buyers.

2. Get rid of all clutter and personal items. Put things in storage or in cabinets. No matter what, make sure your countertops are clean and take all of the magnets off of the fridge.

3. Add a fresh coat of paint. Choose a neutral color, like a nice, basic gray. That will go a long way to make your home look fantastic.

“Hire a professional cleaning crew to make your home sparkle.”

If you have any other questions about the spring market or the home selling process, give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+3+tips+to+prepare+for+the+spring+market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+3+tips+to+prepare+for+the+spring+market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Is your home ready for the spring selling season? If not, here are three simple things you can do now to make your home more appealing to buyers.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Sikora</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Is your home ready for the spring selling season? If not, here are three simple things you can do now to make your home more appealing to buyers.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in North Jersey, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>2 Ways to Calculate Your Investment Return</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/2-ways-to-calculate-your-investment.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate Investment</category>
        
        <author>Brett Sikora</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-14 10:35:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+2+ways+to+figure+out+your+investment+return.mp4</guid>
        <description>

How can you figure out your investment return on your rental property? I’ll go over two ways to do that today.

Want to sell your home? Get a FREE home value report.
Want to buy a home? Search all homes for sale.

How can you calculate what your return will be on an investment? There are actually two ways.

“There are two ways to calculate your investment return depending on whether you used cash or financed the purchase.”

The first way to calculate your return is by figuring out the cap rate. With cap rate, you’re basically going to take your net profit of rental income after taxes and expenses and divide it by the property value. For example, if you are bringing in $10,000 a year on a home you paid $100,000 cash for, your cap rate is 10%.

$10,000 (net rent) / $100,000 (purchase price) = .10 (multiplied by 100 is 10%)

The other way is to figure out your cash-on-cash return. If you’re using a mortgage, you’ll put less money down and will be leveraging the bank’s money, so, you’d take that $10,000 net profit and subtract the debt service. If you spent $20,000 out of pocket to purchase that $100,000 home and the debt service was say, $5,000, your return would be 25%.

$10,000 (net rent) - $5,000 (debt service) = $5,000
$5,000 / $20,000 (down payment with a mortgage) = 0.25 (multiplied by 100 is 25%)

If you have any questions on this topic or if you have any other questions about real estate, please don’t hesitate to reach out. I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+2+ways+to+figure+out+your+investment+return.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+2+ways+to+figure+out+your+investment+return.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

How can you figure out your investment return on your rental property? I’ll go over two ways to do that today.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Sikora</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

How can you figure out your investment return on your rental property? I’ll go over two ways to do that today.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in North Jersey, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3 Tips for Winning a Bidding War</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/3-tips-for-winning-bidding-war.html</link>
        
          <category>North Jersey Real Estate Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brett Sikora</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-01 13:44:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+3+tips+to+win+a+bidding+war.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’re looking to buy, you’re probably going to run into some competition for that dream home. Use these three tips to stand out and win the bidding war.

Want to sell your home? Get a FREE home value report.
Want to buy a home? Search all homes for sale.

With inventory so low, it’s possible you’ll run into a multiple offer situation while trying to snag your dream home. To make sure your offer stands out and wins the bidding war, follow these three steps.

1. Include a letter with your offer. Tell the sellers a little bit about yourself and why you love the home. It adds a personal touch that sellers love.

2. Make the terms easy for the seller. Try to be easy on them as far as the inspection and appraisal goes and allow for a flexible closing date.

3. Figure out the best price to offer based on the market, instead of the list price. It really depends on what the comparables look like and what the competition is doing. With the market so competitive, the list price isn’t going to be what the home sells for, so keep that in mind.

“Craft an offer based on the market instead of the list price.”

If you have any other questions, please feel free to reach out with a phone call or an email. We’re always happy to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+3+tips+to+win+a+bidding+war.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+3+tips+to+win+a+bidding+war.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you’re looking to buy, you’re probably going to run into some competition for that dream home. Use these three tips to stand out and win the bidding war.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Sikora</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you’re looking to buy, you’re probably going to run into some competition for that dream home. Use these three tips to stand out and win the bidding war.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in North Jersey, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Tips For Buying and Selling at the Same Time</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/tips-for-buying-and-selling-at-same-time.html</link>
        
          <category>North Jersey Real Estate Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brett Sikora</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-18 14:55:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+How+to+buy+and+sell+a+home+at+the+same+time.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you are looking to upgrade or transition to a new home, you’ll want to know these three options for buying and selling at the same time.

Want to sell your home? Get a FREE home value report.
Want to buy a home? Search all homes for sale.

If it’s time for you to upgrade or transition to a different home, you might be wondering how you can navigate buying and selling a home at the same time. Here’s a quick rundown on how to make sure the process goes smoothly.

Your first option is to get your home on the market and get an offer from a flexible buyer. A flexible buyer will give you time to find your new home without the looming stress of a closing date. This is also beneficial when buying your new home, as you can tell the seller you are already done with your home inspection and have a buyer waiting for you to close.

“There are a few different ways to make sure you smoothly transition to your new home.”

Another option is to sell your home first and look into temporary housing while you look for a new house. This option gives the seller of your new home a lot of confidence because you are already completely done with your home sale and are ready to purchase their property.

The last option is to find the new property first and then list your home if you are financially prepared to carry two mortgages until your home sells.

Which option is best for you depends on your specific situation, so if you have any questions, please feel free to give me a call or shoot me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+How+to+buy+and+sell+a+home+at+the+same+time.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+How+to+buy+and+sell+a+home+at+the+same+time.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you are looking to upgrade or transition to a new home, you’ll want to know these three options for buying and selling at the same time.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Sikora</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you are looking to upgrade or transition to a new home, you’ll want to know these three options for buying and selling at the same time.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in North Jersey, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Has the Election Affected The Housing Market?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/north-jersey-real-estate-post-election.html</link>
        
          <category>North Jersey Real Estate Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Brett Sikora</author>
        <pubDate>2016-12-09 13:52:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Here’s what’s happening in our post-election real estate market.

Want to sell your home? Get a FREE home value report.
Want to buy a home? Search all homes for sale.

People have been asking me what the market looks like now that the election is over. To be honest, the trend that we are seeing isn’t what I expected. What happened to the real estate market post-election?

For one thing, it has picked up quite a bit. Even though interest rates have hiked by about 0.75%, it didn’t stop buyers whatsoever.

We are also starting to see the luxury market moving again. It seems that people who had money parked and were waiting to see how the election went have decided to stay purchasing homes in the $1 million to $2 million range.

This is also a very active time for investors. It seems that they are focusing on properties that can house five families or more. There are also a lot of 1031 exchanges going on. Please feel free to contact me if you don’t know what those are.

“THERE SEEMS TO BE A LOT OF CONSUMER CONFIDENCE RIGHT NOW.”

All in all, it seems a lot of people are crunching numbers and putting together some pretty big investment deals. Even though the market slowed pre-election, there seems to be a lot of consumer confidence right now, creating a very active market.

If you have any further questions feel free to reach out either by phone or email. I look forward to staying in touch!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Here’s what’s happening in our post-election real estate market.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Sikora</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Here’s what’s happening in our post-election real estate market.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in North Jersey, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Happy Thanksgiving from Our Family to Yours</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/happy-thanksgiving-from-our-family-to.html</link>
        
          <category>Holiday</category>
        
        <author>Brett Sikora</author>
        <pubDate>2016-11-21 13:13:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+We%E2%80%99re+thankful+for+our+clients.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Happy Thanksgiving to all of our clients. Your referrals and support have made this our best year by far.

Want to sell your home? Get a FREE home value report.
Want to buy a home? Search all homes for sale.

With Thanksgiving coming up quickly, I just wanted to take a few moments to say thank you to all of our great clients.

2016 has been our best year by far, and it’s all thanks to your referrals and support. You made this year a success for us, and I just wanted to tell you all how grateful we are to have you as clients.

So Happy Thanksgiving from us to you! I hope that you have a great holiday and enjoy spending this time off with your friends, family, and anyone else important in your life.

“Happy Thanksgiving from us to you!”

I also wanted to let you know that if there is anything that we can do to help you outside of the real estate world, we have a lot of connections within our database from plumbers, electricians, and landscapers to attorneys and lenders. If you need any referrals, feel free to reach out to us and we can connect you with people we trust.

Once again, I hope you all have a happy Thanksgiving. In the meantime, if you have any other questions about real estate, give me a call or send me an email. I’d be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+We%E2%80%99re+thankful+for+our+clients.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+We%E2%80%99re+thankful+for+our+clients.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Happy Thanksgiving to all of our clients. Your referrals and support have made this our best year by far.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Sikora</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Happy Thanksgiving to all of our clients. Your referrals and support have made this our best year by far.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in North Jersey, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Benefits of Buying an Off-Market Property</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/the-benefits-of-buying-and-off-market.html</link>
        
          <category>North Jersey Real Estate Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brett Sikora</author>
        <pubDate>2016-10-19 13:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+What+are+off-market+properties.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Are you tired of getting dragged into bidding wars? Off-market properties may be the solution for you.

Want to sell your home? Get a FREE home value report.
Want to buy a home? Search all homes for sale.

Why would a buyer be interested in an off-market property?

Off-market inventory is very popular for buyers who’ve already missed out on other properties and know exactly what they’re looking for. Time is less of a factor in this case because it takes longer for us to find off-market properties.

For example, let’s say you wanted to purchase a unit in The Hudson Tea here in Hoboken but lost out in a bidding war. What we would do is call the rest of the units in the building and see if any of the owners would be willing to accept the same offer you made on the unit you lost out on.

“Off-market properties allow you to bypass bidding wars.”

If you missed out on a home in the suburbs, we would draw a circle around that home’s entire neighborhood and start reaching out to other homeowners in the event that they might want to sell. This is a great way to find inventory without worrying about getting into another bidding war. If the property makes sense, excellent. If not, that’s fine too. We’ll just keep moving along and see if any of the other neighbors would want to sell their home.

If you’re tired of bidding wars, we’re here to help. I estimate that one out of every 10 transactions we handle is an off-market transaction. Not only does it help buyers, but sellers usually get a great number at the end of the day as well.

If you have any questions about off-market properties, feel free to email me or give me a call. I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+What+are+off-market+properties.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+What+are+off-market+properties.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Are you tired of getting dragged into bidding wars? Off-market properties may be the solution for you.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Sikora</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Are you tired of getting dragged into bidding wars? Off-market properties may be the solution for you.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in North Jersey, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Where Should You Begin Your Home Search?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/where-should-you-begin-your-home-search.html</link>
        
          <category>North Jersey real estate buyer tips</category>
        
        <author>Brett Sikora</author>
        <pubDate>2016-10-04 11:11:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+Where+should+you+begin+your+online+home+search.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Can you trust websites like Zillow and Trulia during your home search? While these are very popular sites for home buyers, their listings may not be updated.

Want to sell your home? Get a FREE home value report.
Want to buy a home? Search all homes for sale.

Many of our clients begin their home searches online by going through the listings on sites like Zillow, Trulia, and Realtor.com. They find a few they like and then ask us to get them private showings of the properties. What will often happen is that we’ll pull a home up on the MLS only to find out that it is already under contract or has already sold.

The reason that properties show up on these sites as “active” is because agents have the ability to put their own listings on sites like Zillow, Trulia, and Realtor.com. However, they often do not take them down once the home has sold. This could either be because the agent forgot to take the listing down, or it could be a strategy that the agent is using to get more leads by baiting buyers with the property and then trying to sell them on another home.

“Not all ‘active’ listings on most websites are still available.”

The nice thing about our website is that our listings come directly from the MLS, so every property that you see listed on our website is still available. It’s very regulated and there aren’t any false listings out there to dash your hopes for a new home.

Our listings are only linked with Hudson County right now, but we plan on expanding our coverage to the surrounding counties soon.

If you have any questions about how to find the home that’s right for you or where to begin your search, don’t hesitate to reach out to us by phone or email. We’re always happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+Where+should+you+begin+your+online+home+search.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+Where+should+you+begin+your+online+home+search.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Can you trust websites like Zillow and Trulia during your home search? While these are very popular sites for home buyers, their listings may not be updated.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Sikora</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Can you trust websites like Zillow and Trulia during your home search? While these are very popular sites for home buyers, their listings may not be updated.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in North Jersey, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Brett Sikora</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Brett Sikora</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Sikora Group - your professional North Jersey Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
