<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Wes Peters Group Real Estate Podcast</title>
    <link>http://wpghomeblog.com</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://wpghomeblog.com"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Wes Peters Group - your professional Baltimore Metropolitan Area Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Wesley Peters</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2018-03-15 14:41:41 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Wesley Peters</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://wpghomeblog.com/img/podcast.png"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Baltimore Metropolitan Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">News &amp; Politics</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>wes@wespetersgroup.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Wesley Peters</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Wesley Peters</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://wpghomeblog.com/img/podcast.png"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Baltimore Metropolitan Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Baltimore Metropolitan Area Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Wes Peters Group - your professional Baltimore Metropolitan Area Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="News &amp; Politics"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Spring Updates From Our Team</title>
        <link>http://wpghomeblog.com/3-spring-updates-from-our-team.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Wesley Peters</author>
        <pubDate>2018-03-13 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/2018/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+Promotion+video.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today, I’d like to bring you just a few messages. First of all, my team and I would like to extend our sincere thanks to everyone who joined us at our recent client appreciation event. We collected almost 200 toys for the Cool Kids Foundation thanks to your participation.

The second message I wanted to share with you has to do with our current real estate market. The spring real estate market in Maryland has been very busy.

With more hours of daylight than in the previous months, people have more time to spend out looking at homes. This allows buyers to visit listings during the week, instead of just on the weekends. As a result, homes stay on the market for shorter amounts of time.

“The spring real estate market in Maryland has been very busy.”

Finally, there’s one more thing I want to let you all know about. My team and I will be hosting a March Madness giveaway. The person whose bracket gains them the highest points will become our lucky winner, so be sure to get in touch with me about how to enter.

If you have any other questions or would like more information about anything I’ve gone over today, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/2018/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+Promotion+video.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://wpghomeblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/2018/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+Promotion+video.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>I’ve got three updates for you today, including some information on how you can enter to win our March Madness giveaway.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Wesley Peters</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>I’ve got three updates for you today, including some information on how you can enter to win our March Madness giveaway.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Baltimore Metropolitan Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Newest Addition to the Wes Peters Group</title>
        <link>http://wpghomeblog.com/the-newest-addition-to-the-wes-peters-group.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Wesley Peters</author>
        <pubDate>2018-02-21 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/2018/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+New+Team+Member.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Our real estate team has been servicing the Baltimore Metro area for the last 30 years or so. Although we’re based out of Columbia, we will go anywhere in the state of Maryland that they’ll let us sell homes for our clients.

Harford County has always been an area that we’ve serviced, but it’s to the point where it’s an hour or so away from us. So, to better service our clients on that side of town, we have recently partnered with Rob Elliot. Rob is a Bel Air and Fallston area native, and we’re really excited to combine our resources with Rob’s local knowledge and expertise on that side of town.

“I am excited to be a part of this team,” says Rob. “I have been a Baltimore County and Harford County resident for 47 years, and my wife and my three children reside in Bel Air. I’ve been in sales most of my adult life, and I’ve been in the real estate market as an investor. I made the decision to work with clients to help them find homes, and I look forward to working with you.”

“Join us on Sunday, February 25 at Horizon Cinemas to watch ‘Peter Rabbit.’”

We are lucky to have Rob as part of our team. If you would like to meet Rob, he is having a client event on Sunday, February 25 at Horizon Cinemas in Fallston at 9:30 a.m. There will be a screening of the movie “Peter Rabbit,” as well as some free breakfast (bagels, donuts, and coffee).

Come on out on February 25 for a great time. We will send out Facebook invitations and other invites soon.

Again, thanks to Rob for joining our team. We look forward to working with him.

As always, if you have any real estate questions, just give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/2018/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+New+Team+Member.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://wpghomeblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/2018/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+New+Team+Member.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Rob Elliott has joined our team so that we can better serve our clients in Harford County. You can meet him at our client event on February 25.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Wesley Peters</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Rob Elliott has joined our team so that we can better serve our clients in Harford County. You can meet him at our client event on February 25.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Baltimore Metropolitan Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>We Have an Inventory Crisis!</title>
        <link>http://wpghomeblog.com/we-have-an-inventory-crisis.html</link>
        
        <author>Wesley Peters</author>
        <pubDate>2018-02-06 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/February+18'/Baltimore%2520Metro%2520Real%2520Estate-%2520Client%2520Event.mp4</guid>
        <description>

At this point in the year, there are a couple of reminders and updates I’d like to share with all of you. First of all, our next client appreciation event is coming up soon.

We hope you’ll join us for a movie day on February 24 at 1:30 p.m. at Arundel Mills Theater.

We’ve already sent out invitations online and through the mail, so please reach out if you haven’t already received yours.

Now, onto a brief market update. We have somewhat of an inventory crisis on our hands right now. Right now, we’re seeing the lowest amount of homes on the market for a decade in our area.

“If you’ve been thinking about selling your home, now is the time to do so.”

For example, there are 61 homes on the market in Catonsville, 74 available homes in Ellicott City, 43 in Columbia, and 74 in Eldersburg.

Overall, our local market has just 2.9 months of inventory. This means that if no new homes came on the market, all inventory would be gone in just 2.9 months. So if you’ve been thinking about selling your home, now is the time to do so.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/February+18'/Baltimore%2520Metro%2520Real%2520Estate-%2520Client%2520Event.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://wpghomeblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/February+18'/Baltimore%2520Metro%2520Real%2520Estate-%2520Client%2520Event.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today, I’ve got two things to share with you: an invitation to a client appreciation event and an update on our market.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Wesley Peters</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today, I’ve got two things to share with you: an invitation to a client appreciation event and an update on our market.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Baltimore Metropolitan Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>We Have Investors That Will Buy Your House As-Is, Cash, No Commission or Expenses to Sell!</title>
        <link>http://wpghomeblog.com/we-have-investors-that-will-buy-your-house-as-is-cash-no-commission-or-expenses-to-sell.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Wesley Peters</author>
        <pubDate>2018-01-23 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+Get+cash+for+your+distressed+property.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Do you own a distressed property that’s in rough shape? Perhaps you know someone who does? If either is the case, I have three options someone in this situation may find useful.

1. Cash offer, quick settlements, and selling as-is.This will allow the seller to list their home without worrying about financial or home inspection contingencies. If they want to leave the house full of unwanted possessions, they are free to do so. Additionally, this option requires no exposure to the market. In all these scenarios, the investor will pay all of the expenses associated with the offer.

“A cash offer will allow the seller to list their home without worrying about financial or home inspection contingencies.”

2. Putting the home on the market.This option is for those who predict that they can find an investor or homeowner who would pay more for the property than a cash buyer off the market. However, here, you’d have to pay for such things as commission, and you may be exposed to contingencies like a financial contingency. If you can’t find a better offer on the market than you could off the market, then the off-market investor would likely still be interested in purchasing your home. This option gets the best of both worlds.

3. Put money back into the home. If you’re in a position such that you can invest some money into renovating your home, we can connect you to contractors to help you fix the property and get it to the top of the market. The downsides to this option are that you’ll have holding costs and you may have to move into temporary housing until you finish work on the property (and then again when you go to sell).

So if you do find yourself in a situation with a house that’s in poor condition, you do have options. If you have questions about this or would like me to come out to your property and give you my opinion about what someone might be willing to pay your distressed home, feel free to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+Get+cash+for+your+distressed+property.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://wpghomeblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+Get+cash+for+your+distressed+property.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Do you own a distressed property that’s in rough shape? Perhaps you know someone who does? If either is the case, I have three options someone in this situation may find useful.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Wesley Peters</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Do you own a distressed property that’s in rough shape? Perhaps you know someone who does? If either is the case, I have three options someone in this situation may find useful.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Baltimore Metropolitan Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Looking for a Career Change in 2018?</title>
        <link>http://wpghomeblog.com/looking-for-a-career-change-in-2018.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Wesley Peters</author>
        <pubDate>2017-12-20 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+Looking+for+a+career+change+in+2018%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I just wanted to let everyone know that we are hiring for 2018.

We are looking to grow our team, and there are a lot of great opportunities.

Whether you had thought about a career in real estate and not had time to transition or are looking for a part-time opportunity, I’d love to talk to you. If you have a license and are looking for full-time opportunities, I’d love to talk to you.

Even if you are an established agent who needs more support for administrative work and marketing, I’d love to talk with you.

We have a good track record of getting new agents into the business through different career paths, and we’re really proud of that. We are looking to grow our team, and we have a great value proposition that I’d love to talk to everyone about.

There are 26,000 real estate agents in Maryland and the D.C. area, and about 100,000 homes sell each year in Maryland. Some might say that the industry is over-serviced, but I disagree.

I can tell you that only about 10% of agents renew their licenses after two years in the business. That means that 90% of agents get out of the business.

There is a huge amount to learn, from technology to contract changes and beyond. As great as some brokerages are, it can be hard to provide everything an agent needs.

That’s why teams are so prevalent now. Teams are able to provide training, accountability, and leadership.Keller Williams has world-class training that we are really proud of.

So, if you or anyone you know would be interested in a career in real estate, I would love to talk to them. In the meantime, I hope you have fun this holiday season.

I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+Looking+for+a+career+change+in+2018%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://wpghomeblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+Looking+for+a+career+change+in+2018%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>I just wanted to let everyone know that we are hiring for 2018.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Wesley Peters</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>I just wanted to let everyone know that we are hiring for 2018.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Baltimore Metropolitan Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Does the Cool Kids Campaign Help Children With Cancer?</title>
        <link>http://wpghomeblog.com/how-does-the-cool-kids-campaign-help-children-with-cancer.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Wesley Peters</author>
        <pubDate>2017-11-13 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+Helping+the+Cool+Kids+Campaign.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I’m joined by Kristen Rutherford and Mackenzie Wieder from the Cool Kids Campaign. Kristin is the Community Relations Coordinator, and Mackenzie is the Operations Coordinator.

This is a local charity that we partner with. We contribute a portion of our commission from every settlement at Keller Williams to the campaign.

The Cool Kids Campaign helps improve the quality of life for pediatric oncology patients and their families. The Cool Kids Campaign focuses on academic, social, and emotional support.

They have many great programs in place. During the summer, there is a “Mommy and Me” drop-off for the kids to come and hang out. They also have a camp for all of the kids and their siblings, as well as a condo in Myrtle Beach, where they send the families for vacation.

“The Cool Kids Campaign helps children with cancer and their families.”

The Cool Kids Campaign also sends care packages out across the country with all of the kids’ favorite things.

Take a look at the video to see their great facility in Towson, Maryland.

We are on track to donate $10,000 to the Cool Kids Campaign this year, and we are proud to help such an amazing organization.

Thanks to Kristen and Mackenzie for joining me today. You can learn more about the Cool Kids Campaign at their website.

If you have any questions, please don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+Helping+the+Cool+Kids+Campaign.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://wpghomeblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+Helping+the+Cool+Kids+Campaign.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I’m joined by Kristen Rutherford and Mackenzie Wieder from the Cool Kids Campaign. Kristin is the Community Relations Coordinator, and Mackenzie is the Operations Coordinator.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Wesley Peters</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I’m joined by Kristen Rutherford and Mackenzie Wieder from the Cool Kids Campaign. Kristin is the Community Relations Coordinator, and Mackenzie is the Operations Coordinator.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Baltimore Metropolitan Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>My Team Is Putting Our Money Where Our Mouth Is for Our Sellers</title>
        <link>http://wpghomeblog.com/my-team-is-putting-our-money-where-our-mouth-is-for-our-sellers.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Wesley Peters</author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-16 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+We+guarantee+your+listings+success.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I wanted to take a minute to tell you all about our Guaranteed Sale Program.

Since we’re currently in a seller’s market, this isn’t something that has been coming into play all that often. Nevertheless, I wanted to give you an idea of what it is and how it works. I personally like to give sellers what I think are the pros and cons of their situation, and what the best and worst-case scenarios are in any given circumstance.

Even though I like to provide this information and feedback, I still want to give sellers the freedom to choose their own initial list price—within reason. Still, a lot of sellers ask me what I would do if I were in their shoes.

This is where the Guaranteed Sale Program comes into play. This program lets me put my money where my mouth is.

“If we can’t sell your home for you within 60 days for a price you’re happy with, we will sell it for free!”

If the seller lists their home at a price my team and I recommend and agree with and doesn’t sell within 30 days, the listing will undergo an agreed-upon price reduction. This reduction is usually about 3%. If the listing still doesn’t sell within 60 days, we will continue to market your property at no cost. Though we’ll still need to pay the buyer’s agent, my team and I will basically be working for free at that point.

This guarantee does not include short sales or tenant-occupied properties, and there needs to be equity in the property.

Pre-appraisals and pre-inspections are both required for the Guaranteed Sale Program.

This allows us to be totally transparent with any potential buyers. This also allows us to take care of any issues that arise in the report ahead of time. With a pre-inspection, a lot of surprises are taken out of the transaction.

The program also requires that you meet with our in-house stager Rose, and agree to any of her recommendations.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+We+guarantee+your+listings+success.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://wpghomeblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+We+guarantee+your+listings+success.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I wanted to take a minute to tell you all about our Guaranteed Sale Program.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Wesley Peters</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I wanted to take a minute to tell you all about our Guaranteed Sale Program.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Baltimore Metropolitan Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Has Technology Changed the World of Lending?</title>
        <link>http://wpghomeblog.com/how-has-technology-changed-the-world-of-lending.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Wesley Peters</author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-04 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+How+has+the+lending+world+changed%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>


Today I’m joined by a special guest, Andy Duda from Caliber Home Loans, to talk about the current state of mortgages.

I’ve been in the business for 13 years, but Andy has been helping me with loans even before then. In the time we’ve known each other, Andy has assisted me with hundreds of loans.

It’s a big deal for my team and I to have lenders that we trust, so professionals like Andy are a huge resource to us. We try to introduce Andy to as many of our clients as possible when they are in need of his services.

Lending has changed a little bit over the year. I always tell people that lending in 2017 is somewhat vanilla. Most lenders have the same products, so the real difference comes down to interest rates and customer service.

According to Andy, the world of lending ultimately changed after the economic crisis in 2007. Ultimately, traditional financing is king. There are niche programs out there, but most people tend to go more standard routes

“As technology moves forward, so does the world of real estate.”

One of the most important things is to talk to your lender early on in the process. Doing so will help you determine what price range you should be shopping in and what programs will be the best fit for you. Having this information will also help your Realtor service you to the highest level.

Even though most loan products are fairly standardized, there are some neat features available these days. For example, Caliber Home Loans has introduced the possibility of a digital mortgage for buyers.

This allows the company to digitally verify income and assets without the hassle of a lot of paperwork. People can become fully approved and can close without ever having to dig up paystubs.

While not all employers will facilitate this as a possibility, it is a great option for those who can make use of it. As technology moves forward, so does the world of real estate.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+How+has+the+lending+world+changed%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://wpghomeblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+How+has+the+lending+world+changed%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I’m joined by a special guest, Andy Duda from Caliber Home Loans, to talk about the current state of mortgages.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Wesley Peters</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I’m joined by a special guest, Andy Duda from Caliber Home Loans, to talk about the current state of mortgages.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Baltimore Metropolitan Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Great News About Our Zillow Reviews and a Quick Market Update</title>
        <link>http://wpghomeblog.com/great-news-about-our-zillow-reviews-and-a-quick-market-update.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Wesley Peters</author>
        <pubDate>2017-09-05 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+We+hit+200+Zillow+reviews+thanks+to+you.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What’s the latest word on our Baltimore market as we head into fall?

First, I have some great news to share with you. Our team has reached 200 reviews on Zillow. It’s taken us years to accumulate this number, and it’s a milestone we’re extremely proud of. If you’re a past client of ours and you contributed one of those reviews, I want to personally thank you.

Also, I want to remind you that we’re hosting an outdoor cookout for all of our past clients on September 23rd at the Columbia Sports Park at 5 p.m. My wife’s been putting a lot of effort into planning this event, so if you’re a past client and you haven’t gotten your invitation in the mail, we’d love for you to come join us. We’ll have a live DJ, an open bar, and plenty of fun activities for the whole family to enjoy.

“We’ll see an uptick in the market in the next 60 to 75 days.”

Now, onto the latest real estate news. The Baltimore market experienced a little bit of a slowdown this past August because of people vacationing later in the year due to a later school year start date. This has caused some frustration among the active buyers out there because of the available inventory.

The good news if you’re a buyer, however, is that you’ll see a new wave of homes coming on the market next week—our team alone has about 10 homes being listed next Wednesday or Thursday.

The good news if you’re a seller is that we’ll see an uptick in the market in the next 60 to 75 days, which will provide you a great window to sell your home. It’s arguably a better time to sell during this timespan than the spring months because—from an appraisal standpoint—you have great comparables of homes that sold in May, June, and July.

If you have any questions about our market or you’re thinking about buying or selling a home soon, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d be glad to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+We+hit+200+Zillow+reviews+thanks+to+you.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://wpghomeblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+We+hit+200+Zillow+reviews+thanks+to+you.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What’s the latest word on our Baltimore market as we head into fall?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Wesley Peters</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What’s the latest word on our Baltimore market as we head into fall?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Baltimore Metropolitan Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Where Does Our Baltimore Market Stand for Buyers and Sellers?</title>
        <link>http://wpghomeblog.com/where-does-our-baltimore-market-stand-for-buyers-and-sellers.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Wesley Peters</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-03 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+Your+latest+Baltimore+metro+market+update.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What’s the latest news from our Baltimore metro area market?

Let’s start by sharing some statistics from the month of June:


  The median sale price was just shy of $279,000, which is the highest it’s been since July 2007.
  There were 4,509 closed sales and 4,313 pending sales—the highest number for either category in a decade.
  Active inventory continued to decline by double digits for the twelfth consecutive month, and ended at 11,097 homes.


To get a more in-depth look at how our market fared in June, check out this article by Real Estate Business Intelligence.

“If you’ve missed out on a home, August might be a great time to find a good value.”

One trend I’ve noticed lately is that many buyers who’ve been trying to secure a home before summer ends and school starts have found what they were looking for. The market tends to slow down in August and then pick back up after Labor Day. I always say this window is the second-best time period to sell your home, after the spring market.

On the buyer side, if you’ve missed out on a home in the last few months, August might present some valuable opportunities since fewer buyers will be in the marketplace.

On a different note, we have a client appreciation event coming up on September 23rd at the Columbia Sports Park from 5 p.m. to 9 p.m., so keep your eyes peeled for an upcoming invitation. It should be a great time for everyone involved, so we hope to see you then.

In the meantime, if you have any questions about our market or are thinking of buying or selling a home, feel free to give me a call or shoot me an email. I’d be happy to speak with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+Your+latest+Baltimore+metro+market+update.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://wpghomeblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+Your+latest+Baltimore+metro+market+update.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What’s the latest news from our Baltimore metro area market?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Wesley Peters</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What’s the latest news from our Baltimore metro area market?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Baltimore Metropolitan Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How You Can Take Advantage of a Great Jumbo Mortgage Program</title>
        <link>http://wpghomeblog.com/how-you-can-take-advantage-of-a-great-jumbo-mortgage-program.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Wesley Peters</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-12 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+Ranked+%252320+In+All+Of+Maryland.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Realtrends.com came out with their list of the top agents in the country recently, and while we weren’t quite able to make the top 1,000 real estate agents in the country, we are excited to announce that we were ranked No. 20 in the state of Maryland for 2016 in terms of all units sold. Considering that there are around 26,000 agents in Maryland and D.C., we are pretty proud of that accomplishment and wanted to thank all of our clients for supporting us.

I also wanted to take a little bit to talk about jumbo mortgages and what’s going on in the jumbo mortgage industry. Traditionally, if you wanted to borrow anywhere from $500,000 to $1 million, it would’ve been more expensive in the Maryland area to borrow $1 million than a couple hundred thousand.

It actually hasn’t been that way for the last couple of years. In Maryland, if you were to borrow under $424,000 with a conventional mortgage with 5% down, your interest rate would be right around 4.5%. If you were to move into the jumbo category and borrow more than $424,000 with 10% down, your interest rate would be about 4.25% and you wouldn’t need mortgage insurance.

“Interest rates do get better as you have a larger down payment.”

You don’t have to put down 20% for a jumbo mortgage in order to get mortgage insurance out of your life, but it’s cheaper to borrow $1 million at 10% down than it is to borrow $200,000 at 5% down. Interest rates do get better as you have a larger down payment, and there are a lot of banks that have programs that are geared toward the more affluent buyer and offer incentives to take your banking to these particular banks.

There is a popular program geared toward people who are looking to buy new construction but have a home to sell.​ If a buyer is willing to put 10% down on a mortgage for a new build and are able to sell their home within six months, they can then recast their mortgage, put an additional 10% with the money they gained from selling the house, and then have their interest rate lowered by 3/8ths of a point. It’s actually a free refinance and you can keep the original interest rate that you locked in when you first acquired the mortgage.

If you have any questions about this topic or need recommendations for some lenders to talk to, please give me a call. I’d be happy to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+Ranked+%252320+In+All+Of+Maryland.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://wpghomeblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+Ranked+%252320+In+All+Of+Maryland.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Realtrends.com came out with their list of the top agents in the country recently, and while we weren’t quite able to make the top 1,000 real estate agents in the country, we are excited to announce that we were ranked No. 20 in the state of Maryland for 2016 in terms of all units sold.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Wesley Peters</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Realtrends.com came out with their list of the top agents in the country recently, and while we weren’t quite able to make the top 1,000 real estate agents in the country, we are excited to announce that we were ranked No. 20 in the state of Maryland for 2016 in terms of all units sold.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Baltimore Metropolitan Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Navigate Our Market as a Move-Up Buyer</title>
        <link>http://wpghomeblog.com/how-to-navigate-our-market-as-a-move-up-buyer.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Wesley Peters</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-23 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+Moving+up+in+our+Maryland+market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Some of the clients I’ve been working with lately are what you call “move-up buyers.” Who are move-up buyers? What are they trying to achieve?

Move-up buyers are often living in their first home and are hitting a point where they need a little bit more space or have different family goals. Hence, they’re seeking a fresh start and a new home. When I meet with these buyers, I’ll ask them a few important questions, such as:


  Are there homes out there that excite you?
  Do you already know the home you want to purchase or do you need to get out there and see what the current inventory looks like?
  Do you need to sell to buy?
  What is your timeline?


Those questions help us put a plan together, and after that initial discussion I typically see three common scenarios. The first is putting a contingent offer on a new home, then settling on the old home and new home on the same day. The second is selling first and then buying. The third is buying first and then selling. Each option has its advantages and disadvantages.

“Having good people in place will help you make good decisions.”

The first option means the purchase of your next home is contingent on the sale of your current home. A couple dominos have to fall in this scenario. It represents the least amount of risk for move-up buyers, but it’s also the least attractive option to sellers—especially when we’re in a seller’s market.

The second option occurs when people want to buy in a specific area and there’s a unique type of home they’re looking for so they sell their current home and move in with friends or relocate to a short-term rental. When that home does come on the market, they can be very nimble, and they can also put a non-contingent offer on it, which makes their offer more attractive to the seller.

The last option happens more than you think. This tends to occur with families with kids or pets and there are a lot of barriers to get their home ready and approved for showings once it’s on the market. By moving into their new home, they can get their old home ready for the market. Once it’s listed, they can approve every showing because they aren’t living there anymore. The downside of this is that family may have to carry two mortgages for a month or two.

If you’re a move-up buyer (or any type of homebuyer), the best advice we can give you is this: set a big goal and make a date when you want to move into your new home. Once you establish that big goal, break it down into smaller micro-goals and collaborate with your agent to put a strategic plan into place to make sure you’re taking the right steps and maximize your potential once you hit the market.

Lastly, have trusted partners you can rely on. Whether it’s a lender, an inspector, or a staging consultant, having good people in place will help you make good decisions.

If you have any questions or are looking to make a move in our market, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+Moving+up+in+our+Maryland+market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://wpghomeblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+Moving+up+in+our+Maryland+market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Some of the clients I’ve been working with lately are what you call "move-up buyers." Who are move-up buyers? What are they trying to achieve?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Wesley Peters</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Some of the clients I’ve been working with lately are what you call "move-up buyers." Who are move-up buyers? What are they trying to achieve?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Baltimore Metropolitan Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What You Can Learn From Zillow's Lawsuit</title>
        <link>http://wpghomeblog.com/what-you-can-learn-from-zillows-lawsuit.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Wesley Peters</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-12 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+Zillow+might+be+in+hot+water+because+of+this.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Recently, Zillow and their Zestimate have been in the news because of a homeowner taking issue with how the Zestimate has negatively affected her home sale.

This homeowner paid $626,000 for the home six years ago and tried to sell it for a similar price. The Zillow Zestimate valued the property at $564,000.

The argument by the homeowner (which hasn’t quite gone to court yet) is that Zillow is acting as if they are an appraiser in this situation. Zillow is adamant that the Zestimate is just an estimate, but they had an average error rate of about 6% in 2016. That can get pretty significant in higher price points.

The Zestimate is meant to be just a starting point for buyers, but many look at it as more of an appraisal, which is not how it intended to be. This homeowner isn’t seeking damages, but rather just to get Zillow out of the appraisal side of things.

“The Zestimate is meant to be just a starting point for buyers.”

If you want to know what your home is worth, you can use a website like Zillow or you can hire a licensed appraiser, and there is an argument to be made for both. A licensed appraiser will take a more analytical approach by accounting for price per square foot and make adjustments for amenities.However, many times, the appraiser hasn’t actually seen the homes they compare yours to when coming up with a value. They don’t know if the home had a strong odor, backed up to power lines, or sat on the market for a long time, for instance.

An appraiser doesn’t have their finger on the pulse of the active market like a real estate agent who has been in the majority of homes that you’re comparing it to.

If you have any questions about finding your home’s value or you want to know what it’s worth, we’d love to help you out. Just give me a call or send me an email soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+Zillow+might+be+in+hot+water+because+of+this.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://wpghomeblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+Zillow+might+be+in+hot+water+because+of+this.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Recently, Zillow and their Zestimate have been in the news because of a homeowner taking issue with how the Zestimate has negatively affected her home sale.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Wesley Peters</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Recently, Zillow and their Zestimate have been in the news because of a homeowner taking issue with how the Zestimate has negatively affected her home sale.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Baltimore Metropolitan Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Introducing Our Newest Staging & Design Expert</title>
        <link>http://wpghomeblog.com/introducing-our-newest-staging-design-expert.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Wesley Peters</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-10 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+Introducing+Rose.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Have you met our expert stager/designer, Rose Bennett?

Rose has been with us almost six months and is a big part of our listing process.She decided to work here because it gave her the unique opportunity to combine her background in interior design with real estate. She works on the listing side of the team helping sellers stage and design their homes for the market and staying with them all the way through settlement.

Her duties consist of coming out to the home and writing up a full staging report so the homeowner knows everything they need to do to prepare the home for the market. With Rose on the team, staged homes have been selling 43% faster than vacant homes and at an average of 97% of the listing price once we’ve gone through the process of getting them ready. Our average days on market is also down to just 16 days.

“I highly recommend using Rose to help you prepare your home for the market.”

Rose’s design background was the perfect match for what we were looking for in her position. She designed model homes for quite some time and has a great sense of style and what’s popular now within the new construction community. She also does design work on her own.

We’re working to bring all of our resources in-house and develop a better process and value for you, and Rose has been a big part of this endeavor. In addition to staging, we also have a licensed contractor who works in conjunction with Rose so she can allocate time management. If you’re thinking about making renovations to your property, I highly recommend reaching out to her. She even helped me design the improvements I made to my home.

If you’d like to reach out to Rose directly, you can email her at Rose@WesPetersGroup.com. If you have any questions or are considering buying or selling a home, don’t hesitate to give us a call or shoot us an email. We look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+Introducing+Rose.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://wpghomeblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+Introducing+Rose.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Rose has been with us almost six months and is a big part of our listing process. She decided to work here because it gave her the unique opportunity to combine her background in interior design with real estate.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Wesley Peters</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Rose has been with us almost six months and is a big part of our listing process. She decided to work here because it gave her the unique opportunity to combine her background in interior design with real estate.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Baltimore Metropolitan Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What National Market Trends Could Mean for Baltimore</title>
        <link>http://wpghomeblog.com/what-national-market-trends-could-mean-for-baltimore.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Wesley Peters</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-12 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+How+Baltimore+reflects+the+national+market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today we’ve got an update for you on the national real estate market and how it affects our local market here in the Baltimore metro area.

I read recently that the collective national real estate average price is higher than it has ever been. The National Association of Realtors also reported that inventory is the lowest it has been since they started tracking it in 1999. With supply and demand, most would expect prices to go up. Because of the low inventory, many economists predict that prices will go down, but so will the number of transactions.

Home builder confidence is at an all-time high, which has to do with expecting decreased regulations. They’re hoping it will make it less expensive and easier to build homes, basically. Job reports look strong; we added 235,000 new jobs in February.

“Our shortage of inventory makes it more important than ever to work with an experienced real estate expert.”

So there’s a lot of encouraging news going on nationally, but what does it mean to our local market?

To understand this, I think it’s important to understand the history of the recent market crash. A lot of things went south in cities like New York and Miami, despite the thought that real estate trends start on the West Coast and move east. However, I believe that’s what’s going on right now. Although national real estate prices are at an all-time high (and up 20% in the last three years), we haven’t seen that in the Baltimore market. I think that’s because we’re typically behind about two to three years. During the market crash prices didn’t bottom out until 2011.

If you look at prices in the metro area for the last few years, we’ve been pretty flat. Now though, we’re starting to see that appreciation that everyone has been hoping and waiting for. I think it’s reasonable to believe that we’re two or three years behind the appreciation trend and that we’re just now starting to see the start of some really good times in our market with prices going up.

We definitely have an inventory issue, which makes working with an experienced real estate agent extremely important right now if you plan to buy or sell a home. If you’re interested in finding out what your house is worth and what it might look like in the next three or four years, give me a call or send me an email. I’d be glad to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+How+Baltimore+reflects+the+national+market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://wpghomeblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+How+Baltimore+reflects+the+national+market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today we've got an update for you on the national real estate market and how it affects our local market here in the Baltimore metro area.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Wesley Peters</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today we've got an update for you on the national real estate market and how it affects our local market here in the Baltimore metro area.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Baltimore Metropolitan Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>An Update on Our Team and the Local Market</title>
        <link>http://wpghomeblog.com/an-update-on-our-team-and-the-local-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Wesley Peters</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-27 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+A+market+update%252C+team+update%252C+and+happy+hour.mp4</guid>
        <description>

My wife Jennifer joined our real estate team about six months ago. She was a teacher at Hillcrest Elementary for 11 years and since she made the switch, she has been a huge part of our growth and success.

Jen helps out behind the scenes with a lot of contract-to-close issues, client functions, and community involvement. In fact, we are excited to announce that we are partnering with the Cool Kids Campaign.

With every real estate transaction this year, we will make a $50 donation to the Cool Kids Campaign. As a former teacher and parent of two young kids, Jen wanted to find a strong, local charity that helped kids. The Cool Kids Campaign improves the lives of children with cancer and lends support to their families. We hope to contribute over $10,000 to the Cool Kids Campaigns this year. It is a really good feeling to know that our clients’ real estate success will carry over to support this foundation and our community.

“We hope to give over $10,000 to the Cool Kids Campaign.”

We plan on selling a lot of houses this year. After all, the more homes we sell, the more money we can give to the Cool Kids Campaign.

We also want to give a quick shout out to Kristen and Dan, who just bought their first house. We were able to save them about $3,000 in moving expenses thanks to our moving truck! We are offering some great services this year and the moving truck is one of them, so spread the word.

Although the weather has been a little crazy lately, the real estate market is on fire. We sold 13 homes last week and almost every one of those had multiple offers and sold at list price. Inventory is also incredibly low. If the market wasn’t crazy enough already, the Federal Reserve just raised their interest rate by 0.25%. Luckily, the market already anticipated that rise, and mortgage interest rates actually went down a bit.

Finally, we want to invite you to our happy hour, organized by Jen, on April 27th at Union Jack’s in Columbia. We hope to see you all there.

In the meantime, if you have any questions about real estate or if you would like to learn more about our current market, give us a call. We look forward to speaking with you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+A+market+update%252C+team+update%252C+and+happy+hour.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://wpghomeblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+A+market+update%252C+team+update%252C+and+happy+hour.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>My wife Jennifer joined our real estate team about six months ago. She was a teacher at Hillcrest Elementary for 11 years and since she made the switch, she has been a huge part of our growth and success.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Wesley Peters</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>My wife Jennifer joined our real estate team about six months ago. She was a teacher at Hillcrest Elementary for 11 years and since she made the switch, she has been a huge part of our growth and success.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Baltimore Metropolitan Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Meet Troy, Our Home Selling Rockstar!</title>
        <link>http://wpghomeblog.com/meet-troy-our-home-selling-rockstar.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Wesley Peters</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-16 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+Have+you+met+Troy%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I’m happy to introduce you to Troy, our team’s lead listing agent. Troy handles all of our listings and was a huge part of our success in 2016.

We had a great year last year and were able to list and sell 58 homes. We sold them for 98.8% of the original list price in 35 days on average. To boot, we sold 40% of our listings last year at or above list price. Compare that to the Baltimore metro average of homes selling at 95% of their list price. Just by deciding to work with us, our clients made 3.8% more for their homes on average.

We have specialists in every area of a real estate transaction, as Troy points out, which is a big benefit for our clients. Troy has a marketing background and works with stagers, photographers, and with our team’s database of buyers. He helps our clients make sure their homes look spectacular the first day they go on the market and gets potential buyers through the door right away.

“Troy played a big part in helping us list and sell 58 homes last year.”

With the spring market coming up and inventory as low as it is, Troy is happy to say that we have 34 homes coming on the market in the next 12 weeks with 10 currently on the market. Homes are selling very quickly in our market right now, making it vitally important to work with a great agent like Troy.

On a final note, Troy and I both want to thank everyone who came out to our client appreciation event recently. I also want to thank Troy for joining me today.

If you have any questions for us or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home in the Baltimore metro, give us a call or send us an email. We’d love to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+Have+you+met+Troy%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://wpghomeblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+Have+you+met+Troy%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I'm happy to introduce you to Troy, our team's lead listing agent. Troy handles all of our listings and was a huge part of our success in 2016.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Wesley Peters</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I'm happy to introduce you to Troy, our team's lead listing agent. Troy handles all of our listings and was a huge part of our success in 2016.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Baltimore Metropolitan Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Some News From Our Office and the Market</title>
        <link>http://wpghomeblog.com/some-news-from-our-office-and-the-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Wesley Peters</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-09 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+The+latest+news+on+the+market+and+our+team.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I want to talk to you about some new services that we are offering and give you the rundown on the early spring market.

One big addition to our team this year is a home stager named Rose Bennett. She has a lot of experience in designing model homes and she is also assisting as a listing coordinator, which is really helping me out. She does a great job helping sellers maximize their home’s potential.

We have also added a moving truck, which is available for current and past clients, and we have brought on a licensed handyman as a permanent part of our staff who can help you get your home ready for sale or help you customize your new one.

“Our handyman can help you get your home ready for sale or help customize your new one.”

Now onto some spring market news.

In January, the median sales price was up 6.8% from last year. Inventory is still low, and active listings are down 17%. The good news is, the median days on the market is 46 days, down from 56 days. Homes are selling quicker and buyers are out there. The surge in buyer activity is likely due to interest rates staying historically low for the moment.

Buyers are looking, but they need more options to get them excited. This is especially true in the Catonsville, North Hartford Baho. Co., Lauraville, Southern Carroll, and Crofton areas.

If you or anyone you know is looking to sell a home, please don’t hesitate to reach out to me. If you have any other real estate questions, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I’d love to work with you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+The+latest+news+on+the+market+and+our+team.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://wpghomeblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+The+latest+news+on+the+market+and+our+team.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I want to talk to you about some new services that we are offering and give you the rundown on the early spring market.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Wesley Peters</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I want to talk to you about some new services that we are offering and give you the rundown on the early spring market.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Baltimore Metropolitan Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>We Are Excited to Offer New Services in 2017</title>
        <link>http://wpghomeblog.com/we-are-excited-to-offer-new-services-in-2017.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Wesley Peters</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-20 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+Our+team+has+made+a+few+changes+this+year.mp4</guid>
        <description>

We have some exciting announcements about new services we have to offer you in 2017.

First of all, we just purchased our first moving truck. We have a 14-foot box truck to help offset some of your moving costs. If you are thinking about moving, we would be happy to help you. We have two guys to drive the truck and move heavy furniture for you.

We also added a licensed contractor to our staff. Whether you want to fix up your home before it hits the market or you need someone to handle repairs after the inspection, we now have someone on our team who can help you out.

“We can help you make repairs, stage your home, and move!”

Finally, Rose Bennett, a very talented designer and home stager, has joined our team. Rose has an extensive background in staging model homes. She can certainly help get your listing ready. A lot of the time, people want to sell their homes but aren’t sure how to prepare their house for the market. Rose can help you figure out exactly where to invest in your home in order to make it more appealing to buyers.

I also wanted to take a minute to invite you to our client appreciation eventon February 25th at the Columbia AMC Theater. Join us to watch “The Lego Batman Movie” at 1 p.m.

In the meantime, if you have any questions or if you are interested in using any of our new services, give us a call or send us an email. My team and I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+Our+team+has+made+a+few+changes+this+year.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://wpghomeblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+Our+team+has+made+a+few+changes+this+year.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Our team has a few new services to offer you in 2017. I also want to invite you to our client appreciation event on February 25th!</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Wesley Peters</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Our team has a few new services to offer you in 2017. I also want to invite you to our client appreciation event on February 25th!</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Baltimore Metropolitan Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Market Update for Baltimore in 2017</title>
        <link>http://wpghomeblog.com/market-update-for-baltimore-in-2017.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Wesley Peters</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-19 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+Latest+Baltimore+real+estate+news.mp4</guid>
        <description>

As we head into 2017, we are bringing you the latest on the Baltimore real estate market and what we’re seeing right now. Essentially, we have low inventory across the board. We’ll talk about some specific areas later, but right now let’s look at some of the latest statistics for the Baltimore metro as a whole.

There are about 11,000 homes on the market right now. It may sound like a lot, but it really isn’t when you consider how many homes are actually out there. This is the 15th consecutive month of decreased inventory, and inventory is what drives demand in this market.

One specific area that has particularly low inventory is Catonsville. They only have about 3.5 months of available homes. A balanced market has an inventory level between four and six months. Anything higher than that is considered a buyer’s market. Anything lower is considered a seller’s market. Because of that low inventory, prices are up by about 4% in the last year.

“We have low inventory across the board.”

Another statistic from Catonsville that jumped out at me was that they had more than 90 home sales between June 2015 and June 2016. That’s the best month for them as far back as they have kept records. If you’re thinking about selling your home during June 2017, you’ll need to get it on the market in April or May. We are encouraging a lot of our sellers to meet with stagers right now and get their homes inspected and appraised so they can price perfectly for this market.

In the Eldersburg, Sykesville area, there are only about two months worth of inventory. In Ellicott City, there are only about three. All zip codes in Columbia, Maryland are under two months. As you can see, there is not a lot to choose from in many places in the Baltimore Metro and this is about as active as you will see the market in January.

If you have any particular questions or are thinking about buying or selling a home, give us a call or send us an email. We would love to hear from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+Latest+Baltimore+real+estate+news.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://wpghomeblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Wes+Peters/Baltimore+Metro+Real+Estate-+Latest+Baltimore+real+estate+news.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>We are currently in the midst of our 15th consecutive month of decreased inventory. Some areas in Baltimore have lower inventory than others, but our levels are low across the board.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Wesley Peters</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We are currently in the midst of our 15th consecutive month of decreased inventory. Some areas in Baltimore have lower inventory than others, but our levels are low across the board.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Baltimore Metropolitan Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Wesley Peters</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Wesley Peters</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Wes Peters Group - your professional Baltimore Metropolitan Area Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
