<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Palm Beach Real Estate Podcast with The Treu Group</title>
    <link>http://treugroupsouthflorida.com</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://treugroupsouthflorida.com"/>
    <description>I'll update you with how to make a smart decision in real estate, improve the value of your home, and keep you up to date on what's happening in our local Palm Beach & Martin County real estate market.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>The Treu Group</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2017-08-10 16:14:05 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>The Treu Group</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://i.imgur.com/9KV2FyM.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real,Estate,Palm,Beach,Market,Sale,Lisa,Treu,Group,Tips,Tricks,South,Florida,agents,educational,informative,housing,house,short,talk,show,radio,martin,county</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>lisa@treugroup.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>The Treu Group</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>The Treu Group</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://i.imgur.com/9KV2FyM.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real,Estate,Palm,Beach,Market,Sale,Lisa,Treu,Group,Tips,Tricks,South,Florida,agents,educational,informative,housing,house,short,talk,show,radio,martin,county</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Real Estate Tips and Tricks for the Palm Beach and Martin County market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>I'll update you with how to make a smart decision in real estate, improve the value of your home, and keep you up to date on what's happening in our local Palm Beach & Martin County real estate market.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Hot, the Cold, & International Opportunities</title>
        <link>http://treugroupsouthflorida.com/the-hot-the-cold-international-opportunities.html</link>
        
          <category>WJNO Radio show</category>
        
        <author>The Treu Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-07 11:44:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/+Radio+Show/The+hot%2C+the+col+%26+the+international+opportunities+Mixdown+1.mp3</guid>
        <description>

What is contributing to the local South Florida real estate market? Everything from sellers in Toronto to millennial buyers have an impact on the sale or purchase of your home. What kind of opportunities are on the market for you? Real estate is very local, different cities and even different communities can have varied real estate markets. Treu Group will help you find the opportunity in your own local market.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/+Radio+Show/The+hot%2C+the+col+%26+the+international+opportunities+Mixdown+1.mp3" length="" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treugroupsouthflorida.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/+Radio+Show/The+hot%2C+the+col+%26+the+international+opportunities+Mixdown+1.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Treu Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real,Estate,Palm,Beach,Market,Sale,Lisa,Treu,Group,Tips,Tricks,South,Florida,agents,educational,informative,housing,house,short,talk,show,radio,martin,county</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why You Need to Take Advantage of the Market Now</title>
        <link>http://treugroupsouthflorida.com/why-you-need-to-take-advantage-of-the-market-now.html</link>
        
          <category>2017 Real Estate Market</category>
        
        <author>The Treu Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-01 05:18:27 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/The+News+You+Can+Use+%257C+Palm+Beach.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Whether you’re a buyer or seller, I have important news to share with you.  

Interest rates, as we know, have been on the rise. Why does this matter?  

If you’re a buyer and rates go up just 1%, you’ll lose 10% of your buying power. This means you may have to settle for not living in the neighborhood you want or giving up that pool you wanted. That’s not what you want, right? I know that’s not what I want for you.

If you’re a seller, rising interest rates mean fewer buyers can afford your home. Fewer buyers mean fewer offers.

“TAKE ADVANTAGE OF THE OPPORTUNITY OUR MARKET IS GIVING YOU RIGHT NOW.”

There was a study published recently that no one’s talking about but I think you deserve to know about. The study showed that in South Florida, there’s less than a 10% chance that our real estate prices will decrease in the next two years.

As a buyer, you might have both higher interest rates and higher prices, and that’s not good for anybody.

We are here to help you capitalize on the opportunity in the current market, so if you have any questions or you’re thinking of buying or selling real estate, don’t hesitate to give us a call. We look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/The+News+You+Can+Use+%257C+Palm+Beach.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treugroupsouthflorida.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/The+News+You+Can+Use+%257C+Palm+Beach.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Rising interest rates mean now is the time for both buyers and sellers to make a move in our market.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Treu Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Rising interest rates mean now is the time for both buyers and sellers to make a move in our market.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real,Estate,Palm,Beach,Market,Sale,Lisa,Treu,Group,Tips,Tricks,South,Florida,agents,educational,informative,housing,house,short,talk,show,radio,martin,county</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Things to Know About the Palm Beach County Market</title>
        <link>http://treugroupsouthflorida.com/things-to-know-about-palm-beach-county.html</link>
        
          <category>2017 Real Estate Market</category>
        
        <author>The Treu Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-27 10:31:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

The real estate market can be a little bit confusing, especially if you’re getting your information from friends, family, or the news. So I wanted to give you some accurate information about the Palm Beach County market.

Last month, we had 5.1 months of inventory. That means we’re still in a seller’s market. If you’re looking to buy, you’re going to need to be prepared, and if you’re looking to sell, you’re going to be pretty happy.

35.7% of all transactions that closed last month were cash. There were no appraisal contingencies and no financing in these transactions. The median price was $327,000 and that number keeps rising. We still have room to grow, as the number when we were at the height of our market was around $375,000.

A question frequently asked is this: “Are you buying or selling in a buyer’s market or seller’s market?” It depends on two things: the area and the price range that you’re in. For example, if you’re buying or selling a single-family home in the $200,000 to $250,000 range, then you’re in a very strong seller’s market. There are only about two months inventory in this price range.

“THERE’S ALWAYS AN OPPORTUNITY IN THE MARKET.”

If you increase your budget and you’re buying or selling in the $300,000 to $400,000 range, then you’re still in a seller’s market and there’s only about three months of inventory. Sellers are receiving multiple offers for these homes and buyers are going to have a hard time beating out the competition.

If you move into the luxury market ($600,000 to $1 million range), you’ll see we’re in a buyer’s market. We have nine months of inventory in this market, so if you’re looking to buy then you’ll have plenty to choose from. The same goes for homes that are priced at $1 million or more. We have 16 months of inventory available in this market, making it a strong buyer’s market as well.

There’s always an opportunity in the market. The question is how do you capitalize on that? Here at True Group Real Estate, we’ve been helping buyers in the seller’s market get the home of their dreams. If you’re selling, we want to help you get the most money for your home.

If you’re in the luxury market and you’re frustrated because your home isn’t selling, we have the right formula to get a sold sign in the yard and you to the closing table. The formula is simple, but it isn’t easy; you need the right price, the right condition, and the right marketing. We can help.

If you have any other questions about real estate, or you’re looking to buy or sell a home, please give a call or shoot us an email. We’d love to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treugroupsouthflorida.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

The real estate market can be a little bit confusing, especially if you’re getting your information from friends, family, or the news. So I wanted to give you some accurate information about the Palm Beach County market.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Treu Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

The real estate market can be a little bit confusing, especially if you’re getting your information from friends, family, or the news. So I wanted to give you some accurate information about the Palm Beach County market.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real,Estate,Palm,Beach,Market,Sale,Lisa,Treu,Group,Tips,Tricks,South,Florida,agents,educational,informative,housing,house,short,talk,show,radio,martin,county</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Tips for Buying a Home</title>
        <link>http://treugroupsouthflorida.com/tips-for-buying-home.html</link>
        
          <category>WJNO Radio show</category>
        
        <author>The Treu Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-19 11:44:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/+Radio+Show/Your+best+buy+with+the+Treu+Group+(1).mp3</guid>
        <description>
Buying your first home can be an intimidating process. Lisa Treu, of Treu Group Real Estate, talks about everything you should know before making your first real estate purchase. Did you know that most people underestimate their ability to buy a home? From tips on saving up for that down payment, to advice on building your credit score, Lisa covers everything first time homebuyers need to take into consideration before selecting their home.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/+Radio+Show/Your+best+buy+with+the+Treu+Group+(1).mp3" length="" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treugroupsouthflorida.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/+Radio+Show/Your+best+buy+with+the+Treu+Group+(1).mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
Buying your first home can be an intimidating process. Lisa Treu, of Treu Group Real Estate, talks about everything you should know before making your first real estate purchase. Did you know that most people underestimate their ability to buy a home? From tips on saving up for that down payment, to advice on building your credit score, Lisa covers everything first time homebuyers need to take into consideration before selecting their home.
</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Treu Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
Buying your first home can be an intimidating process. Lisa Treu, of Treu Group Real Estate, talks about everything you should know before making your first real estate purchase. Did you know that most people underestimate their ability to buy a home? From tips on saving up for that down payment, to advice on building your credit score, Lisa covers everything first time homebuyers need to take into consideration before selecting their home.
</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real,Estate,Palm,Beach,Market,Sale,Lisa,Treu,Group,Tips,Tricks,South,Florida,agents,educational,informative,housing,house,short,talk,show,radio,martin,county</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Does Zillow Hurt Your Chances of Buying or Selling?</title>
        <link>http://treugroupsouthflorida.com/does-zillow-hurt-your-chances-of-buying-or-selling.html</link>
        
        <author>The Treu Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-07 14:06:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>
Sites like Zillow, Realtor.com, and Trulia can be a challenge for buyers and sellers. Why?

Let’s say that you are buying a home and looking for your dream home on these sites. If you call the listing agent, you will probably hear that the property has already sold. That’s because there is a delay between what you see on those websites and what professional agents see. As real estate agents, we actually get a head start of up to seven days on the best properties.

So, how can you find a listing online that hasn’t already gone under contract?

You can do one of two things. First, you can search on a site like ours, which pulls information directly from the MLS. That way, when a home hits the market, you will know right away. The other option is to allow us to do all of the hard work for you.

“OUR WEBSITE PULLS INFORMATION DIRECTLY FROM THE MLS.”

The last few buyers we’ve worked with only viewed four homes until they found their dream home. That might not seem very impressive, but one of those buyers had been searching with another agent and on their own for two long years.

If you are selling your home, are those websites your friends? Not really. It’s important to understand how Zillow impacts your pool of buyers. If Zillow has a wrong Zestimate or other incorrect information, it can cost you thousands of dollars. It may even cost you the home sale.

It’s important to understand how these sites work and competitively list your home in the right place.

At Treu Group real estate, we understand how to help you buy, sell, and, most importantly, how to help you win. If you have any questions, we are here to help you. Just give us a call!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treugroupsouthflorida.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
Sites like Zillow, Realtor.com, and Trulia can be a challenge for buyers and sellers. Why?

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Treu Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
Sites like Zillow, Realtor.com, and Trulia can be a challenge for buyers and sellers. Why?

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real,Estate,Palm,Beach,Market,Sale,Lisa,Treu,Group,Tips,Tricks,South,Florida,agents,educational,informative,housing,house,short,talk,show,radio,martin,county</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What's your Word? Discover your Word with Chris Pan from MyIntent.org.</title>
        <link>http://treugroupsouthflorida.com/whats-your-word-discover-your-word-with.html</link>
        
          <category>WJNO Radio show</category>
        
        <author>The Treu Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-05 09:53:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/+Radio+Show/Treu+intentions+featuring+Chris+Pan.mp3</guid>
        <description>
Lisa discussed how she met Chris Pan and discovered MyIntent.org and the power of Treu Group Real Estate’s Word. The 2017 Word is Commitment. It is a constant reminder that they will Say What needs to be said, Do whatever needs to be done and Go where they need to go to help them accomplish their clients and team goals. Chris Pan, the founder of myintent.org, shares that bracelet product that is more than just a fashion piece. Chris talked about the bracelet not as jewelry but as a reminder of one’s idea of what he/she wants more from life, what challenges he/she wants to overcome, or what is something he/she is really passionate about in life.

Chris was kind enough to offer a 20% discount code which you get by listening to the show. These are great gifts or can be used for your personal or corporate Word.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/+Radio+Show/Treu+intentions+featuring+Chris+Pan.mp3" length="" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treugroupsouthflorida.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/+Radio+Show/Treu+intentions+featuring+Chris+Pan.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
Lisa discussed how she met Chris Pan and discovered MyIntent.org and the power of Treu Group Real Estate’s Word. The 2017 Word is Commitment. It is a constant reminder that they will Say What needs to be said, Do whatever needs to be done and Go where they need to go to help them accomplish their clients and team goals. Chris Pan, the founder of myintent.org, shares that bracelet product that is more than just a fashion piece. Chris talked about the bracelet not as jewelry but as a reminder of one’s idea of what he/she wants more from life, what challenges he/she wants to overcome, or what is something he/she is really passionate about in life.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Treu Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
Lisa discussed how she met Chris Pan and discovered MyIntent.org and the power of Treu Group Real Estate’s Word. The 2017 Word is Commitment. It is a constant reminder that they will Say What needs to be said, Do whatever needs to be done and Go where they need to go to help them accomplish their clients and team goals. Chris Pan, the founder of myintent.org, shares that bracelet product that is more than just a fashion piece. Chris talked about the bracelet not as jewelry but as a reminder of one’s idea of what he/she wants more from life, what challenges he/she wants to overcome, or what is something he/she is really passionate about in life.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real,Estate,Palm,Beach,Market,Sale,Lisa,Treu,Group,Tips,Tricks,South,Florida,agents,educational,informative,housing,house,short,talk,show,radio,martin,county</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>International Interest In South Florida Is An Opportunity For You</title>
        <link>http://treugroupsouthflorida.com/international-interest-in-south-florida.html</link>
        
          <category>WJNO Radio show</category>
        
        <author>The Treu Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-02 10:06:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/+Radio+Show/International+interst+in+South+Florida+is+an+opportunity+for+you.mp3</guid>
        <description>
Out of all 50 states, Florida has the most international buyers. This means more opportunities for you! This means more potential buyers for your home and an active real estate market. Most international buyers pay cash for vacation homes, and add to the local economy when they come to visit. Understanding which countries are interested in Florida is important, and at Treu Group Real Estate we stay informed of what’s happening abroad. Our understanding of the international market helps us better navigate our local real estate markets, and help you make an informed decision when making your next big real estate transaction.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/+Radio+Show/International+interst+in+South+Florida+is+an+opportunity+for+you.mp3" length="" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treugroupsouthflorida.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/+Radio+Show/International+interst+in+South+Florida+is+an+opportunity+for+you.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
Out of all 50 states, Florida has the most international buyers. This means more opportunities for you! This means more potential buyers for your home and an active real estate market. Most international buyers pay cash for vacation homes, and add to the local economy when they come to visit. Understanding which countries are interested in Florida is important, and at Treu Group Real Estate we stay informed of what’s happening abroad. Our understanding of the international market helps us better navigate our local real estate markets, and help you make an informed decision when making your next big real estate transaction.
</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Treu Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
Out of all 50 states, Florida has the most international buyers. This means more opportunities for you! This means more potential buyers for your home and an active real estate market. Most international buyers pay cash for vacation homes, and add to the local economy when they come to visit. Understanding which countries are interested in Florida is important, and at Treu Group Real Estate we stay informed of what’s happening abroad. Our understanding of the international market helps us better navigate our local real estate markets, and help you make an informed decision when making your next big real estate transaction.
</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real,Estate,Palm,Beach,Market,Sale,Lisa,Treu,Group,Tips,Tricks,South,Florida,agents,educational,informative,housing,house,short,talk,show,radio,martin,county</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What's Happening with PBC Real Estate Right Now</title>
        <link>http://treugroupsouthflorida.com/whats-happening-with-pbc-real-estate.html</link>
        
          <category>WJNO Radio show</category>
        
        <author>The Treu Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-08 12:10:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/+Radio+Show/What%27s+happening+with+PBC+real-estate+right+now+Mixdown+1+(1).mp3</guid>
        <description>
Lisa Treu shares the low down on what’s happening right now in the real estate market of Palm Beach County. Are we currently in a buyer’s or seller’s market; and what’s the difference? Tune in to hear Lisa’s expert advice on how to go about selling or buying your home in today’s market. Get the latest scoop on everything from luxury real estate to active adult communities.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/+Radio+Show/What%27s+happening+with+PBC+real-estate+right+now+Mixdown+1+(1).mp3" length="" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treugroupsouthflorida.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/+Radio+Show/What%27s+happening+with+PBC+real-estate+right+now+Mixdown+1+(1).mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
Lisa Treu shares the low down on what’s happening right now in the real estate market of Palm Beach County. Are we currently in a buyer’s or seller’s market; and what’s the difference? Tune in to hear Lisa’s expert advice on how to go about selling or buying your home in today’s market. Get the latest scoop on everything from luxury real estate to active adult communities.
</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Treu Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
Lisa Treu shares the low down on what’s happening right now in the real estate market of Palm Beach County. Are we currently in a buyer’s or seller’s market; and what’s the difference? Tune in to hear Lisa’s expert advice on how to go about selling or buying your home in today’s market. Get the latest scoop on everything from luxury real estate to active adult communities.
</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real,Estate,Palm,Beach,Market,Sale,Lisa,Treu,Group,Tips,Tricks,South,Florida,agents,educational,informative,housing,house,short,talk,show,radio,martin,county</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>We Dont Play Games When It Comes to Achieving Results for You</title>
        <link>http://treugroupsouthflorida.com/we-dont-play-games-when-it-comes-to-achieving-results-for-you.html</link>
        
        <author>The Treu Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-05 15:35:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>
Playgrounds are a lot of fun for kids. They can be fun for us, too. However, you don’t want the job of helping you buy or sell a home becoming a game for your agent.

If you’re looking to buy or sell here in Palm Beach County, you probably know about some of the many challenges that could cause the deal to fall apart. There are issues with financing and inspections that may need to be solved. Lack of experience could play a role as well.

“GAMES ARE FUN, BUT SO IS A SUCCESSFUL REAL ESTATE TRANSACTION.”

At Treu Group Real Estate, we want you to have a professional on your side that is going to be there for you to help you overcome all of the challenges you might face in order to get you to the closing table.

Experience matters, and experts say that it takes 10,000 hours to master a skill. We have mastered the skill of doing business in the real estate market, and we’d love to share that skill with you.

Don’t monkey around with your real estate transaction. If you have any questions or need any help, our team is just a phone call or email away. We look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treugroupsouthflorida.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
Playgrounds are a lot of fun for kids. They can be fun for us, too. However, you don’t want the job of helping you buy or sell a home becoming a game for your agent.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Treu Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
Playgrounds are a lot of fun for kids. They can be fun for us, too. However, you don’t want the job of helping you buy or sell a home becoming a game for your agent.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real,Estate,Palm,Beach,Market,Sale,Lisa,Treu,Group,Tips,Tricks,South,Florida,agents,educational,informative,housing,house,short,talk,show,radio,martin,county</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Treu Solutions To Avoid The 5 Biggest Real Estate Pitfalls</title>
        <link>http://treugroupsouthflorida.com/treu-solutions-to-avoid-5-biggest-real.html</link>
        
          <category>WJNO Radio show</category>
        
        <author>The Treu Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-21 11:28:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/+Radio+Show/Treu+Solutions+to+avoid+the+5+biggest+real-estate+pitfalls.mp3</guid>
        <description>
It takes 10,000 hours to master something. Having the right agent who knows what to do when dealing with a unique contract is essential in avoiding a real estate pitfall. At Treu Group Real Estate, our team of experts works together to help you avoid pitfalls, and to work through them when they do arise. Listen in for details on how to close your real estate deal and avoid the pitfalls.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/+Radio+Show/Treu+Solutions+to+avoid+the+5+biggest+real-estate+pitfalls.mp3" length="" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treugroupsouthflorida.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/+Radio+Show/Treu+Solutions+to+avoid+the+5+biggest+real-estate+pitfalls.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
It takes 10,000 hours to master something. Having the right agent who knows what to do when dealing with a unique contract is essential in avoiding a real estate pitfall. At Treu Group Real Estate, our team of experts works together to help you avoid pitfalls, and to work through them when they do arise. Listen in for details on how to close your real estate deal and avoid the pitfalls.
</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Treu Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
It takes 10,000 hours to master something. Having the right agent who knows what to do when dealing with a unique contract is essential in avoiding a real estate pitfall. At Treu Group Real Estate, our team of experts works together to help you avoid pitfalls, and to work through them when they do arise. Listen in for details on how to close your real estate deal and avoid the pitfalls.
</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real,Estate,Palm,Beach,Market,Sale,Lisa,Treu,Group,Tips,Tricks,South,Florida,agents,educational,informative,housing,house,short,talk,show,radio,martin,county</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 Steps To Buying Success</title>
        <link>http://treugroupsouthflorida.com/5-steps-to-buying-success.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>The Treu Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-10 13:42:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/+Radio+Show/The+Treu+Group%27s+5+steps+to+buying+success+Mixdown+1.mp3</guid>
        <description>
There’s more to buying a home than just buying. Do you know the difference between pre-qualified and pre-approved? When you’re buying a home, the deal isn’t done until all the paperwork is signed. Treu Group Real Estate has broken down the buying process into 5 simple steps so you can know what to expect throughout the buying process.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/+Radio+Show/The+Treu+Group%27s+5+steps+to+buying+success+Mixdown+1.mp3" length="" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treugroupsouthflorida.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/+Radio+Show/The+Treu+Group%27s+5+steps+to+buying+success+Mixdown+1.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
There’s more to buying a home than just buying. Do you know the difference between pre-qualified and pre-approved? When you’re buying a home, the deal isn’t done until all the paperwork is signed. Treu Group Real Estate has broken down the buying process into 5 simple steps so you can know what to expect throughout the buying process.
</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Treu Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
There’s more to buying a home than just buying. Do you know the difference between pre-qualified and pre-approved? When you’re buying a home, the deal isn’t done until all the paperwork is signed. Treu Group Real Estate has broken down the buying process into 5 simple steps so you can know what to expect throughout the buying process.
</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real,Estate,Palm,Beach,Market,Sale,Lisa,Treu,Group,Tips,Tricks,South,Florida,agents,educational,informative,housing,house,short,talk,show,radio,martin,county</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3 Unique Opportunities in the Market Today</title>
        <link>http://treugroupsouthflorida.com/3-unique-opportunities-in-market-today.html</link>
        
          <category>2017 Real Estate Market</category>
        
        <author>The Treu Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-31 11:36:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

There are opportunities in every real estate market, and I want to share three of them with you today.

First of all, a recent study revealed that almost 50% of all millennials in south Florida live at home. If you want to build wealth in the United States, the first step in creating wealth is to own your own home.

While this may not be possible for all millennials right now, some millennials should definitely consider packing up and buying their first home. If you have a great job, a steady income, and you’ve saved some money or have access to gift money, then now is a great time to get into a new property.

Let me tell you a quick story: When I first purchased a home, I got a 13.5% adjustable mortgage rate. Compared to today’s low interest rate, you can see that homes are more affordable. You can ask your friends and your parents what their first home’s interest rates were, and I think you will agree that even a 4% interest rate is an absolute gift to the real estate market.

“OWNING A HOME IS THE FIRST STEP IN CREATING YOUR OWN WEALTH.”

Secondly, if you already own your first home, now is a great time to upgrade to your next home or maybe even your dream home. Why? If you sell your current home, you are probably selling in a seller’s market. Depending on what price range you are moving up to, you will likely be buying in a buyer’s market. So, the market currently allows you to sell in the best position possible and have more options when you go to buy.

Finally, if you are ready to retire and want top dollar for your home, you can definitely win in this market, especially if your home lines up with what millennials are interested in. Why? Right now, we have a shortage of great homes in certain price ranges. Anything under $500,000 often receives multiple offers, great prices, and great terms.

So, it is time to capitalize on these three great opportunities in our current market. If you have any questions about buying or selling a home, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treugroupsouthflorida.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

There are opportunities in every real estate market, and I want to share three of them with you today.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Treu Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

There are opportunities in every real estate market, and I want to share three of them with you today.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real,Estate,Palm,Beach,Market,Sale,Lisa,Treu,Group,Tips,Tricks,South,Florida,agents,educational,informative,housing,house,short,talk,show,radio,martin,county</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Maximizing Your Real Estate Success</title>
        <link>http://treugroupsouthflorida.com/maximizing-your-real-estate-success.html</link>
        
          <category>WJNO Radio show</category>
        
        <author>The Treu Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-27 15:33:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/+Radio+Show/Maximizing+your+real-estate+success+(2).mp3</guid>
        <description>
Lisa Treu of Treu Group Real Estate to talks mortgage rates, special loan programs, and explains what Treu Group Real Estate can do for you when you’re getting ready to buy a home. Lisa talks about raving fans, property taxes, why the rent is rising, and reasons you should join the homeowner’s club.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/+Radio+Show/Maximizing+your+real-estate+success+(2).mp3" length="" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treugroupsouthflorida.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/+Radio+Show/Maximizing+your+real-estate+success+(2).mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
Lisa Treu of Treu Group Real Estate to talks mortgage rates, special loan programs, and explains what Treu Group Real Estate can do for you when you’re getting ready to buy a home. Lisa talks about raving fans, property taxes, why the rent is rising, and reasons you should join the homeowner’s club.
</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Treu Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
Lisa Treu of Treu Group Real Estate to talks mortgage rates, special loan programs, and explains what Treu Group Real Estate can do for you when you’re getting ready to buy a home. Lisa talks about raving fans, property taxes, why the rent is rising, and reasons you should join the homeowner’s club.
</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real,Estate,Palm,Beach,Market,Sale,Lisa,Treu,Group,Tips,Tricks,South,Florida,agents,educational,informative,housing,house,short,talk,show,radio,martin,county</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Master Your Mortgage With The Treu Group</title>
        <link>http://treugroupsouthflorida.com/master-your-mortgage-with-treu-group.html</link>
        
          <category>WJNO Radio show</category>
        
        <author>The Treu Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-10 16:47:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/+Radio+Show/Master+your+mortgage+with+the+Treu+Group.mp3</guid>
        <description>
Treu Group Real Estate and Erick Cantele from Academy Mortgage team up to share all you need to know before buying a home. What are your best options for types of loans? What do you need for a down payment? Do you need to be pre-approved, or pre-qualified? Listen in to let Lisa and Erick answer all your questions about getting ready to buy a new home.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/+Radio+Show/Master+your+mortgage+with+the+Treu+Group.mp3" length="" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treugroupsouthflorida.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/+Radio+Show/Master+your+mortgage+with+the+Treu+Group.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
Treu Group Real Estate and Erick Cantele from Academy Mortgage team up to share all you need to know before buying a home. What are your best options for types of loans? What do you need for a down payment? Do you need to be pre-approved, or pre-qualified? Listen in to let Lisa and Erick answer all your questions about getting ready to buy a new home.
</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Treu Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
Treu Group Real Estate and Erick Cantele from Academy Mortgage team up to share all you need to know before buying a home. What are your best options for types of loans? What do you need for a down payment? Do you need to be pre-approved, or pre-qualified? Listen in to let Lisa and Erick answer all your questions about getting ready to buy a new home.
</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real,Estate,Palm,Beach,Market,Sale,Lisa,Treu,Group,Tips,Tricks,South,Florida,agents,educational,informative,housing,house,short,talk,show,radio,martin,county</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Getting Down To Business With Kelly Smallridge</title>
        <link>http://treugroupsouthflorida.com/getting-down-to-business-with-kelly_24.html</link>
        
          <category>WJNO Radio show</category>
        
        <author>The Treu Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-24 11:34:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/+Radio+Show/Getting+down+to+business+with+Kelly+Smallridge.mp3</guid>
        <description>
Lisa Treu of Treu Group Real Estate would like to invite you to join us with Kellly Smallridge, President and CEO of the Business Development Board of Palm Beach County. Kelly shares how she is working to bring business to our area and the concerns of corporations considering moving to Palm Beach County.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/+Radio+Show/Getting+down+to+business+with+Kelly+Smallridge.mp3" length="" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treugroupsouthflorida.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/+Radio+Show/Getting+down+to+business+with+Kelly+Smallridge.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
Lisa Treu of Treu Group Real Estate would like to invite you to join us with Kellly Smallridge, President and CEO of the Business Development Board of Palm Beach County. Kelly shares how she is working to bring business to our area and the concerns of corporations considering moving to Palm Beach County.
</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Treu Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
Lisa Treu of Treu Group Real Estate would like to invite you to join us with Kellly Smallridge, President and CEO of the Business Development Board of Palm Beach County. Kelly shares how she is working to bring business to our area and the concerns of corporations considering moving to Palm Beach County.
</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real,Estate,Palm,Beach,Market,Sale,Lisa,Treu,Group,Tips,Tricks,South,Florida,agents,educational,informative,housing,house,short,talk,show,radio,martin,county</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3 Ways We Can Help You Reach Your Real Estate Goals</title>
        <link>http://treugroupsouthflorida.com/3-ways-we-can-help-you-reach-your-real.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>The Treu Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-22 14:24:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

No matter what your goals are in real estate, the Treu Group can help. Here are three specific ways that our team can assist you in achieving your real estate dreams:


  
    When you’re looking to buy. Whether it’s your first home, your dream home, or an investment property, we are here to help. We serve the areas of Palm Beach County, Martin County, and even Broward County. If you want to buy something in another state, we can help you out there too with our network of referral partners.
  
  
    When you want to sell. Marketing is really important, and we understand the formula that will get your home sold for top dollar. It involves the right price, the right condition, and the right marketing. We expose your property locally, nationally, and internationally to maximize the number of potential buyers who will see it online.
  


“YOU DESERVE A TEAM LIKE OURS.”


  When you want to buy new construction. Many people are unaware that the builder will happily pay for you to have a buyer’s agent on your side, someone to help you make great decisions in the short and long term. We’ve been able to help our clients make great choices with selections, floor plans, and even upgrades. Builders won’t give you a discount if you walk in by yourself. In fact, they will probably take advantage of that fact.


You deserve to have a team like True Group Real Estate by your side whether buying, selling, investing, or building. If you have any questions for us or are thinking about making a move yourself, give us a call or send us an email today. We would love to hear from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treugroupsouthflorida.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

No matter what your goals are in real estate, the Treu Group can help. Here are three specific ways that our team can assist you in achieving your real estate dreams:

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Treu Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

No matter what your goals are in real estate, the Treu Group can help. Here are three specific ways that our team can assist you in achieving your real estate dreams:

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real,Estate,Palm,Beach,Market,Sale,Lisa,Treu,Group,Tips,Tricks,South,Florida,agents,educational,informative,housing,house,short,talk,show,radio,martin,county</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Buying Wise With The Treu Group</title>
        <link>http://treugroupsouthflorida.com/buying-wise-with-treu-group.html</link>
        
          <category>Radio Show</category>
        
        <author>The Treu Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-17 16:50:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/+Radio+Show/Buying+wise+with+the+Treu+Group.mp3</guid>
        <description>
Whether it’s your first home, one of many, or just an investment, the Treu team will represent you, not the transaction. Treu Group is the best option for representation when you’re buying a home. Having the expertise and connections of the entire Treu team on your side will not only save you money on the deal, you don’t pay us any fees! We have a few secret weapons for getting you to the closing table fast. Tune in to hear how Treu Group can help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/+Radio+Show/Buying+wise+with+the+Treu+Group.mp3" length="" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treugroupsouthflorida.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/+Radio+Show/Buying+wise+with+the+Treu+Group.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
Whether it’s your first home, one of many, or just an investment, the Treu team will represent you, not the transaction. Treu Group is the best option for representation when you’re buying a home. Having the expertise and connections of the entire Treu team on your side will not only save you money on the deal, you don’t pay us any fees! We have a few secret weapons for getting you to the closing table fast. Tune in to hear how Treu Group can help you!
</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Treu Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
Whether it’s your first home, one of many, or just an investment, the Treu team will represent you, not the transaction. Treu Group is the best option for representation when you’re buying a home. Having the expertise and connections of the entire Treu team on your side will not only save you money on the deal, you don’t pay us any fees! We have a few secret weapons for getting you to the closing table fast. Tune in to hear how Treu Group can help you!
</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real,Estate,Palm,Beach,Market,Sale,Lisa,Treu,Group,Tips,Tricks,South,Florida,agents,educational,informative,housing,house,short,talk,show,radio,martin,county</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Buying a Home and Making a Difference</title>
        <link>http://treugroupsouthflorida.com/buying-home-and-making-difference.html</link>
        
          <category>Buying a Home</category>
        
        <author>The Treu Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-07 13:08:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

It turns out that the FHA will no longer implement a reduction in fees. Because of this change, there are some things you should know about buying a home in 2017.

If the FHA fee reduction had gone through, it would have saved the average FHA buyer $500 to $600 a year. That means the loss of that reduction won’t impact your ability to buy a home.

Also, Realtor.com reported that in December 2016, the number of people looking at properties increased from 40% to 80% compared to December 2015.

Many buyers are trying to purchase a new property before interest rates rise, which is smart as increased interest rates would greatly impact buying power. That’s why if you’re looking to buy, you need to hire the right agent to ensure a quick and successful home purchase.

“YOU CAN STILL BUY A HOME WITHOUT THE REDUCTION IN FHA FEES.”

I’d also like to talk to you about how $20 can have a huge impact on our community. The Treu Group is doing a diaper drive to help assist the one out of every three families who are struggling to buy diapers. Many members of those low-income families would like to go back to work, but children are not allowed to go attend daycare without diapers.

Our diaper drive will be taking place in three different locations: Lighthouse Cove Adventure Golf in Jupiter, iHeart Media in West Palm Beach, and the Treu Group Real Estate office in Del Ray Beach.

If none of those are convenient, we can come pick up your donation or even buy the diapers for you if you prefer to make a monetary donation.

If you’re looking to buy or sell a home or if you would like more information on our diaper drive, please feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I would be more than happy to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treugroupsouthflorida.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

It turns out that the FHA will no longer implement a reduction in fees. Because of this change, there are some things you should know about buying a home in 2017.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Treu Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

It turns out that the FHA will no longer implement a reduction in fees. Because of this change, there are some things you should know about buying a home in 2017.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real,Estate,Palm,Beach,Market,Sale,Lisa,Treu,Group,Tips,Tricks,South,Florida,agents,educational,informative,housing,house,short,talk,show,radio,martin,county</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Palm Beach County stats to start 2017</title>
        <link>http://treugroupsouthflorida.com/palm-beach-county-stats-to-start-2017.html</link>
        
          <category>WJNO Radio show</category>
        
        <author>The Treu Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-30 17:13:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/+Radio+Show/Palm+Beach+County+stats+to+start+2017.mp3</guid>
        <description>
What’s happening in local real estate? The stats are out, and Lisa Treu will let you know what this data means for real estate in Palm Beach County.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/+Radio+Show/Palm+Beach+County+stats+to+start+2017.mp3" length="" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treugroupsouthflorida.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/+Radio+Show/Palm+Beach+County+stats+to+start+2017.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
What’s happening in local real estate? The stats are out, and Lisa Treu will let you know what this data means for real estate in Palm Beach County.
</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Treu Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
What’s happening in local real estate? The stats are out, and Lisa Treu will let you know what this data means for real estate in Palm Beach County.
</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real,Estate,Palm,Beach,Market,Sale,Lisa,Treu,Group,Tips,Tricks,South,Florida,agents,educational,informative,housing,house,short,talk,show,radio,martin,county</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Getting real with Palm Beach County Real Estate</title>
        <link>http://treugroupsouthflorida.com/getting-real-with-palm-beach-county.html</link>
        
          <category>WJNO Radio show</category>
        
        <author>The Treu Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-30 17:09:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/+Radio+Show/Getting+real+with+Palm+Beach+County+Real-Estate+Mixdown+1.mp3</guid>
        <description>
Sell or stay? Will 2017 be your year to by or sell? What’s new in the real estate market for the new year?
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/+Radio+Show/Getting+real+with+Palm+Beach+County+Real-Estate+Mixdown+1.mp3" length="" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treugroupsouthflorida.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/+Radio+Show/Getting+real+with+Palm+Beach+County+Real-Estate+Mixdown+1.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
Sell or stay? Will 2017 be your year to by or sell? What’s new in the real estate market for the new year?
</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Treu Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
Sell or stay? Will 2017 be your year to by or sell? What’s new in the real estate market for the new year?
</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real,Estate,Palm,Beach,Market,Sale,Lisa,Treu,Group,Tips,Tricks,South,Florida,agents,educational,informative,housing,house,short,talk,show,radio,martin,county</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Selling Your Home During Major Life Changes</title>
        <link>http://treugroupsouthflorida.com/selling-your-home-during-major-life.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>The Treu Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-12 11:02:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>WHICH OPTION WORKS BEST FOR YOU?</guid>
        <description>

A major life change can definitely impact your real estate transaction. When people face trying times, they tend to make mistakes during their real estate transaction. We’re only human after all. Today, I’ll go over a few common mistakes for you to avoid.

First of all, if you suddenly lose your job but can afford to keep your home, don’t put it on the market right away. See if you can get a new job in the same area before you sell. If you can’t make your mortgage payments without your job, call us right away.

Another stressful life event that can impact your transaction is a divorce. You need to deal with what makes sense. Should you offer a buyout? Should you agree to sell the home? Which option is the best one for you?

“”

When people get divorced, they are dealing with a loss of the future. They are thinking about all of the dreams that they planned as a couple and watching them disappear. People try to hold onto that future and make emotional decisions, such as paying too much to retain the home. Sometimes, it makes sense to sell the home and get a new start.

The third major life event that can be challenging is when you lose a loved one. The biggest mistake I see is that people either sell too quickly or hold on too long. I believe that there is a natural period where you need to have your time to grieve. Don’t do anything now.

My team and I are here to help you so that you can make the right decisions for your situation. There is no one-size-fits-all solution. We are here to help you come up with the right plan, so if you find yourself in a stressful situation, give us a call. We would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="WHICH OPTION WORKS BEST FOR YOU?" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treugroupsouthflorida.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="WHICH OPTION WORKS BEST FOR YOU?" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

A major life change can definitely impact your real estate transaction. When people face trying times, they tend to make mistakes during their real estate transaction. We’re only human after all. Today, I’ll go over a few common mistakes for you to avoid.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Treu Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

A major life change can definitely impact your real estate transaction. When people face trying times, they tend to make mistakes during their real estate transaction. We’re only human after all. Today, I’ll go over a few common mistakes for you to avoid.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real,Estate,Palm,Beach,Market,Sale,Lisa,Treu,Group,Tips,Tricks,South,Florida,agents,educational,informative,housing,house,short,talk,show,radio,martin,county</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Will You Take Advantage of the 2017 Palm Beach Market?</title>
        <link>http://treugroupsouthflorida.com/will-you-take-advantage-of-2017-palm.html</link>
        
          <category>2017 Real Estate Market</category>
        
        <author>The Treu Group</author>
        <pubDate>2016-12-30 16:03:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Three groups will have big opportunities in the 2017 Palm Beach real estate market. Today I’ll explain how the groups stand to benefit from market conditions.

We believe there’s always a great opportunity to be had in the real estate market, and you just have to position yourself to take advantage of it. That’s why today, I wanted to talk a bit about some of the great opportunities that will be available in the Palm Beach market in 2017.

The first opportunity lies with people currently renting homes. As a renter, your rent payment goes up when your landlord’s costs go up. By buying a house in 2017, you can lock in two things: your interest rate and your property taxes. If you rent, it’s time to get off the fence and into your new home.

Move-up buyers also have big opportunities in 2017. Many homeowners have a home in a seller’s market price range, giving them the perfect chance to move up into their dream home. If you own a house under $400,000, it’s likely the best time for you to take advantage of the record-low rates and the cooling luxury market. You would be selling in a seller’s market and likely moving up to a buyer’s market.

“IF YOU RENT, IT’S TIME TO GET OFF THE FENCE AND INTO YOUR NEW HOME.”

Finally, the third big opportunity is for those of you looking to buy real estate as an investment to have tenants and positive cash flow.

If you have any questions about how you can take advantage of the market in 2017, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We would love to help you.

Finally, if you take a look in the video above, you’ll see that I’m in an iconic part of Palm Beach. Do you know where I am? Send your guess and you might just win a prize! All you have to do is reply to this email with your guess.

I hope to hear from you soon!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treugroupsouthflorida.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Three groups will have big opportunities in the 2017 Palm Beach real estate market. Today I’ll explain how the groups stand to benefit from market conditions.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Treu Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Three groups will have big opportunities in the 2017 Palm Beach real estate market. Today I’ll explain how the groups stand to benefit from market conditions.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real,Estate,Palm,Beach,Market,Sale,Lisa,Treu,Group,Tips,Tricks,South,Florida,agents,educational,informative,housing,house,short,talk,show,radio,martin,county</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Get the Best Mortgage Rates Right Away</title>
        <link>http://treugroupsouthflorida.com/how-to-get-best-mortgage-rates-right.html</link>
        
          <category>WJNO Radio show</category>
        
        <author>The Treu Group</author>
        <pubDate>2016-12-22 15:57:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/Radio+Show+2016/How+to+get+the+best+mortgage+rates+right+now+Mixdown+1.mp3</guid>
        <description>
Let’s talk mortgage rates! What could increasing rates mean for the buying or selling of your home? Mortgage expert, Eric Cantele, from American Academy Mortgage give his take on today’s and tomorrow’s mortgage rates. December is a great time to be on the market in South Florida, listen to what you should know before listing!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/Radio+Show+2016/How+to+get+the+best+mortgage+rates+right+now+Mixdown+1.mp3" length="" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treugroupsouthflorida.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/Radio+Show+2016/How+to+get+the+best+mortgage+rates+right+now+Mixdown+1.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
Let’s talk mortgage rates! What could increasing rates mean for the buying or selling of your home? Mortgage expert, Eric Cantele, from American Academy Mortgage give his take on today’s and tomorrow’s mortgage rates. December is a great time to be on the market in South Florida, listen to what you should know before listing!
</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Treu Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
Let’s talk mortgage rates! What could increasing rates mean for the buying or selling of your home? Mortgage expert, Eric Cantele, from American Academy Mortgage give his take on today’s and tomorrow’s mortgage rates. December is a great time to be on the market in South Florida, listen to what you should know before listing!
</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real,Estate,Palm,Beach,Market,Sale,Lisa,Treu,Group,Tips,Tricks,South,Florida,agents,educational,informative,housing,house,short,talk,show,radio,martin,county</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Is the International Market Affecting South Florida Real Estate?</title>
        <link>http://treugroupsouthflorida.com/how-is-international-market-affecting.html</link>
        
          <category>market update</category>
        
        <author>The Treu Group</author>
        <pubDate>2016-12-05 12:05:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>WE KNOW HOW TO MARKET YOUR PROPERTY TO INTERNATIONAL BUYERS.</guid>
        <description>

South Florida is a destination spot for many international homebuyers, but which two countries will affect the real estate market the most?

The biggest impact will come from our neighbors to the east, China. China is planning on investing $21 billion outside of their country over the next few years, and a decent amount of that will be poured into the South Florida market. Not only is South Florida attractive for its stability and opportunity, but our rental market is incredibly strong, making the area very attractive to Chinese buyers.

Canada will be the other country impacting our market trends. Over the past few years, Canadians have been a huge influence on the South Florida real estate market. However, we currently have a currency issue. Because the U.S. dollar is so strong right now, Canadians have to pay 25% more to make the same purchase they would have made a few years ago.

“”

It’s very important that South Florida home sellers are in the know when it comes to the international market. We make sure our clients’ properties are put right in front of international buyers by using our customized marketing approach. We know who the buyers are, where they are located, and how to get your property in front of them.

We are also introducing a new game called “Where’s Lisa?” I will be at different locations in South Florida in our videos, and the first person to guess where I am wins a prize. Simply reply to this email with your answer, or go to our Facebook or Twitter page with your answer followed by #TreuGroupContest. Here are your hints:


  Behind me is the Intercoastal waterway.
  From this location you can get onto something and go see beautiful homes with holiday lights.
  It’s perfect for people of all ages.


If you think you know where I am, don’t forget to reply to this email or go to our Facebook or Twitter page with your answer followed by #TreuGroupContest. In the meantime, if you have any other questions feel free to give us a call or send us an email!
</description>
        <enclosure url="WE KNOW HOW TO MARKET YOUR PROPERTY TO INTERNATIONAL BUYERS." length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treugroupsouthflorida.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="WE KNOW HOW TO MARKET YOUR PROPERTY TO INTERNATIONAL BUYERS." type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

South Florida is a destination spot for many international homebuyers, but which two countries will affect the real estate market the most?

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Treu Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

South Florida is a destination spot for many international homebuyers, but which two countries will affect the real estate market the most?

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real,Estate,Palm,Beach,Market,Sale,Lisa,Treu,Group,Tips,Tricks,South,Florida,agents,educational,informative,housing,house,short,talk,show,radio,martin,county</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Homes For The Holidays - Changing Rates & Real Estate</title>
        <link>http://treugroupsouthflorida.com/homes-for-holidays-changing-rates-real.html</link>
        
          <category>Radio Show</category>
        
        <author>The Treu Group</author>
        <pubDate>2016-11-29 10:05:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/Radio+Show+2016/Homes+for+the+holidays+-+Changing+rates+%26+real-estate+Mixdown+1+(1).mp3</guid>
        <description>
Everything you need to know about buying a home during the holiday season. Listen to what Lisa has to say about current interest rates and how this will impact the purchase or sale of your home. Let Treu Group Real Estate bring you home for the holidays!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/Radio+Show+2016/Homes+for+the+holidays+-+Changing+rates+%26+real-estate+Mixdown+1+(1).mp3" length="" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treugroupsouthflorida.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/Radio+Show+2016/Homes+for+the+holidays+-+Changing+rates+%26+real-estate+Mixdown+1+(1).mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
Everything you need to know about buying a home during the holiday season. Listen to what Lisa has to say about current interest rates and how this will impact the purchase or sale of your home. Let Treu Group Real Estate bring you home for the holidays!
</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Treu Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
Everything you need to know about buying a home during the holiday season. Listen to what Lisa has to say about current interest rates and how this will impact the purchase or sale of your home. Let Treu Group Real Estate bring you home for the holidays!
</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real,Estate,Palm,Beach,Market,Sale,Lisa,Treu,Group,Tips,Tricks,South,Florida,agents,educational,informative,housing,house,short,talk,show,radio,martin,county</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Treu Tips to Save Money on Your Home</title>
        <link>http://treugroupsouthflorida.com/treu-tips-to-save-money-on-your-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Treu Group Tips</category>
        
        <author>The Treu Group</author>
        <pubDate>2016-11-16 13:38:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/Radio+Show+2016/Palm+Beach+Real+Estate+Agent+Treu+Tips+to+Save+Money+on+Your+Home.mp3</guid>
        <description>
Looking at the principal you owe on your home can be incredibly daunting, but there are some steps you can take to lower the amount. Even if you are just at the point of looking into buying, there are some things you should consider when it comes to what type of mortgage to get. Listen to hear our podcast on saving money and making smart financial decisions in the world of real estate.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/Radio+Show+2016/Palm+Beach+Real+Estate+Agent+Treu+Tips+to+Save+Money+on+Your+Home.mp3" length="" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treugroupsouthflorida.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/Radio+Show+2016/Palm+Beach+Real+Estate+Agent+Treu+Tips+to+Save+Money+on+Your+Home.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
Looking at the principal you owe on your home can be incredibly daunting, but there are some steps you can take to lower the amount. Even if you are just at the point of looking into buying, there are some things you should consider when it comes to what type of mortgage to get. Listen to hear our podcast on saving money and making smart financial decisions in the world of real estate.
</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Treu Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
Looking at the principal you owe on your home can be incredibly daunting, but there are some steps you can take to lower the amount. Even if you are just at the point of looking into buying, there are some things you should consider when it comes to what type of mortgage to get. Listen to hear our podcast on saving money and making smart financial decisions in the world of real estate.
</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real,Estate,Palm,Beach,Market,Sale,Lisa,Treu,Group,Tips,Tricks,South,Florida,agents,educational,informative,housing,house,short,talk,show,radio,martin,county</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3 Great Opportunities in Palm Beach Real Estate </title>
        <link>http://treugroupsouthflorida.com/3-great-opportunities-in-palm-beach.html</link>
        
          <category>market update</category>
        
        <author>The Treu Group</author>
        <pubDate>2016-11-03 09:26:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

The current Palm Beach real estate market has three amazing opportunities for buyers, sellers, and investors. I will go over each of them today.

There are opportunities all around us, and today, I want to share the three biggest opportunities available in the current Palm Beach real estate market.


  
    For the move-up buyers: If you have a home in the $300,000 to $400,000 price range, now is the time for you to move up into that dream home. You have the unique opportunity to sell your home at top dollar and then move up into a less competitive price range. Not only will you have more homes to choose from, you may also get a better deal!
  
  
    For the investors: I have a list of really great deals. Many of these happen to be foreclosure properties. These properties range from $200,000 all the way up to the luxury market, so there is truly a deal for everyone. To help make it easier for you, we are starting a VIP Investor Program that our clients can use free of charge. To sign up, click here.
  


“NOW IS A GREAT TIME TO SELL FOR TOP DOLLAR AND MOVE UP INTO A LESS COMPETITIVE MARKET.”


  For the sellers: If you have a home to sell and your home is priced at or below $500,000, you can get multiple offers on your home and sell for over asking price. We have also been negotiating great terms for sellers in this price range. You can get post-occupancy agreements and a lot of other perks that you couldn’t get under other market conditions.


No matter which opportunity you choose, we always want to help you get that competitive advantage in the real estate market. If you have any questions about buying, selling, or investing in a home, just give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treugroupsouthflorida.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

The current Palm Beach real estate market has three amazing opportunities for buyers, sellers, and investors. I will go over each of them today.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Treu Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

The current Palm Beach real estate market has three amazing opportunities for buyers, sellers, and investors. I will go over each of them today.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real,Estate,Palm,Beach,Market,Sale,Lisa,Treu,Group,Tips,Tricks,South,Florida,agents,educational,informative,housing,house,short,talk,show,radio,martin,county</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Latest Real Estate Update</title>
        <link>http://treugroupsouthflorida.com/latest-real-estate-update.html</link>
        
        <author>The Treu Group</author>
        <pubDate>2016-10-31 15:58:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/Palm+Beach+County+Real+Estate+Agent+-+Latest+Real+Estate+Update.mp3</guid>
        <description>
Home values are on the rise! Everything you need to know about buying or selling a home in Palm Beach County. Home values are rising which could be both good or bad news. Tune in to get the latest updates on home appreciation, renting vs. buying, and property tax.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/Palm+Beach+County+Real+Estate+Agent+-+Latest+Real+Estate+Update.mp3" length="" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treugroupsouthflorida.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/Palm+Beach+County+Real+Estate+Agent+-+Latest+Real+Estate+Update.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
Home values are on the rise! Everything you need to know about buying or selling a home in Palm Beach County. Home values are rising which could be both good or bad news. Tune in to get the latest updates on home appreciation, renting vs. buying, and property tax.
</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Treu Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
Home values are on the rise! Everything you need to know about buying or selling a home in Palm Beach County. Home values are rising which could be both good or bad news. Tune in to get the latest updates on home appreciation, renting vs. buying, and property tax.
</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real,Estate,Palm,Beach,Market,Sale,Lisa,Treu,Group,Tips,Tricks,South,Florida,agents,educational,informative,housing,house,short,talk,show,radio,martin,county</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Financing Tips</title>
        <link>http://treugroupsouthflorida.com/financing-tips.html</link>
        
          <category>WJNO Radio show</category>
        
        <author>The Treu Group</author>
        <pubDate>2016-10-14 15:03:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/Palm+Beach+County+Real+Estate+Agent-+Financing+Tips.mp3</guid>
        <description>
Learn how you can increase your chance of getting your dream with the right lender. Understanding the mortgage timeline is critical especially as we are heading into the end of the year. There is still time to close by the Holiday season or the end of the year to qualify for the homestead exemption.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/Palm+Beach+County+Real+Estate+Agent-+Financing+Tips.mp3" length="" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treugroupsouthflorida.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/Palm+Beach+County+Real+Estate+Agent-+Financing+Tips.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
Learn how you can increase your chance of getting your dream with the right lender. Understanding the mortgage timeline is critical especially as we are heading into the end of the year. There is still time to close by the Holiday season or the end of the year to qualify for the homestead exemption.
</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Treu Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
Learn how you can increase your chance of getting your dream with the right lender. Understanding the mortgage timeline is critical especially as we are heading into the end of the year. There is still time to close by the Holiday season or the end of the year to qualify for the homestead exemption.
</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real,Estate,Palm,Beach,Market,Sale,Lisa,Treu,Group,Tips,Tricks,South,Florida,agents,educational,informative,housing,house,short,talk,show,radio,martin,county</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Saving Thousands of Dollars on Property Taxes</title>
        <link>http://treugroupsouthflorida.com/saving-thousands-of-dollars-on-property.html</link>
        
          <category>Treu Group Real Esate</category>
        
        <author>The Treu Group</author>
        <pubDate>2016-10-12 11:05:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Since market values have gone up 9.5% on our taxes for homes
in the past year, you need to know how to budget for your tax amount.

Property taxes are an important part of our budgets when we’re buying a new property or looking at how a property cash flows. This past year, our market values went up 9.5% on our proposed taxes for our homes. What does that mean?

If your property was homesteaded, it likely means absolutely nothing. For example, for my primary home, the market value actually went up $125,000, and yet, my assessed value only went up $2,000. If you own an investment property or a commercial property, however, you don’t have that benefit. You may be a little shocked this year when you get your tax bill, but you can make that payment in November.

The other person who might be a little shocked this year is the one who purchased a home last year, especially if that home had the “save the home” benefit. You may have budgeted for a lower tax amount or had a lower tax amount in your escrow account, and now you’re having to make up for last year, plus your lender will adjust your escrow account for next year.

“IT’S NOT IMPORTANT WHAT THE TAXES ARE TODAY, BUT WHAT THEY’LL BE IN THE LONG TERM.”

We’re getting a lot of calls from buyers and sellers who are confused about taxes, especially those who’ve just made their purchase. If this includes you, here’s my advice:

If you already own a home and it’s not homesteaded, and it’s now a financial challenge for you, give us a call and let’s look through your options. Maybe that property that did create cash flow is no longer the right option.


  
    If you just purchased a new home, make sure you file for homestead exemption. That will save you thousands of dollars in the future, plus provide other benefits.
  
  
    If you’re in the home buying process, it’s not important what the taxes are today; focus on what they’ll be in the long term. What you need to do is look at the current owner’s market value versus the assessed value. If there is a differential, your taxes will likely go up in the future. That’s OK as long as you budget accordingly.
  


This is important to remember if you know your escrow account might be a little short. You can set that money aside and you won’t be as surprised next year when you receive a higher tax bill.

So, go ahead and file for the homestead if you can. If you sold a home in Florida and purchased another home in Florida this year, you have another benefit called “portability.” That means you take some of your benefits of that previous home—the tax savings—and bring it to your new home.

If you’re interested in learning more about property taxes and homestead exemption in Florida, click here. If you have any more questions about property taxes, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treugroupsouthflorida.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Since market values have gone up 9.5% on our taxes for homes
in the past year, you need to know how to budget for your tax amount.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Treu Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Since market values have gone up 9.5% on our taxes for homes
in the past year, you need to know how to budget for your tax amount.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real,Estate,Palm,Beach,Market,Sale,Lisa,Treu,Group,Tips,Tricks,South,Florida,agents,educational,informative,housing,house,short,talk,show,radio,martin,county</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Latest Real Estate Market Update</title>
        <link>http://treugroupsouthflorida.com/latest-real-estate-market-update.html</link>
        
          <category>WJNO Radio show</category>
        
        <author>The Treu Group</author>
        <pubDate>2016-10-05 12:38:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/Palm+Beach+County+Real+Estate+Agent+-+Latest+Real+Estate+Market+Update.mp3</guid>
        <description>
The latest real estate update with the latest statistics including the hot and cool areas in Palm Beach County.  Listen to learn the strategies and best opportunities to position yourself to win when buying or selling real estate.  If you are a move up buyer now may be your time to shine. Homes in the luxury market are having a harder time selling, and that is why you need the right price and the right marketing! We are also noticing some neighborhoods are in finally in recovery, and there are less distress sales. This is important to those who are thinking of selling their home in the near future. With fewer short sales and foreclosures many sellers are no longer underwater.  Please check us out at treugroup.com for real time updates on homes for sale in your area.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/Palm+Beach+County+Real+Estate+Agent+-+Latest+Real+Estate+Market+Update.mp3" length="" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treugroupsouthflorida.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/Palm+Beach+County+Real+Estate+Agent+-+Latest+Real+Estate+Market+Update.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
The latest real estate update with the latest statistics including the hot and cool areas in Palm Beach County.  Listen to learn the strategies and best opportunities to position yourself to win when buying or selling real estate.  If you are a move up buyer now may be your time to shine. Homes in the luxury market are having a harder time selling, and that is why you need the right price and the right marketing! We are also noticing some neighborhoods are in finally in recovery, and there are less distress sales. This is important to those who are thinking of selling their home in the near future. With fewer short sales and foreclosures many sellers are no longer underwater.  Please check us out at treugroup.com for real time updates on homes for sale in your area.
</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Treu Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
The latest real estate update with the latest statistics including the hot and cool areas in Palm Beach County.  Listen to learn the strategies and best opportunities to position yourself to win when buying or selling real estate.  If you are a move up buyer now may be your time to shine. Homes in the luxury market are having a harder time selling, and that is why you need the right price and the right marketing! We are also noticing some neighborhoods are in finally in recovery, and there are less distress sales. This is important to those who are thinking of selling their home in the near future. With fewer short sales and foreclosures many sellers are no longer underwater.  Please check us out at treugroup.com for real time updates on homes for sale in your area.
</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real,Estate,Palm,Beach,Market,Sale,Lisa,Treu,Group,Tips,Tricks,South,Florida,agents,educational,informative,housing,house,short,talk,show,radio,martin,county</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The 4 Valuable Lessons I Learned in Greece</title>
        <link>http://treugroupsouthflorida.com/the-4-valuable-lessons-i-learned-in.html</link>
        
          <category>The Treu Group</category>
        
          <category>Palm Beach County Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>The Treu Group</author>
        <pubDate>2016-09-27 11:51:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today I wanted to switch things up a bit and share with you the four lessons that I learned while on vacation in Greece. There are lessons all around us everywhere we go.

The first is to be open-minded. One thing I was really concerned about was the cuisine because I wasn’t sure if I’d like it. I didn’t like Greek yogurt, but what I discovered was that I just had never had great Greek yogurt. In Greece, we enjoyed fresh Greek yogurt every morning, and it was delicious! Imagine if I had been unwilling to try something new— I would have missed out on discovering one of my new favorite things.

The second thing I learned was to be willing to try something new. We also rented scooters and ATVs in Greece, which scared me a bit because we weren’t familiar with the area, and honestly, they drive a little bit crazy over there. We decided to try something new, though, and we got to see parts of Greece that we would never have gotten to see if we hadn’t been willing to just give it a try.

“ALWAYS BE WILLING TO TRY SOMETHING NEW.”

Another thing I learned was to treat everything like an adventure. Even something like getting lost can be fun. Look at life that way— what are you doing in the moment, and how can you make it fun and exciting instead of just looking at what’s wrong.

Finally, the fourth thing I learned was to set big goals and allow yourself to dream bigger. My husband and I were celebrating our 30th wedding anniversary, and we thought back to our honeymoon. It was very different than this trip; it was a very short weekend trip, which we thought was wonderful at the time. Because we’ve allowed ourselves to think big and dream big, we were able to take this amazing trip.

I hope you’ll take these four lessons I’ve learned and give them a try to create something amazing for yourself. If you have any questions for me, please don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I’d love to keep this conversation going!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treugroupsouthflorida.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today I wanted to switch things up a bit and share with you the four lessons that I learned while on vacation in Greece. There are lessons all around us everywhere we go.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Treu Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today I wanted to switch things up a bit and share with you the four lessons that I learned while on vacation in Greece. There are lessons all around us everywhere we go.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real,Estate,Palm,Beach,Market,Sale,Lisa,Treu,Group,Tips,Tricks,South,Florida,agents,educational,informative,housing,house,short,talk,show,radio,martin,county</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Property Taxes and Your Palm Beach County Home</title>
        <link>http://treugroupsouthflorida.com/property-taxes-and-your-palm-beach.html</link>
        
          <category>WJNO Radio show</category>
        
        <author>The Treu Group</author>
        <pubDate>2016-09-20 11:51:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>
Palm Beach County proposed property tax notices are out. The question we get most is: will my taxes go up?  It really depends on where you live. Lisa Treu and Brian Mudd welcome in this episode the Appraiser Gary Nikolits to discuss property taxes and how property owners may be impacted by the latest changes and updates.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treugroupsouthflorida.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
Palm Beach County proposed property tax notices are out. The question we get most is: will my taxes go up?  It really depends on where you live. Lisa Treu and Brian Mudd welcome in this episode the Appraiser Gary Nikolits to discuss property taxes and how property owners may be impacted by the latest changes and updates.
</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Treu Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
Palm Beach County proposed property tax notices are out. The question we get most is: will my taxes go up?  It really depends on where you live. Lisa Treu and Brian Mudd welcome in this episode the Appraiser Gary Nikolits to discuss property taxes and how property owners may be impacted by the latest changes and updates.
</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real,Estate,Palm,Beach,Market,Sale,Lisa,Treu,Group,Tips,Tricks,South,Florida,agents,educational,informative,housing,house,short,talk,show,radio,martin,county</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Tips on Preparing to Buy a New Home and Opportunities in a New Market</title>
        <link>http://treugroupsouthflorida.com/tips-on-preparing-to-buy-new-home-and.html</link>
        
          <category>WJNO Radio show</category>
        
        <author>The Treu Group</author>
        <pubDate>2016-09-16 10:08:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/Palm+Beach+County+Real+Estate+-+Tips+on+Preparing+to+Buy+a+New+Home+and+Opportunities+in+a+New+Market.mp3</guid>
        <description>
In this ever changing market you need to pay close attention to tips on how to make buying a home easier for you. Lenders look closely at credit history, scores and work history. Now is the time where there are opportunities in the luxury market for move up buyers. Investors are now looking to buy for long term. More people are now buying for cash flow, and making the market more competitive.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/Palm+Beach+County+Real+Estate+-+Tips+on+Preparing+to+Buy+a+New+Home+and+Opportunities+in+a+New+Market.mp3" length="" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treugroupsouthflorida.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/Palm+Beach+County+Real+Estate+-+Tips+on+Preparing+to+Buy+a+New+Home+and+Opportunities+in+a+New+Market.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
In this ever changing market you need to pay close attention to tips on how to make buying a home easier for you. Lenders look closely at credit history, scores and work history. Now is the time where there are opportunities in the luxury market for move up buyers. Investors are now looking to buy for long term. More people are now buying for cash flow, and making the market more competitive.
</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Treu Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
In this ever changing market you need to pay close attention to tips on how to make buying a home easier for you. Lenders look closely at credit history, scores and work history. Now is the time where there are opportunities in the luxury market for move up buyers. Investors are now looking to buy for long term. More people are now buying for cash flow, and making the market more competitive.
</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real,Estate,Palm,Beach,Market,Sale,Lisa,Treu,Group,Tips,Tricks,South,Florida,agents,educational,informative,housing,house,short,talk,show,radio,martin,county</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>See My Latest Endorsement from Real Estate Guru Barbara Corcoran</title>
        <link>http://treugroupsouthflorida.com/see-my-latest-endorsement-from-real.html</link>
        
          <category>endorsement</category>
        
        <author>The Treu Group</author>
        <pubDate>2016-08-16 11:18:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

I’m proud to serve the Palm Beach County real estate market and call it home. I’m also very proud to be the only agent in Palm Beach County with the endorsement of Barbara Corcoran. You may have seen Barbara on ABC’s hit show “Shark Tank,” where she has invested her own money into more than 20 businesses and shepherded them to success.

Barbara is one of the most renowned names in all of real estate, which is why I’m proud to share her my latest TV commercial with you. Barbara is big believer in the Treu Group Guaranteed Sale Program and I’m happy to have her on my side!

Won’t you take 30 seconds and check out my latest TV commercial, featuring Barbara Corcoran?

Thank you again for your time. If you have any questions at all about our Guaranteed Sale Program, please feel free to call or email us today!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treugroupsouthflorida.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

I’m proud to serve the Palm Beach County real estate market and call it home. I’m also very proud to be the only agent in Palm Beach County with the endorsement of Barbara Corcoran. You may have seen Barbara on ABC’s hit show “Shark Tank,” where she has invested her own money into more than 20 businesses and shepherded them to success.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Treu Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

I’m proud to serve the Palm Beach County real estate market and call it home. I’m also very proud to be the only agent in Palm Beach County with the endorsement of Barbara Corcoran. You may have seen Barbara on ABC’s hit show “Shark Tank,” where she has invested her own money into more than 20 businesses and shepherded them to success.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real,Estate,Palm,Beach,Market,Sale,Lisa,Treu,Group,Tips,Tricks,South,Florida,agents,educational,informative,housing,house,short,talk,show,radio,martin,county</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Updates in Real Estate in Palm Beach: Tips and Advice to Sell Your Home.</title>
        <link>http://treugroupsouthflorida.com/updates-in-real-estate-in-palm-beach.html</link>
        
          <category>Treu Group Real Esate</category>
        
          <category>WJNO Radio show</category>
        
        <author>The Treu Group</author>
        <pubDate>2016-08-05 16:53:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/Palm+Beach+County+Real+Estate+Agent+-+Updates+in+Real+Estate+in+Palm+Beach+-+Tips+and+Advice+to+Sell+Your+Home.mp3</guid>
        <description>
In this fluctuating market, traditional subdivision are selling faster and easier than luxury homes. It is really important for sellers to have the three factors right: price, condition, and marketing to reach a successful closing. It is also imperative for high-end property owners to do something especial to stand out. Having the help of an agent that knows and understand those changes in the market can make all the difference. Join Lisa Treu and Brian Mudd while they share the most reliable market analysis and the best advice to get your home sold fast and for the most money.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/Palm+Beach+County+Real+Estate+Agent+-+Updates+in+Real+Estate+in+Palm+Beach+-+Tips+and+Advice+to+Sell+Your+Home.mp3" length="" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treugroupsouthflorida.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/Palm+Beach+County+Real+Estate+Agent+-+Updates+in+Real+Estate+in+Palm+Beach+-+Tips+and+Advice+to+Sell+Your+Home.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
In this fluctuating market, traditional subdivision are selling faster and easier than luxury homes. It is really important for sellers to have the three factors right: price, condition, and marketing to reach a successful closing. It is also imperative for high-end property owners to do something especial to stand out. Having the help of an agent that knows and understand those changes in the market can make all the difference. Join Lisa Treu and Brian Mudd while they share the most reliable market analysis and the best advice to get your home sold fast and for the most money.
</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Treu Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
In this fluctuating market, traditional subdivision are selling faster and easier than luxury homes. It is really important for sellers to have the three factors right: price, condition, and marketing to reach a successful closing. It is also imperative for high-end property owners to do something especial to stand out. Having the help of an agent that knows and understand those changes in the market can make all the difference. Join Lisa Treu and Brian Mudd while they share the most reliable market analysis and the best advice to get your home sold fast and for the most money.
</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real,Estate,Palm,Beach,Market,Sale,Lisa,Treu,Group,Tips,Tricks,South,Florida,agents,educational,informative,housing,house,short,talk,show,radio,martin,county</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Fun Things to Do in Palm Beach County</title>
        <link>http://treugroupsouthflorida.com/fun-things-to-do-in-palm-beach-county.html</link>
        
          <category>Palm Beach County</category>
        
        <author>The Treu Group</author>
        <pubDate>2016-08-03 11:23:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

People ask me all the time what my favorite things to do are in and around Palm Beach County. There is so much to do that I don’t know if I’ll be able to get to it all, but I’ll try.

One place I love to go that’s great for the whole family is Lighthouse Cove Adventure Golf. They have two 18-hole courses, which are both beautifully maintained. They are North Palm Beach County’s premiere mini-golf courses. After you’ve played a round, you can go have a burger or ice cream sundae at their fast casual restaurant inside. They do corporate events as well as children’s parties.

South Florida has no shortage of great restaurants. One of our favorites is &lt;a href=”http://www.roccostacos.com/” target=”_blank&gt;Rocco’s Tacos.&lt;/a&gt; They even have multiple locations in the area, so you’re never too far from one. They make delicious tableside guacamole. &lt;a href=”http://www.utikibeach.com/” target=”_blank&gt;U-Tiki&lt;/a&gt; is a great place too. They are right on the water, so you can arrive by car or boat.

Another great restaurant is &lt;a href=”http://www.jupiterlighthouse.org/” target=”_blank&gt;Guanabanas.&lt;/a&gt; At this place, you’ll enjoy beautiful views, outdoor dining, and great entertainment. When you’re done eating, you can head on down to their dock and hop on a paddleboard or kayak, which you can rent right there.

If history is more of your thing, check out the &lt;a href=”http://harboursideplace.com/” target=”_blank&gt;Jupiter Inlet Museum.&lt;/a&gt; It’s an amazing place, and you can even take a tour of the lighthouse.

“MANY OF OUR BEACHES ARE WORLD-FAMOUS.”

One of my favorite parts about Palm Beach County is the abundance of shopping, restaurant, and entertainment options available. &lt;a href=”” target=”_blank&gt;Harbourside&lt;/a&gt; in Jupiter, Downtown West Palm Beach, and City Place in Clematis are all great hotspots. Downtown Delray Beach is a great place, too, and has some of the most beautiful beaches around.

&lt;a href=”https://www.lioncountrysafari.com/” target=”_blank&gt;Lion Country Safari&lt;/a&gt; is Florida’s only drive-thru safari where animals roam free and humans roam in cars. It’s really a special place.

Our tour wouldn’t be complete without a trip to the beach. Many of our beaches in the area are world-famous. There are quiet beaches, touristy beaches, or pet-friendly beaches. You’ll love it.

If you have any questions for us about any of the places we’ve talked about today, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treugroupsouthflorida.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

People ask me all the time what my favorite things to do are in and around Palm Beach County. There is so much to do that I don’t know if I’ll be able to get to it all, but I’ll try.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Treu Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

People ask me all the time what my favorite things to do are in and around Palm Beach County. There is so much to do that I don’t know if I’ll be able to get to it all, but I’ll try.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real,Estate,Palm,Beach,Market,Sale,Lisa,Treu,Group,Tips,Tricks,South,Florida,agents,educational,informative,housing,house,short,talk,show,radio,martin,county</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Technology, New Trends and Real Estate: The Impact of Millennial Buyers in Real Estate</title>
        <link>http://treugroupsouthflorida.com/technology-new-trends-and-real-estate.html</link>
        
          <category>WJNO Radio show</category>
        
        <author>The Treu Group</author>
        <pubDate>2016-07-25 11:31:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/Palm+Beach+County+Real+Estate+Agent+-+Technology%2C+New+Trends+and+Real+Estate+-+The+Impact+of+Millennial+Buyers+in+Real+Estate.mp3</guid>
        <description>One of the main challenges that many real estate agents face these days is the growing demands on technology, new trends, and creative marketing. Innovation is an always-changing subject. What works today may not work tomorrow as the millennial buyers are changing the way real estate agents communicate and market properties. Pokémon Go popularity is a great example and the question that we are always asking ourselves is “How will the new craze impact real estate?”. Treu Group Real Estate is committed to having the latest technology, the best tools and a team that can create innovative ideas and adapt to the fast paced changes out there. We are always ready for whatever comes next.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/Palm+Beach+County+Real+Estate+Agent+-+Technology%2C+New+Trends+and+Real+Estate+-+The+Impact+of+Millennial+Buyers+in+Real+Estate.mp3" length="" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treugroupsouthflorida.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/Palm+Beach+County+Real+Estate+Agent+-+Technology%2C+New+Trends+and+Real+Estate+-+The+Impact+of+Millennial+Buyers+in+Real+Estate.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>One of the main challenges that many real estate agents face these days is the growing demands on technology, new trends, and creative marketing. Innovation is an always-changing subject. What works today may not work tomorrow as the millennial buyers are changing the way real estate agents communicate and market properties. Pokémon Go popularity is a great example and the question that we are always asking ourselves is “How will the new craze impact real estate?”. Treu Group Real Estate is committed to having the latest technology, the best tools and a team that can create innovative ideas and adapt to the fast paced changes out there. We are always ready for whatever comes next.
</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Treu Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>One of the main challenges that many real estate agents face these days is the growing demands on technology, new trends, and creative marketing. Innovation is an always-changing subject. What works today may not work tomorrow as the millennial buyers are changing the way real estate agents communicate and market properties. Pokémon Go popularity is a great example and the question that we are always asking ourselves is “How will the new craze impact real estate?”. Treu Group Real Estate is committed to having the latest technology, the best tools and a team that can create innovative ideas and adapt to the fast paced changes out there. We are always ready for whatever comes next.
</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real,Estate,Palm,Beach,Market,Sale,Lisa,Treu,Group,Tips,Tricks,South,Florida,agents,educational,informative,housing,house,short,talk,show,radio,martin,county</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Technology for the Home: What Upgrades May Increase the Value of Your Property?  </title>
        <link>http://treugroupsouthflorida.com/technology-for-home-what-upgrades-may.html</link>
        
          <category>WJNO Radio show</category>
        
        <author>The Treu Group</author>
        <pubDate>2016-07-12 17:05:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/Palm+Beach+County+Real+Estate+Agent+-+Technology+for+the+Home+-+What+Upgrades+May+Increase+the+Value+of+Your+Property.mp3</guid>
        <description>Technology is all around us, and in the past years has become an important part of our lives and everyday activities. The technology advances have not left behind homeowners. Every day we see more and more products and systems for homes in the market, and with mainstream usage comes accessibility. Using technological upgrades in our homes is easy, affordable and convenient. With over 350 million mobile device users in the United States alone and Millennials in charge of technology trends, smart systems and smart technology for the home is becoming part of the everyday standards for homeowners.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/Palm+Beach+County+Real+Estate+Agent+-+Technology+for+the+Home+-+What+Upgrades+May+Increase+the+Value+of+Your+Property.mp3" length="" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treugroupsouthflorida.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/Palm+Beach+County+Real+Estate+Agent+-+Technology+for+the+Home+-+What+Upgrades+May+Increase+the+Value+of+Your+Property.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Technology is all around us, and in the past years has become an important part of our lives and everyday activities. The technology advances have not left behind homeowners. Every day we see more and more products and systems for homes in the market, and with mainstream usage comes accessibility. Using technological upgrades in our homes is easy, affordable and convenient. With over 350 million mobile device users in the United States alone and Millennials in charge of technology trends, smart systems and smart technology for the home is becoming part of the everyday standards for homeowners.
</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Treu Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Technology is all around us, and in the past years has become an important part of our lives and everyday activities. The technology advances have not left behind homeowners. Every day we see more and more products and systems for homes in the market, and with mainstream usage comes accessibility. Using technological upgrades in our homes is easy, affordable and convenient. With over 350 million mobile device users in the United States alone and Millennials in charge of technology trends, smart systems and smart technology for the home is becoming part of the everyday standards for homeowners.
</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real,Estate,Palm,Beach,Market,Sale,Lisa,Treu,Group,Tips,Tricks,South,Florida,agents,educational,informative,housing,house,short,talk,show,radio,martin,county</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Ready to Get App Happy?</title>
        <link>http://treugroupsouthflorida.com/essential-apps-for-homeowners.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Owner Tips</category>
        
        <author>The Treu Group</author>
        <pubDate>2016-07-05 09:53:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Your smartphone can be a great ally to you whether you’re buying, selling, or simply owning a home. We are excited to share with you a few of our favorite “home” apps that will help you do everything from scheduling a plumber to remodeling your kitchen. Here are our favorites:


  
    Treu Group Real Estate. This is our very own free app in the app store. It has all of the local companies that we know and trust. Whether you need a good local contractor, or want a restaurant or doctor’s recommendation. We even have some of the various charities we support on there.
  
  
    Handy. Handy is an app where you can get a handyman or home cleaner to come over and do necessary work on your home. We have also given you a referral code so you can save on your first cleaning.
  
  
    Pinterest. This app isn’t just popular for brides to be and home chefs, it can also be used to update your home. There are so many great home improvement ideas on the site. In fact, we recently did an update in our kitchen and the idea came directly from Pinterest.
  
  
    iHandy level free. Who has a level anymore? Well, if you have a smartphone, you don’t need one. This app works great for hanging art or pictures up on the wall.
  
  
    Encircle. This app will allow you to document and store information about all of your valuables in case of a future insurance claim.
  
  
    Houzz interior design ideas. If you’re looking for ways to spruce up your home, this app has plenty of them.
  
  
    iScape free landscape designs. If you’re going to be doing some outdoor landscaping, before you go out and make it happen you can use this app to see what the before and after will look like. You’ll be able to get an idea of how things will look without making a commitment.
  


“THESE ARE JUST A FEW OF OUR FAVORITE APPS.”

These are just a few of our favorite apps. If you have any questions about any of them or if you’re looking to buy or sell, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treugroupsouthflorida.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Your smartphone can be a great ally to you whether you’re buying, selling, or simply owning a home. We are excited to share with you a few of our favorite “home” apps that will help you do everything from scheduling a plumber to remodeling your kitchen. Here are our favorites:

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Treu Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Your smartphone can be a great ally to you whether you’re buying, selling, or simply owning a home. We are excited to share with you a few of our favorite “home” apps that will help you do everything from scheduling a plumber to remodeling your kitchen. Here are our favorites:

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real,Estate,Palm,Beach,Market,Sale,Lisa,Treu,Group,Tips,Tricks,South,Florida,agents,educational,informative,housing,house,short,talk,show,radio,martin,county</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Tales of Two Markets: Analyzing the Latest Statistics in Our Real Estate Market. </title>
        <link>http://treugroupsouthflorida.com/how-to-win-in-palm-beach-county.html</link>
        
          <category>WJNO Radio show</category>
        
        <author>The Treu Group</author>
        <pubDate>2016-06-27 10:37:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/Palm+Beach+County+Real+Estate+-+How+to+Win+in+Palm+Beach+County.mp3</guid>
        <description>
In a market defined as a Seller’s Market we are experiencing a divided scene with separation being around the $500,000 threshold. For those selling or buying under this line the market is showing quick sales and multiple offers. For those selling with a price tag over the mentioned level, the market shows a slower panorama with fewer buyers and more inventory available and by consequence property prices are getting higher. Join Lisa Treu in this episode of the Real Estate 911 podcast where the latest data and statistics are analyzed to understand the two markets we are experiencing in the area.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/Palm+Beach+County+Real+Estate+-+How+to+Win+in+Palm+Beach+County.mp3" length="" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treugroupsouthflorida.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/Palm+Beach+County+Real+Estate+-+How+to+Win+in+Palm+Beach+County.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
In a market defined as a Seller’s Market we are experiencing a divided scene with separation being around the $500,000 threshold. For those selling or buying under this line the market is showing quick sales and multiple offers. For those selling with a price tag over the mentioned level, the market shows a slower panorama with fewer buyers and more inventory available and by consequence property prices are getting higher. Join Lisa Treu in this episode of the Real Estate 911 podcast where the latest data and statistics are analyzed to understand the two markets we are experiencing in the area.
</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Treu Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
In a market defined as a Seller’s Market we are experiencing a divided scene with separation being around the $500,000 threshold. For those selling or buying under this line the market is showing quick sales and multiple offers. For those selling with a price tag over the mentioned level, the market shows a slower panorama with fewer buyers and more inventory available and by consequence property prices are getting higher. Join Lisa Treu in this episode of the Real Estate 911 podcast where the latest data and statistics are analyzed to understand the two markets we are experiencing in the area.
</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real,Estate,Palm,Beach,Market,Sale,Lisa,Treu,Group,Tips,Tricks,South,Florida,agents,educational,informative,housing,house,short,talk,show,radio,martin,county</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Can You Still Get Financing After a Foreclosure?</title>
        <link>http://treugroupsouthflorida.com/can-you-still-get-financing-after.html</link>
        
          <category>palm beach foreclosures</category>
        
        <author>The Treu Group</author>
        <pubDate>2016-06-16 11:19:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

One of the common questions I get from my clients is how quickly can they enter back into the real estate market if they have suffered through a short sale, deed-in-lieu, foreclosure, Chapter 7 bankruptcy, or Chapter 13 bankruptcy.

You need to know a few things first. Depending on the type of loan product you used and which of the four procedures you went through, your time away from being allowed to purchase will vary.

However, most people can enter back into the market in two to seven years in order to get financing.

“NON-TRADITIONAL FINANCING MAY BE A VALID OPTION FOR YOU.”

One other option if you’re almost done with your waiting period is to use non-traditional financing. The interest rate for these loans will be a bit higher, but you can qualify one day after a foreclosure or a short sale. That way, you can get into a home, and then refinance after your waiting period is over.

Last but not least, don’t forget to check out one of our favorite restaurants in Palm Beach: Old Key Lime House. Come and enjoy the great views, amazing food, entertainment, and a nice cocktail if you’re in the mood!

If you have any questions, please don’t hesitate to contact us!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treugroupsouthflorida.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

One of the common questions I get from my clients is how quickly can they enter back into the real estate market if they have suffered through a short sale, deed-in-lieu, foreclosure, Chapter 7 bankruptcy, or Chapter 13 bankruptcy.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Treu Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

One of the common questions I get from my clients is how quickly can they enter back into the real estate market if they have suffered through a short sale, deed-in-lieu, foreclosure, Chapter 7 bankruptcy, or Chapter 13 bankruptcy.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real,Estate,Palm,Beach,Market,Sale,Lisa,Treu,Group,Tips,Tricks,South,Florida,agents,educational,informative,housing,house,short,talk,show,radio,martin,county</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Staged For Success: Importance of Home Staging and Tips to Sell Your Home for the Most Money</title>
        <link>http://treugroupsouthflorida.com/staged-for-success.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>The Treu Group</author>
        <pubDate>2016-06-10 11:17:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/Palm+Beach+County+Real+Estate+-+Staged+For+Success.mp3</guid>
        <description>
Over 95% of realtors believe that staging directly impacts your chances of getting your home sold for the most money. Accompany us while Lisa Treu shares her professional tips to increase your home’s appeal and positively influence the value of the property through staging. This Treu Real Estate 911 podcast brings you the best professional advice while coaching you about the latest trends in the Real Estate market.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/Palm+Beach+County+Real+Estate+-+Staged+For+Success.mp3" length="" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treugroupsouthflorida.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Lisa+Treu/Palm+Beach+County+Real+Estate+-+Staged+For+Success.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
Over 95% of realtors believe that staging directly impacts your chances of getting your home sold for the most money. Accompany us while Lisa Treu shares her professional tips to increase your home’s appeal and positively influence the value of the property through staging. This Treu Real Estate 911 podcast brings you the best professional advice while coaching you about the latest trends in the Real Estate market.
</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Treu Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
Over 95% of realtors believe that staging directly impacts your chances of getting your home sold for the most money. Accompany us while Lisa Treu shares her professional tips to increase your home’s appeal and positively influence the value of the property through staging. This Treu Real Estate 911 podcast brings you the best professional advice while coaching you about the latest trends in the Real Estate market.
</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real,Estate,Palm,Beach,Market,Sale,Lisa,Treu,Group,Tips,Tricks,South,Florida,agents,educational,informative,housing,house,short,talk,show,radio,martin,county</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>The Treu Group</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">The Treu Group</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">I'll update you with how to make a smart decision in real estate, improve the value of your home, and keep you up to date on what's happening in our local Palm Beach & Martin County real estate market.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
