<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>http://davefriedmancoaching.com</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://davefriedmancoaching.com"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Dave Friedman Team - your professional Charleston Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Dave Friedman</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2018-03-22 15:16:31 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Dave Friedman</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://davefriedmancoaching.com/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Charleston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">News &amp; Politics</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Dave@DaveFriedmanTeam.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Dave Friedman</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Dave Friedman</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://davefriedmancoaching.com/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Charleston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Charleston Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Dave Friedman Team - your professional Charleston Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="News &amp; Politics"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>Answering Your Questions About Zillow as a Lead Source</title>
        <link>http://davefriedmancoaching.com/answering-your-questions-about-zillow-as-a-lead-source.html</link>
        
        <author>Dave Friedman</author>
        <pubDate>2018-03-12 10:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/2018/What+Is+The+ROI+For+Zillow%253F+-+Charleston+%2526+Mt.+Pleasant+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Lately, I’ve been getting a lot of questions about  Zillow, including whether I use it to purchase leads, what kind of ROI it brings, and whether the site is worthwhile as an advertising tool at all.

Zillow is a great, user-friendly platform, but it does have some drawbacks. It doesn’t update in real time, for instance. There are a lot of listings our buyer clients might find on there that are shown as active on the site despite already actually being under contract or closed. This can cause a lot of frustration for consumers.

As for whether it’s worth it to purchase leads on Zillow, it depends on your market. I can tell you that if you visit the site’s advertising portal, it’ll actually show you the availability for each ZIP code as well as ROI projections based on how much you spend. I’ve found that these ROI calculations are pretty accurate. They have a lot of data to draw upon. According to Zillow, the average Realtor who purchases ZIP code leads through their site will see a 3% to 4% conversion rate. In other words, an agent purchasing a hundred leads would end up closing on three to four of them.

Some Zillow representatives have even claimed to see a conversion rate of up to 10%. This is fantastic, but you would really have to work your leads to see such high conversion. Having said that, the ROI Zillow estimates you will make on a specific ZIP code is based on a few different factors.  It’s based on the average price point for the area and also the assumption that you are seeing a conversion rate of 3% or 4%.In addition, it also depends on how many leads you’re purchasing and how much those leads cost.

In our area, the average ROI that is shown across local ZIP codes is usually about 2.2x to 3.5x. The more expensive the ZIP code, the higher the cost per lead is. Consumers in these more affluent areas, though, may be more careful about giving out personal information and therefore more difficult to reach. It can be easier to convert leads in ZIP codes with lower price points, but you have to convert more leads to make the same amount of money when working with lower price points as opposed to higher ones.

“The ROI you are willing to earn in your business is completely up to you.”

The ROI you are willing to earn in your business is completely up to you. It’s all relative to the lead sources you could, or already do, invest in. However, returns look much different for single agents versus teams. Let’s say an average team will pay out 50% of their commissions to an agent. If that commission check is $10,000 and the ROI is 3x. If you’re investing $3,300 into 16 Zillow leads and you’re able to convert one, that $10,000 commission check is essentially a 3x return for a single agent.

However, if a team owner invests $3,300 into 16 Zillow leads and converts one, this is a pretty high conversion. The $10,000 commission check is then split between the agent and the team owner. So the agent gets $5,000 and the team leader gets $5,000. But if you look at the true revenue, which subtracts expenses from the net total, your ROI ends up only being 1.5x. In other words, you would be spending $3,300 to be making approximately $5,000 in total. For most teams, this simply isn’t worth it.

There are a lot of lead sources out there that can bring returns as high as 30x to 40x. A source that brings you a consistent rate of return is the obvious choice. It doesn’t make sense to allocate your resources into an investment that brings smaller returns. If you do plan on investing in Zillow, make sure you negotiate with them on getting either your 10 most expensive or 10 most recent listings for free. Getting the ROI on ZIP code leads from Zillow is all about striking an equilibrium.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/2018/What+Is+The+ROI+For+Zillow%253F+-+Charleston+%2526+Mt.+Pleasant+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://davefriedmancoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/2018/What+Is+The+ROI+For+Zillow%253F+-+Charleston+%2526+Mt.+Pleasant+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Is Zillow a worthwhile lead source? Today, we will be going over a few things you need to know before investing in the site.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Friedman</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Is Zillow a worthwhile lead source? Today, we will be going over a few things you need to know before investing in the site.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Charleston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Should You Be Advertising on Realtor.com?</title>
        <link>http://davefriedmancoaching.com/should-you-be-advertising-on-realtor-com.html</link>
        
        <author>Dave Friedman</author>
        <pubDate>2018-02-14 10:17:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/2018/Should+I+Advertise+On+Realtor.com%253F+-+Charleston+%2526+Mt.+Pleasant+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

A lot of people have been asking me recently about how to advertise on Realtor.com.

There are actually two different ways to advertise on this website: Connections With Buyers and Advantage Pro. Today, I’ll start with some of the things I like and dislike about each of these options.

Let’s start with Advantage Pro. In my opinion, Advantage Pro is something every Realtor should be paying for. It’s pretty simple. You’re paying to get the leads from your listings.

The way Realtor.com charges depends on how many listings you carry, the average price point of those listings, and how many of listings you sell.These and other factors are put into an algorithm to give you the price you’ll end up paying for this service.

Think of it this way: An agent in California who is selling $2 million properties should probably be paying more for their leads than an agent in our local area selling properties at an average list price of $100,000.

For me and my market, I have an average price point of $285,000. So, I’m paying about $40 to $43 per lead through Advantage Pro. At the end of the day, I’m getting a 4.5x return on my investment. When you buy an Advantage Pro lead, you are the only agent who has access to that lead.

These Realtor.com leads also often convert a lot faster than leads you get from other sources.

The other way to invest in Realtor.com is by using Connections With Buyers, which is where you are purchasing ZIP code leads. There are two ways to use this.

“Advantage Pro is something every Realtor should be paying for.”

You can either purchase a lead and be the only agent who receives that specific lead, or you can share the lead with another Realtor. In the latter option, you and another Realtor, chosen at random, have an equal opportunity to capture the lead. It all comes down to who is able to reach out more quickly. Splitting leads as opposed to having sole access actually makes the investment more cost-effective.

If you’re really good at lead conversion and have a quick response time, there’s no reason you shouldn’t be splitting leads when using this service. In fact, the ROI on these leads is higher when you split them. When you split these leads, the ROI can be between 3.5x or 4x your investment. If you aren’t splitting them, the ROI on those leads is about 2.5x your investment.

I personally don’t invest in Connections With Buyers anymore, though. In my opinion, it just isn’t worth it.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.

</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/2018/Should+I+Advertise+On+Realtor.com%253F+-+Charleston+%2526+Mt.+Pleasant+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://davefriedmancoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/2018/Should+I+Advertise+On+Realtor.com%253F+-+Charleston+%2526+Mt.+Pleasant+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>People have been asking me lately about ways agents can invest in Realtor.com. Today, I will share the two options you have.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Friedman</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>People have been asking me lately about ways agents can invest in Realtor.com. Today, I will share the two options you have.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Charleston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Realtor’s Guide to the Industry: How to Get Online Reviews</title>
        <link>http://davefriedmancoaching.com/a-realtors-guide-to-the-industry-how-to-get-online-reviews.html</link>
        
        <author>Dave Friedman</author>
        <pubDate>2018-01-29 05:05:09 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

How can you get online reviews from mainstream websites such as Zillow, Realtor.com, Google, and others that potential buyers and sellers are likely to use?

First of all, Realtor.com doesn’t have any client testimonials. Homes.com, on the other hand, allows you to copy testimonials you may have from other websites and place them on their site. Sites like Zillow require the client to put a review into their systems. They have validation techniques to make sure that people aren’t fabricating reviews.

You can take advantage of the closing process to get reviews from clients. Have your Zillow or Google profile pulled up while you’re at the closing table and, in the middle of your conversation about their experience, simply ask your clients to leave a review for you.

On our team, we like to hold review contests. These are best done on a quarterly basis, and usually result in a flurry of reviews. You don’t have to choose incredibly expensive prizes and gifts to incentivize clients, but in order to see whether or not that affects the outcome, we are offering up an iPad Mini, an Amazon Echo, and also an Apple Watch for our next contest.

For these contests, we call up past clients and ask them to participate in the review contest. One review on Zillow or Google, for example, will equal one entry into the drawing per site. If they leave a review on both websites, it will equal three entries. The contest lasts about three months, and when it’s over, we’ll draw three winners and announce them to our database. It will help to incorporate the news of these contests into your videos. For example, in some of my own videos, I will attach the announcement to a market update video, with the announcement gaining more urgency as the contest draws to an end.

“Consumers will choose the Realtors that they want to work with based on online reviews, much the same way that people choose restaurants or other establishments.”

Consumers will choose the Realtors that they want to work with based on online reviews, much the same way that people choose restaurants or other establishments. Getting a five-star review is critical. Anything less than that could hurt you substantially. Using these contests is a way for you to get more five-star ratings.

Websites like Yelp are a little more difficult. It’s not quite as popular in Charleston as it in California. If a client happens to use Yelp, their review will only stay on the site if they are an active user. Reviews that are left by one-time users appear suspicious to the site, which might assume that a business person created their own profile to leave reviews and boost their own business. In these cases, reviews are removed after a certain amount of time.

It’s so critical to have a strong online presence with reviews. People will research you and your company to make sure that you have a good reputation and brand. It’s especially critical if you do invest money in websites such as Zillow to get leads because they’re advertising multiple people on the same listing; if you have more reviews than the other agents listed, then it’s more likely that someone will reach out to you for a question. The same is true for agents with more detailed profiles set up.

Hopefully, this information can help you garner more reviews which are so essential to the business. If you have any more questions, don’t hesitate to reach out. I’d be more than happy to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://davefriedmancoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Are you struggling to find ways to get clients to leave you positive reviews online? Here are some ways you can change that.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Friedman</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Are you struggling to find ways to get clients to leave you positive reviews online? Here are some ways you can change that.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Charleston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Few Tips & Tricks to Grow Your Database</title>
        <link>http://davefriedmancoaching.com/a-few-tips-tricks-to-grow-your-database.html</link>
        
        <author>Dave Friedman</author>
        <pubDate>2018-01-10 05:01:46 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

If you’re interested in growing your database, here are a few tips I used right off the bat with my own database that will help you.

The first place you should go is LinkedIn. There’s a feature you can use that can export all of your contacts out of LinkedIn, along with those contacts’ phone numbers, names, work addresses, and email addresses. Those are all critical pieces of information you need in order to communicate value to those contacts through your database marketing plan.

The next place to look is Facebook. Facebook has made some changes that have made exporting your contacts through them more difficult, but if you have a Yahoo email account, there’s a way to sync it with your Facebook account so all your Facebook contacts can be exported into your Yahoo contacts.

“LinkedIn is a great place to start building your database.”

Aside from those two avenues, we also all use multiple email accounts, including spam accounts, personal accounts, and business accounts, that each have the capacity to export all of your contacts. Most of these accounts are pretty reliable when it comes to saving contacts as you communicate with people.

There are other methods we used to build up our database as well, so if you’d like to know more about this topic or you have any other questions, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d be glad to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://davefriedmancoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>We want to share a few tips that helped us grow our database to 65,000 people that can help you achieve that kind of growth with your own database.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Friedman</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We want to share a few tips that helped us grow our database to 65,000 people that can help you achieve that kind of growth with your own database.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Charleston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Are You Going to Meet Your Goals in 2018?</title>
        <link>http://davefriedmancoaching.com/how-are-you-going-to-meet-your-goals-in-2018.html</link>
        
        <author>Dave Friedman</author>
        <pubDate>2017-12-21 03:51:29 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>



Whatever your goals for your business are in the coming new year, I’ve got a great tool to share with you that can help you achieve them.

This tool is a spreadsheet that will tell you exactly what your activities must be throughout the year to reach a certain income. I’ve used this goal calculator for years and am actually going to be teaching a course on it soon. If you’re interested in joining that class, let me know so I can get you enrolled.

Here’s how it works. You input your income goals into the calculator along with a breakdown of your business and a couple of easy conversions. For example, what percentage of your listings go under contract? 

This calculator breaks down your lead generation activities on the seller side of things as well as the number of clients you’ll need to work with on the buyer’s side to reach your goals.

I have all the metrics we’ve been measuring on my team for the last four years, so I can share those metrics with you if it would help. I can also give you some tips and tricks forleveling up your conversions.

This calculator gives you an exact plan for meeting your goals. It will also help you budget all the necessary expenses to run your business.  

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.

 
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://davefriedmancoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Do you have a plan for meeting your business goals in 2018? Today, I’d like to share some information with you about a great tool that makes meeting your goals much easier.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Friedman</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Do you have a plan for meeting your business goals in 2018? Today, I’d like to share some information with you about a great tool that makes meeting your goals much easier.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Charleston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How the Abelson DISC Assessment Helps Our Team Find New Members</title>
        <link>http://davefriedmancoaching.com/how-the-abelson-disc-assessment-helps-our-team-find-new-members.html</link>
        
        <author>Dave Friedman</author>
        <pubDate>2017-12-05 03:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

A lot of people have been asking me recently how we find our new team members.

While behavioral assessments are a big part of this process, it’s important to note that the Tony Robbins DISC assessment is not geared toward use for business.

Instead, the best thing to use is something called the Abelson DISC. By using this route, you can assess people based on a specific area of business. There is a sales DISC assessment, a management DISC assessment, and more.

“The Tony Robbins DISC assessment is not geared toward use for business.”

People are scored based on different categories directly pertaining to how well they might function within a role at a business.

My team has actually developed benchmarks for every position we have that are based on categories related to this assessment. I can send you these benchmarks if you are interested.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://davefriedmancoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>One of the best ways to find new team members is by implementing the Abelson DISC assessment into your decision.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Friedman</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>One of the best ways to find new team members is by implementing the Abelson DISC assessment into your decision.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Charleston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>These 5 Books Can Help You Develop the Perfect Business Plan</title>
        <link>http://davefriedmancoaching.com/these-5-books-can-help-you-develop-the-perfect-business-plan.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Dave Friedman</author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-31 07:04:57 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/2017+Recruiting/5+Books+To+Help+Your+Business+-+Charleston+%2526+Mt.+Pleasant+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

A lot of people have been asking me how to develop a great business plan. As I started writing down notes on the subject, I reflected on the steps I took to create my business plan and what it took to follow through on it. Today, I’d like to discuss this subject and also tell you about five books I believe will help your business.

There are seven components I wrote down pertaining to the development of a great business plan. The first is to have a vision. You need to understand why it is you want your business to be successful. For some further reading on this point, I recommend checking out Simon Sinek’s “Start With Why.” This will help you develop the mission of your business, which will then carry through to helping you create a culture and energy that fits your vision.

The next book I recommend is “The SWOT Analysis” by Lawrence G. Fine. SWOT stands for strengths, weaknesses, opportunities, and threats. The first two components are internal qualities you should examine within yourself, and the last two components refer to external factors. Thinking critically about these components will help you narrow down the purpose of your business and how you want to target that purpose.

“In order to reach your goals, you’ll need a strategic plan.”

Another book I think you should check out is “SMART Goals” by Jacob Gudger. This book specifically will help you set and reach goals in a practical manner. SMART stands for specific, measurable, attainable,  realistic, and timely. These are all qualities that a good goal should have. An example of a good goal would be wanting to earn $100,000 in real estate from ‘X’ number of homes at an average commission over the next 12 months.

But in order to reach these goals, you’ll need a strategic plan. For this, I recommend reading “Mastering the Rockefeller Habits” by Vern Harnish. (You could also read “Traction” by Gino Wickman, and/or “Rocket Fuel” by Gino Wickman and Marc C. Winters.)

Next, you want to consider the time frame. Develop your plan for moving forward by dividing goals and projects into the next one, three, and five years. If you just develop three to five goals you need to accomplish each quarter, you will reach your goal in five years. Gary Keller’s “The One Thing” is a good read that covers this subject.

The final thing you should do is to develop systems and processes. The best thing you can do is to stay in production, but hire an admin to help you develop these things while you’re continuing to produce.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/2017+Recruiting/5+Books+To+Help+Your+Business+-+Charleston+%2526+Mt.+Pleasant+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://davefriedmancoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/2017+Recruiting/5+Books+To+Help+Your+Business+-+Charleston+%2526+Mt.+Pleasant+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today, I’d like to go over the process of developing a business plan. I’d also like to tell you about five books I believe will help you moving forward.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Friedman</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today, I’d like to go over the process of developing a business plan. I’d also like to tell you about five books I believe will help you moving forward.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Charleston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Can You Establish Your Personal Brand as a New Agent?</title>
        <link>http://davefriedmancoaching.com/how-can-you-establish-your-personal-brand-as-a-new-agent.html</link>
        
        <author>Dave Friedman</author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-17 06:17:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/2017+Recruiting/Establishing+Your+Brand+-+Charleston+%2526+Mt.+Pleasant+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

How can you establish your personal brand as a new agent? It’s not as difficult as you think it is.

First of all, you have to define why you are doing what you’re doing.  From there, you can establish the values you have within your team or within your business if you want to be a solo agent.

Think about the people you want to impact, why you want to impact them, and what kind of market you want to work in.

Once you define that, you can develop your own personal image. Since you don’t have anything to fall back on as far as your business image, it’s a great time to recreate that for yourself.

Pick things for your logo that are emblematic of your own values. That will ring true for the culture you have for your business when you meet with new clients or hire new people. It’s really important to identify those values and make sure people see them through your marketing.

“Define why you are doing what you do.”

Finally, determine your unique selling proposition as a Realtor. What makes you unique? Why would someone hire you as opposed to a different Realtor?

There are many things you can offer to set yourself apart. We offer different guarantees so that our consumers know we have a higher level of accountability. Some people decide to work within a defined area and become an expert in that area. No matter what it is, choose something that makes you unique and differentiates you from other Realtors out there.

Everyone has a relative or friend in real estate. You need to make sure that you stand out from the crowd and come up with good reasons why people would like to work with you.

If you have any other questions about establishing your brand, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/2017+Recruiting/Establishing+Your+Brand+-+Charleston+%2526+Mt.+Pleasant+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://davefriedmancoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/2017+Recruiting/Establishing+Your+Brand+-+Charleston+%2526+Mt.+Pleasant+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>How can you establish your own brand as a newer real estate agent? I have a few tips to help get you started.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Friedman</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>How can you establish your own brand as a newer real estate agent? I have a few tips to help get you started.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Charleston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Check Out My Full Appearance on Real Estate Uncensored</title>
        <link>http://davefriedmancoaching.com/check-out-my-full-appearance-on-real-estate-uncensored.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Dave Friedman</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-30 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>I recently had the pleasure of being a guest on the Real Estate Uncensored podcast with Greg McDaniel and Matt Johnson. We had a wide-ranging discussion that touched on a number of topics.

Click here to listen to the full podcast.

The main area of focus was how I went from being a solo agent doing 40 deals a year to being a team leader who was doing 400 deals a year in a short time. I also had some time to answer questions, both from the viewers and from Matt and Greg about my business. Here’s a summary of our discussions with timestamps so you can skip ahead if any part particularly interests you.

3:30- How I like to handle hesitant clients.

12:00- How I developed my method for getting more referrals.

19:00- How I’m continuing to grow my database even today.

25:30- How my 71-touch program is getting me a 55x ROI and making up a third of my business.

33:00- Why discipline and culture are the two keys to our dramatic growth.

“Discipline and culture are the two biggest keys to our growth.”

36:00- How we discovered our team members’ motivations and how that has impacted the culture.

43:00- What motivates me today?

47:00- How letting my system take over improved my business and my life in general.

52:00- Hungry and humble is the name of the game.

If you have any questions for me, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I’m here for you anytime.

</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://davefriedmancoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>I was recently a guest on one of my favorite real estate podcasts. Check out the full interview here.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Friedman</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>I was recently a guest on one of my favorite real estate podcasts. Check out the full interview here.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Charleston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Our Comprehensive Open House Marketing Plan</title>
        <link>http://davefriedmancoaching.com/our-comprehensive-open-house-marketing-plan.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Dave Friedman</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-10 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/2017+Recruiting/Our+Comprehensive+Open+House+Marketing+Plan+-+Charleston+%2526+Mt.+Pleasant+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Many sellers have recently asked me how we have such great turnout at our open houses, so I wanted to share some quick advice.

We have a 15-page marketing page that explains our whole open house process that I’d be happy to send to you, but for now, I wanted to give you the main points.

Start by keeping the home clean and maximizing the curb appeal. The home should be completely decluttered and the curb appeal should be 10/10 because it means everything. People will drive up to the house, take a look, and keep on driving if the curb appeal isn’t up to par. If it needs to be painted, get it painted. If it needs pine straw or mulch, get some. To get people inside the home, the outside has to be beautiful.

It takes about 90 minutes to prepare for our open houses because we put up more than 100 signs. We’ll put one sign per turn in the neighborhood, and once we get to the major arteries outside the neighborhood, we’ll put 10 directional signs pointing to your neighborhood from one direction and 10 more from the other direction. That way, traffic on both sides of the street can see the signage.

“To get people inside the home, the outside has to be beautiful.”

Additionally, we generate a lot of interest with our digital marketing. We have a database of more 800 active buyers looking to buy a home, so we’ll not only market to them, but target people on social media who are likely to make a move. We run marketing campaigns for about a week in advance to drum up interest.

Publications also work great, so I publish a 15-page real estate-related newspaper that goes to 28,000 homes with an open house section where we feature homes. Finally, we try to get everyone to register once they come in so we can follow up with them and ask questions.

Again, if you’d like our full 15-page document, I’d be happy to share it with you. If you have any questions about open houses or anything in your real estate career, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I hope to hear from you soon!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/2017+Recruiting/Our+Comprehensive+Open+House+Marketing+Plan+-+Charleston+%2526+Mt.+Pleasant+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://davefriedmancoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/2017+Recruiting/Our+Comprehensive+Open+House+Marketing+Plan+-+Charleston+%2526+Mt.+Pleasant+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Our team has a proven track record of successful open houses, so I thought I'd share some of our secrets.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Friedman</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Our team has a proven track record of successful open houses, so I thought I'd share some of our secrets.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Charleston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How I Increased My Business by Working My Database</title>
        <link>http://davefriedmancoaching.com/how-i-increased-my-business-by-working-my-database.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Dave Friedman</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-17 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/2017+Recruiting/How+I+doubled+my+business+in+one+year+-+Charleston+%2526+Mt.+Pleasant+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Above, you’ll find a replay of my full discussion with Frank Klesitz of Vyral Marketing. Here is what we covered with timestamps so you can jump to the section that most interests you:

(0:50) My professional story. How I got into real estate and built my company from the ground up.
(5:00) How I took the next step in my business by implementing different systems.
(8:05) How many people I talk to a week and how I went from three to 30 sales a year from my database.
(10:25) How many opt-ins I get every week.
(15:20) What caused my recent increase in production? The conversion of previous leads we already had or the increased attention to my database?
(20:00) How to avoid spam when marketing online.
(21: 50) My take on traditional real estate farming.
(26:45) What do I recommend for you to feed your database?
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/2017+Recruiting/How+I+doubled+my+business+in+one+year+-+Charleston+%2526+Mt.+Pleasant+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://davefriedmancoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/2017+Recruiting/How+I+doubled+my+business+in+one+year+-+Charleston+%2526+Mt.+Pleasant+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>I went from only getting three deals from my database each year to more than thirty last year. Here’s how I did it.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Friedman</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>I went from only getting three deals from my database each year to more than thirty last year. Here’s how I did it.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Charleston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Our Team Finds Success With This Unique Tool</title>
        <link>http://davefriedmancoaching.com/how-our-team-finds-success-with-this.html</link>
        
          <category>Increase Business</category>
        
        <author>Dave Friedman</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-14 11:46:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

A lot of people want to know how our team is able to be so productive. Our agents’ 40 transactions per year, do over $10 million in volume, and take home big paychecks. How are they able to do this? A lot of their success is due to one simple tool that will change the way you approach your career.

It’s a simple form called “Dominate your day, win your week!” and it’s something our team members fill out each day. It helps you plan out your day to make it as productive as possible. There are six steps to personal productivity mastery:


  Focus, do not multi-task, and eliminate distractions.
  Make lists based on dollar-producing activities. 20% of your activities will produce 80% of the results.
  Prioritize everything you do based on your goals.
  Protect your time blocks. Plan your day in 30-minute increments and don’t let anything interfere.
  Eliminate clutter.
  Plan your week on Sunday and plan each day in advance.


Once you figure out what your top money making activities are, put those on your list first. Then, you can fill out the different time slots, noting when you plan to start and stop. As we move down the form, you have sections for determining how much each activity is worth to you so you can wrap your head around what it will cost you to neglect those activities.

There’s also a section on there for you to write down your “10 wins for the day” to give yourself a more positive focus. Sometimes a win is setting an appointment. Sometimes it’s having lunch with your spouse. It’s important to keep things in perspective.

Finally, there’s a section on the form for you to write down notes. Anything that comes to mind during the day can be written, including notes for the day and things you might need to add to your dollar-producing activities.

If you have any questions about this form or would like to get a copy of your own, just give me a call or send me an email and I’d be happy to get you one. I look forward to hearing from you soon.

Send me an email and I’d be happy to get you one. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://davefriedmancoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

A lot of people want to know how our team is able to be so productive. Our agents’ 40 transactions per year, do over $10 million in volume, and take home big paychecks. How are they able to do this? A lot of their success is due to one simple tool that will change the way you approach your career.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Friedman</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

A lot of people want to know how our team is able to be so productive. Our agents’ 40 transactions per year, do over $10 million in volume, and take home big paychecks. How are they able to do this? A lot of their success is due to one simple tool that will change the way you approach your career.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Charleston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What’s Sexy About Consistency?</title>
        <link>http://davefriedmancoaching.com/whats-sexy-about-consistency.html</link>
        
          <category>Increase Business</category>
        
        <author>Dave Friedman</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-21 16:12:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Recently, I had the pleasure of being a guest on Patrick Lilly’s Real Estate Success Rocks podcast. Patrick puts on phenomenal masterminds with a select group of top-producing real estate agents across North America; his podcasts are a great way to get a sneak peek into those masterminds.

When I was on his show, Patrick and I discussed the importance of consistency in your business. Here are a few things we went over:When I was on his show, Patrick and I discussed the importance of consistency in your business. Here are a few things we went over:

My Daily Routine

  The Miracle Morning
  Tell Me Something Good call
  Dominate your day
  Daily prospecting using Mojo
  Daily follow up


Weekly Routine

  Pipeline report
  List of opportunities
  Hopper system
  Weekly one-on-one meetings
  Weekly team meetings
  Our 70-touch system for our database
  Using quarterly lookbacks and a business grading score card.


As Patrick likes to say, there is nothing sexier than consistency. You can listen to the full episode here.

If you are interested in any of the resources Patrick and I discuss on the show, check out this list:


  www.SoldWithDave.com
  twitter.com/realestaterants


I highly recommend that you listen to all of the Real Estate Success Rocks podcast episodes. You will learn a lot from Patrick and other agents across the country.

As always, if you have any questions about how to improve your business, just give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://davefriedmancoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Recently, I had the pleasure of being a guest on Patrick Lilly’s Real Estate Success Rocks podcast. Patrick puts on phenomenal masterminds with a select group of top-producing real estate agents across North America; his podcasts are a great way to get a sneak peek into those masterminds.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Friedman</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Recently, I had the pleasure of being a guest on Patrick Lilly’s Real Estate Success Rocks podcast. Patrick puts on phenomenal masterminds with a select group of top-producing real estate agents across North America; his podcasts are a great way to get a sneak peek into those masterminds.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Charleston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Do You Build a Winning Real Estate Team? </title>
        <link>http://davefriedmancoaching.com/how-do-you-build-winning-real-estate.html</link>
        
          <category>Build a Real Estate Team</category>
        
        <author>Dave Friedman</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-06 10:56:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>I recently had the pleasure of appearing on Pat Hiban’s Real Estate Rockstars Radio, where Pat interviews the top voices in the real estate industry. On this episode, you’ll learn:


  A bit of my business background.
  Why I decided to build a real estate team instead of becoming an individual agent.
  How I close a deal per open house.
  How long it took me to build a team.
  How my ISA helps drive my business.
  How many appointments I get thanks to the systems I set up within my team.
  The biggest part of my business.
  How to break through your goals.


That is just a sample of the great conversation I had with Pat HIban. You can listen to the full episode here.

If you are interested in any of the resources we mention on the show, here is a complete list:


  Dave Friedman Real Estate
  Facebook
  clickcharlestonsc.com
  Twitter
  Vulcan 7
  Mojo Dialer
  Kunversion
  REDX


I highly recommend listening to the rest of Pat Hiban’s Real Estate Rockstars episodes to learn more from the top producing agents, coaches, and brokers in the industry.

Of course, if you have any questions for me, please don’t hesitate to reach out. I would be happy to help you!


</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://davefriedmancoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>I recently had the pleasure of appearing on Pat Hiban’s Real Estate Rockstars Radio, where Pat interviews the top voices in the real estate industry. On this episode, you’ll learn:

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Friedman</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>I recently had the pleasure of appearing on Pat Hiban’s Real Estate Rockstars Radio, where Pat interviews the top voices in the real estate industry. On this episode, you’ll learn:

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Charleston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Join Us and Make 2017 the Best Year of Your Life</title>
        <link>http://davefriedmancoaching.com/join-us-and-make-2017-best-year-of-your.html</link>
        
          <category>Increase Business</category>
        
        <author>Dave Friedman</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-19 15:03:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Did you reach all of your personal and professional goals in 2016? Do you want to do better in 2017?

We’re looking for motivated, energetic, talented people to join our team, and today I wanted to you tell about** a great tool we started using to hold ourselves accountable so we can hit all of our personal and professional goals and make 2017 the best year of our lives.

On average each agent produces $10M in volume and sells 40 homes per year. In comparison to the average agent who sells 4 homes a year, its obvious our team has created a proven and repeatable system for Realtors to become extremely successful. If you didn’t achieve what you set out to do in 2016, this tool will help you immensely.

“This tool will help you reach all of your personal and professional goals.”

We have many job openings listed on this blog, so if you’re interested in achieving all the goals that you didn’t in 2016, reach out to me so I can share this tool with you and discuss the opportunities we have to offer.

I look forward to hearing from you! , reach out to me so I can share this tool with you and discuss the opportunities we have to offer.

I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://davefriedmancoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Did you reach all of your personal and professional goals in 2016? Do you want to do better in 2017?

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Friedman</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Did you reach all of your personal and professional goals in 2016? Do you want to do better in 2017?

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Charleston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How I Doubled My Dealings In One Year</title>
        <link>http://davefriedmancoaching.com/how-i-doubled-my-dealings-in-one-year.html</link>
        
          <category>Increase Business</category>
        
        <author>Dave Friedman</author>
        <pubDate>2016-12-13 14:28:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Here is an overview of what we covered with time-stamps so you can jump to the section that most interests you:

2:00- How I dealt with the problems and challenges of closing so many buyer sides in one year and how I supercharged my business by adding the right systems.

3:30- All the pillars I’ve implemented in my business, and how that helped me get to where I am today.  ** 6:30**- How I implemented and executed an expired system to increase my listing business and get a 6x ROI.

8:30- How I got 30 deals and a 70x ROI  from my database marketing in one year.

11:00- An overview of our business dashboard and how it helps us stay organized.

13:00- How we use our goal tracker to keep our agents on the path to success.

15:00- Other systems that help us dial in what my business is looking like.  If you have any questions on what we talked about, reach out to me through a call or email. I’d love to chat and see what I can do to help you! ut, reach out to me through a call or email. I’d love to chat and see what I can do to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://davefriedmancoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Here is an overview of what we covered with time-stamps so you can jump to the section that most interests you:

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Friedman</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Here is an overview of what we covered with time-stamps so you can jump to the section that most interests you:

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Charleston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Dave Friedman</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Dave Friedman</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Dave Friedman Team - your professional Charleston Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
