<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>http://www.danjonescoaching.com</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://www.danjonescoaching.com"/>
    <description></description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor></managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2017-08-22 09:33:57 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright></media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://www.danjonescoaching.com"/>
    <media:keywords></media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd"></media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Sold@MyHomeCarolinas.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name></itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author></itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://www.danjonescoaching.com"/>
    <itunes:keywords></itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle></itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text=""/>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tracking Your Numbers Is the Key to Success</title>
        <link>http://www.danjonescoaching.com/tracking-your-numbers-is-key-to-success.html</link>
        
          <category>Charlotte Real Estate Business Partner</category>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-27 12:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/2017/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+Recruiting+Video+-+Track+Numbers.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Our agents at Carolina Real Estate Experts know the key to closing 40, 50, or more sales per year. The secret is all about your numbers.

If you’re a real estate agent looking for work in our area, as part of Carolina Real Estate Experts, I want to share with you just a few things that set our team apart.

**Agents on our team are held accountable for their numbers—they sell 40, 50, or more homes a year and consistently make six figures. **

So, if you are at a place in your real estate career where joining our team could be your next step, one major thing you need to do is to start tracking your numbers.

“TRACKING ON A DAILY, WEEKLY, AND MONTHLY BASIS WILL ALLOW YOU TO FIND TRENDS IN YOUR NUMBERS AND USE THEM TO HIT 40 TO 50 SALES PER YEAR.”

If keeping records of your work isn’t something you already do, now is the time to start. You can do this by quantifying your hours prospecting, the number of dials you made during that time, how many people you have contacted or, even better, made meaningful contact with, and also how many appointments you’ve had versus offers written under contract.

For an example of this, I looked to the first quarter numbers for one of our first full year agents. In January, they had six written offers, five in February, seven in both March and April, as well as 10 in May. And, as of the end of May, 21 of those homes have been closed on.

With numbers like this from the first five months of the year alone, it’s clear that this agent will make over 50 sales by the end of this year.

Tracking on a daily, weekly, and monthly basis will allow you to find trends in your numbers and use them to hit 40 to 50 sales per year.

If you, too, would like to have this kind of success and are thinking of joining our team, feel free to reach out to us by email, phone, or through our blog.  We look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/2017/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+Recruiting+Video+-+Track+Numbers.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.danjonescoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/2017/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+Recruiting+Video+-+Track+Numbers.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Our agents at Carolina Real Estate Experts know the key to closing 40, 50, or more sales per year. The secret is all about your numbers.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Our agents at Carolina Real Estate Experts know the key to closing 40, 50, or more sales per year. The secret is all about your numbers.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords></itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The 4-Step Process to Handle Agent Request Leads </title>
        <link>http://www.danjonescoaching.com/the-4-step-process-to-handle-agent.html</link>
        
          <category>Charlotte Real Estate Business Partner</category>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-13 16:35:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/2017/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+How+to+Handle+an+Agent+Request+Lead.mp4</guid>
        <description>

How can you hit agent request leads out of the park? Use our four-step process.

How should you handle an agent request lead?

When a potential buyer reaches out to you about one of your properties, that is a fastball right down the plate. A lot of agents miss them, but you should be hitting them out of the park.

We have a four-step process to handle these calls.

First, you have to get them into the house. Assume that they are pre-qualified and say, “What questions do you have about the home and when would you like to preview it?” You need to ask when they want to see the home right away. Otherwise, if you just ask what questions they have about the home, they will hang up once you give them the answer. You need to ask those two questions right off the bat.

Once you set the appointment, why should you show them just one house? Ask, “Are there any other homes you’ve been looking at?” Most of the time, the answer is yes, so go ahead and set the appointment.

“ASK WHEN THEY WANT TO SEE THE HOME RIGHT AWAY!”

A lot of people don’t want to set an appointment without a pre-qualification. At this point in the call, though, you have no rapport with this person, so go ahead and set the appointment. You can always cancel if they aren’t pre-qualified. If you have a lender you can put them in touch with that day, then you can help them get pre-qualified.

The next question you need to ask is, “Are you working with an agent?” You don’t want to step on any toes, so ask if they have signed anything with another agent.

Finally, ask them if they are pre-qualified. At this point, you have built some rapport and you have an appointment. Have them send you their pre-approval and then you are ready to go look at some houses.

This is part of our team’s training and it works very well. If you have any other questions about agent request leads or if there is anything else you have questions about, give us a call. We would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/2017/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+How+to+Handle+an+Agent+Request+Lead.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.danjonescoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/2017/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+How+to+Handle+an+Agent+Request+Lead.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

How can you hit agent request leads out of the park? Use our four-step process.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

How can you hit agent request leads out of the park? Use our four-step process.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords></itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>2 Prospecting Tips to Sell Real Estate at a Higher Level</title>
        <link>http://www.danjonescoaching.com/2-prospecting-tips-to-sell-real-estate.html</link>
        
          <category>Charlotte Real Estate Business Partner</category>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-27 12:18:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/2017/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+Prospecting+Tips.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When it comes to prospecting, these two tips will help you improve your game immensely.

Looking to improve your real estate career? We’re here to help you make a smart decision when it comes to growing your business, improving your bottom line, and choosing a place to work in real estate sales. If you’d like to learn more about working with us, contact us at
704-800-6459  or dan@myhomecarolinas.com.

Today I want to share some prospecting tips that will help you be a better agent and sell real estate at a higher level.

The first tip is to go for the appointment. I know a lot of agents who get a lead, ask their buyer for a price, send them homes in that price range, and then play the chasing game. The problem with that is there’s never a real connection between you and the buyer. In that situation, they’re receiving random homes without knowing which one’s a good deal and they don’t have anybody giving them access to all the better deals. They’re missing out on homes, and that in itself is a good reason to ask for an appointment.

“DON’T PLAY THE CHASING GAME—GO FOR THE APPOINTMENT.”

My next tip is for when you have a client who needs to buy and sell at the same time. In this case, you must ask “Which do you prefer to do first?” Do they need to sell first before they buy or buy first and then sell? If you don’t ask this question, how do you know which appointment to go for?

Agents who don’t ask this question end up sending comps and other random ideas and play the chasing game all over again. Once you get the appointment, you need to know which needs to happen first—buying or selling. If the client says “buy,” you need to start asking buyer questions. If they say “sell,” you need to get all their information on the sell side and then ask some questions on the buy side to solidify both appointments.

It’s almost impossible to go for a double appointment because most of the time buyers or sellers or both have an agenda. If you focus on one side first and then hint toward the second side, you can land both sides of the transaction.

If you have any more questions about prospecting, please feel free to give me a call or shoot me an email. If you’re thinking of joining a team, we coach at a high level, prospect at a high level, and sell a ton of houses, so I’d be happy to sit down and talk with you to see if you’d be a good fit.

In either case, I’d be happy to help. Talk to you soon!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/2017/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+Prospecting+Tips.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.danjonescoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/2017/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+Prospecting+Tips.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

When it comes to prospecting, these two tips will help you improve your game immensely.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

When it comes to prospecting, these two tips will help you improve your game immensely.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords></itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Do You Have What It Takes to Join Us?</title>
        <link>http://www.danjonescoaching.com/do-you-have-what-it-takes-to-join-us.html</link>
        
          <category>We're Hiring</category>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-12 11:21:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+recruiting.mp4</guid>
        <description>

A lot of agents set goals but never reach them. That’s not how we do things on our team.

Our team hit all our goals for 2016, and we are ready to crush it even more in the new year. We are looking to close on more than 300 homes this year, but we need some help.

We are looking to hire two buyer agents to help us reach our goals. The ideal candidate is fearless, bold, energetic, and enthusiastic. Accountability is huge, too—it’s at the top of our list. We do a ton of coaching and goal achievement to help keep our agents on track.

A lot of agents who set goals of selling 40 or 50 homes end up closing six and calling it good. That’s not what we do here. We really thrive on goal achievement and setting ourselves up for success by making sure our priorities are taken care of.

“OUR TEAM HIT ALL OUR GOALS FOR 2016.”

We don’t charge desk fees, we provide a ton of quality leads, and we teach you the best practices in converting those leads. We want you to know what to do with a lead so you can gameplan for yourself and make sure you have a good year.

If this is something that sounds interesting to you, feel free to email me directly or just give me a call. I would love to meet with you, get your resume, and chat. Even if you’re a new agent, we’d love to hear from you too. In fact, one of our new agents is on track to sell 50 homes this year.

If you possess the mindset to succeed in this role, we look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+recruiting.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.danjonescoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+recruiting.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

A lot of agents set goals but never reach them. That’s not how we do things on our team.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

A lot of agents set goals but never reach them. That’s not how we do things on our team.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords></itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright></copyright>
    <media:credit role="author"></media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain"></media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
