<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Charleston Real Estate Video Blog with Dave Friedman</title>
    <link>davefriedmantv.com</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="davefriedmantv.com"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Dave Friedman Team - your professional Charleston Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Dave Friedman</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2017-08-16 14:17:31 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Dave Friedman</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://i.imgur.com/eBUH7tb.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Charleston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">News &amp; Politics</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Dave@DaveFriedmanTeam.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Dave Friedman</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Dave Friedman</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://i.imgur.com/eBUH7tb.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Charleston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Charleston Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Dave Friedman Team - your professional Charleston Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="News &amp; Politics"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Shockingly High Margin of Error With Zestimates</title>
        <link>davefriedmantv.com/the-shockingly-high-margin-of-error-with-zestimates.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Dave Friedman</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-10 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/2017/The+Shockingly+High+Margin+of+Error+With+Zestimates+-+Charleston+%2526+Mt.+Pleasant+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

How accurate are Zillow’s Zestimates? 

Zestimates are within 20% of a home’s sale price 80% of the time, which is a huge margin of error. For a $300,000 home, that margin of error could swing from $240,000 to $360,000. 

Zestimates are within 10% of the sale price just 70% of the time as well. In our $300,000 example home, the Zestimate could be off by $30,000 on the high or low side seven out of 10 times.

“Zestimates are within 5% of a home’s actual value less than half the time.”

Finally, Zillow’s Zestimates are within 5% of the sales price just 45% of the time. That’s still a $30,000 margin of error, and that’s as accurate as they get. 

As a professional real estate agent, I would have been out of the business a long time ago if I was off by 5% on home value estimates that often. That would mean I either overprice the home and it won’t sell, or I underprice it and leave thousands and thousands of dollars on the table!

If you have any questions about how to find your home’s actual value or about using Zillow, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I’m always happy to help.
 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/2017/The+Shockingly+High+Margin+of+Error+With+Zestimates+-+Charleston+%2526+Mt.+Pleasant+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="davefriedmantv.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/2017/The+Shockingly+High+Margin+of+Error+With+Zestimates+-+Charleston+%2526+Mt.+Pleasant+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Just how accurate are those Zestimate home values you see on Zillow? Far less than you think.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Friedman</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Just how accurate are those Zestimate home values you see on Zillow? Far less than you think.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Charleston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Do Homebuyers Need to Work With a Buyer’s Agent?</title>
        <link>davefriedmantv.com/why-do-homebuyers-need-to-work-with-a-buyers-agent.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Dave Friedman</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-31 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/2017/Why+Do+Homebuyers+Need+to+Work+With+a+Buyers+Agent%253F+-+Charleston+%2526+Mt.+Pleasant+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

A lot of people have been asking me recently, “What’s up with the buyer agency agreement? What does it even mean?”

When you call the number on a ‘For Sale’ sign inquiring about the home that’s for sale, you end up talking to the listing agent that the seller has hired. That person has a legal obligation to sell that person’s home for the most amount of money in the least amount of time.

Is that the person you want to work with? The person who has a direct responsibility to the seller to fulfill those obligations? I don’t think so.

That’s why the state came up with buyer representation. In the words of a good friend of mine, “It’s the best money you haven’t spent.” It doesn’t cost you anything to work with a buyer’s agent, so why wouldn’t you?

There are many benefits to working with a buyer’s agent, such as:


  We make sure you don’t overpay for a home.
  We shop interest rates for you to make sure you have the best financing available.
  We negotiate the best deal for you.
  We find the best home inspector to make sure the home doesn’t have any problems. If it does, we have the seller fix them for you.


Furthermore, there are other guarantees packaged into our team’s buyer agency agreement. For example, you can cancel our agreement at any time. Most Realtors want to lock you into a late fee contract, but not us. We want to hold ourselves accountable to you because we know for a fact that as long as you’re happy, you’ll have no reason to work with anybody else.

“Working with a buyer’s agent is the best money you haven’t spent.”

Even if you walk into a home and immediately fall in love with it, we’ll give you reasons why you shouldn’t buy it. We don’t want you to make a bad decision, which alludes to our second guarantee: if you buy a home and you’re dissatisfied with it for whatever reason within the first 24 months, I’ll come over and sell it for free. Lastly, if we can’t negotiate a home warranty into the contract for you, then we’ll buy the house for you.

If you have any more questions about the legal obligations and requirements of the buyer’s agency agreement, don’t hesitate to give me a call. I’d be more than happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/2017/Why+Do+Homebuyers+Need+to+Work+With+a+Buyers+Agent%253F+-+Charleston+%2526+Mt.+Pleasant+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="davefriedmantv.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/2017/Why+Do+Homebuyers+Need+to+Work+With+a+Buyers+Agent%253F+-+Charleston+%2526+Mt.+Pleasant+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re a homebuyer, there are many reasons you need to work with a buyer’s agent instead of a listing agent</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Friedman</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re a homebuyer, there are many reasons you need to work with a buyer’s agent instead of a listing agent</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Charleston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Let Us Take You Out to the Ballgame at Riverdog Stadium</title>
        <link>davefriedmantv.com/let-us-take-you-out-to-the-ballgame-at-riverdog-stadium.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Dave Friedman</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-15 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/2017/Let+Us+Take+You+Out+to+the+Ballgame+at+Riverdog+Stadium+-+Charleston+%2526+Mt.+Pleasant+Agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

You’re hereby invited to our annual community appreciation event at the Riverdog Stadium on June 7th at 7:05 p.m.

This is a very special event in which we’ve teamed up with ServiceMaster Lawton Hayes to host it for the last three years. We’ll have drinks, food, and for every person who attends the game, I’ll donate $10 to the Burned Children’s Fund at MUSC.

This fund is truly amazing, and I know for a fact that all the money that was raised at this same event last year was used to install 3,000 smoke detectors into homes that needed them. Two different people have even confirmed for a fact that their lives were saved based on this event and everybody showing up and contributing.

“We’d love for you to join us at the ballpark.”

The best part? It’s 100% free. If you’re interested in attending, just reply back to our email and let me know how many ticket vouchers you need. Look for me in front inside the Dave Friedman Team tent where you can exchange your vouchers for tickets.

If you have any questions about this event, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I look forward to seeing you soon!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/2017/Let+Us+Take+You+Out+to+the+Ballgame+at+Riverdog+Stadium+-+Charleston+%2526+Mt.+Pleasant+Agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="davefriedmantv.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/2017/Let+Us+Take+You+Out+to+the+Ballgame+at+Riverdog+Stadium+-+Charleston+%2526+Mt.+Pleasant+Agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Our annual client appreciation event at Riverdog Stadium is coming up, and you’re officially invited.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Friedman</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Our annual client appreciation event at Riverdog Stadium is coming up, and you’re officially invited.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Charleston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>An Update on Our Market Through the 1st Quarter</title>
        <link>davefriedmantv.com/an-update-on-our-market-through-the-1st-quarter.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Dave Friedman</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-26 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/2017/An+Update+on+Our+Market+Through+the+1st+Quarter+-+Charleston+%2526+Mt.+Pleasant+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

As we head into the summer, I wanted to reach out and check in with you about what we saw in the first quarter in our market.

The number of transactions in the market as a whole is up by 13.5% from last year and the median sale price is up by 4.5% too, which is fantastic. However, there is something strange going on in three specific markets out there where the median sale price is down in comparison to last year. Those markets would be Hanahan, Cainhoy, and Mt. Pleasant.

Overall, things are great though. There are 17 different mini-markets out there that have less than 4.5 months of inventory available, making them all seller’s markets. At the same time, there are about seven mini-markets that are right around six months of inventory, which is considered a balanced market. If you want to know what kind of market you are in specifically, don’t hesitate to reach out to me.

“We’re having a very strong year.”

We’re having a very strong year. In fact, this could be the best year ever for our market. It could very well be the first year we have more than 18,000 home sales in this market.

I’ll keep you updated with changes in the market as they come. If you have any questions in the meantime, give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/2017/An+Update+on+Our+Market+Through+the+1st+Quarter+-+Charleston+%2526+Mt.+Pleasant+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="davefriedmantv.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/2017/An+Update+on+Our+Market+Through+the+1st+Quarter+-+Charleston+%2526+Mt.+Pleasant+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Our market has been doing fantastic. Sales are up, prices are up, and we are anticipating our strongest year ever.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Friedman</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Our market has been doing fantastic. Sales are up, prices are up, and we are anticipating our strongest year ever.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Charleston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Which Home Renovations Get the Best Returns?</title>
        <link>davefriedmantv.com/which-home-renovations-get-the-best-returns.html</link>
        
        <author>Dave Friedman</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-14 13:13:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/2017/Which+Home+Renovations+Get+the+Best+Returns%253F+-+Charleston+%2526+Mt.+Pleasant+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>
When you are preparing your home for the market, you may want to make some renovations in order to net more money on your home sale. Which renovations get better returns than others?

Keep in mind that less is more. Large-scale jobs aren’t likely to return their full costs but there are investments worth doing in anticipation of an upcoming sale. Some renovations return 100% of their costs while others get less than half of the money back. Still, some renovations can improve your market position and the probability that your home will sell.

Lower cost projects tend to return greater value. For example, the national average cost for a steel front door replacement is $1,200. That is the least expensive project on the list and it also gets the highest return. In fact, you can expect a 101% return on investment. In 43 of 102 markets surveyed, new doors recoup more than 100% of their costs.

Other projects that get a good return on investment are mid-range garage door replacements or upscale garage door replacements, mid-range wood window replacements, and minor kitchen remodels. Notice a pattern here? With the exception of a kitchen remodel, these are all replacement projects.

In general, replacements cost less and provide a bigger payback than remodeling or adding square footage to a home. First impressions are very important to buyers, so replacing things that they will see right away, like the front door, garage door, or siding will help you net more money on your home sale. Manufactured veneer gets a 92% return on investment.

When it comes to remodels, though, kitchens will still get you the most bang for your buck. For example, a small, $20,000 remodel will get you a payback of 80%.

Just how much you recoup from home improvements depends on which updates you make and which region of the country you are in. Other factors to take into account include figuring out which updates are typical for your specific neighborhood and, of course, the quality of the work.

Check out this cost versus value report before you get into any renovations or remodels. We even have a professional stager on our staff who can tell you exactly which repairs will help your home sell for the most money.

If you have any questions, please don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/2017/Which+Home+Renovations+Get+the+Best+Returns%253F+-+Charleston+%2526+Mt.+Pleasant+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="davefriedmantv.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/2017/Which+Home+Renovations+Get+the+Best+Returns%253F+-+Charleston+%2526+Mt.+Pleasant+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Some renovations are better than others when it comes to preparing your home for the market. Think about the renovation cost versus the return you will get on your investment.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Friedman</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Some renovations are better than others when it comes to preparing your home for the market. Think about the renovation cost versus the return you will get on your investment.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Charleston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Introducing a Tool That Will Make 2017 Your Best Year Yet</title>
        <link>davefriedmantv.com/introducing-a-tool-that-will-make-2017-your-best-year-yet.html</link>
        
        <author>Dave Friedman</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-07 16:32:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/2017/Introducing+a+Tool+That+Will+Make+2017+Your+Best+Year+Yet+-+Charleston+%2526+Mt.+Pleasant.mp4</guid>
        <description>
Today I have a tool that I want to show you that will help you achieve the success you desire in 2017. This tool is a goal-setting template, and it’s the same one my team and I use to reach our goals. Within this template, there are 10 categories through which you can divide your goals for a more comprehensive personal and professional development:


  Professional Growth/Expanding Skillset
  Sales
  Team Culture
  Conversion
  Tracking
  Faith
  Family
  Fun
  Fitness
  Finances


The goal you set for each individual category should conform to the criteria of the SMART method. That is to say, your goal should be specific, measurable, attainable, realistic, and timely.

In the video above, I’ve used the finances category as an example of how effective this tool can be if one of your goals is moderating and protecting your monetary interests.

“I’m challenging you to implement this simple tool that will change your life.”

I really hope you use this tool so that 2017 is the best year you’ve ever had. I know that it’s going to create the best year for me, and I want the same for you, too. If you have any questions about this tool or would like me to email it to you, please reach out to me so I can share it with you. I would be happy to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/2017/Introducing+a+Tool+That+Will+Make+2017+Your+Best+Year+Yet+-+Charleston+%2526+Mt.+Pleasant.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="davefriedmantv.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/2017/Introducing+a+Tool+That+Will+Make+2017+Your+Best+Year+Yet+-+Charleston+%2526+Mt.+Pleasant.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>I have a tool that I want to show you that will help you make 2017 the best year of your life.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Friedman</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>I have a tool that I want to show you that will help you make 2017 the best year of your life.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Charleston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Are Rising Interest Rates Shaping Our Market?</title>
        <link>davefriedmantv.com/how-are-rising-interest-rates-shaping-our-market.html</link>
        
        <author>Dave Friedman</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-18 10:14:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/2017/How+Are+Rising+Interest+Rates+Shaping+Our+Market%253F+-+Charleston+%2526+Mt.+Pleasant.mp4</guid>
        <description>
In case you haven’t heard, the Federal Reserve increased interest rates last December and are planning an aggressive approach in 2017. Since the election, rates have risen in total by about 0.75%, and we can expect them to rise further by a full percentage point by mid-summer.

What does that mean for you as a buyer or seller?

If you’re a buyer, the same home that you could’ve purchased last year will now cost you more. The monthly payment for a $500,000 house, for example, will now cost $200 to $300 more. If you’re a seller, your buyer pool is shrinking because not as many homes are affordable to them anymore.

The good news is that we still have historically low inventory and interest rates. There are also still plenty of buyers out there looking to buy. We know this because, despite this uptick in rates, we still get a lot of inquiries. Buyers even have a bit more wiggle room to negotiate than they would have had in the past because there aren’t as many multiple offer situations happening.

If you’re planning on buying, do it now while you have a much better chance to lock in a low rate. If you’re a seller, you should also act now before your buyer pool shrinks even further thanks to those rising rates.

If you have any questions or are interested in buying or selling soon, feel free to pick up the phone and give me a call. I look forward to helping you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/2017/How+Are+Rising+Interest+Rates+Shaping+Our+Market%253F+-+Charleston+%2526+Mt.+Pleasant.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="davefriedmantv.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/2017/How+Are+Rising+Interest+Rates+Shaping+Our+Market%253F+-+Charleston+%2526+Mt.+Pleasant.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Interest rates are on the rise in our market. If you’re planning on buying or selling, here’s what you need to do.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Friedman</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Interest rates are on the rise in our market. If you’re planning on buying or selling, here’s what you need to do.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Charleston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What You Should Know About Flood Insurance</title>
        <link>davefriedmantv.com/what-you-should-know-about-flood-insurance.html</link>
        
        <author>Dave Friedman</author>
        <pubDate>2016-12-16 12:34:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/Old+Videos/What+You+Should+Know+About+Flood+Insurance+-+Charleston+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>
We all know that weather can be unpredictable, and although hurricane Matthew was luckily not as bad as we expected it to be, it showed how important it is to have flood insurance in the Charleston area.

Insurance expert Mark Allen dropped by to explain why it’s so important to have an insurance plan in place and what to look out for when selecting a policy. Here are some things to consider when selecting flood insurance:


  Think of your insurance policy as an invisible safety net. Living on the coast has its perks, but if Mother Nature takes a turn for the worse, having a plan to fall back on for repair or damage costs will make sure you can sleep easy.
  Most homeowners insurance policies will cover not only flood but also wind and hail damage. Making sure you cover all your bases when it comes to unpredictable weather is key. Luckily, you can select a policy that will have you covered in any circumstance.
  Make sure you check to see if you have one or several policies covering you for flood and weather related damage. Homeowners insurance should cover everything, and it’s much easier to have one policy than have several with different deductibles and coverages.
  Remember that not all policies are created equal. Different policies will include different deductibles or coverage amounts and different types of coverage as well. Make sure your policy is right for you and your home.
  Don’t fall for the “sticker price.” Many insurance agencies will try to sell you a policy without combing over the fine details. Different coverage amounts and types of coverage can sneak in, so make sure you know exactly what is and is not in your policy.
  Don’t forget about your personal items inside the home. Make sure you have proper coverage for both the inside and outside of your home.
  Talk to someone who will insure your home in the way they would want their home insured. 1. Finding an insurance agent who walks you through your policy and makes sure you understand all the details, like what you are taking out or including, will help make sure you are getting the right coverage for the right house.
  Get a flood quote. At the very least, you will understand what it is going to cost to include your personal items in your flood coverage.


If you have any further questions regarding flood or homeowners insurance feel free to give Mark a call, visit 1stCapitalIns.com, or shoot him an email. If you have any questions about the Charleston or Mt. Pleasant real estate markets or you’re considering buying or selling a home, give me a call or send me an email. I’d be happy to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/Old+Videos/What+You+Should+Know+About+Flood+Insurance+-+Charleston+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="davefriedmantv.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/Old+Videos/What+You+Should+Know+About+Flood+Insurance+-+Charleston+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>I sat down with insurance expert Mark Allen to find out the keys things you need to know when considering flood insurance.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Friedman</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>I sat down with insurance expert Mark Allen to find out the keys things you need to know when considering flood insurance.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Charleston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Meat and Potatoes of Homeowners Insurance</title>
        <link>davefriedmantv.com/the-meat-and-potatoes-of-homeowners-insurance.html</link>
        
        <author>Dave Friedman</author>
        <pubDate>2016-12-02 14:35:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/Old+Videos/The+Meat+and+Potatoes+of+Homeowners+Insurance+%2528Part+1%2529-+Charleston+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>
As we all know, weather isn’t exactly predictable. That’s why, as a homeowner, it’s absolutely necessary that you have an insurance plan in place that will protect you and your property in the long run. Insurance agents provide an invisible safety net that saves you money and time down the line.

With that in mind, today we’re joined by Mark Allen from 1st Capital Insurance to explain the basics of what sort of insurance plans you should investigate and the typical costs of obtaining them.

According to Mark, the number one thing that Lowcountry residents need to look out for when looking for insurance in a home are the deductibles. What are they covering? There are differences between an ‘all other peril’ (AOP) deductible and a ‘wind and hail’ and/or ‘named storm’ deductible. The named storm or wind and hail deductible is normally a percentage of your dwelling. For example, let’s say you have a $300,000 house and you have a 2% named storm or wind and hail deductible. That means your cost would be $6,000. The all other peril deductible has to do with fire, vandalism, theft, water damage, and other things of that nature.

As to how much flood insurance costs, it depends on your house’s location and its elevation. Normally people in Mark’s business get what is called an “elevation certificate,” which tells them how high the house is and how well the house is vented so that they know how much to charge appropriately.

To Mark’s estimate, the typical cost of a flood policy for a $300,000 to $500,000 home would be around $500 a year, which covers $250,000 on the building and $100,000 in contest. That’s the maximum that FEMA allows. You can get other policies that cover you over and above that, but that’s the typical FEMA policy.

“Lowcountry residents need to be mindful of deductibles.”

For homeowners living around water areas, Mark’s advice is to watch for how much the house would cost to rebuild, because that’s what insurance companies measure to determine their rate. If you make any major changes or renovations to your home, make sure to call your insurance company and update your policy information.

Stay tuned for part two of our series with Mark where we’ll cover the business of homeowners insurance in greater depth. In the meantime, if you want to get in touch with him, you can call his office at (843) 216-2772 or visit his company’s website at www.1stcapitalins.com, or email him at Mark@1stcapitalins.com.

If you have any other questions, feel free to give me a call or shoot me an email. I look forward to helping you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/Old+Videos/The+Meat+and+Potatoes+of+Homeowners+Insurance+%2528Part+1%2529-+Charleston+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="davefriedmantv.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/Old+Videos/The+Meat+and+Potatoes+of+Homeowners+Insurance+%2528Part+1%2529-+Charleston+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Getting homeowners insurance can only help you in the long run, but knowing what plan works best for you depends on a few important factors we’ll discuss today.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Friedman</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Getting homeowners insurance can only help you in the long run, but knowing what plan works best for you depends on a few important factors we’ll discuss today.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Charleston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Pie-ing and Selling in the Charleston Marketplace</title>
        <link>davefriedmantv.com/pie-ing-and-selling-in-the-charleston-marketplace.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Dave Friedman</author>
        <pubDate>2016-11-03 16:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/Old+Videos/Charleston+Real+Estate+Agent-+Our+pie+giveaway+and+our+shifting+market.mp4</guid>
        <description>
Today, I wanted to discuss our annual pie giveaway and give you a quick market update.

For years, our team has been giving away pies to all of our fans. It’s that time of year again, and we already have people calling us to RSVP for their pie. Because we’re so grateful to our wonderful community for supporting our business, giving you a pie is the least we can do.

To RSVP, please call us at (843) 972-3833 by the November 17th deadline. You can then pick up your pie at my office at 496 Bramson Court, Suite 200 in Mount Pleasant. The dates available for pickup are Nov. 21st from 9 a.m. to 3 p.m. and Nov. 22nd from 1 p.m. to 5 p.m.

“There aren’t many buyers out there, but there are even fewer sellers.”

Now, what’s happening in the Charleston real estate market? A lot of sellers are taking their houses off the market because they presume that there aren’t as many buyers out there. That is true; however, in midsummer, housing inventory hovered around 4.2 months, and now it’s at 3.9 months. That means you currently have better odds of selling your home now than you did a few months ago.

How? There are fewer buyers, but there are also even fewer sellers. That means less competition for you to deal with.

If you have any questions about buying or selling a home, please feel free to give me a call or shoot me an email for a free consultation or a free home evaluation report. I look forward to helping you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/Old+Videos/Charleston+Real+Estate+Agent-+Our+pie+giveaway+and+our+shifting+market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="davefriedmantv.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/Old+Videos/Charleston+Real+Estate+Agent-+Our+pie+giveaway+and+our+shifting+market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Our annual free pie giveaway is right around the corner, and if you have a house that you need to sell, now is the time to list it.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Friedman</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Our annual free pie giveaway is right around the corner, and if you have a house that you need to sell, now is the time to list it.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Charleston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Do Buyers Know If a Home Is Priced Fairly?</title>
        <link>davefriedmantv.com/how-do-buyers-know-if-a-home-is-priced-fairly.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Dave Friedman</author>
        <pubDate>2016-10-06 13:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/Old+Videos/Charleston+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+do+you+know+if+a+home+is+priced+fairly%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>
All home buyers have one thing in common: they do not want to get ripped off. In today’s increasingly busy housing market, sales have risen to 5.46 million, which, according to the National Association of Realtors, is 7.7% higher than last year. In this busy market, it’s especially important to make sure that you’re getting the right price.

How do you know if you’re getting a fair value? Even if you’re in a tight market, you can figure out if a home is priced fairly before you make the offer. There are certain ways you can evaluate whether the price of any home is a sound investment or if you’re getting ripped off.

First of all, look at recently sold comparable properties. Comparable properties are similar in size, condition, neighborhood, and amenities. Your real estate agent is your best resource for accurate, up-to-date information on comparable properties, also known as comps.

You should also look at comparable properties that are currently on the market, under contract, or not selling at all. If a comparable property failed to sell because it was overpriced, the property you are interested in is probably overpriced too.

“Look at comparable properties to see if the home you want is priced fairly.”

You also have to consider the appreciation rates in the area. Are prices going up? Are prices going down? What do the days on the market look like? If you are in a seller’s market with very low inventory, high demand, and low days on market, you will have a better idea of what a seller is willing to accept. In an appreciating market, you can buy now and reap the benefits of further appreciation down the line.

If you are in a market with high days on market, lots of inventory, and very little demand, then you know that prices are starting to depreciate. In that case, make sure you buy 5% to 10% below the market value so that you don’t lose value as prices continue to drop. In depreciating markets, you need to buy your equity up front in order to make the best investment.

If you have any other questions about determining market value or about real estate in general, give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/Old+Videos/Charleston+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+do+you+know+if+a+home+is+priced+fairly%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="davefriedmantv.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/Old+Videos/Charleston+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+do+you+know+if+a+home+is+priced+fairly%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>All home buyers have one thing in common: they do not want to get ripped off. Luckily, there are a few ways you can tell if a home is priced fairly.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Friedman</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>All home buyers have one thing in common: they do not want to get ripped off. Luckily, there are a few ways you can tell if a home is priced fairly.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Charleston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Can You Predict How Home Values Will Appreciate?</title>
        <link>davefriedmantv.com/can-you-predict-how-home-values-will-appreciate.html</link>
        
        <author>Dave Friedman</author>
        <pubDate>2016-09-16 13:56:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/Old+Videos/Charleston+Real+Estate+Agent-+Predicting+home+value+appreciation.mp4</guid>
        <description>
I’m often asked about appreciation, so I wanted to talk about how you can predict the annual appreciation or depreciation for your real estate investment.

My team and I study the market daily to predict appreciation rates for our clients. We look at sales over the last year compared to the current inventory, and based on this, we can determine the months of inventory.

Because real estate is very location-driven, the months of inventory will change from neighborhood to neighborhood. Months of inventory will determine the appreciation (or depreciation) rate you can expect for your home or investment. The future prospects for your chosen neighborhood can have a big impact on price.

If a big development is planned, such as a big mall or an extension of a light rail or highway, or there’s a new company moving to the area, the prospects of future appreciation look good. Even small developments like plans to add a road or a small school are good signs. On the other hand, if grocery stores and gas stations are slowly closing down, then you can probably determine that home values will depreciate, and you might consider moving out of the area.

New developments in housing can take it either way. If the area is hot, it’s likely in high demand and increasing your home’s value. However, if there is a surplus in new development (like a lot of new construction that you’re competing against), it could hurt the value of your home and your appreciation.

If a builder came in and bought land at a very good value and started developing a lot of homes and devaluing homes in the surrounding area because of what they started selling those homes at, it could have a negative impact on you.

If you’d like a report about appreciation rates in your specific area, I’d be more than happy to put one together for you at no cost. If you have any questions about the Charleston market, give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/Old+Videos/Charleston+Real+Estate+Agent-+Predicting+home+value+appreciation.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="davefriedmantv.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/Old+Videos/Charleston+Real+Estate+Agent-+Predicting+home+value+appreciation.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
I’m often asked about appreciation, so I wanted to talk about how you can predict the annual appreciation or depreciation for your real estate investment.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Friedman</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
I’m often asked about appreciation, so I wanted to talk about how you can predict the annual appreciation or depreciation for your real estate investment.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Charleston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Benefits of Owning a Home Over Renting One</title>
        <link>davefriedmantv.com/the-benefits-of-owning-a-home-over-renting-one.html</link>
        
        <author>Dave Friedman</author>
        <pubDate>2016-08-25 16:03:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/Old+Videos/Charleston+Real+Estate+Agent-+Owning+a+home+vs.+renting+one.mp4</guid>
        <description>
Why does it make more sense for a person to own a home rather than rent one? There are many benefits, but according to a recent study done by Harvard University, all of them fall under two categories: financial reasons and emotional reasons. These two reasons can sometimes overlap, but we’ll review some of the financials first.

For starters, housing is a leveraged investment. Ask yourself—what else can you get a 30-year fixed low-interest rate loan on for an investment? On top of that, homes in our area appreciate anywhere between 3% and 5% per year. The second financial benefit is that you’re paying for a home whether you own it or rent it. You need shelter and a place to live, right? You might as well own it and turn it into an investment instead of making your landlord rich.

The third financial benefit is that owning a home is a forced way of saving money. By that I mean a portion of that mortgage payment you’re making is going toward the principal that you owe on the home. As you pay that principal down over time, that becomes equity in your home. When you sell it, you get all of that money back.

There are also substantial benefits in regards to property taxes. For example, you can write off certain expenses of your home investment against your income. At the end of the year, then, you’ll either be paying less in taxes or getting a larger cash refund. For greater detail on all the specific tax benefits, be sure to talk to your CPA. Owning a home also allows you to hedge against inflation, since real estate is a tangible asset.

The emotional reasons need far less explanation. For one thing, we all share the basic human need for physical shelter. After that’s accomplished and you perhaps decide that you want children, you need a place to raise them. After those boxes are checked off, you have the ability to pass along wealth to your family. And finally, owning a home means having control over your living space.

If you have any questions about real estate or homeownership, give me a call or send me an email. I’d be happy to help you out!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/Old+Videos/Charleston+Real+Estate+Agent-+Owning+a+home+vs.+renting+one.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="davefriedmantv.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/Old+Videos/Charleston+Real+Estate+Agent-+Owning+a+home+vs.+renting+one.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
Why does it make more sense for a person to own a home rather than rent one? There are many benefits, but according to a recent study done by Harvard University, all of them fall under two categories: financial reasons and emotional reasons. These two reasons can sometimes overlap, but we’ll review some of the financials first.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Friedman</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
Why does it make more sense for a person to own a home rather than rent one? There are many benefits, but according to a recent study done by Harvard University, all of them fall under two categories: financial reasons and emotional reasons. These two reasons can sometimes overlap, but we’ll review some of the financials first.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Charleston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>We Want to Take You Out to the Ballgame</title>
        <link>davefriedmantv.com/we-want-to-take-you-out-to-the-ballgame.html</link>
        
        <author>Dave Friedman</author>
        <pubDate>2016-06-09 09:47:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/Old+Videos/Charleston+Real+Estate+Agent-+Were+taking+you+out+to+the+ball+game.mp4</guid>
        <description>
We want to invite you to a Charleston RiverDogs game at Joseph P. Riley Jr. Park as a way to say thank you, and we’re also raising money for charity. All of our friends, colleagues, and past and current clients are welcome. The game is on June 14th, and our free picnic will start at 6:00 p.m.

For every person that attends, we will donate $10 to the MUSC Children’s Fund in order to send children to Camp Can-Do, which is over on Seabrook Island.

Our goal is to donate at least $3,000, but we need your help to do so! We still have lots of tickets left, so just call the number on the screen and tell us how many tickets we should reserve.

There will be free food and drinks starting at 6:00 p.m., and the baseball game will start at 7:00 p.m.

Last but not least - it’s still a great time to sell a home in Charleston. We’re still in a seller’s market, but when rates rise it may be more difficult to sell a home. If you list now you can cash out and then buy a home when the market is in your favor.

Buyers should also be aware that it’s a great time to purchase with interest rates still so low. However, they may see a small rate hike in June that could affect affordability. If you’re thinking of buying, get in touch with us now before your affordability takes a hit and you’re knocked out of your ideal price bracket.

If you have any questions about this event or about our local real estate market, please don’t hesitate to contact me!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/Old+Videos/Charleston+Real+Estate+Agent-+Were+taking+you+out+to+the+ball+game.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="davefriedmantv.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/Videos/Old+Videos/Charleston+Real+Estate+Agent-+Were+taking+you+out+to+the+ball+game.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
We want to invite you to a Charleston RiverDogs game at Joseph P. Riley Jr. Park as a way to say thank you, and we’re also raising money for charity. All of our friends, colleagues, and past and current clients are welcome. The game is on June 14th, and our free picnic will start at 6:00 p.m.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Friedman</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
We want to invite you to a Charleston RiverDogs game at Joseph P. Riley Jr. Park as a way to say thank you, and we’re also raising money for charity. All of our friends, colleagues, and past and current clients are welcome. The game is on June 14th, and our free picnic will start at 6:00 p.m.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Charleston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Dave Friedman</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Dave Friedman</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Dave Friedman Team - your professional Charleston Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
