<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Michael Kaim Team - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Michael Kaim</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2017-05-01 13:02:54 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Michael Kaim</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>KaimTeam@gmail.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Michael Kaim</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Michael Kaim</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the  Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Michael Kaim Team - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sell Your Home Fast Using These 5 Tips</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/sell-your-home-fast-using-these-5-tips.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Michael Kaim</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-19 10:44:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Michael+Kaim/+Videos/2017/April/Northeast+Ohio+Real+Estate+Agent-+Sell+Your+Home+Fast+Using+These+5+Tips.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When selling your home, you want to make sure you sell quickly and for the most money. I’ll go over five tips that will help you do just that.


  
    Update your landscaping. Curb appeal is crucial. When we take exterior photos, which is the main presentation that we have online, you want to make sure the beds are clean and the landscaping looks good in order to attract the greatest amount of buyers.
  
  
    Move out of the house or make it appear as though you’re moved out. Declutter and rent a storage facility to store all of your belongings. Buyers want to be able to picture their own things in a home, which is much easier when your things aren’t there.
  


“IF YOU DON’T HAVE NEUTRAL COLORS, HAVE THE HOUSE PAINTED TO MAKE IT LOOK FRESH.”


  
    Add fresh paint or flooring as needed. If you don’t have neutral colors, have the house painted to make it look fresh. If your carpet is old, replace it.
  
  
    Utilize professional photos and video. These are the best ways to attract buyers and get them to want to see a home in person.
  
  
    Price your home to sell. Make sure you are staying competitive with your neighbors or even offering a better deal.
  


If you have questions about selling your home or if you have any other real estate questions, please feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Michael+Kaim/+Videos/2017/April/Northeast+Ohio+Real+Estate+Agent-+Sell+Your+Home+Fast+Using+These+5+Tips.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Michael+Kaim/+Videos/2017/April/Northeast+Ohio+Real+Estate+Agent-+Sell+Your+Home+Fast+Using+These+5+Tips.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Michael Kaim</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Now Is Such a Great Time to Sell Your House</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/why-now-is-such-great-time-to-sell-your.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Michael Kaim</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-15 13:09:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Michael+Kaim/+Videos/Michael+Kaim-+Why+Now+Is+Such+a+Great+Time+to+Sell+Your+House.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There are three big reasons why now is a great time to sell your house here in northeast Ohio.


  
    Consumer confidence: The election’s finally over, and we’re seeing record stock prices and a lot of homebuyers flooding the market.
  
  
    Interest rates are on the rise: After the recent rise, people are flocking to the market to buy a home before rates go up again. By the end of the year, rates are anticipated to go up quite a bit more, so even more buyers will want to lock in a low interest rate on their mortgage before this happens.
  


“HOMEBUYERS ARE FLOODING THE MARKET TO BUY BEFORE RATES GO UP AGAIN.”


  Inventory is extremely low: A ton of houses came off the market in the winter, and now I see a lot of houses listed again this year. Many of these sellers are pricing their homes to sell, meaning you can get as good of a deal or better than you could have last year.


If you’re considering selling your property this year, give me a call or send me an email soon before these favorable conditions expire. I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Michael+Kaim/+Videos/Michael+Kaim-+Why+Now+Is+Such+a+Great+Time+to+Sell+Your+House.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Michael+Kaim/+Videos/Michael+Kaim-+Why+Now+Is+Such+a+Great+Time+to+Sell+Your+House.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Michael Kaim</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Fall and Winter: Underrated Selling Seasons</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/fall-and-winter-underrated-selling.html</link>
        
          <category>Mentor</category>
        
          <category>ohio real estate other</category>
        
        <author>Michael Kaim</author>
        <pubDate>2014-10-15 15:24:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Michael+Kaim/Winter.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When fall rolls around, a lot of people decide it’s time to take their home off the market if it hasn’t sold, and wait until spring. Although this is the conventional way of thinking in the real estate business, it doesn’t mean that it’s absolute or definitive.

We are here today to tell you that the real estate business just doesn’t stop. In fact, there are a lot of advantages to keeping your home on the market during the latter part of the year. Here are 3 of them:


  
    Less competition
 There will be a lot of homes that come off the market in the next few weeks as it gets colder. In the fall selling season, there is a reduced amount of inventory, resulting in less competition
  
  
    More effective showings
 In the fall and winter, showings are extremely efficient. People won’t just be walking through a house during the cold winter season with snow on the ground if they aren’t serious buyers.
  
  
    You get a better price
 Every year, without fail, we get offers in November and December, typically from people who sold their home and are needing to buy now. As a result of low inventory, they will pay good money for a good home that they like, most often near asking price.
  

</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Michael+Kaim/Winter.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Michael+Kaim/Winter.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Michael Kaim</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Determine your Purchasing Power</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-to-determine-your-purchasing-power.html</link>
        
          <category>Chesterland greater cleveland real estate</category>
        
        <author>Michael Kaim</author>
        <pubDate>2014-08-13 16:28:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Michael+Kaim/Video+13.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Purchasing a home is a big deal. It’s one of the largest investments you will make and you want to make sure you are doing everything correctly so your transaction goes as smoothly as possible. We want all of you to accomplish this feat, so we will be sharing with you today the 1st 5 steps to take when you decide to purchase a home. These 5 factors will greatly affect your buying power and what kind of loan you will qualify for when purchasing a home.


  
    Get Pre-Qualified
 This is always the first step when you purchase a new home. Go talk to your lender and get this step squared away first. If you need to get in touch with a lender, we have a list of preferred lenders that we know and trust to put you on the right path.
  
  
    Credit Score
 Before you go in to talk to the lender, be sure your credit score is in order. This is the first thing that lenders will pull. They take 3 scores from the 3 different credit bureaus, and usually take the middle score. Usually a credit score of 620 or higher will get you qualified to purchase a home.
  
  
    Income and Job
 Next, lender will verify that you have solid employment and look at how long you have been employed with your current company. They also look at how much money you make and determine whether it will be you alone or whether a partner or spouse will be on the loan with you. If so, they will take their income and job into effect as well.
  
  
    Debt-to-Income Ratio
 This is a key component in determining your purchasing power. If you have a high income, but high debt, you may not qualify. This ratio is determined by your annual income divided by your expenses.
  
  
    Down Payment
 This is an essential factor. Setting a lot of money aside is a great way to increase your buying power. If, however, you can’t put a lot of money down, there are a lot of programs out there for you that don’t require you to put as much down, even if you’re a second or third time home buyer.
  

</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Michael+Kaim/Video+13.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Michael+Kaim/Video+13.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Michael Kaim</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Improve Your Credit Score</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-to-improve-your-credit-score.html</link>
        
        <author>Michael Kaim</author>
        <pubDate>2014-07-30 12:05:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Michael+Kaim/Ohio+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Welcome back to our video blog. Today we are going to talk about how to improve your credit score so you can buy a home. Your credit score is an essential piece ind determining your buying power. Today we are going to talk about the 3 main components you have to look at to increase your credit score. Here are the 3 steps to improving your score


  
    Know your credit score
There are a lot of different options out there for you to determine what your credit score is. There are 3 different bureaus that determine your score. You can get your scores directly from the Transunion, Equifax, and Experion bureaus, which you will have to pay for, or you can get them from any number of free credit score sites.
  
  
    Get your score up
In order to do this, you have to limit your debt and make sure you are managing your credit wisely. Making payments on time and reducing your amount of debt will help you out immensely.
  
  
    Get some help
For this step, you need to get out there and talk to someone who can help you out. A credit repair company is one option, or you can give us a call and we can get you in touch with some people that can help you out.
  


Thanks for taking the time to check out our blog today. If you have any questions about improving your credit score or anything else, please don’t hesitate to contact us. We would love to help you out.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Michael+Kaim/Ohio+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Michael+Kaim/Ohio+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Michael Kaim</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Improve Your Real Estate Career With This Amazing Opportunity</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/real-estate-career-ohio.html</link>
        
          <category>ohio real estate other</category>
        
        <author>Michael Kaim</author>
        <pubDate>2014-06-06 14:41:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Michael+Kaim/Improve+Your+Real+Estate+Career+with+this+Amazing+Opportunity.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Do you feel like your talents as a real estate agent are being underutilized? How much better do you think you could perform if you were negotiating 30-40 offers per week?  How about if you went on 10-15 listing presentations every week as well? I have an opportunity for you to do exactly this.

I am currently hiring a full-time licensed Realtor as an apprentice to work side by side with me to teach you the ins and outs of this business. This isn’t your typical part-time apprenticeship. It’s a full time position with salary and opportunities for bonuses

As an apprentice your responsibilities will include going on listing presentations with me and on my behalf. You will also be negotiating and writing offers for my clients, as well as prospecting and doing lead generations every  day. I’m not looking for a typical agent, however. The person who gets this job will need to have a lot of ambition. Somebody that is organized and carries themselves like a true professional.

This apprenticeship will last anywhere between 6 and 12 months, after which I will transition you to a full time sales position within my team. This is an opportunity you will not want to miss out on. The last two people we had in this position did between 4 and 5 million dollars in sales their first year!

If you are looking to take your career to the next level, give me a call at  (440)974-0404. Don’t miss out on this incredible opportunity!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Michael+Kaim/Improve+Your+Real+Estate+Career+with+this+Amazing+Opportunity.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Michael+Kaim/Improve+Your+Real+Estate+Career+with+this+Amazing+Opportunity.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Michael Kaim</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 Tips to Prepare Your Home For a Top-Dollar Sale</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-to-sell-your-home-for-highest-price.html</link>
        
          <category>Ohio Real Estate Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Michael Kaim</author>
        <pubDate>2014-05-23 13:04:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Michael+Kaim/5+Tips+to+Prepare+Your+Home+for+a+Top-Dollar+Sale.mp4</guid>
        <description>

5 Tips to Prepare Your Home For a Top Dollar Sale

Now is a great time to sell your home in Ohio. The spring and summer weather has heated up the market significantly, and if you’re considering selling then it would be wise to listen to my advice. My goal is to get you ready to sell for top dollar.


  
    Declutter: Make sure your counters are clean and clear of appliances. Remove any extra furniture or tables, chairs, etc. You don’t want your buyers to be distracted by an untidy home when they come and view your property. This can also help make your rooms look larger and more open and inviting.
  
  
    Touch Up Paint &amp; Clean Carpets: These two minor repairs can really improve the look of your home. Buyers love to see these things, and it instantly adds extra value to your property.
  
  
    Stage the House: This is one of the best tips that we have for our sellers. It really improves the overall look of your home and buyers usually feel much more comfortable in a home that has been staged properly by a professional. We have a professional stager that can assist you if you are interested in professionally staging your property.
  
  
    Check Maintenance Issues: Have a technician come and check your furnace and your air conditioner. Have your roof looked at and make sure that your septic system has been cleaned out. You could also consider having a pre-home inspection where an inspector will go through your property and tell you about any issues a buyer would bring up during a showing.
  
  
    Curb Appeal: People often forget that what draws buyers to their home is the exterior. It is very important to have a nice, green yard and fresh mulch. Plant flowers and also do a little spring clean up. Make sure everything looks fresh and crisp because the outside of your home is what draws buyers inside.
Like I said earlier, this is a great time to list in Ohio. We’re getting multiple offers on properties and selling lots of homes at full price. If you’re interested in selling your home, please do not hesitate to contact me.
  

</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Michael+Kaim/5+Tips+to+Prepare+Your+Home+for+a+Top-Dollar+Sale.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Michael+Kaim/5+Tips+to+Prepare+Your+Home+for+a+Top-Dollar+Sale.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Michael Kaim</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>It is a Great Time to Sell in Ohio and get More Money for your Home</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/its-awesome-time-to-sell-in-ohio.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Michael Kaim</author>
        <pubDate>2014-03-20 16:44:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Michael+Kaim/Mentor+Real+Estate+-+4+reasons+to+sell+your+home+this+Spring</guid>
        <description>

Should I Put My Home Up For Sale?
A lot of clients here in Northeast Ohio have been asking me lately if it’s a good idea to put their homes on the market. I actually have 4 reasons why it is a fantastic time to sell your home.


  
    Low Inventory: This is the lowest inventory that we’ve seen in years. With such a high demand for homes, you will be able to dictate what you want for your home, and you will likely receive multiple offers that will drive up the sales price of your home.
  
  
    Home Prices will Rise: Home values have increased by 10% in the last few years, and are expected to keep climbing. In Cleveland, some homes appreciated by 3-5% last year.
  
  
    Interest Rates Remain Low: Interest rates are at historical lows right now. You can get a rate below 5% right now, and this could save you hundreds of thousands of dollars over the life of a mortgage. If you’re a seller this will help you too because buyers will be spurred to action by the predictions of rising interest at the beginning of next year.
  
  
    Spring Rush: If you list now, you will be swarmed by buyers because this is the time of year that people look to buy homes. Plus the low inventory will funnel buyers right to your property, and you should be able to sell for top dollar.
These are my four reasons why you should sell, and I hope you’ve found them helpful. The thing to remember is that time is beginning to run out, so if you want to sell, do it soon to make sure that you beat the spring rush.
  


Be sure to contact me if you ever need help with real estate in Northeast Ohio.
Have a great day!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Michael+Kaim/Mentor+Real+Estate+-+4+reasons+to+sell+your+home+this+Spring" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Michael+Kaim/Mentor+Real+Estate+-+4+reasons+to+sell+your+home+this+Spring" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Michael Kaim</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Michael Kaim</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Michael Kaim</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Michael Kaim Team - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
