<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>New Haven & Fairfield County Real Estate Podcast with Jonathan Carbutti</title>
    <link>localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Carbutti & Co Realtors - your professional New Haven & Fairfield County Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Jonathan Carbutti</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2017-08-28 14:39:43 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Jonathan Carbutti</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in New Haven & Fairfield County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Jonathan.Carbutti@gmail.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Jonathan Carbutti</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Jonathan Carbutti</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in New Haven & Fairfield County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the New Haven & Fairfield County Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Carbutti & Co Realtors - your professional New Haven & Fairfield County Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to Alyssa’s Cakery</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/welcome-to-alyssas-cakery.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Jonathan Carbutti</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-23 07:09:29 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jonathan%20Carbutti/Community%20Spotlight-%20Welcome%20to%20Alyssas%20Cakery.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Have you been to Alyssa’s Cakery yet? If not, you’ll be pleasantly surprised to hear that this isn’t just another gourmet cupcake shop, it’s a full-blown bakery. Alyssa is with us today to talk about what they have to offer your sweet tooth. 

Of course, they have a wide variety of delicious baked goods, from mini cupcakes to scones, muffins, and iced coffee. They’ve also got mugs, candles, cards, and other items from local businesses for sale as well.

“They offer a variety of baked goods, not just cakes.”

They design custom wedding, anniversary, and birthday cakes for all different kinds of people. The more creative, the better, says Alyssa.

Their delicious food is just one of the things they offer. Every Tuesday through Friday, there’s a Ladies Night Out, where a group comes in with a bottle of wine to decorate their own cake! They do the same kind of thing for kids birthday parties as well (without the wine of course). The kids’ parties even have a pinata at the end.

Alyssa was born and raised in Wallingford, so she loves the fact that her shop is located right on Center St in the heart of the community. She takes pride in being part of the community and brings that attitude to her business each day. If you haven’t been to Alyssa’s Cakery yet, you need to go soon.

To learn more about Alyssa’s Cakery, visit their Facebook here and their Instagram here. 

If you or someone you know has a business that wants to be featured on one of our videos, let us know by reaching out via phone or email. We look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jonathan%20Carbutti/Community%20Spotlight-%20Welcome%20to%20Alyssas%20Cakery.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jonathan%20Carbutti/Community%20Spotlight-%20Welcome%20to%20Alyssas%20Cakery.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Alyssa’s Cakery is more than just cakes. Here are all the different things they offer.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Jonathan Carbutti</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Alyssa’s Cakery is more than just cakes. Here are all the different things they offer.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in New Haven & Fairfield County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Home Makeover Contest for Frustrated Sellers </title>
        <link>localhost:4000/the-carbutti-home-makeover-contest-is.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Jonathan Carbutti</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-25 11:14:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jonathan%20Carbutti/A%20Home%20Makeover%20Contest%20for%20Frustrated%20Sellers.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The Carbutti Home Makeover Contest is now open! If you’re a frustrated home seller, you have a chance to win a free home makeover that will help you finally sell that property.

Today I’m excited to announce that we are running a small contest.

We are looking for frustrated home sellers. If you’ve had your house on the market for awhile and it hasn’t sold yet for one reason or another, this contest is for you.

We will do a complete home makeover on your property. Our treat.

We’ll bring in a professional home staging company who will bring in new furniture and beautifully redecorate and rearrange your home. We will even paint and make small repairs—with your permission. Remember, all of these updates are on us.

“OUR GOAL IS TO HELP YOU SELL YOUR HOME.”

We will document the whole process from start to finish. Our goal is to succeed very quickly and sell your home, even if it failed to sell in the first place.

So, how do you enter the contest?

Simply send an email to jonathan.carbutti@gmail.com and include the subject line, “Carbutti Home Makeover Contest.” In the body of the email, briefly explain your situation and include your address and a valid phone number.

Then, we will reach out to you to ask a few more questions and interview you for the contest.

I look forward to reading your submissions and working on your home!
</description>
        <enclosure url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jonathan%20Carbutti/A%20Home%20Makeover%20Contest%20for%20Frustrated%20Sellers.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jonathan%20Carbutti/A%20Home%20Makeover%20Contest%20for%20Frustrated%20Sellers.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

The Carbutti Home Makeover Contest is now open! If you’re a frustrated home seller, you have a chance to win a free home makeover that will help you finally sell that property.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Jonathan Carbutti</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

The Carbutti Home Makeover Contest is now open! If you’re a frustrated home seller, you have a chance to win a free home makeover that will help you finally sell that property.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in New Haven & Fairfield County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Summer 2017 New Haven Market Update</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/today-i-wanted-to-give-you-update-on.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Jonathan Carbutti</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-17 12:34:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jonathan%20Carbutti/Summer%202017%20New%20Haven%20Market%20Update.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I wanted to give you an update on how the market is doing, and what that means for you as a seller.

Today I wanted to talk about how the market is doing, especially here in New Haven and around Wallingford.

The median list price in the Wallingford is around $299,900. The demand is actually increasing and the days on the market for properties are trending downward, so we’re actually seeing a lot more multiple offer situations on a lot of these properties, which is great for sellers. The market action index for Wallingford is around 36.2, which is incredible because about six months ago, it was under 30.

“WE’RE SEEING A LOT MORE MULTIPLE-OFFER SITUATIONS, WHICH IS GREAT FOR SELLERS.”

The market action index tells us how the market is doing by measuring what’s for sale versus what’s actually selling. Any market action index below a 30 implies a buyer’s advantage. Any index of a 30 or above implies a seller’s advantage.

So today’s value of 36.2 means a seller’s advantage, and it’s actually trending upward. What that means is if you’re thinking about selling your home, now is the time to put it on the market. There is high demand in Wallingford, New Haven, and Fairfield counties. In most of Connecticut, there is a high demand for homes. Yes, there is a lot of inventory, but there aren’t a lot of good homes for sale. Good homes tend to sell a lot quicker.

If you’re thinking about selling your home, give us a call and let us come down to take a look at your home. We’ll give you an honest, real estimate of what your home is worth. We’d also love to show you some of the innovative marketing that we’re doing to help get homes sold, like professional photography and videography.

If you have any questions about this topic or you’re looking to buy or sell a home, give me a call. I look forward to working with you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jonathan%20Carbutti/Summer%202017%20New%20Haven%20Market%20Update.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jonathan%20Carbutti/Summer%202017%20New%20Haven%20Market%20Update.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today I wanted to give you an update on how the market is doing, and what that means for you as a seller.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Jonathan Carbutti</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today I wanted to give you an update on how the market is doing, and what that means for you as a seller.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in New Haven & Fairfield County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Importance of Marketing & Positioning Your Home Online</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/the-importance-of-marketing-positioning.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Jonathan Carbutti</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-19 12:09:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jonathan%20Carbutti/The%20Importance%20of%20Marketing%20%2526%20Positioning%20Your%20Home%20Online.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Homes are getting left behind in today’s market because they’re not marketed properly online. There’s a way you can ensure your home doesn’t suffer the same fate.

If you’re a home seller, marketing and positioning your property online in today’s marketplace is critical.

Nobody knows better what buyers are looking for than the buyers themselves. They usually know whether a home is right for them within the first few minutes or even the first 30 to 60 seconds after walking in the front door. The problem is getting them excited enough to actually come see your property in person. If you can’t get them to commit to physically seeing your property, they’ll never have a chance fall in love with it.

One of the problems we’ve been experiencing in the marketplace is gorgeous properties being marketed and positioned all wrong. There are buyers in the marketplace whom these properties are perfect for, but these buyers overlook these properties because of the quality of their photos or videos or they lack professional photography and/or videos altogether.

“THERE’S NEVER BEEN A BETTER TIME TO MARKET YOUR HOME ONLINE.”

There has never been a better time to market your home online, and we can help you do it the right way. Our team offers professional photography, professional video services, professional floor plans, and 360-degree matterport videos that people can view from the comfort of their own home.

If you’re looking at selling your home and you’re looking to work with a professional real estate marketing company and not just a real estate agent, give us a call. We’d love to help you sell your house for top dollar.
</description>
        <enclosure url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jonathan%20Carbutti/The%20Importance%20of%20Marketing%20%2526%20Positioning%20Your%20Home%20Online.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jonathan%20Carbutti/The%20Importance%20of%20Marketing%20%2526%20Positioning%20Your%20Home%20Online.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Homes are getting left behind in today’s market because they’re not marketed properly online. There’s a way you can ensure your home doesn’t suffer the same fate.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Jonathan Carbutti</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Homes are getting left behind in today’s market because they’re not marketed properly online. There’s a way you can ensure your home doesn’t suffer the same fate.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in New Haven & Fairfield County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What a Fantastic Endorsement From Gary LeVox of Rascal Flatts</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/what-fantastic-endorsement-from-gary.html</link>
        
          <category>Carbutti Realtors</category>
        
        <author>Jonathan Carbutti</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-18 15:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jonathan%20Carbutti/What%20a%20Fantastic%20Endorsement%20from%20Gary%20LeVox%20of%20Rascal%20Flatts.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Recently, we were fortunate enough to be endorsed by Gary LeVox of Rascal Flatts. Here’s what he had to say about our team.

We were fortunate enough to recently land an endorsement from one of our favorite musicians, Gary LeVox of Rascal Flatts. You can check out the full endorsement in the video above, but what really stood out to us was that the message of his music and the message of our business aren’t so different after all.

“When ‘I’m Moving On’ won the award for ACM song of the year, it struck a chord with folks who understand the challenges that come with life’s big changes. For many, that time comes when they sell their home. If you’re moving on, you want a team that will make selling your home easy and stress-free.” - Gary LeVox

“IT’S ALWAYS OUR GOAL TO MAKE THINGS AS STRESS-FREE AS POSSIBLE.”

He hit the nail on the head there. It’s always our goal to make things as stress-free as possible for all of our buyers and sellers. We outsold every agent in Fairfield and New Haven County in 2016 and if we can’t sell your home at a price and deadline that we both agree to, we will buy it.

If you have any questions for us, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jonathan%20Carbutti/What%20a%20Fantastic%20Endorsement%20from%20Gary%20LeVox%20of%20Rascal%20Flatts.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jonathan%20Carbutti/What%20a%20Fantastic%20Endorsement%20from%20Gary%20LeVox%20of%20Rascal%20Flatts.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Recently, we were fortunate enough to be endorsed by Gary LeVox of Rascal Flatts. Here’s what he had to say about our team.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Jonathan Carbutti</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Recently, we were fortunate enough to be endorsed by Gary LeVox of Rascal Flatts. Here’s what he had to say about our team.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in New Haven & Fairfield County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Kind Words From Danny Lyons About Carbutti & Co.</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/kind-words-from-danny-lyons-about.html</link>
        
          <category>Carbutti Realtors</category>
        
        <author>Jonathan Carbutti</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-15 15:02:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jonathan%20Carbutti/Danny%20Lyons%20Testimonial%20for%20Carbutti%20%2526%20Co.mp4</guid>
        <description>

We appreciate all the kind words we receive from our past clients. Here’s one of them, WEBE 108’s Danny Lyons.

We were recently fortunate enough to talk to Danny Lyons from WEBE 108 right in the Lyon’s Den. Danny has worked with us in the past and has a lot of nice things to say about his experience, such as:

“Jonathan’s a family man. That’s really important to me. He’s also loyal like I am. I’ve been loyal to my listeners for over 30 years and I know that if you were to hire Jonathan to be your agent, he would be loyal to you and commit himself completely to getting the job done.”

“WE’RE PROUD TO HAVE DANNY IN OUR CORNER.”

A lot of real estate companies have their phone lines set up to go to a switchboard or a team of ISAs who may or may not be able to connect you with the person you’re looking for, even if you just had a quick question. That’s not what we do, as Danny points out.

“When you call that number, I think it’s Jonathan’s cell phone. The first time I called it, he answered the phone. To me, that means a lot. To be able to get right through to the guy who has his name on the company? That’s customer service.”

Thanks to Danny for the kind words. We appreciate having him in our corner. If you have any questions for us or want to know what we can do specifically to help you with your real estate goals, give us a call or send us an email. We would love to hear from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jonathan%20Carbutti/Danny%20Lyons%20Testimonial%20for%20Carbutti%20%2526%20Co.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jonathan%20Carbutti/Danny%20Lyons%20Testimonial%20for%20Carbutti%20%2526%20Co.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

We appreciate all the kind words we receive from our past clients. Here’s one of them, WEBE 108’s Danny Lyons.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Jonathan Carbutti</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

We appreciate all the kind words we receive from our past clients. Here’s one of them, WEBE 108’s Danny Lyons.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in New Haven & Fairfield County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why HUD Homes Are Hidden Gems in Our Market</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/why-hud-homes-are-hidden-gems-in-our.html</link>
        
          <category>New Haven and Fairfield County Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Jonathan Carbutti</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-06 12:56:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jonathan%20Carbutti/HUD%20Homes%20in%202017.mp4</guid>
        <description>

HUD homes are a great option for buyers. Here’s why.

I know, I sound like a broken record talking about HUD homes. You’re probably sick of me talking about them, but listen. The reason I’m continuing to discuss these homes is because I want to get some of you off the fence by seeing the incredible value here.

Just this morning, a three bedroom, one bathroom home came on the market in Wallingford. It’s a 3-bedroom, one-bathroom, and a one-car garage home on a half-acre lot. This home is currently listed for sale at $149,000. It’s available to owner-occupants first, meaning that if you plan on living in the property, you get the first shot at it.

Here’s the other great news about this HUD home in particular. It’s marked as insurable. That means is that HUD will sell this property to someone who is going for an FHA mortgage and insure it for only a 3.5% down payment.

If you’re a first-time buyer, you would have to be crazy not to consider jumping on these homes. Yes, they might need a paint job or new flooring, but the bones are all there. If an HUD home is marked as insurable, that means the electric, plumbing, and furnace all work, so you don’t have to worry about replacing them, unless you find something different at your inspection.

“AN INSURED HUD HOME IS IDEAL.”

Another great thing about HUD homes is that you can inspect them. A lot of people think they can’t, but they’re wrong. It’s true that you do have to buy these properties as-is, but an inspection can be a very useful tool in deciding whether you’re making the right decision. If you have an inspection done and find something wrong with the home you didn’t know about before, you have two options. You can either make the decision to go through with the purchase or you can back out of the deal, get your deposit back, and go buy something else.

I’m oversimplifying the process, but the truth is that it is simple for me because I’ve sold and purchased so many of them. I’ve sold and bid on hundreds of HUD homes. If you have any questions about them whatsoever or would like more details about what the process is like, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. We look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jonathan%20Carbutti/HUD%20Homes%20in%202017.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jonathan%20Carbutti/HUD%20Homes%20in%202017.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

HUD homes are a great option for buyers. Here’s why.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Jonathan Carbutti</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

HUD homes are a great option for buyers. Here’s why.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in New Haven & Fairfield County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Latest Trends in Our Local Real Estate Market </title>
        <link>localhost:4000/the-latest-trends-in-our-local-real.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Jonathan Carbutti</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-27 13:15:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jonathan%20Carbutti/January%202017%20Real%20Estate%20Market%20Update%20Report.mp4</guid>
        <description>

How is the market doing in Wallingford and New Haven County? This January has been the busiest start to a new year that we’ve seen in awhile, and it looks like the spring market will be extremely busy, too.

Here is your market update for Wallingford and New Haven County:

The median list price is at $299,900. That is the median list price, not the median sales price. Inventory has been tightening and days on market are decreasing, which is great news for sellers.

Personally, I’ve noticed that January of 2017 has been the busiest start to a new year that we’ve seen in three years. If that’s any indication of how the spring market is going to be, things are looking good.

“IT LOOKS LIKE THE SPRING MARKET WILL BE AN EXTREMELY BUSY ONE!”

If you are looking to upgrade from your first home, now is one of the best times to do so. You will get the most house for your money because of these low interest rates. Rates are expected to rise as the year goes on, so the sooner you can buy, the better. Remember, as interest rates go up, your buying power goes down.

One of the other things I want to point out is the market action index. The market action index tells us how the market is doing by measuring what’s for sale versus what’s actually selling. Anything 30 or below means that the buyer has an advantage in the market, while anything over 30 means that sellers have the advantage. Right now, the market action index is at 29.1, so the market is fairly balanced. However, that number is heading upwards, which is good news for sellers.

If you have any other questions about the marketplace or about selling your home, give us a call or send us an email. My team and I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jonathan%20Carbutti/January%202017%20Real%20Estate%20Market%20Update%20Report.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jonathan%20Carbutti/January%202017%20Real%20Estate%20Market%20Update%20Report.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

How is the market doing in Wallingford and New Haven County? This January has been the busiest start to a new year that we’ve seen in awhile, and it looks like the spring market will be extremely busy, too.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Jonathan Carbutti</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

How is the market doing in Wallingford and New Haven County? This January has been the busiest start to a new year that we’ve seen in awhile, and it looks like the spring market will be extremely busy, too.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in New Haven & Fairfield County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Happy New Year</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/happy-new-year.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Jonathan Carbutti</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-04 15:49:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Happy New Year!

It’s the start of a new year, and I wanted to give you an important real estate tip. The spring market starts now! Even if you’re thinking about putting your house on the market in May or June, you should be speaking with a real estate professional now, to come up with a game-plan.

If you’re thinking about putting your home on the market, please contact us for a free consultation. We’ll be happy to set up an appointment with you to go over the value of your home, and our marketing plans.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Happy New Year!

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Jonathan Carbutti</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Happy New Year!

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in New Haven & Fairfield County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Holiday Greetings from Carbutti & Company</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/holiday-greetings-from-carbutti-company.html</link>
        
          <category>Happy Holidays</category>
        
        <author>Jonathan Carbutti</author>
        <pubDate>2016-12-20 14:39:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jonathan%20Carbutti/Happy%20Holidays%202016%2521.mp4</guid>
        <description>

As the year winds down, I wanted to send you a special message. Thanks for your support this year.

I just wanted to take a moment to stop by and wish everyone happy holidays and a happy New Year.

2016 was a record-breaking year here at Carbutti &amp; Company, and I just wanted to say thank you to everyone who supported us and tell you how grateful I am that you chose us to help you with your real estate needs.

I am looking forward to seeing each and every one of you in 2017. God bless, have a great holiday, and I look forward to talking to you next year. If you have any questions or any real estate needs in the meantime, give me a call or send me an email. We’re always here to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jonathan%20Carbutti/Happy%20Holidays%202016%2521.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jonathan%20Carbutti/Happy%20Holidays%202016%2521.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

As the year winds down, I wanted to send you a special message. Thanks for your support this year.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Jonathan Carbutti</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

As the year winds down, I wanted to send you a special message. Thanks for your support this year.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in New Haven & Fairfield County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Renovation Loans Are Available?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/what-renovation-loans-are-available.html</link>
        
          <category>New Haven Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Jonathan Carbutti</author>
        <pubDate>2016-11-10 15:13:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jonathan%20Carbutti/Renovation%20Loans.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Home renovation loans are great for homeowners and investors alike. You can make your home look just the way you want it with any of these products.

There is a lot of confusion surrounding renovation loans. Can you really borrow money to fix up your home and make it exactly the way you want it to be?

The answer is yes. There are some really great renovation loan products in the marketplace right now. For example, the FHA 203k renovation loan is a federally insured mortgage that allows you to use just 3.5% of your own money. You can also build in the cost of the rehab right into the loan.

“THERE ARE SOME GREAT RENOVATION LOAN PRODUCTS IN THE MARKETPLACE RIGHT NOW.”

Another renovation loan you might not have heard of is the Fannie Mae HomeStyle Renovation Mortgage. This program is for owner-occupants who want to fix up the home and live there.

If you are an investor, there is also a great product out there for you. You can use just 15% of your own money for the whole renovation, flip the house, and then resell for a profit.

We use a great company called Prospect Mortgage, one of the largest renovation loan providers in the country. We would be happy to refer you to them.

In fact, Carbutti &amp; Co. Realtors will be teaming up with Prospect Mortgage to provide an informative seminar for people looking to buy a home. This seminar will help potential home buyers understand some of the in’s and out’s of the home buying process that you might not be aware of if you have never gone through this complex process. Click here to register for that seminar on Tuesday, December 6th from 6:00pm-9:00pm.

If you want to find out more about these renovation loans, give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you out!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jonathan%20Carbutti/Renovation%20Loans.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jonathan%20Carbutti/Renovation%20Loans.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Home renovation loans are great for homeowners and investors alike. You can make your home look just the way you want it with any of these products.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Jonathan Carbutti</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Home renovation loans are great for homeowners and investors alike. You can make your home look just the way you want it with any of these products.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in New Haven & Fairfield County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Do Professional Home Staging Companies Work?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-do-professional-home-staging.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Jonathan Carbutti</author>
        <pubDate>2016-09-15 14:46:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

We recently took a vacant home and had it professionally staged before it hit the market. Today, I wanted to introduce you to Jennifer Napolitano with Design House Interiors, the company that staged the property.

Jennifer is a certified home stager. She knows that selling a home can sometimes be very daunting. When people come into your home, they might not know where to put their furniture or how it’s going to look, which makes things very stressful for the buyers as well. Certain layouts and rooms can be difficult to stage, but home stagers are here to help you figure it out.

For example, keep in mind that scale is very important. You need the right-sized pieces in each room so that the rooms appear bigger and functional. Having the right furniture in each space also shows buyers the traffic patterns in the home.

When you work with Design House Interiors, you also get the benefit of working with professional interior designers. Jennifer and her team can help you make your home look great by choosing fresh, trendy pieces to make your home pop. Your home will be showroom-ready when it hits the real estate market.

This particular house had an island in the kitchen, and it is a nice-looking piece of furniture that stands out. When you are working with the bedrooms, it can be difficult to figure out where to put the bed because the bed is the focal point of the room. It needs to make a statement and look beautiful.

For this house, Jennifer and her team decided to put the bed a little off-center on the wall. It’s a great focal point and the buyer can still see that there is plenty of room to add a dresser and still walk around the space.

They also created an easy flow in the dining room by using a circular dining room table. As you can see in the video above, home staging is an absolute must to help buyers figure out how they can best utilize the space for their family.

“YOUR HOME WILL BE SHOWROOM-READY WHEN IT HITS THE MARKET.”

This home sold three days after it hit the market, so I want to say a huge thank you to Design House Interiors. If you need to stage your home or if you have any questions about interior design, visit their website at designhousect.com or visit their showroom at 6 North Main Street in Wallingford.

As always, if you have any real estate questions, please don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

We recently took a vacant home and had it professionally staged before it hit the market. Today, I wanted to introduce you to Jennifer Napolitano with Design House Interiors, the company that staged the property.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Jonathan Carbutti</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

We recently took a vacant home and had it professionally staged before it hit the market. Today, I wanted to introduce you to Jennifer Napolitano with Design House Interiors, the company that staged the property.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in New Haven & Fairfield County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Jonathan Carbutti</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Jonathan Carbutti</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Carbutti & Co Realtors - your professional New Haven & Fairfield County Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
