<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Dallas Real Estate Podcast with Chad Smith</title>
    <link>localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Chad Smith Real Solutions Team - your professional Dallas Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Chad Smith</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2017-07-20 11:00:19 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Chad Smith</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dallas, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>thechadsmithteam@gmail.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Chad Smith</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Chad Smith</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dallas, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Dallas Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Chad Smith Real Solutions Team - your professional Dallas Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>What You Need to do to Get Your Home Ready for Sale</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/arlington-texas-real-estate.html</link>
        
          <category>seller tips</category>
        
        <author>Chad Smith</author>
        <pubDate>2014-06-25 15:34:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Chad+Smith/6.15/Arlington+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Have+Great+Curb+Appeal.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Summertime is here in Dallas and the market is heating up. Many people are getting ready to sell their homes this summer, so we thought we would provide some helpful tips on what a seller really needs to do in order to sell their home.

When you are getting ready to sell, you obviously want to have your home looking as good as possible. What i’m going to tell you today is probably a little different than you might expect.

The number 1 things most sellers think about when preparing their home for sale is curb appeal. While I agree that the home does need to look good from the outside, I would advise against putting a lot of money into the outer appearance of your home. Let me tell you why.

90% of all home buyers start their home searches online. Since 2008, we have used professional photography and professional staging for most of our homes because those pictures of your home that you have online are so important in today’s market.

Having great curb appeal was the first impression in the past. Today, those online photographs are your first impression and our use of professional photography is what has gotten us such great results for our clients.

In terms of getting the rest of your home ready, I recommend we set an appointment together. We can advise you on what renovations or improvements to make so that you can **get the best return possible for your home. **

If you would like more information on how to get your home ready to sell, please give us a call. We look forward to talking with you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Chad+Smith/6.15/Arlington+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Have+Great+Curb+Appeal.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Chad+Smith/6.15/Arlington+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Have+Great+Curb+Appeal.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Summertime is here in Dallas and the market is heating up. Many people are getting ready to sell their homes this summer, so we thought we would provide some helpful tips on what a seller really needs to do in order to sell their home.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Chad Smith</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Summertime is here in Dallas and the market is heating up. Many people are getting ready to sell their homes this summer, so we thought we would provide some helpful tips on what a seller really needs to do in order to sell their home.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dallas, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Sell Your Home Quickly and For Top Dollar: Make Sure It's Priced Accurately</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/arlington-real-estate-home-price-is.html</link>
        
          <category>seller tips</category>
        
        <author>Chad Smith</author>
        <pubDate>2014-02-14 12:03:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today we wanted to talk about the importance of pricing but before I go into that, I wanted to point out a few features of my blog. If you’re looking to buy a home, follow the link on our blog that will give you the most up to date information about the available properties. We also have a home valuation tool if you’re interested in the current value of your home.

**What Determines Whether and Propery Sells or Not **

There are three things that will determine whether or not a property will sell: how it is priced, the condition and how it shows and the marketing. If you’re working with a great realtor, they will team up with you to decide on the price and on the condition. The profession, proactive realtors know how to maximize your exposure in terms of marketing.

**What is the Most Important Factor **

Out of all of these determining factors, pricing makes for 80% of its success. When pricing your home, realize that you’re in a competition and at some point you have to win first place. When buyers choose properties, they narrow down their top 5-8 choices. After those choices are made, buyers drive to these properties to view them in person. If you or someone you know has listed a home and it never showed, usually that means that they were very far out of the price bracket they would have sold in.

If you price your home and it shows consistently but you never get an offer, you become the home that sells the other houses. Buyers look at your house but compare it to a reasonably priced home and make an offer on it. Only when your home is priced right where the home should sell is where you will maximize your opportunity. When you make it to that point, buyers who have to buy that day will converge on your home and create a multiple offer scenario.

When our clients are able to listen to us, analyze market data realistically and we price the home right where it should sell, we generate multiple offers. This is a very consistent trend and we have even been selling homes for more than what they’re listed for. A professional realtor understands how important price is and studies the market on a daily basis.

If you or someone you know needs help selling a property, I would be honored to sit down with them and analyze their situation. Thanks and have a great day!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today we wanted to talk about the importance of pricing but before I go into that, I wanted to point out a few features of my blog. If you’re looking to buy a home, follow the link on our blog that will give you the most up to date information about the available properties. We also have a home valuation tool if you’re interested in the current value of your home.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Chad Smith</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today we wanted to talk about the importance of pricing but before I go into that, I wanted to point out a few features of my blog. If you’re looking to buy a home, follow the link on our blog that will give you the most up to date information about the available properties. We also have a home valuation tool if you’re interested in the current value of your home.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dallas, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What You Can Expect to see in the North Texas Real Estate Market in 2014</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/arlington-tx-real-estate-market-update.html</link>
        
          <category>Arlington Texas Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Chad Smith</author>
        <pubDate>2014-02-06 10:39:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

I am always asked about the current state of the market; so today we will talk about what 2014 real estate in North Texas will look like.

One of the important things to consider when looking ahead to 2014 is to understand what happened at the end of 2013 for our local area. December 2013 showed a 20% increase in the volume of sales in comparison to December 2012. It actually was the highest sales volume in our recorded history! As a matter of fact, each of the last 10 months of 2013 was the biggest month of North Texas realty. Rolling in 2014, that is exactly what we’re looking at.

Most price points show the evidence of a seller’s market. The reasoning behind this is the lower number of foreclosures coming onto the market. Since more people are relocating into North Texas more than any other major metropolitan area in the nation, new home builders are cranking back into full swing. With interest rates still staying low, our outlook for 2014 is very strong. Due to the Fed tapering back their stimulus package, interest rates may be on the rise.

However, there is no one answer for everybody. Here at the Chad Smith Team, we focus on taking all of this information and listening to what’s most important for our clients. From there, we let them know what is most important; it may or may not be the right time to make a move in the market and we understand that.

If you or anyone you know is weighing the option of making a move this year, we would love to sit down with you analyze your situation so you can make a sound business decision. Thanks and have a great day!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

I am always asked about the current state of the market; so today we will talk about what 2014 real estate in North Texas will look like.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Chad Smith</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

I am always asked about the current state of the market; so today we will talk about what 2014 real estate in North Texas will look like.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dallas, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Is Now the Right Time to Sell?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/is-now-right-time-to-sell.html</link>
        
        <author>Chad Smith</author>
        <pubDate>2013-10-31 13:34:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

As we progress through fall and into winter, I wanted to give you a quick market update. So far, it has been an amazing year for real estate. Summer is usually the hottest time for the market and when autumn sets in, people feel as if they should wait out the market until spring. Historically, the middle of summer is always the peak time for real estate with the sales volume dropping going into fall. This year is following the same trend; however, September 2013 is 30% higher in North Texas than it was last year. There are more homes selling versus homes coming on the market now than in the last 10-15 years. Although we always hear summer is the best time to sell, right now that isnt the case. If you were to list your home now, you would have less competition at any point in the last decade.

With these big opportunities, I wanted to point out a few things about listing your home in the fall and winter months. You will typically have fewer showings; however, the showings will be much higher quality. If someone is coming to look at your home in the middle of the holidays, you know theyre for real. Another benefit of buying now is that if you were to buy your home in the spring, you would be able to write a non-contingent offer since your home is already sold.

With the market set up perfectly to sell, I would like to offer you a free home evaluation. I will sit down with you and analyze exactly what is happening with your home in your immediate area and figure out if the right time to sell is now. If youre interested, call me at (817) 635-1019 or email me at thechadsmithteam@gmail.com. I look forward to talking to you soon. e at (817) 635-1019 or email me at thechadsmithteam@gmail.com. I look forward to talking to you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

As we progress through fall and into winter, I wanted to give you a quick market update. So far, it has been an amazing year for real estate. Summer is usually the hottest time for the market and when autumn sets in, people feel as if they should wait out the market until spring. Historically, the middle of summer is always the peak time for real estate with the sales volume dropping going into fall. This year is following the same trend; however, September 2013 is 30% higher in North Texas than it was last year. There are more homes selling versus homes coming on the market now than in the last 10-15 years. Although we always hear summer is the best time to sell, right now that isnt the case. If you were to list your home now, you would have less competition at any point in the last decade.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Chad Smith</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

As we progress through fall and into winter, I wanted to give you a quick market update. So far, it has been an amazing year for real estate. Summer is usually the hottest time for the market and when autumn sets in, people feel as if they should wait out the market until spring. Historically, the middle of summer is always the peak time for real estate with the sales volume dropping going into fall. This year is following the same trend; however, September 2013 is 30% higher in North Texas than it was last year. There are more homes selling versus homes coming on the market now than in the last 10-15 years. Although we always hear summer is the best time to sell, right now that isnt the case. If you were to list your home now, you would have less competition at any point in the last decade.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dallas, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Chad Smith</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Chad Smith</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Chad Smith Real Solutions Team - your professional Dallas Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
