<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Utah Real Estate Podcast with David Robinson</title>
    <link>http://www.canovogroup.tv</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://www.canovogroup.tv"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Canovo Group - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>The Canovo Group</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2017-08-18 12:26:54 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>The Canovo Group</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Info@canovogroup.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>The Canovo Group</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>The Canovo Group</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the  Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Canovo Group - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why a Discount Brokerage Isn't the Best for Selling Your Home</title>
        <link>http://www.canovogroup.tv/why-a-discount-brokerage-isnt-the-best-for-selling-your-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>The Canovo Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-26 06:46:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+The+benefits+of+going+with+a+pro.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I’m with my good friend Ali Garbero, who is a listing specialist on our team. She’s been a good friend for a long time, knows the business very well, and is one of the top agents in our market.

Awhile back, we did a video talking about Homie and some of the services they provide, as well as the advantages and disadvantages of working with them. There have been a few recent developments involving Homie.

As you know, they have been promoting working with their service over using a real estate agent to buy or sell property and, in an ironic twist, they just became a real estate brokerage. As far as I understand, they were under investigation by the Division of Real Estate—who was trying to determine if they were practicing real estate without a license—and now they’re a real estate brokerage.

So today, I’ve brought Ali on to talk about the benefits of working with a professional real estate agent or team rather than working with any one of these discount brokerages.

“People need people, and when you’re selling a home, it’s more than just the very black and white transaction,” Ali says. Selling a home involves a lot of emotion—you’re negotiating one of your largest if not the largest asset that you have, and it affects your bottom line financially.

Having someone to walk you through the process step-by-step, especially if you’ve never sold your home or it’s your second time going through it, will make the entire transaction easier.

Working with a professional real estate agent means you also have access to a network of professional vendors. “Getting a home sell-ready is also going to be a process,” Ali says, is a valuable asset.

Ultimately, it’s an emotional process selling your home. Having a trusted advisor to help you make decisions is a welcome thing. Additionally, she says, “We’re so confident we’re going to sell your home for top dollar and the least amount of time, that we really charge no upfront costs to start working with us.

The discount brokerages will charge you upfront, and then they really have no skin in the game. If your home sells for top dollar or for rock bottom price doesn’t matter— they’ve already been paid. When you work with a professional agent, you can rest assured that they only get paid when the home sells.

“Professional agents only get paid when the home sells.”

Here at the Canovo Group, we don’t charge any upfront fees. We have a very flexible commission structure and a cancellation guarantee. If you’re not happy with our services, you can cancel our agreement with you at any time, for any reason, and without any repercussions.

Our flexible commission structure works like this: we have a 7% commission structure on the high end, which is usually for homeowners who have a huge remodel or another project that needs to be done on their home, but don’t want to deal with contractors personally. So we’ll take that on with the commission and manage the entire transaction for them.

Another part of our commission structure is the more traditional 6% commission, where we represent the seller exclusively and another agent represents the buyer. In this transaction, we would share 3% of our commission with the buyer’s agent.

Lastly, if we have a client who is interested in just having us manage the transaction itself—they’ve already found a buyer and just need help getting through all the paperwork—then we will service that client for 1% of the sales price of the property.

If you have any questions for me or Ali about this topic, or you’re looking to buy or sell a home, please give us a call. We would love to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+The+benefits+of+going+with+a+pro.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.canovogroup.tv" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+The+benefits+of+going+with+a+pro.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I have listing specialist Ali Garbero with me to talk about the benefits of working with a professional real estate agent or team.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Canovo Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I have listing specialist Ali Garbero with me to talk about the benefits of working with a professional real estate agent or team.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What’s the Biggest Challenge Facing Sellers in Our Utah Market?</title>
        <link>http://www.canovogroup.tv/whats-the-biggest-challenge-facing-sellers-in-our-utah-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>The Canovo Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-11 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+Common+challenges+in+our+Utah+market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What are some of the challenges sellers currently face in our market?

According to Dane Hill, our director of operations who has extensive experience in transaction management, one of the biggest challenges is appraisal issues. There is a lot of demand but not a lot of track record of homes being sold for the prices which the current market warrants.

For example, we can encourage a client of ours to list a home at $375,000 and they can get an offer for $395,000, but once the buyer tries to get an appraisal done to satisfy their financing obligations, the appraiser won’t have enough track record of other sales at that price to warrant that $395,000 offer. The lender will only lend at what the home appraises for, so in this situation the buyer has to come up with the extra cash to close the difference or both parties have to renegotiate the sale price so the buyer can close on it.

Each home sale is unique, but the most common way to settle a low-appraisal situation like this is for the buyer and seller to meet in the middle between what the offer price is and where the appraisal came in at.

The seller typically loses some concessions during this process. If they’re paying the buyer’s closing costs, then they’ll remove those from the contract and/or drop the home warranty or other repairs they’d previously negotiated. In return, they’ll drop the price so the buyer can get the loan and close on the property.

If both parties can’t find some common ground to make the sale work, the buyer will usually cancel their offer and the seller will relist their property for another buyer who perhaps has more cash or is in a better financial situation.

I want to give special thanks to Dane for joining me today to discuss this topic. There are other potential solutions to this problem that we didn’t get into, so if you have any questions about this topic or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d be glad to help.

“The buyer and seller usually meet somewhere in the middle to resolve a low appraisal.”
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+Common+challenges+in+our+Utah+market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.canovogroup.tv" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+Common+challenges+in+our+Utah+market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Low appraisals are one of the most common issues hounding sellers in our market. There are a couple ways to resolve a situation like this during a home sale.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Canovo Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Low appraisals are one of the most common issues hounding sellers in our market. There are a couple ways to resolve a situation like this during a home sale.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Risks of Selling Your Home Without a Professional Agent</title>
        <link>http://www.canovogroup.tv/the-risks-of-selling-your-home-without-a-professional-agent.html</link>
        
        <author>The Canovo Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-03 04:05:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+Be+wary+of+going+down+this+path.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I recently had a conversation with a group of my top agents about some of the big challenges they have been facing in helping their buyers find good properties at good prices. The dialogue shifted to where they were finding the best opportunities to find the lowest priced properties and the easiest deals.

There were two sources in particular that they mentioned where they were having the most success at getting good deals. One was FSBO homes, which makes sense because the people selling like this are most likely not real estate professionals. The other was homes that were using Homie.com to help sell their home. Homie is a Utah startup that claims to be the solution to all your real estate problems. They say they can save you more than $10,000 on your transaction while giving you all the tools you need to sell your home without an agent.

Why are the homes listed with Homie such easy pickings for our agents? In many cases, they are finding that sellers are drastically underpricing their homes. Homie doesn’t have the tools and technology necessary to help sellers value their property the same way a professional, experienced agent can. These homes don’t get nearly as much exposure either, and oftentimes have to suffer through price reductions.

“These homes don’t get nearly as much exposure as they should.”

Many homes on the market today receive multiple offers and sell over asking price when they are listed with an agent. This doesn’t happen nearly as much with homes listed with Homie. Sometimes, it doesn’t happen at all.

I don’t want to corner Homie into a box and say that everyone that uses them is sabotaging their transaction, because there’s definitely a place for their services in our market. However, it’s very important that if you are considering selling you are comfortable with pricing and marketing your home so you don’t leave tens of thousands of dollars on the table. It’s one thing to save 3% on commission, it’s another to leave 10% in value on the market.

If you have any questions about Homie, selling your home on your own, or anything else related to real estate, give me a call or send me an email today. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+Be+wary+of+going+down+this+path.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.canovogroup.tv" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+Be+wary+of+going+down+this+path.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>I recently sat down with some of my top agents. We discussed where they were finding some of their biggest successes, and the answer was surprising. Many of my agents were having great success in finding their buyer’s homes through Homie.com. They found that many of the homes listed through this real estate service are underpriced. To find out why that is, watch this short video.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Canovo Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>I recently sat down with some of my top agents. We discussed where they were finding some of their biggest successes, and the answer was surprising. Many of my agents were having great success in finding their buyer’s homes through Homie.com. They found that many of the homes listed through this real estate service are underpriced. To find out why that is, watch this short video.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Agent Highlight: Meet Brandon Evans</title>
        <link>http://www.canovogroup.tv/agent-highlight-meet-brandon-evans.html</link>
        
        <author>The Canovo Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-23 14:05:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+Meet+our+team+Brandon+Evans.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today, I’m excited to introduce you to Brandon Evans, one of our real estate agents. The Agent Highlight series will help you get to know some of the agents that you’re working with.

Brandon worked as a police officer for about five years. “I have a lot of respect for police officers, but it just wasn’t my area of expertise,” says Brandon. “I had some good learning experiences, but it just wasn’t my thing.”

“I came across the Keller Williams website, started inquiring more about it, and met with someone in the Riverton office,” Brandon adds. “She sent me down here, and I had several positive conversations that let me know that this is the place where I wanted to work.”

Brandon continued working graveyard shifts while he went through real estate school. “Then I got set up with David and the rest is history,” Brandon says. “I found the right home.”

One of the biggest challenges Brandon faced when he dove in as a full-time real estate agent was the financial aspect. “I spent 20 years working hourly jobs and getting a paycheck every two weeks, and this job is sales,” says Brandon. “I got one deal in three months and it wasn’t that big—I only got $1,200 from it—but everything counts. Then, it started clicking, things started rolling, and I’ve had a pretty steady paycheck since then.”

One of the things I’ve noticed over the years is that agents get into real estate for two reasons: an unlimited income ceiling and flexibility. However, those are also the two reasons why people leave. They think they will immediately make money and that there won’t be any lag between your efforts and your results.

The truth is that you will work for at least 90 days before you see any income, and it will take about six months before you start to see consistent income. If you work through that, you can be a successful agent.

The freedom and flexibility is great, but many agents leave because they are not used to holding themselves accountable. As a result, they don’t keep up with the tasks they need to generate the kind of results that will provide for themselves and their families.

Family is very important to Brandon. “I’ve been married for eight years now, and we have four kids,” says Brandon. “We like to get out and do some motorcycle riding, and I’m a fan of all sports. I love football, and I am a Seahawks fan. Plus, we’re in the process of building our own home, so we’ve got our hands full right now.”

According to Brandon, the best thing about working in real estate is that you have the potential to provide a lifestyle for your family. “I never thought I would be able to come out and build on property,” says Brandon. “Police officers aren’t paid very much. They aren’t paid enough. We see that all the time and it’s unfortunate, but I wanted to be able to build a home and provide a life for my kids. I don’t want to have to say no when they ask to play this sport or go to dance school. My family is my driving force to get out there, work hard, and be successful.”

“My family is my driving force to get out there, work hard, and be successful.”

Brandon is a great person and a great real estate agent. I hope this has given you some insight into who he is. If you have any questions about real estate, please don’t hesitate to reach out to Brandon or anyone else on our real estate team.

If you are interested in learning more about getting into the real estate business or if you are curious about joining our team, simply fill out this form. We look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+Meet+our+team+Brandon+Evans.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.canovogroup.tv" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+Meet+our+team+Brandon+Evans.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today, I’m excited to introduce you to Brandon Evans, one of our real estate agents. The Agent Highlight series will help you get to know some of the agents that you’re working with. 
 
Brandon worked as a police officer for about five years. “I have a lot of respect for police officers, but it just wasn’t my area of expertise,” says Brandon. “I had some good learning experiences, but it just wasn’t my thing.” 
 
“I came across the Keller Williams website, started inquiring more about it, and met with someone in the Riverton office,” Brandon adds. “She sent me down here, and I had several positive conversations that let me know that this is the place where I wanted to work.” 
 
Brandon continued working graveyard shifts while he went through real estate school. “Then I got set up with David and the rest is history,” Brandon says. “I found the right home.” 
 
One of the biggest challenges Brandon faced when he dove in as a full-time real estate agent was the financial aspect. “I spent 20 years working hourly jobs and getting a paycheck every two weeks, and this job is sales,” says Brandon. “I got one deal in three months and it wasn’t that big—I only got $1,200 from it—but everything counts. Then, it started clicking, things started rolling, and I’ve had a pretty steady paycheck since then.” 
 
One of the things I’ve noticed over the years is that agents get into real estate for two reasons: an unlimited income ceiling and flexibility. However, those are also the two reasons why people leave. They think they will immediately make money and that there won’t be any lag between your efforts and your results. 
 
The truth is that you will work for at least 90 days before you see any income, and it will take about six months before you start to see consistent income. If you work through that, you can be a successful agent. 
 
The freedom and flexibility is great, but many agents leave because they are not used to holding themselves accountable. As a result, they don’t keep up with the tasks they need to generate the kind of results that will provide for themselves and their families. 
 
Family is very important to Brandon. “I’ve been married for eight years now, and we have four kids,” says Brandon. “We like to get out and do some motorcycle riding, and I’m a fan of all sports. I love football, and I am a Seahawks fan. Plus, we’re in the process of building our own home, so we’ve got our hands full right now.”
 
According to Brandon, the best thing about working in real estate is that you have the potential to provide a lifestyle for your family. “I never thought I would be able to come out and build on property,” says Brandon. “Police officers aren’t paid very much. They aren’t paid enough. We see that all the time and it’s unfortunate, but I wanted to be able to build a home and provide a life for my kids. I don’t want to have to say no when they ask to play this sport or go to dance school. My family is my driving force to get out there, work hard, and be successful.” 
 
Brandon is a great person and a great real estate agent. I hope this has given you some insight into who he is. If you have any questions about real estate, please don’t hesitate to reach out to Brandon or anyone else on our real estate team. 
 
If you are interested in learning more about getting into the real estate business or if you are curious about joining our team, simply fill out this form. We look forward to hearing from you!</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Canovo Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today, I’m excited to introduce you to Brandon Evans, one of our real estate agents. The Agent Highlight series will help you get to know some of the agents that you’re working with. 
 
Brandon worked as a police officer for about five years. “I have a lot of respect for police officers, but it just wasn’t my area of expertise,” says Brandon. “I had some good learning experiences, but it just wasn’t my thing.” 
 
“I came across the Keller Williams website, started inquiring more about it, and met with someone in the Riverton office,” Brandon adds. “She sent me down here, and I had several positive conversations that let me know that this is the place where I wanted to work.” 
 
Brandon continued working graveyard shifts while he went through real estate school. “Then I got set up with David and the rest is history,” Brandon says. “I found the right home.” 
 
One of the biggest challenges Brandon faced when he dove in as a full-time real estate agent was the financial aspect. “I spent 20 years working hourly jobs and getting a paycheck every two weeks, and this job is sales,” says Brandon. “I got one deal in three months and it wasn’t that big—I only got $1,200 from it—but everything counts. Then, it started clicking, things started rolling, and I’ve had a pretty steady paycheck since then.” 
 
One of the things I’ve noticed over the years is that agents get into real estate for two reasons: an unlimited income ceiling and flexibility. However, those are also the two reasons why people leave. They think they will immediately make money and that there won’t be any lag between your efforts and your results. 
 
The truth is that you will work for at least 90 days before you see any income, and it will take about six months before you start to see consistent income. If you work through that, you can be a successful agent. 
 
The freedom and flexibility is great, but many agents leave because they are not used to holding themselves accountable. As a result, they don’t keep up with the tasks they need to generate the kind of results that will provide for themselves and their families. 
 
Family is very important to Brandon. “I’ve been married for eight years now, and we have four kids,” says Brandon. “We like to get out and do some motorcycle riding, and I’m a fan of all sports. I love football, and I am a Seahawks fan. Plus, we’re in the process of building our own home, so we’ve got our hands full right now.”
 
According to Brandon, the best thing about working in real estate is that you have the potential to provide a lifestyle for your family. “I never thought I would be able to come out and build on property,” says Brandon. “Police officers aren’t paid very much. They aren’t paid enough. We see that all the time and it’s unfortunate, but I wanted to be able to build a home and provide a life for my kids. I don’t want to have to say no when they ask to play this sport or go to dance school. My family is my driving force to get out there, work hard, and be successful.” 
 
Brandon is a great person and a great real estate agent. I hope this has given you some insight into who he is. If you have any questions about real estate, please don’t hesitate to reach out to Brandon or anyone else on our real estate team. 
 
If you are interested in learning more about getting into the real estate business or if you are curious about joining our team, simply fill out this form. We look forward to hearing from you!</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Have You Met New Agent Daniel Pust?</title>
        <link>http://www.canovogroup.tv/utah-real-estate-agent-meet-one-of-our.html</link>
        
          <category>The Canovo Group</category>
        
        <author>The Canovo Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-08 14:05:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today it’s my pleasure to introduce you to one of the new agents on our team, Daniel Pust.

Daniel is happily married with a young son in 1st grade. He grew up in the Santaquin/Payson area and still lives there because he loves it. He worked in law enforcement for seven years and eventually became a detective before transitioning into real estate.

Ironically enough, he came into his new profession through a failed transaction, which inspired him to educate himself about our line of work. When he bought his first home in 2004, the market was so hot he hardly remembers even talking to his agent at the time. Three years later, he and his wife had built up quite a bit of equity in that home, and when they found their dream home up in the Santaquin mountains, they decided they wanted to buy it.

Unfortunately, the two agents who worked on that transaction didn’t know what they were doing and it cost them that home purchase. That experience inspired Daniel to take it upon himself to treat his clients with professionalism, stay on top of what’s going on, and provide them with whatever they need, whether they’re buying a home or selling one.

Daniel chose Keller Williams because of the education we provide. As a detective, his job was very demanding, and KW offered training sessions that were compatible with his schedule. He also credits his mentor for taking time out of her busy schedule and encouraging him to stay involved. He ended up here at the Canovo Group through knowing someone who also worked here whose life was transformed positively because of the experience. Working with fellow agents Dane Hill and Ali Garbero on a transaction, which he describes as an “amazing experience,” also sealed the deal.

Daniel’s goal is to establish our brand in South Utah County. He works hard every day and has run into quite a few people who want to move but haven’t put much thought in how they’re going to do it. He enjoys being able to provide a resource for them. Daniel is a person who has both his clients’, friends’, and family’s best interests at heart. He’s full of integrity and will do the right thing regardless of how it impacts him and his business.

“DANIEL ALWAYS HAS HIS CLIENTS’ BEST INTERESTS AT HEART.”

We’re certainly excited to have him on our team. If you’d like to contact him, you can reach him at (801) 850-5656. If you have any other questions, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. We look forward to serving you in the future!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.canovogroup.tv" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today it’s my pleasure to introduce you to one of the new agents on our team, Daniel Pust. Daniel is happily married with a young son in 1st grade. He grew up in the Santaquin/Payson area and still lives there because he loves it. He worked in law enforcement for seven years and eventually became a detective before transitioning into real estate.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Canovo Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today it’s my pleasure to introduce you to one of the new agents on our team, Daniel Pust. Daniel is happily married with a young son in 1st grade. He grew up in the Santaquin/Payson area and still lives there because he loves it. He worked in law enforcement for seven years and eventually became a detective before transitioning into real estate.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Has the Utah Real Estate Market Improved over Last Year?</title>
        <link>http://www.canovogroup.tv/utah-real-estate-agent-comparing-utah.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>The Canovo Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-21 15:22:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+Has+the+Utah+real+estate+market+improved+over+last+year.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The first quarter of the year has nearly come and gone, so I wanted to show you some of the most recent numbers from the Utah market and compare them to what we saw in the first quarter of 2016.

The average days on market for homes listed for sale stayed pretty steady. We went from an average of 33 days in 2016 to an average of 34 days in 2017. Homes are still selling really fast. Home sales have gone down from 6,300 at this point last year to just 6,000 this year. However, inventory is down by around 10% too.

Finally, let’s talk about home appreciation. It seems to be the one thing everyone asks about. To determine this, we’ll look at the median sale price in our market. At this point in 2016, it was $230,000. There has been a significant jump since, and the median sale price in our market right now is $251,000.

As we have predicted in the past, the market remains strong. As long as rates remain relatively low, we’ll continue to see this trend and we will see anywhere from 4% to 7% appreciation again this year. Some of the top economists in the country have made predictions on the higher end of that spectrum.

“AS LONG AS RATES STAY LOW, OUR MARKET WILL CONTINUE ITS RISE.”

If you are thinking about taking advantage of current market conditions by buying or selling a home, give me a call or send me an email. I would love to hear from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+Has+the+Utah+real+estate+market+improved+over+last+year.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.canovogroup.tv" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+Has+the+Utah+real+estate+market+improved+over+last+year.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>The first quarter of the year has nearly come and gone, so I wanted to show you some of the most recent numbers from the Utah market and compare them to what we saw in the first quarter of 2016. The average days on market for homes listed for sale stayed pretty steady. We went from an average of 33 days in 2016 to an average of 34 days in 2017. Homes are still selling really fast. Home sales have gone down from 6,300 at this point last year to just 6,000 this year. However, inventory is down by around 10% too.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Canovo Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>The first quarter of the year has nearly come and gone, so I wanted to show you some of the most recent numbers from the Utah market and compare them to what we saw in the first quarter of 2016. The average days on market for homes listed for sale stayed pretty steady. We went from an average of 33 days in 2016 to an average of 34 days in 2017. Homes are still selling really fast. Home sales have gone down from 6,300 at this point last year to just 6,000 this year. However, inventory is down by around 10% too.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Buying Just Got Easier With the NHF Sapphire Program</title>
        <link>http://www.canovogroup.tv/utah-real-estate-agent-how-nhf-sapphire.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>The Canovo Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-13 16:52:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today, a good friend of mine and my preferred lender, Austin Ingersoll with Academy Mortgage, is joining me to have a chat about a new program that just became available for buyers in our market.

It’s called the NHF Sapphire Program and it’s a true grant program, which means you don’t have to repay the funds that are given to you. You can use the program for a VA, USDA, or an FHA loan.

Depending on your credit score, you can get all the way up to 4.5% of your loan amount given to you. To put that into perspective, on a $300,000 loan, that’s $13,500 which can be used for your down payment and closing costs.

As far as requirements go for qualifying, they mirror the loan you are applying for whether it’s an FHA, VA, or a USDA loan. However, to get the most out of this program, you want to have a credit score of at least 680, but you can go as low as 620.

“This program can help get buyers off the sidelines and into their new homes.”

All in all this program is great for buyers out there who are sitting on the sidelines because they may think they don’t have enough money for a down payment.

To see if you qualify for this program or if you have any other real estate questions, give me a call or send me an email. I would be more than happy to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.canovogroup.tv" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today, a good friend of mine and my preferred lender, Austin Ingersoll with Academy Mortgage, is joining me to have a chat about a new program that just became available for buyers in our market.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Canovo Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today, a good friend of mine and my preferred lender, Austin Ingersoll with Academy Mortgage, is joining me to have a chat about a new program that just became available for buyers in our market.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Can You Expect From the 2017 Real Estate Market?</title>
        <link>http://www.canovogroup.tv/utah-real-estate-agent-2017-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>The Canovo Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-24 19:17:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+2017+market+predictions.mp4</guid>
        <description>

How did our market do in 2016? What can you expect from the 2017 market?

To get a sense of how the market did overall last year, I wanted to compare some key statistics from the year before. Here’s what happened between 2015 and 2016:

• The average days on market dropped 45% from 53 days to 29 days.
• The number of homes sold rose by 1.7% from 8,400 to 8,550.
• The median sale price increased by 6.9%.

“We had a great 2016, and it’s all thanks to you.”

All in all, it was a great year for real estate. What about 2017?

This year, I believe the average days on market will gradually creep back up. I don’t foresee a significant increase, but I do think homes will stay on the market slightly longer than they did in the recent past. Sales, on the other hand, should remain fairly steady and may even drop slightly due to the predicted rise in interest rates and how that will remove a portion of buyers from the market. Overall, though, I predict that we’ll still see some appreciation of between 4% and 7%.

The market is looking strong for 2017, so if you have any real estate needs at all, please don’t hesitate to reach out to me or anyone on my team. We look forward to helping you and we hope you have a great year!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+2017+market+predictions.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.canovogroup.tv" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+2017+market+predictions.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>How did our market do in 2016? What can you expect from the 2017 market? To get a sense of how the market did overall last year, I wanted to compare some key statistics from the year before. Here’s what happened between 2015 and 2016</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Canovo Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>How did our market do in 2016? What can you expect from the 2017 market? To get a sense of how the market did overall last year, I wanted to compare some key statistics from the year before. Here’s what happened between 2015 and 2016</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Should You Sell This Winter?</title>
        <link>http://www.canovogroup.tv/utah-real-estate-agent-should-you-sell_12.html</link>
        
          <category>Utah Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>The Canovo Group</author>
        <pubDate>2016-12-12 18:15:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+Should+you+sell+your+home+now+or+wait.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Every year around this time, we’re asked the same thing by sellers: “Should I sell my home now or wait until spring?” Many of our clients are thinking of hunkering down, waiting out the winter, and selling in the spring. I want to give you four reasons why you might want to consider selling now versus waiting until spring to do so.


  
    More competition during the spring. That means less competition right now. While many people have the same thought process as most of our clients and are waiting until spring, you can get a jump on the competition by selling now and taking advantage of the low inventory.
  
  
    Interest rates may be higher in the spring. Right now, rates are near all-time lows. With the election passing and the Federal Reserve saying they won’t be making any adjustments in the near future, that’s good news for buyers right now. If rates do tick up a bit this spring, it will eliminate a lot of buyers in the market and diminish the purchasing power of many others.
  
  
    A lot of job transfers happen at the beginning of the year. A lot of these people are looking for homes as we speak. This is just another segment of buyers you won’t be able to capture in the spring and summer.
  
  
    More serious buyers. If you’re a buyer out looking for homes during the cold, snowy winter months, there is a good reason for doing so. These buyers are likely motivated to get into a home as soon as possible.
  


“These are just a few reasons to consider selling now.”

These are just four of the reasons why you should consider selling now to take advantage of the market. If you have any questions for us or are thinking about selling, give us a call or send us an email. We’d be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+Should+you+sell+your+home+now+or+wait.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.canovogroup.tv" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+Should+you+sell+your+home+now+or+wait.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Every year around this time, we’re asked the same thing by sellers: “Should I sell my home now or wait until spring?” Many of our clients are thinking of hunkering down, waiting out the winter, and selling in the spring. I want to give you four reasons why you might want to consider selling now versus waiting until spring to do so.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Canovo Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Every year around this time, we’re asked the same thing by sellers: “Should I sell my home now or wait until spring?” Many of our clients are thinking of hunkering down, waiting out the winter, and selling in the spring. I want to give you four reasons why you might want to consider selling now versus waiting until spring to do so.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Can You Keep Your Home Safe During Your Holiday Vacation?</title>
        <link>http://www.canovogroup.tv/utah-real-estate-agent-protecting-your.html</link>
        
          <category>Educate Yourself</category>
        
        <author>The Canovo Group</author>
        <pubDate>2016-11-29 15:08:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+Protecting+your+home+while+you%E2%80%99re+on+vacation.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The holidays are just around the corner, which means you may have a fun family vacation in the works. Here are five tips to keep your home safe while you’re away:


  
    Get a Wi-Fi doorbell. If you don’t already have an alarm system installed in your home, you might want to consider this. How does it work? The doorbell is connected to your smartphone, so anytime someone rings the doorbell, you will be able to see who it is and respond accordingly.
  
  
    Add some exterior lighting. If you have areas around your property that are dark, you may want to consider installing new lighting fixtures or just double-check that the bulbs in the existing light fixtures work. To go a step further, you may want to also consider installing a motion sensor light.
  


“Extra lighting is an excellent deterrent for potential intruders.”


  
    Let a trusted neighbor know that you’ll be gone. Tell them when you’re leaving and when you’re coming back so they can keep an eye on things.
  
  
    Adjust delivery of your mail and newspapers. If you’re still one of those people that receives a newspaper, you want to make sure those aren’t accumulating atop your driveway. That’s a surefire indicator to any watchful intruder that nobody’s home. Ditto for mail overflowing out of your mailbox or packages piling up on your front steps.
  
  
    Double-check that all doors and windows are locked. According to Safewise.com, 30% of all home invasions happen through an unforced entry. This means almost a full third of every home invasion occurs because someone forgot to lock a window or door. Before you leave, check one last time that everything is locked.
  


If you have any questions about what’s going on in the market or you’re curious about your home’s value, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We hope to talk to you soon!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+Protecting+your+home+while+you%E2%80%99re+on+vacation.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.canovogroup.tv" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+Protecting+your+home+while+you%E2%80%99re+on+vacation.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>The holidays are just around the corner, which means you may have a fun family vacation in the works. Here are five tips to keep your home safe while you’re away</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Canovo Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>The holidays are just around the corner, which means you may have a fun family vacation in the works. Here are five tips to keep your home safe while you’re away</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Every Great Seller's Market Has Its End</title>
        <link>http://www.canovogroup.tv/utah-real-estate-agent-every-great.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>The Canovo Group</author>
        <pubDate>2016-10-25 10:26:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+Every+great+seller%E2%80%99s+market+has+its+end.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There has been a lot of discussion about the great appreciation and quick home sales we’ve been experiencing in our market lately. No one knows for sure how long this will last, but we do know that markets always shift. It has happened in the past and it will happen again.

I’ve got some strategies to share today that are quite useful in a shifting market. Pricing your home is one of the most important aspects of your sale. Here are some strategies that we share with our sellers on how to price appropriately in a shifting market.

In an appreciating market, you usually see low inventory and high demand. This is what drives prices up. Sellers have the luxury of pricing ahead in this type of market. As long as the market continues in an upward trend, they will get their price.

Things are different in a depreciating market. When supply goes up and demand drops, home prices come back down. If you try to price ahead in a depreciating market, you may find yourself chasing that market down and you may never get your price.

“Pricing ahead in a depreciating market can be toxic.”

We like to consult our clients about what’s happening in the market right now and we are in a funny place today. We have seen a lot of sellers get away with pricing ahead, but that is a recipe for disaster if we start to shift to a depreciating market.

If you have any questions about how to price your home appropriately in a shifting market, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+Every+great+seller%E2%80%99s+market+has+its+end.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.canovogroup.tv" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+Every+great+seller%E2%80%99s+market+has+its+end.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There has been a lot of discussion about the great appreciation and quick home sales we’ve been experiencing in our market lately. No one knows for sure how long this will last, but we do know that markets always shift. It has happened in the past and it will happen again.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Canovo Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There has been a lot of discussion about the great appreciation and quick home sales we’ve been experiencing in our market lately. No one knows for sure how long this will last, but we do know that markets always shift. It has happened in the past and it will happen again.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Much Has Our Market Changed in a Year?</title>
        <link>http://www.canovogroup.tv/utah-real-estate-agent-fantastic.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>The Canovo Group</author>
        <pubDate>2016-10-11 11:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

We are diving deep into the numbers today. The statistics are in for the third quarter of this year, and we’re going to compare them to the numbers we saw at the same time last year.

In the 3rd quarter of 2015, we saw 16,023 homes listed on the market. This year, we saw 16,606 homes listed in the same time frame. That’s an increase of nearly 4%, which hasn’t happened in a while.

As for home sales, the 3rd quarter of 2015 saw 12,661 homes sell. This year, that number was 12,156. This is about a 4% decrease. Inventory is going up and sales are going down. I think this is something we really need to keep an eye on because it may be an indication that things are starting to change in our market.

“We need to keep an eye on how things progress.”

The next thing we want to focus on is the days on market. We saw a huge 38% drop from 2015 to 2016. In the 3rd quarter of 2015, the average days on market was 24. At the end of the 3rd quarter this year, that number was at 15. I didn’t think homes could sell any faster than they did last year, but I was wrong. Homes that are priced right and in good condition are selling within weeks and sometimes even within days.

Finally, let’s talk about home appreciation. At the end of the 3rd quarter in 2015, our median home price was $230,000. This year, that number is at $250,000. This 8.7% increase is even more good news for sellers.

We are seeing fantastic conditions for sellers right now, but how long is it going to last? No one knows for sure. What we do know, however, is that increased appreciation and such few days on market is a great recipe for seller success.

If you have any questions for me or if you’re thinking about buying or selling a home, give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.canovogroup.tv" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>We are diving deep into the numbers today. The statistics are in for the third quarter of this year, and we’re going to compare them to the numbers we saw at the same time last year.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Canovo Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We are diving deep into the numbers today. The statistics are in for the third quarter of this year, and we’re going to compare them to the numbers we saw at the same time last year.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Are Your Utah Property Tax Valuations Too High?</title>
        <link>http://www.canovogroup.tv/utah-real-estate-agent-are-you-paying.html</link>
        
          <category>Educate Yourself</category>
        
        <author>The Canovo Group</author>
        <pubDate>2016-08-27 12:49:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+Are+you+paying+too+much+in+property+taxes.mp4</guid>
        <description>

By now, you have probably seen your property tax valuation. What happens if the property tax valuation is wrong?

Most of the time, clients have property tax valuations that are much lower than the appraised value or the fair market value of their home, which means you are probably paying less in property taxes than you should be. If this is the case, you probably don’t want to dispute the property tax valuation.

However, if your property tax valuation seems too high, we can help. We will do a free home value analysis and provide the paperwork you need to dispute the valuation. Disputing your property taxes may seem like an overwhelming process, but it is actually quite simple, and we are here to guide you through it.

If you have any questions about your property tax valuation, give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+Are+you+paying+too+much+in+property+taxes.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.canovogroup.tv" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+Are+you+paying+too+much+in+property+taxes.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>By now, you have probably seen your property tax valuation. What happens if the property tax valuation is wrong?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Canovo Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>By now, you have probably seen your property tax valuation. What happens if the property tax valuation is wrong?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Tips for Buying and Listing a Home at the Same Time</title>
        <link>http://www.canovogroup.tv/utah-real-estate-agent-listing-buying.html</link>
        
          <category>Educate Yourself</category>
        
        <author>The Canovo Group</author>
        <pubDate>2016-08-18 12:08:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+Listing+%26+buying+a+home+at+the+same+time.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Is it really better to find the home you plan on buying first, or should you sell your current home before you start looking at other properties?

This is the main question I get from clients who are looking to buy and sell at the same time. Most clients want to find the home they are going to purchase before they even list their current property. They don’t want to sell their current home and then get left high and dry; they want to make the transition from the sale of their current home to the new one as smooth as possible by only moving once.

**When a client waits to list their home until they find the home they want to purchase, it can become a very frustrating experience. Here is what happens: **

You decided to wait to list your home but start searching the market. Our buyer specialist then finds you the perfect home for your family. You want to write an offer but, since your current home isn’t even on the market yet, that offer is subject to the sale of your existing home.

The problem with that situation is we are in a seller’s market. Generally, if a home is priced right and in good condition, someone else will fall in love with that property, too. Buyers often end up competing. If the seller gets your offer and it’s subject to the sale of your home, you may end up having a seller reject your offer. The seller may tell you to come back when your current home is under contract, but in the meantime, the seller will continue to market the home to other buyers.

In other words, making your offer subject to the sale of your current home could mean losing out on your dream home because you are in a poor position to negotiate with the seller.
Instead of making a contingent offer, attack both angles with a more effective strategy. Go ahead and start looking for that perfect home, but put your current home on the market at the same time. We will work to generate an offer on your home so that when you go to make an offer on your dream home, the seller will be more willing to accept your offer.

“List your current home and generate offers while you look at new homes.”

If you haven’t found a new home yet and you receive an offer on a current home, you can make the sale subject to you finding a replacement home within a certain period of time. This strategy makes the entire process easier and keeps you in a strong negotiating position.

As you can see, the process of buying and selling a home at the same time can be a little complex. Please don’t hesitate to call me with any questions you may have. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+Listing+%26+buying+a+home+at+the+same+time.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.canovogroup.tv" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+Listing+%26+buying+a+home+at+the+same+time.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Is it really better to find the home you plan on buying first, or should you sell your current home before you start looking at other properties?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Canovo Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Is it really better to find the home you plan on buying first, or should you sell your current home before you start looking at other properties?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Comparing the 2nd Quarter Performances of 2016 and 2015</title>
        <link>http://www.canovogroup.tv/utah-real-estate-agent-utah-2nd-quarter.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>The Canovo Group</author>
        <pubDate>2016-07-18 13:35:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+Utah+2nd+quarter+market+update.mp4</guid>
        <description>

How does this year’s 2nd quarter compare to last year’s 2nd quarter?

In 2015, the number of new listings that came on the market was 3,456. This year, the number of new listings is 3,631. That’s an increase in inventory of 5%. In 2015, there was a total of 2,508 homes sold. This year, the total is 2,389 homes sold. That’s a drop of 5% in sold listings - the first significant drop in sales in about five years. Whether the drop will continue is something to keep an eye on in the future.

The 2nd quarter median sales price rose from $235,000 in 2015 to $255,000 in 2016. That’s an increase of 8.6%. This is a good thing. Values continue to rise– the only question is how high they are going to go and whether or not this rise presents any sort of risk.

“Home values continue to rise, the only question is how high they’ll go.”

Homes are selling very fast. The average number of days on market dropped from 22 in 2015 to 12 in 2016. Right now the best homes - if they’re priced right and in good condition - are going in a matter of weeks, if not days.

Home values continue to rise; the only concern is the 5% drop in the number of home sales. The market is still hot, however, and with interest rates as low as they are, I feel we’ll see a strong 3rd and 4th quarter here in Utah.

If you have any questions about what’s going on in your area, or have friends/family looking to buy or sell a home, please reach out to me or a member of my team by phone or email. We’d love to help you out.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+Utah+2nd+quarter+market+update.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.canovogroup.tv" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+Utah+2nd+quarter+market+update.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>How does this year’s 2nd quarter compare to last year’s 2nd quarter? In 2015, the number of new listings that came on the market was 3,456. This year, the number of new listings is 3,631. That’s an increase in inventory of 5%. In 2015, there was a total of 2,508 homes sold.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Canovo Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>How does this year’s 2nd quarter compare to last year’s 2nd quarter? In 2015, the number of new listings that came on the market was 3,456. This year, the number of new listings is 3,631. That’s an increase in inventory of 5%. In 2015, there was a total of 2,508 homes sold.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3 Home Staging Secrets for Utah Sellers</title>
        <link>http://www.canovogroup.tv/utah-real-estate-agent-three-utah-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>The Canovo Group</author>
        <pubDate>2016-06-14 16:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+3+Utah+home+staging+tips.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The point of staging your home is to make it look open, clean, and inviting to potential buyers. You want to make your home stand apart from others on the market, and you can do this in three different ways.


  
    The 50% Rule: This means that you should eliminate 50% of everything in your home. When you’re preparing to move out of your home, it’s a good opportunity to get rid of what you don’t need. Either donate it, put it in storage, or toss it. This goes for furniture, decor, and everything else.
  
  
    The Basketball Rule: Eliminate anything smaller than the size of a basketball. Small objects can make a room feel cramped and compact, so get rid of picture frames, books, knickknacks, and other things that are smaller than the size of a basketball.
  
  
    Bare Countertops Rule: Clearing off your countertops is an essential part of making your home feel larger and more open. Whatever you have laying around on your countertops, get rid of it. You’ll thank us later.
  


“Clear off your countertops!”

If you’d like a copy of our 67-point Home Staging Checklist, please don’t hesitate to reach out to us. It’s a great time to get your home ready to sell!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+3+Utah+home+staging+tips.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.canovogroup.tv" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+3+Utah+home+staging+tips.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>The point of staging your home is to make it look open, clean, and inviting to potential buyers. You want to make your home stand apart from others on the market, and you can do this in three different ways.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Canovo Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>The point of staging your home is to make it look open, clean, and inviting to potential buyers. You want to make your home stand apart from others on the market, and you can do this in three different ways.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Should You Consider a Pre-Sale Inspection?</title>
        <link>http://www.canovogroup.tv/utah-real-estate-agent-should-you.html</link>
        
          <category>Accurate Pricing</category>
        
        <author>The Canovo Group</author>
        <pubDate>2016-05-06 14:10:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+Should+you+consider+pre-sale+inspections.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Are pre-sale inspections a good idea or a bad idea? Can they help you save money? What’s the deal?

This is where a lot of sellers lose money or even their buyers. For instance, if you’ve accepted an offer, many buyers add a contingency in the contract, which includes a home inspection. If the inspection comes back with items of concern, that’s another area a buyer can negotiate with you. They might not only want you to fix these repairs but bring down the price of their offer. It might even deter buyers to withdraw their offer entirely.

Don’t let this happen to you! We want to put you in charge as a seller. There’s a simple way to take control of the situation before you even list your property in Utah.

By conducting a pre-sale inspection, you remove inspection-related contingencies from the contract. This benefits you because it no longer becomes something to negotiate with the buyer. You additionally have the opportunity to repair those problem areas before you even list your property on the market. We want you to be comfortable and confident that issues won’t arise after you’ve listed your home.

“We want you to be comfortable and confident.”

If you’re thinking about buying or selling a Utah home, I’d be happy to help and answer your questions. Give me a call or send me an email at your earliest convenience!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+Should+you+consider+pre-sale+inspections.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.canovogroup.tv" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+Should+you+consider+pre-sale+inspections.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Are pre-sale inspections a good idea or a bad idea? Can they help you save money? What’s the deal?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Canovo Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Are pre-sale inspections a good idea or a bad idea? Can they help you save money? What’s the deal?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Heres How the Market Has Changed in Just a Year</title>
        <link>http://www.canovogroup.tv/utah-real-estate-agent-great-changes.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>The Canovo Group</author>
        <pubDate>2016-04-26 15:33:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+Great+changes+we%E2%80%99re+seeing+in+the+market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today we’re going to be talking about what’s been going on in the Wasatch Front market since this time last year. There’s been a lot of changes, and a lot of positive changes at that.

The first thing we want to mention is the days on market, a measurement of how long it takes a home to sell. Last year at this time, it was around 30 days. Since then, we’ve seen a 48% drop and the average now sits at 20 days. Homes that are priced right for their condition are continuing to sell extremely fast.

“Homes are selling in an average of 20 days!”

The number of home sales has dropped a little bit from last year, by about 6%. However, inventory has dropped as well, by almost 8%. Even though sales are down, inventory is down even lower. That’s causing homes to continue to increase in price while selling quickly.

Finally, we wanted to mention appreciation, or median sales price. We went from $233,000 last year to $250,000 this year, a 6% jump.

There you have it. As you can see, we’re in a great market for buyers or sellers right now. The big question in the industry is whether or not we are in a bubble. There’s currently a debate going on and there’s a pretty good argument that in the future, a shift will take place in the market. However, we don’t see anything happening this year, as there’s still a lot of growth taking place right now in the Wasatch Front.

If you have any questions for us, or you’re thinking about buying or selling, give us a call or send us an email. We would love to hear from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+Great+changes+we%E2%80%99re+seeing+in+the+market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.canovogroup.tv" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+Great+changes+we%E2%80%99re+seeing+in+the+market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today we’re going to be talking about what’s been going on in the Wasatch Front market since this time last year. There’s been a lot of changes, and a lot of positive changes at that.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Canovo Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today we’re going to be talking about what’s been going on in the Wasatch Front market since this time last year. There’s been a lot of changes, and a lot of positive changes at that.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Do You Need a Preliminary Title Report to Sell in Utah?</title>
        <link>http://www.canovogroup.tv/utah-real-estate-agent-stop-real-estate.html</link>
        
          <category>Preliminary Title Report</category>
        
        <author>The Canovo Group</author>
        <pubDate>2016-04-05 11:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+Stop+a+real+estate+disaster.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I’m going to talk about why it’s important to get a preliminary title report when you’re selling a home in Utah. This issue doesn’t come into play extremely often, but when it does, it can be disastrous for your home sale.

“This prevents a disaster before it happens.”

Hiring a title company to find out whether there are any liens or judgements on your property is critical because a buyer will not come anywhere near your home if it does. We’ve seen many home sellers find out that there were liens or judgements against their home, and they had no idea about them even while they had lived in the property for a number of years.

If you’re thinking of selling your home, please contact us. We know a lot of good title professionals in the area who can make sure you have no outstanding liens on your home. This is one way to clear the bumps in the road.

We look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+Stop+a+real+estate+disaster.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.canovogroup.tv" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+Stop+a+real+estate+disaster.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I’m going to talk about why it’s important to get a preliminary title report when you’re selling a home in Utah. This issue doesn’t come into play extremely often, but when it does, it can be disastrous for your home sale.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Canovo Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I’m going to talk about why it’s important to get a preliminary title report when you’re selling a home in Utah. This issue doesn’t come into play extremely often, but when it does, it can be disastrous for your home sale.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Whats the Secret to Finding the True Value of Your Utah Home? </title>
        <link>http://www.canovogroup.tv/utah-real-estate-agent-do-your-homework.html</link>
        
          <category>Educate Yourself</category>
        
        <author>The Canovo Group</author>
        <pubDate>2016-03-31 10:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

When determining the sales price for your Utah home, it’s crucial to do your homework. Many agents in our market today don’t take the time and effort that they should in helping their clients determine the proper sales price for their home. Oftentimes, an agent gets a call from a friend or family member asking them if they’ll list their home; the agent usually takes the time to pull up a few comparable properties, but not much else. They then come up with a sales price based solely on the comparables without even stepping foot in the home!

Here at the Canovo Group, we go far more in depth to determine a list price for our clients. When we have a client who is looking to sell, the first thing we do is a rough estimate. This is a basic analysis used to determine what price range you can expect to sell your home in; the purpose of this is to give you some information to go off of to start making some basic decisions about whether you even want to move forward with the sale of your home.

If your home falls in a price range that makes sense for you, and you want to pursue it further, we will then schedule a walkthrough appointment of your home. During it, we will take notes and snap some pictures in order to become familiar with your property. We want to understand the condition, the fixtures, the finishes – the unique selling features of your home. We want to experience all this for ourselves so we can determine what makes your home unique and figure out how we can leverage those features to sell your home quickly and for top dollar.

Once this part of the process is down, we head back to the office in order to do a full, in-depth equity evaluation. From there, we will develop a comprehensive selling strategy for you. Over the last 12 years of selling real estate, we have devised a very specific selling system to help us identify the optimal sales price for you. We want to avoid leaving money on the table, but we also want to avoid overpricing your home and having it sit on the market for months with no interest.

“When determining the sales price for your Utah home, it’s crucial to do your homework.”

We’re going to do our due diligence and take some time to really make sure that we’ve done our job to ensure that we’re helping you make a decision on where you price your home to get top dollar and sell it quickly. So, make sure you do your homework before you put a price on your home! A good agent will walk you through the entire process I just described, so it doesn’t need to be a stressful or difficult experience!

If you have any questions about this topic or about real estate in general, please don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We would love to hear from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.canovogroup.tv" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>When determining the sales price for your Utah home, it’s crucial to do your homework. Many agents in our market today don’t take the time and effort that they should in helping their clients determine the proper sales price for their home.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Canovo Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>When determining the sales price for your Utah home, it’s crucial to do your homework. Many agents in our market today don’t take the time and effort that they should in helping their clients determine the proper sales price for their home.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Don't Rely on Third Party Data When Pricing Your Home for Sale</title>
        <link>http://www.canovogroup.tv/utah-real-estate-agent-dont-rely-on.html</link>
        
          <category>Accurate Pricing</category>
        
        <author>The Canovo Group</author>
        <pubDate>2016-02-03 15:27:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+Don%27t+rely+on+Third+Party+Data+when+Pricing+Your+Home+for+Sale.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today we are talking about our third tip to sell your home faster and for more money. Today we are talking about one of the most important aspects of your home sale, home pricing.

When you’re getting ready to sell and figuring out where to price, one thing you want to avoid is relying on third-party data, like a Zillow Zestimate or other automated home valuation sites. This information can give you a misunderstanding about what your home value is.

“Zillow’s Zestimate is pretty inaccurate.”

We recently heard of a new agent in the business who was using tax data to determine the value of a home they were selling. The value they came up with was drastically below market value, and was a steal for the buyer that gobbled it up. Zillow’s Zestimate is pretty inaccurate, as they don’t take into account any upgrades or improvements made on your house.

What you really need to price your home correctly is a great agent who knows what they are doing when it comes to pricing. Someone who can use current market data and facts to help determine your home’s true value.

If you have any questions for us, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We would love to hear from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+Don%27t+rely+on+Third+Party+Data+when+Pricing+Your+Home+for+Sale.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.canovogroup.tv" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+Don%27t+rely+on+Third+Party+Data+when+Pricing+Your+Home+for+Sale.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today we are talking about our third tip to sell your home faster and for more money. Today we are talking about one of the most important aspects of your home sale, home pricing.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Canovo Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today we are talking about our third tip to sell your home faster and for more money. Today we are talking about one of the most important aspects of your home sale, home pricing.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Expert Tip for Utah Home Sellers</title>
        <link>http://www.canovogroup.tv/utah-real-estate-agent-why-keep-secrets.html</link>
        
          <category>Confidential Selling</category>
        
        <author>The Canovo Group</author>
        <pubDate>2016-02-03 15:01:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+Why+Keep+secrets+when+selling.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I have another home selling tip for you, and it has to do with keeping your motivation for selling under wraps. If a buyer knows why you’re selling, they can use that against you.

Your reason for selling will have a major impact on negotiations. For example, if you need to relocate to an area quickly, this will impact the sale. If the buyer knew you were on a deadline, they could use that against you in a negotiation. We don’t want to give the buyer any reason to think that they have an advantage against us.

“Keep your motives for selling confidential.”

You’re better off keeping your reason for selling confidential. Only speak about this with your listing agent. This will put you in the best possible position when you negotiate for price.

If you need any other assistance when buying or selling, please don’t hesitate to contact me!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+Why+Keep+secrets+when+selling.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.canovogroup.tv" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/David+Robinson/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent+Why+Keep+secrets+when+selling.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I have another home selling tip for you, and it has to do with keeping your motivation for selling under wraps. If a buyer knows why you’re selling, they can use that against you.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Canovo Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I have another home selling tip for you, and it has to do with keeping your motivation for selling under wraps. If a buyer knows why you’re selling, they can use that against you.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>The Canovo Group</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">The Canovo Group</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Canovo Group - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
