<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Utah Homes Team - your professional Utah County Real Estate Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Andrew Ford</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2017-04-28 10:03:17 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Andrew Ford</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Utah County Real Estate, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>andrew@theutahhomes.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Andrew Ford</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Andrew Ford</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Utah County Real Estate, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Utah County Real Estate Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Utah Homes Team - your professional Utah County Real Estate Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>Buying an older home? Check for water-wasters</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/buying-an-older-home-check-for-water-wasters.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Andrew Ford</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-24 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>If you’re buying an older home, you may be shocked the first time you receive a water bill. Older homes don’t always have the latest in water-saving devices. Some even have a few water-gobbling features!

The good news? A lot of these problems can be fixed quickly and cheaply.

Here’s what to look out for:

Little leaks. Always keep an eye for a leak! A dripping faucet can send up to 20 gallons of water down the drain every day. This is the first place to start when checking for waste. Change the washers on your sinks or keep the old ones but make sure that they are all well-maintained.

Inefficient shower heads. Putting in new, water-saving shower heads can have a big impact on your bill. Look for low-flow shower heads that average 2.5 gallons or less per minute.

Problem toilets. Do this food coloring test. In your toilet tank, put some drops of food coloring. If the color begins to appear in the bowl within 30 minutes without flushing, you have a leak that should be repaired immediately. Older toilets can use a lot more water than newer models, especially if an older one has a leak. Take a few minutes to inspect each toilet; you can typically hear and see evidence of leaks. Dual-flush and low-flush toilets can save a great deal of water and money.

Check the water meter.

If there is no water being used, the water meter should have the same reading after two hours.  If the meter does not read exactly the same, there is a leak.

Another good way to save?

Talk to your water company. Many municipalities have water-saving programs and incentives that can save you money. In some cases, they may be able to determine if you need a water pressure regulator, which could help cut down on your water use.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re buying an older home, you may be shocked the first time you receive a water bill. Older homes don’t always have the latest in water-saving devices. Some even have a few water-gobbling features!</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Andrew Ford</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re buying an older home, you may be shocked the first time you receive a water bill. Older homes don’t always have the latest in water-saving devices. Some even have a few water-gobbling features!</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Utah County Real Estate, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Interest Rates: Where To, Now?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/interest-rates-where-to-now.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Andrew Ford</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-13 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>WHERE ARE INTEREST RATES HEADED?

If you are considering moving up to your dream home, it may be better to do it sooner than later. The two components of your monthly mortgage payment (home prices and interest rates) are both projected to increase as the year moves forward, and interest rates may increase rather dramatically. Here are some predictions on where rates will be by the end of the year:

HSH.com:

“We think that conforming 30-year fixed rates probably make it into the 4.625 percent to 4.75 percent range at some point during 2017 as a peak.”

Svenja Gudell, Zillow’s Chief Economist:

“I wouldn’t be surprised if the 30-year fixed mortgage rate hits 4.75 percent.”

Mark Fleming, the Chief Economist at First American: 

“[I see] mortgage rates getting much closer to 5 percent at the end of next year.”

Lawrence Yun, NAR Chief Economist:

“By this time next year, expect the 30-year fixed rate to likely be in the 4.5 percent to 5 percent range.”

Bottom Line

If you are feeling good about your family’s economic future and are considering making a move to your dream home, doing it sooner rather than later makes the most sense!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>WHERE ARE INTEREST RATES HEADED?  If you are considering moving up to your dream home, it may be better to do it sooner than later.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Andrew Ford</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>WHERE ARE INTEREST RATES HEADED?  If you are considering moving up to your dream home, it may be better to do it sooner than later.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Utah County Real Estate, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Power of Interest Rates</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/the-power-of-interest-rates.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Andrew Ford</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-12 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Can low interest rates affect your purchasing power? How exactly?

According to Freddie Mac’s latest Primary Mortgage Market Survey, interest rates for a 30-year fixed rate mortgage are currently around 4%, which is still very low in comparison to recent history!

The interest rate you secure when buying a home not only greatly impacts your monthly housing costs, but also impacts your purchasing power.

Purchasing power, simply put, is the amount of home you can afford to buy for the budget you have available to spend. As rates increase, the price of the house you can afford will decrease if you plan to stay within a certain monthly housing budget.

The chart below shows what impact rising interest rates would have if you planned to purchase a home within the national median price range, and planned to keep your principal and interest payments at or about $1,100 a month.



With each quarter of a percent increase in interest rate, the value of the home you can afford decreases by 2.5%, (in this example, $6,250). Experts predict that mortgage rates will be closer to 5% by this time next year.

It will be really wise to act NOW and get that dream house for your hard-earned money.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Can low interest rates affect your purchasing power? How exactly?  According to Freddie Mac’s latest Primary Mortgage Market Survey, interest rates for a 30-year fixed rate mortgage are currently around 4%, which is still very low in comparison to recent history!</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Andrew Ford</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Can low interest rates affect your purchasing power? How exactly?  According to Freddie Mac’s latest Primary Mortgage Market Survey, interest rates for a 30-year fixed rate mortgage are currently around 4%, which is still very low in comparison to recent history!</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Utah County Real Estate, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Myths About Buying A Home: Debunked, Explained, Unmasked!</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/myths-about-buying-a-home-debunked-explained-unmasked.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Andrew Ford</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-12 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Here are the 2 myths that may be holding you back from buying. 

Fannie Mae’s article, “What Consumers (Don’t) Know About Mortgage Qualification Criteria,” revealed that “only 5 to 16 percent of respondents know the correct ranges for key mortgage qualification criteria.”

Myth #1: “I Need a 20% Down Payment” 

Fannie Mae’s survey revealed that consumers overestimate the down payment funds needed  to qualify for a home loan. According to the report, 76% of Americans either don’t know (40%) or are misinformed (36%) about the minimum down payment required.

Many believe that they need at least 20% down to buy their dream home, but many programs actually let buyers put down as little as 3%.
On the right are the results of a Digital Risk survey of Millennials who recently purchased a home. As you can see, 64.2% were able to purchase their home by putting down less than 20%, with 43.8% putting down less than 10%!

Myth #2: “I Need a 780 FICO® Score or Higher to Buy” 

The survey revealed that 59% of Americans either don’t know (54%) or are misinformed (5%) about what FICO® score is necessary to qualify.

Many Americans believe a ‘good’ credit score is 780 or higher. To help debunk this myth, let’s take a look at Ellie Mae’s latest Origination
Insight Report, which focuses on recently closed (approved) loans. As you can see on the right, 54.7% of approved mortgages had a credit score of 600-749.

Bottom Line

Whether buying your first home or moving up to your dream home, knowing your options will make the mortgage process easier. Your dream home may already be within your reach!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here are the 2 myths that may be holding you back from buying</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Andrew Ford</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here are the 2 myths that may be holding you back from buying</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Utah County Real Estate, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4 Steps to Selling Your Home</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/4-steps-to-selling-your-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Andrew Ford</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-01 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>The best part in homeownership is the one where you and your loved ones create lifetime memories together. It is your own sanctuary of emotions and experiences. But there will come a time when you’ll be in great need to move on in life, and selling your beloved home which mirrors who you will be fundamental.

Selling your home is saying goodbye to an irreplaceable part of you. As difficult as it may be, you have to go through it. So how to do it? Here are some tips:

* Price
- Pricing you home too high will do the opposite of attracting potential buyers. Pricing too low might take away the rightful profit you deserve.
- The key here is to price it not too high and not too low, base it on the current market. You need someone to help you with this. To know for sure you can check in with us to fully valuate your property. We determine market value based on comparable sales in the market.

* Condition
- Making sure your home is in it’s best state is an art. It takes a few easy, basic tips and tricks to get you there.

* Marketing
- Take good photos, and we’re not only talking about the resolution but also the angle of each shot. We want buyer gasping in AWE - not restraining themselves from screaming “What are they thinking?”.
- Suggest an open house to your agent.
- Make sure to ask your agent to create a video of your home to be uploaded online. A lot of buyers spend majority of their home search online.

* Hire a Professional
- Agents save you on the hassles of spending time, money, and effort on selling your house.
- Studies have shown that homes typically sell for more money when handled by a real estate  professional.

Happy selling!


</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>The best part in homeownership is the one where you and your loved ones create lifetime memories together. It is your own sanctuary of emotions and experiences. But there will come a time when you'll be in great need to move on in life, and selling your beloved home which mirrors who you will be fundamental.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Andrew Ford</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>The best part in homeownership is the one where you and your loved ones create lifetime memories together. It is your own sanctuary of emotions and experiences. But there will come a time when you'll be in great need to move on in life, and selling your beloved home which mirrors who you will be fundamental.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Utah County Real Estate, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Expectation In Home Inspection</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/expectation-in-home-inspection.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Andrew Ford</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-26 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>So you made an offer, it was accepted, and  now your next task is to have the home  inspected prior to closing. More often than  not, your agent may have made your offer  contingent on a clean home inspection.

This contingency allows you to renegotiate  the price paid for the home, ask the sellers  to cover repairs, or even, in some cases, walk  away. Your agent can advise you on the best  course of action once the report is filed.

Now, what to expect when home inspecting?

How to Choose an Inspector

Your agent will most likely have a short list of inspectors that they have worked with in the  past that they can recommend to you. Realtor.com suggests that you consider the following 5  areas when choosing the right home inspector for you:

Qualifications – Find out what’s included in your inspection &amp; if the age or location of your home may warrant specific certifications or specialties.

Sample Reports – Ask for a sample inspection report so you can review how thoroughly  they will be inspecting your dream home. The more detailed the report the better in  most cases.

References – Do your homework. Ask for phone numbers and names of past clients that  you can call to ask about their experience.

Memberships – Not all inspectors belong to a national or state association of home  inspectors, and membership in one of these groups should not be the only way to  evaluate your choice. Often membership in one of these organizations means that there is  continued training and education provided.

Errors &amp; Omission Insurance – Find out what the liability of the inspector or inspection company is once the inspection is over. The inspector is only human after all, and it is possible that they might miss something they should have seen.

Ask your inspector if it’s okay for you to tag along during the inspection. That way they can point out anything that should be addressed or fixed.

Don’t be surprised to see your inspector climbing on the roof, crawling around in the attic,  and on the floors. The job of the inspector is to protect your investment and find any issues  with the home, including but not limited to:


  roof
  plumbing
  electrical components
  appliances
  heating &amp; air conditioning systems
  ventilation
  windows
  fireplace &amp;  chimney
  the foundation &amp; so much more!


Bottom Line

They say ‘ignorance is bliss,’ but not when investing your hard-earned money in a home of  your own. Work with a professional you can trust to give you the most information possible  about your new home so that you can make the most educated decision about your purchase.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>So you made an offer, it was accepted, and  now your next task is to have the home  inspected prior to closing. More often than  not, your agent may have made your offer  contingent on a clean home inspection.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Andrew Ford</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>So you made an offer, it was accepted, and  now your next task is to have the home  inspected prior to closing. More often than  not, your agent may have made your offer  contingent on a clean home inspection.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Utah County Real Estate, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Closing Costs: Who's Paying How Much?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/closing-costs-whos-paying-how-much.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Andrew Ford</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-26 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Have you put aside enough for closing costs?

There are many potential homebuyers, and even sellers, who believe that you need at least a  20% down payment in order to buy a home, or move on to their next home. Time after time,  we have dispelled this myth by showing that there are many loan programs that allow you to  put down as little as 3% (or 0% with a VA loan).

If you have saved up your down payment and are ready to start your home search, one other  piece of the puzzle is to make sure that you have saved enough for your closing costs.

Freddie Mac defines closing costs as:

“Closing costs, also called settlement fees, will need to be paid when you obtain a  mortgage. These are fees charged by people representing your purchase, including  your lender, real estate agent, and other third parties involved in the transaction.

Closing costs are typically between 2 and 5% of your purchase price.

We’ve recently heard from many first-time homebuyers that they wished that someone had  let them know that closing costs could be so high. If you think about it, with a low down  payment program, your closing costs could equal the amount that you saved for your down  payment.

Here is a list of just some of the fees/costs that may be included in your closing costs,  depending on where the home you wish to purchase is located:


  Government recording costs
  Appraisal fees
  Credit report fees
  Lender origination fees
  Title services (insurance, search fees)
  Tax service fees
  Survey fees
  Attorney fees
  Underwriting fees


Is there any way to avoid paying closing costs?

Work with your lender and real estate agent to see if there are any ways to decrease or defer  your closing costs. There are no-closing mortgages available, but they end up costing you  more in the end with a higher interest rate, or by wrapping the closing costs into the total  cost of the mortgage (meaning you’ll end up paying interest on your closing costs).

Home buyers can also negotiate with the seller over who pays these fees. Sometimes the seller will agree to assume the buyer’s closing fees in order to get the deal finalized.

Bottom Line

Speak with your lender and agent early and often to determine how much you’ll be  responsible for at closing. Finding out you’ll need to come up with thousands of dollars right  before closing is not a surprise anyone is ever looking forward to.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There are many potential homebuyers, and even sellers, who believe that you need at least a  20% down payment in order to buy a home, or move on to their next home. Time after time,  we have dispelled this myth</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Andrew Ford</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There are many potential homebuyers, and even sellers, who believe that you need at least a  20% down payment in order to buy a home, or move on to their next home. Time after time,  we have dispelled this myth</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Utah County Real Estate, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>2017: Great Housing Year, Will It Be?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/2017-great-housing-year-will-it-be.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Andrew Ford</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-23 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>We’re going to have a good year. The question is: will it be a great year?

Consumer confidence is through the roof. That means people are feeling good about the economy. They’re feeling good about their own personal finances. And that means that people are going to be moving out of the house they’re currently in, moving into a bigger home, maybe downsizing where they are and buying a vacation home, either in the mountains or on the water. Things are going to… People just feel good right now. Now, part of the reason, as we’ll explain in some of these news clips, that people are feeling good, is that after the election, they see the country going in a very positive direction.

Consumer confidence is at a good place. People feel good about their own finances. People feel good about making a move right now. People feel good about where they stand, better than… better since 2004.

American households are expecting a Donald Trump administration to deliver. Consumers are more upbeat about the prospects of the economy, labor market, and their incomes. It’s a time right now that people are going to be making moves. They’re going to jump into their first house.

The biggest challenge we have going into 2017 is a whole bunch of people that want to buy a home. And not enough homes to sell. It’s crucial…  It has been said now for eight months, that if, unless the housing inventory will be fixed, we’re not going to be able to take full advantage of the market we’re in right now.

Prices are continuing to escalate. It means people have more equity. And the equity in their home is something they should be able to do something with.

There’s equity in a house. That equity they could use. They can use that equity to move down to where they currently are living where they might still have family or finishing up the last couple of years of the job and take the additional equity and buy that vacation home that eventually will be their retirement home.

A lot of people did refinance, some to a fifteen-year loan.  That means they’re building more equity every single month. And that equity is important for what reason? That means that they will sell their house and make a good financial decision.

They can make the move now that they planned to make in retirement. And now is a better time than waiting until then. If we look at the percentage of homes with positive equity by state, we can see that 93.7% of all the homes in this country with a mortgage on it… Remember one third don’t even have a mortgage on it. We’re talking about the other close to 70%. Ninety-three-point seven percent of that other 70% have positive equity now.

There’s enough equity in your home, that if you ever dreamt about moving. Instead of living around the corner from the water,  but moving to the water. Instead of staying in the four-bedroom colonial now that the kids have moved out, you can downsize and use that additional equity, either to put it into the stock market or put it into another piece of real estate that you’re going to use later in your life.

What people believe their house is worth and what they’re getting appraised for are much, much closer now. So, we don’t really have to worry about pricing. People have got the right price. The sellers got the right price in their head. There’s plenty of buyers out there. What we need to watch out for is the number of  listings the market needs.

Foot traffic is an indicator of how many houses people actually will go to see. The reason foot traffic is down is not because there’s less people going out. And the challenge is the buyers don’t have any houses to go see in some markets or very few. That’s why that number is down.

SmartAsset.com, just this past month, had an article about housing. And this is what they said, whether you’re preparing to purchase a new home or sell an old house in the new year, it’s important to know how housing trends could affect you. Keeping your finger on the pulse of the market can prevent you from being left out of the cold by rising interest rates or a widening gap between supply and demand.

You need to know! Whether you want to buy or sell, you need to know exactly what’s happening. That’s why we do. You need someone you can trust for up-to-date information, and we are here to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>We’re going to have a good year. The question is: will it be a great year?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Andrew Ford</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We’re going to have a good year. The question is: will it be a great year?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Utah County Real Estate, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Importance Of "Access" In Getting Your House Sold</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/importance-of-access-in-getting-your-house-sold.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Andrew Ford</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-10 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>The Role Access Plays In Getting Your House SOLD!

So you’ve decided to sell your house. You’ve hired a real estate professional to help you with the entire process and they have asked you what level of access you want to provide to potential buyers.

There are four elements to a quality listing. At the top of the list is Access, followed by Condition, Financing and Price. There are many levels of access that you could provide to your agent to be able to show your home.

Here are five levels of access that you could provide to a buyer with a brief description:

• Lockbox On the Door – this allows buyers the ability to see the home as soon as they are aware of the listing, or at their convenience.

• Providing a Key to the Home – although the buyer’s agent may need to stop by an office to pick up the key, there is little delay in being able to show the home.

• Open Access with a Phone Call – the seller allows showing with just a phone call’s notice.

• By Appointment Only (example: 48 Hour Notice) – Many out-of-town/state buyers and relocation buyers visit an area they would like to move to and only have the weekend to view homes. They may not be able to plan that far in advance, or may be unable to wait the 48 hours to be shown the house.

• Limited Access (example: the home is only available on Mondays or Tuesdays at 2pm or for only a couple of hours a day) – This is the most difficult way to be able to show your house to potential buyers.

In a competitive marketplace, access can make or break your ability to get the price you are looking for, or even sell your house at all.

So you’ve decided to sell your house. You’ve hired a real estate professional to help you with the entire process and they have asked you what level of access you want to provide to potential buyers.

There are four elements to a quality listing. At the top of the list is Access, followed by Condition, Financing and Price. There are many levels of access that you could provide to your agent to be able to show your home.

“”
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>So you’ve decided to sell your house. You’ve hired a real estate professional to help you with the entire process and they have asked you what level of access you want to provide to potential buyers.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Andrew Ford</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>So you’ve decided to sell your house. You’ve hired a real estate professional to help you with the entire process and they have asked you what level of access you want to provide to potential buyers.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Utah County Real Estate, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How To Make An Effective And Irresistible Offer</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-to-make-an-effective-and-irresistible-offer.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Andrew Ford</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-09 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>READY TO MAKE AN OFFER? 4 TIPS FOR SUCCESS

So you’ve been searching for that perfect house to call a ‘home’ and you finally found one! The price is right, and in such a competitive market you want to make sure you make a good offer so that you can guarantee your dream of making this house yours comes true!

Freddie Mac covered “4 Tips for Making an Offer” in their latest Executive Perspective. Here are the 4 tips they covered along with some additional information for your consideration:

1. Understand How Much You Can Afford

“While it’s not nearly as fun as house hunting, fully understanding your finances is critical in making an offer.”

This ‘tip’ or ‘step’ really should take place before you start your home search process.

Getting pre-approved is one of many steps that will show home sellers that you are serious about buying, and will allow you to make your offer with the confidence of knowing that you have already been approved for a mortgage for that amount. You will also need to know if you are prepared to make any repairs that may need to be made to the house (ex: new roof, new furnace).

2. Act Fast

“Even though there are fewer investors, the inventory of homes for sale is also low and competition for housing continues to heat up in many parts of the country.”

The inventory of homes listed for sale has remained well below the 6-month supply that is needed for a ‘normal’ market. Buyer demand has continued to outpace the supply of homes for sale, causing buyers to compete with each other for their dream home.

Make sure that as soon as you decide that you want to make an offer, you work with your agent to present it as soon as possible.

3. Make a Solid Offer

Freddie Mac offers this advice to help make your offer the strongest it can be:

“Your strongest offer will be comparable with other sales and listings in the neighborhood. A licensed real estate agent active in the neighborhoods you are considering will be instrumental in helping you put in a solid offer based on their experience and other key considerations such as recent sales of similar homes, the condition of the house and what you can afford.”

Consider ways of making your offer stand out! Many buyers write a personal letter to the seller letting them know how much they would love to be the new homeowners. Your agent will be able to help you figure out if there are any other ways your offer could stand above the rest.

4. Be Prepared to Negotiate

“It’s likely that you’ll get at least one counteroffer from the sellers so be prepared. The two things most likely to be negotiated are the selling price and closing date. Given that, you’ll be glad you did your homework first to understand how much you can afford.

Your agent will also be key in the negotiation process, giving you guidance on the counteroffer and making sure that the agreed-to contract terms are met.”

If your offer is approved, Freddie Mac urges you to “always get an independent home inspection, so you know the true condition of the home. If the inspection uncovers undisclosed problems or issues, you can typically re-negotiate the terms or cancel the contract.”

Bottom Line

Whether buying your first home or your fifth, having a local real estate professional who is an expert in their market on your side is your best bet to make sure the process goes smoothly. Let’s talk about how we can make your dreams of homeownership a reality!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>So you’ve been searching for that perfect house to call a ‘home’ and you finally found one! The price is right, and in such a competitive market you want to make sure you make a good offer so that you can guarantee your dream of making this house yours comes true!</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Andrew Ford</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>So you’ve been searching for that perfect house to call a ‘home’ and you finally found one! The price is right, and in such a competitive market you want to make sure you make a good offer so that you can guarantee your dream of making this house yours comes true!</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Utah County Real Estate, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Rising Home Prices: What's In It For You as a Home Owner</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/rising-home-prices-whats-in-it-for-you-as-a-home-owner.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Andrew Ford</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-06 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>THE ‘GREAT NEWS’ ABOUT RISING PRICES

Recently there has been a lot of talk about home prices and if they are accelerating too quickly. In some areas of the country, seller supply (homes for sale) cannot keep up with the number of buyers out looking for a home, which has caused prices to rise.

The great news about rising prices, however, is that according to CoreLogic’s latest US Economic Outlook, the average American household gained over $11,000 in equity over the course of the last year, largely due to home value increases.

The map below was created from CoreLogic’s report and shows the average equity gain per mortgaged home over the past year.

For those who are worried that we are doomed to repeat 2006 all over again, it is important to note that homeowners are investing their new found equity in their homes and themselves, not in depreciating assets.

The added equity is helping families put their children through college, and even invest in starting small businesses, allowing them to pay off their mortgage sooner or move up to the home that will better suit their needs now.

Bottom Line

CoreLogic predicts that home prices will appreciate by another 5% by this time next year. If you are a homeowner looking to take advantage of your home equity by moving up to your dream home, let’s discuss your options!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Recently there has been a lot of talk about home prices and if they are accelerating too quickly. In some areas of the country, seller supply (homes for sale) cannot keep up with the number of buyers out looking for a home, which has caused prices to rise.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Andrew Ford</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Recently there has been a lot of talk about home prices and if they are accelerating too quickly. In some areas of the country, seller supply (homes for sale) cannot keep up with the number of buyers out looking for a home, which has caused prices to rise.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Utah County Real Estate, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>2 Steps To Help You Find Your Next Home</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/2-steps-to-help-you-find-your-next-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Andrew Ford</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-05 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

STARTING TO LOOK FOR A HOME? KNOW WHAT YOU WANT VS. WHAT YOU NEED

In this day and age of being able to shop for anything anywhere, it is really important to know what you’re looking for when you start your home search.

If you’ve been thinking about buying a home of your own for some time now, you’ve probably come up with a list of things that you’d LOVE to have in your new home. Many new homebuyers fantasize about the amenities that they see on television or Pinterest, and start looking at the countless homes listed for sale with rose-colored glasses.

Do you really need that farmhouse sink in the kitchen in order to be happy with your home choice? Would a two-car garage be a convenience or a necessity? Could the man cave of your dreams be a future renovation project instead of a make or break now?

The first step in your home buying process should be to get pre-approved for your mortgage. This allows you to know your budget before you fall in love with a home that is way outside of it.

The next step is to list all the features of a home that you would like, and to qualify them as follows:

• ‘Must Haves’ – if this property does not have these items, then it shouldn’t even be considered. (ex: distance from work or family, number of bedrooms/bathrooms)

• ‘Should Haves’ – if the property hits all of the must haves and some of the should haves, it stays in contention, but does not need to have all of these features.

• ‘Absolute Wish List’ – if we find a property in our budget that has all of the ‘must haves,’ most of the ‘should haves,’ and ANY of these, it’s the winner!

Bottom Line

Having this list flushed out before starting your search will save you time and frustration, while also letting your agent know what features are most important to you before starting to show you houses in your desired area.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>n this day and age of being able to shop for anything anywhere, it is really important to know what you’re looking for when you start your home search.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Andrew Ford</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>n this day and age of being able to shop for anything anywhere, it is really important to know what you’re looking for when you start your home search.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Utah County Real Estate, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Do Home Prices Continue To Rise?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/why-do-home-prices-continue-to-rise.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Andrew Ford</author>
        <pubDate>2016-12-30 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>BUYER DEMAND CONTINUES TO OUTPACE INVENTORY OF HOMES FOR SALE

The price of any item is determined by the supply of that item, as well as the market demand.

The National Association of Realtors (NAR) surveys “over 50,000 real estate practitioners about their expectations for home sales, prices and market conditions” for their Realtors Confidence Index. Their latest edition sheds some light on the relationship between Seller Traffic (supply) and Buyer Traffic (demand).

Buyer Demand

The map on the right was created after asking the question:

“How would your rate buyer traffic in your area?”

The darker the blue, more buyers are looking for homes in that area. Only four states came in with a weak demand level.

Seller Supply

The Index also asked:

“How would you rate seller traffic in your area?”

As you can see from the map on the left, the majority of the country has weak Seller Traffic, meaning there are far fewer homes on the market than what is needed to satisfy the buyers who are out looking for their dream homes.

Bottom Line

Looking at the maps above, it is not hard to see why prices are appreciating in many areas of the country. Until the supply of homes for sale starts to meet the buyer demand, prices will continue to increase.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>The price of any item is determined by the supply of that item, as well as the market demand.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Andrew Ford</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>The price of any item is determined by the supply of that item, as well as the market demand.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Utah County Real Estate, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Is Renting For The Better?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/is-renting-for-the-better.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Andrew Ford</author>
        <pubDate>2016-12-29 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Well, here’s one way to answer that question -

BUYING IS NOW 37.7% CHEAPER THAN RENTING IN THE US.

Yes, you read that right. The results of the latest Rent vs. Buy Report from Trulia show that homeownership remains cheaper than renting with a traditional 30-year fixed rate mortgage in the 100 largest metro areas in the United States.

The updated numbers actually show that the range is an average of 17.4% less expensive in Honolulu (HI), all the way up to 53.2% less expensive in Miami &amp; West Palm Beach (FL), and 37.7% nationwide!

Other interesting findings in the report include:

• Interest rates have remained low, and even though home prices have appreciated around the country, they haven’t greatly outpaced rental appreciation.

• Home prices would have to appreciate by a range of over 23% in Honolulu (HI), up to over 45% in Ventura County (CA), to reach the tipping point of renting being less expensive than buying.

• Nationally, rates would have to reach 9.1%, a 145% increase over today’s average of 3.7%, for renting to be cheaper than buying. Rates haven’t been that high since January of 1995, according to Freddie Mac.

Bottom Line

Buying a home makes sense socially and financially. If you are one of the many renters out there who would like to evaluate your ability to buy this year, let’s get together to find your dream home.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>BUYING IS NOW 37.7% CHEAPER THAN RENTING IN THE US.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Andrew Ford</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>BUYING IS NOW 37.7% CHEAPER THAN RENTING IN THE US.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Utah County Real Estate, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Making the Most of a Winter Sale</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/making-the-most-of-a-winter-sale.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Andrew Ford</author>
        <pubDate>2016-12-13 10:32:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Andrew+Ford/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+prepare+your+house+for+a+winter+sale.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you sell your home in the fall or winter, there are a few specific things that you really need to pay attention to.

First, don’t forget about curb appeal. Make sure you rake up the leaves and make sure the flowerbeds have some dark, rich mulch in them. Your trees and bushes will lose their leaves, so you need to make the house look as good as you can from a curb appeal perspective since your home might not look as good in the winter as it will in the spring or summer.

You can also help out your entrance by painting the front door and taking a look at the weather stripping. This is especially important in the winter when selling because you don’t want a buyer walking in your home and feeling a big draft immediately after.

Since it’s the holiday season, go easy on the displays. Some pumpkins and gourds are nice for Halloween and Thanksgiving, but you need to know the difference between decorating for the festivities and making your house look like a farmers market. As for Christmas—you don’t need to compete with the Griswolds, you just need to keep it tasteful. Buyers want to enter a home and feel like they could see themselves living there, so don’t overdo it.

“Focus on making your living space comfortable and inviting.”

Next, focus on making your living space comfortable and inviting. After living in your house for so long, you forget what it’s like; it’s like sign-blindness in that you see things so often that you forget that they are there. Invite over a friend who can be candid with you and give you an opinion on the furniture and clutter situation in your house. You want your space to be open and bright. Keep the windows open and sparkling clean, and get some lamps to add light indoors if need be.

If you have a fireplace, don’t forget to clean the covering, especially if it’s glass. You want buyers to come in and feel a nice, cozy fire and not see a dingy screen. If you have a wood-burning fireplace, clean out all the ashes and paint the back if necessary, as well as stacking the logs nicely for an inviting situation. It just gives a warm feel.

Finally, use the holiday scents to your advantage. Don’t go overboard since some people have allergies, but have a nice, subtle winter scent going to make the house more inviting.

If you have any other questions about preparing your home to sell in the fall and winter or you have any questions about real estate in Utah, give me a call or send me an email today. I’d love to help you out!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Andrew+Ford/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+prepare+your+house+for+a+winter+sale.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Andrew+Ford/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+prepare+your+house+for+a+winter+sale.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you sell your home in the fall or winter, there are a few specific things that you really need to pay attention to.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Andrew Ford</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you sell your home in the fall or winter, there are a few specific things that you really need to pay attention to.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Utah County Real Estate, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 Questions You Need to Ask Yourself Before Buying a Home</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/5-questions-you-need-to-ask-yourself-before-buying-a-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Andrew Ford</author>
        <pubDate>2016-11-27 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Andrew+Ford/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent-+Making+the+leap+from+renting+to+owning.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you currently live in a rental property and you’re thinking about buying your first house, there are a few questions you need to ask yourself before you make that leap:

1. Are you financially prepared? When you’re buying a home, even if you do a zero-down mortgage, there will be other unexpected costs to account for. If you’re renting a home and the toilet backs up, for example, you can simply call the landlord. When you own a home, the burden falls on you.

2. Are you prepared to make some compromises? It’s important to know things like the areas you want to live in, the square footage you’re comfortable with, and how long you planning on living at the home in question. If it’s your first home, you have to figure out what you can live with.

3. Are you emotionally ready? If you can manage those aforementioned compromises, you’ll be in far better shape in answering this question.

&lt;a href=”https://twitter.com/home/?status=”If you own a home, you’re free to do what you want.”%20localhost:4000/5-questions-you-need-to-ask-yourself-before-buying-a-home.html%20via%40” target=’_blank’ class=”pullquote”&gt;““If you own a home, you’re free to do what you want.””&lt;/a&gt;

4. Will owning a home pay off in the long run? If you’re going to live in the home for less than two years, there’s a good chance it’s not worth buying. If you’re going to be there longer, not only will you build some equity in the home, but you’ll also get a good tax deduction from the mortgage interest.

5. Has your lifestyle outgrown your rental property? Maybe you want to get a dog but your landlord won’t allow it. Maybe you want to paint a wall a certain color or tear one out completely to make your kitchen bigger. If you live in a rental, you have to adjust your lifestyle accordingly. If you own a home, you’re free to do what you want.

If you have any questions on this topic or have a topic in mind you’d like to see me discuss in a future video, feel free to reach out to me by phone or email. I look forward to helping you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Andrew+Ford/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent-+Making+the+leap+from+renting+to+owning.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Andrew+Ford/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent-+Making+the+leap+from+renting+to+owning.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you currently live in a rental property and you’re thinking about buying your first house, there are a few questions you need to ask yourself before you make that leap:</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Andrew Ford</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you currently live in a rental property and you’re thinking about buying your first house, there are a few questions you need to ask yourself before you make that leap:</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Utah County Real Estate, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Do You Know Which Realtor to Work With?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-do-you-know-which-realtor-to-work-with.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Andrew Ford</author>
        <pubDate>2016-11-23 10:34:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Andrew+Ford/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+choose+the+best+Realtor.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There are many Realtors out there for you to choose from. How do you know which Realtor you should work with?

First of all, you need to work with someone who really cares. Look for a Realtor who has the heart of a teacher. They will come in prepared to discuss the current market and explain how your choices will impact you down the road.

You need a Realtor who will be a strategic partner with you, someone who will map out a plan. Your Realtor should be your trusted advisor. A good real estate agent can give you advice and good news, but a great agent knows how to deliver the bad news whether you want to hear it or not.

As you go through the home buying process, it’s important to work with someone that you’re comfortable with and confident in. Your Realtor should be someone that you want to have lunch with, but they should also pay attention to you and listen throughout the process.

“Look for a Realtor who has the heart of a teacher.”

My favorite movie as a kid was The Swiss Family Robinson. In the movie, the family dug some pits and covered them up, hoping to catch some wild animals. A fierce, ferocious tiger came along, saw some meat, reached out to get it, and fell in the pit. The same thing can happen to home buyers and sellers.

Sometimes, we get too excited about a house or an offer and forget to look around us, so we end up getting trapped. You need to work with a trusted advisor who knows how to avoid those pitfalls.

We can certainly help you do that. If you have any questions, just give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Andrew+Ford/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+choose+the+best+Realtor.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Andrew+Ford/Utah+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+choose+the+best+Realtor.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There are many Realtors out there for you to choose from. How do you know which Realtor you should work with?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Andrew Ford</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There are many Realtors out there for you to choose from. How do you know which Realtor you should work with?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Utah County Real Estate, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Even FANNIE MAE Agrees: Hire A Pro To Sell Your House</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/even-fannie-mae-agrees-hire-a-pro-to-sell-your-house.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Andrew Ford</author>
        <pubDate>2016-11-12 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Do you really need an agent to sell your house in today’s market? Here’s what Fannie Mae suggests to sellers on the “Know Your Options” section of their website:

“Select how you’ll market and list the home (e.g., with a real estate agent or for sale by owner). There are pros and cons to each, but unless you are experienced at selling homes, it usually makes financial sense to get professional help—homes sold by agents typically sell at a higher price and spend less time on the market. An agent will also help you determine the best pricing for the house, they’ll market the home, and they’ll be your advocate throughout the process.”

Let’s go over the points they made:

• Homes sold by agents typically sell at a higher price

• Homes sold by agents typically spend less time on the market

• An agent will help you determine the best pricing for the house

• An agent will market the home

• An agent will be your advocate throughout the process

If Fannie Mae says that using an agent probably makes sense, perhaps you should interview an agent before putting your house up for sale.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Do you really need an agent to sell your house in today’s market? Here’s what Fannie Mae suggests to sellers on the “Know Your Options” section of their website:</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Andrew Ford</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Do you really need an agent to sell your house in today’s market? Here’s what Fannie Mae suggests to sellers on the “Know Your Options” section of their website:</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Utah County Real Estate, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Can Homeownership Benefit Your Children?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-can-homeownership-benefit-your-children.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Andrew Ford</author>
        <pubDate>2016-11-04 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>There are a lot of things that homeownership brings to communities. Homeownership provides social benefits beyond pure financial economic benefits.

Young people that grow up in a situation with homeownership, they’re in a different place than those people that are not. It’s not saying that every renter’s kid is not going to go well in school, have a drug problem, and commit a crime. But the stability of owning a home and everything that brings, helps, gives kids an advantage. Why not give as many of those kids an advantage as you possibly can.

Homeowners are more likely to be involved in a community. Studies have shown this. Academic studies have shown this. Civic engagements, local elections, and volunteer work compared to renters, again, with other things being equal. That not only makes sense, we call it pride of ownership.

If you own a house in a neighborhood, you just care more about that house than if you’re going to be transient and rent, then rent the next neighborhood or the next city in two years from now. You get more involved because you’re putting roots down there.

This has been an argument for the last couple of years. People who own homes have an equity they can tap into, and perhaps when their children, their teenage children, decide that they’re going to go to college.

Well, people that are homeowners can help their kids out with that. They can look their kids in the eye and say, “Are you worth the investment? Is it worth me taking money out of the house to invest in you?” And so many parents see that yes, it is. And that’s what the study from Boston Federal Reserve shows. Homeowners’ children – the income of homeowners’ children rises as values rise. The more they’re able to invest in their kids, the better future their kids have.

Again, we don’t list and sell houses for a living. We change people’s lives for a living. We do it by listing and selling homes.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There are a lot of things that homeownership brings to communities. Homeownership provides social benefits beyond pure financial economic benefits.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Andrew Ford</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There are a lot of things that homeownership brings to communities. Homeownership provides social benefits beyond pure financial economic benefits.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Utah County Real Estate, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Should You Sell Your Home This Fall? Five Reasons Why You Should!</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/should-you-sell-your-home-this-fall-five-reasons-why-you-should.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Andrew Ford</author>
        <pubDate>2016-10-19 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>The fall real estate market is upon us. Should you sell your home now or wait for spring? Here are five reasons why you should consider listing your home now:

1. Demand is very strong right now. There is a lot of pent-up demand out there. People have been wanting to sell their homes for a long time and they are finally able to do it. There are also a lot of buyers who have been sitting in rentals and waiting for their credit to be cleaned up and are now ready to go. Not only that, a lot of people want to get into their new homes before the holidays.

2. There is less competition. Although people want to get into their new homes for the holidays, you don’t have to worry about that summer crowd full of people who are just shopping around. Buyers won’t have to compete with 10, 15, or 20 other offers — instead, if you’re buying a home, you may only face off against one or two other people. Buyers in the fall are also more serious about purchasing a home.

3. The whole process can be quicker in the fall. In the summer, many people run into underwriting and closing issues at the end of the month. Since there are fewer people in the market, underwriters, processors, and title companies are able to move a bit quicker, ensuring a smoother process for you.

4. It is a good time to buy a home right now. CoreLogic projects that property values will go up 5.3% this coming year. If you’ve been thinking about selling your current home and moving up into a bigger one, now is a good time to do so and capitalize on that appreciation. By this time next year, interest rates will be about 0.5% higher. This combination adds a lot of money to your bottom line immediately and will compound over time.

5. What are your reasons for moving? Consider why you are selling your house. Is it time for you to move closer to family or closer to work? Do you need to move up or downsize? If now is the time to sell your home and buy another, don’t wait for spring. Your reason for moving is the most important reason to consider buying or selling this fall.

If you have any other questions about the fall market or about real estate in general, give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!

 

 
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>The fall real estate market is upon us. Should you sell your home now or wait for spring? Here are five reasons why you should consider listing your home now:</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Andrew Ford</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>The fall real estate market is upon us. Should you sell your home now or wait for spring? Here are five reasons why you should consider listing your home now:</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Utah County Real Estate, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Andrew Ford</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Andrew Ford</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Utah Homes Team - your professional Utah County Real Estate Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
