<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Dave Hooke Team LLC - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Dave Hooke</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2017-03-28 13:52:39 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Dave Hooke</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">News &amp; Politics</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Dave@hhande.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Dave Hooke</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the  Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Dave Hooke Team LLC - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="News &amp; Politics"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Determine Whether Internet Leads Are Right for Your Business</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-to-determine-whether-internet-leads.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate Business Tips</category>
        
        <author>Dave Hooke</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-22 15:49:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Are Internet leads worth your time and money? 20% of real estate business comes from these leads, but it’s not quite that simple for everyone.*

Join The Team

Should you spend your time and money on Internet leads like Zillow and Realtor.com? There’s a lot of talk in the industry about these kinds of leads and whether they’re worth your while. A lot of teams have success with Internet leads, but the question is whether it’s worth your while for you specifically. Two years ago, an NAR study showed that referral business was still the No. 1 source of real estate business in the United States, but also that 20% of real estate business was generated by Internet leads. Keep in mind that an MIT response study found that if you can’t follow up with an Internet lead in five minutes or less, it’s probably not worth your while. Do you have the technology, systems, and capacity to follow up with them that quickly? The average agent last year took 61 hours to follow up with an Internet lead, so consider that before you decide to invest your time and money in them. Secondly, be aware that it takes seven to eight follow-ups to build a rapport with a lead. Do you have that kind of time and capacity?

“Overall, it takes a lot of money, time, systems, and technology to do it well.”

Third, remember that the money generated from Internet leads are often generated in long-term follow-up. Most Internet leads are six to 12 months from their buy-in window at the time that they inquire. Not only do you have to follow up quickly and often, you have to follow up for a long time. Overall, it takes a lot of money, time, systems, and technology to do it well. If you’re at a point in your business where you’ve leveraged help from other people and you have the time and money to spend on systems and technology to pursue Internet leads, it might be a great decision for your business. I hope you found this discussion helpful. If you have any questions or you’d like to talk further about building your business, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Are Internet leads worth your time and money? 20% of real estate business comes from these leads, but it’s not quite that simple for everyone.*

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Are Internet leads worth your time and money? 20% of real estate business comes from these leads, but it’s not quite that simple for everyone.*

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Don’t Let Your Business Run You</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/dont-let-your-business-run-you.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate Business Tips</category>
        
        <author>Dave Hooke</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-27 12:53:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Don’t let your business run you. Implement these three strategies to run your business.*
Join The Team
&gt;How do you make sure that you are running your business instead of letting your business run you? I use three strategies in my day-to-day business that work really well.
First of all, set a daily voicemail. It only takes about 30 seconds. Say something along the lines of, “This is Dave Hooke. Today is Wednesday, February such-and-such. I will be available from 9 a.m. to 5 p.m. today. Your call is important to me and will be returned as soon as possible. If you call after 5:30, I will call you back tomorrow. Thank you and have a great day.”
That voicemail gives me peace of mind because it lets my customers know right away when they will hear back from me depending on when they call.
We’ve all gotten a call at 7 p.m. or 8 p.m. from a customer. I used to feel guilty or like I was slacking off if I didn’t answer the call. Now, thanks to the voicemail, there are boundaries. The customer knows that I am on top of things and that they will get a call back tomorrow. After you use the voicemail for a couple of months, your customers will start any calls after 5:30 p.m. with an apology.

Secondly, make sure to include an office hours page in each and every buyer and seller presentation. This sheet summarizes when your team is open for business. Ask your team to abide by those hours as much as they can. The office hours sheet sets expectations with the buyer or seller before they sign with you.

When you explain that, like any other business, yours has business hours, your clients will respect that. Let them know that if there is an emergency, you’ll get back to them as soon as possible. The office hours sheet combined with the daily voicemail will make a big difference in your business.

“Set expectations and boundaries with your clients.”

Finally, make sure that you time block your important, but not urgent, tasks. We know what those are because these are tasks we like to procrastinate on. Those tasks really drive our lives and businesses forward. Whether it’s managing your database or sending handwritten notes to clients, block out an hour or two every day to take care of those tasks.

I like to go a step further and time block for exercising and family time. After 5:30 p.m., my rule is no work, no exceptions. If you have kids, add a note in your calendar that says, “We are counting on you, Mom!” or “We are counting on you, Dad!” It might feel like you are missing out on some things at work for the first couple of weeks but after a month or so, things will fall into place. Keep those time blocks in place, no exceptions.

Implementing these three strategies will help you run your business instead of allowing your business to run you. If you have any questions, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Don’t let your business run you. Implement these three strategies to run your business.*
Join The Team
&gt;How do you make sure that you are running your business instead of letting your business run you? I use three strategies in my day-to-day business that work really well.
First of all, set a daily voicemail. It only takes about 30 seconds. Say something along the lines of, “This is Dave Hooke. Today is Wednesday, February such-and-such. I will be available from 9 a.m. to 5 p.m. today. Your call is important to me and will be returned as soon as possible. If you call after 5:30, I will call you back tomorrow. Thank you and have a great day.”
That voicemail gives me peace of mind because it lets my customers know right away when they will hear back from me depending on when they call.
We’ve all gotten a call at 7 p.m. or 8 p.m. from a customer. I used to feel guilty or like I was slacking off if I didn’t answer the call. Now, thanks to the voicemail, there are boundaries. The customer knows that I am on top of things and that they will get a call back tomorrow. After you use the voicemail for a couple of months, your customers will start any calls after 5:30 p.m. with an apology.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Dave Hooke</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Don’t let your business run you. Implement these three strategies to run your business.*
Join The Team
&gt;How do you make sure that you are running your business instead of letting your business run you? I use three strategies in my day-to-day business that work really well.
First of all, set a daily voicemail. It only takes about 30 seconds. Say something along the lines of, “This is Dave Hooke. Today is Wednesday, February such-and-such. I will be available from 9 a.m. to 5 p.m. today. Your call is important to me and will be returned as soon as possible. If you call after 5:30, I will call you back tomorrow. Thank you and have a great day.”
That voicemail gives me peace of mind because it lets my customers know right away when they will hear back from me depending on when they call.
We’ve all gotten a call at 7 p.m. or 8 p.m. from a customer. I used to feel guilty or like I was slacking off if I didn’t answer the call. Now, thanks to the voicemail, there are boundaries. The customer knows that I am on top of things and that they will get a call back tomorrow. After you use the voicemail for a couple of months, your customers will start any calls after 5:30 p.m. with an apology.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Dave Hooke</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Dave Hooke</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Dave Hooke Team LLC - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
