<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Roanoke Real Estate Podcast with Damon Gettier</title>
    <link>http://swvirginiarealestatecareers.com/</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://swvirginiarealestatecareers.com/"/>
    <description>A podcast about real estate careers and training in the Roanoke, Virginia area, brought to you by Damon Gettier of Damon Gettier & Associates.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Damon Gettier</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2017-10-16 11:31:40 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Damon Gettier</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://swvirginiarealestatecareers.com//img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Roanoke Real Estate, Real Estate Careers, Real Estate Professionals, Realtors, Real estate industry, how much do realtors make</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Damon@DamonGettier.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Damon Gettier</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Damon Gettier</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://swvirginiarealestatecareers.com//img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Roanoke Real Estate, Real Estate Careers, Real Estate Professionals, Realtors, Real estate industry, how much do realtors make</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Boost your Career with Veteran Real Estate Agent Damon Gettier</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>A podcast about real estate careers and training in the Roanoke, Virginia area, brought to you by Damon Gettier of Damon Gettier & Associates.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Is Education So Important to Real Estate Agents?</title>
        <link>http://swvirginiarealestatecareers.com//the-one-thing-you-need-to-do-to-be.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate Coaching</category>
        
        <author>Damon Gettier</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-05 14:57:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Coaching/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+key+to+success+in+real+estate.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The one thing you need to do to be a successful real estate agent is to make sure that you get an education, and I’m not talking about studying for your licensing exam.

Book a FREE Business Strategy Session

One of the keys to success in our business is education.

If I can name one thing that a real estate agent should do, it’s to make sure that you get an education.

I’m not talking about getting your real estate license. When you get a real estate license, you take a course, you take a test, and then you forget all about it.

I’m talking about learning how to sell. I don’t mean selling real estate. No one in real estate sells houses. You need to learn how to sell your own skills and expertise. Nobody on my team has sold a house to a client because the client picks the house.

We sell what we do for the client. We sell how we can do that better than anyone else.

“YOU NEED TO LEARN HOW TO SELL YOUR SKILLS AND EXPERTISE.”

Selling is helping people realize that where they think they want to be might not be where they actually want to be. Selling is about overcoming self-imposed objections.

If you’re going to be a professional agent, you need to learn your craft. This is not something to be taken lightly. This is not a hobby. Anyone who wants to be the best should learn from the best.

Thankfully, we have a group of mentors here who have helped us, taught us, and brought us along on the journey. If you want to learn how to sell houses at a very high level, give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Coaching/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+key+to+success+in+real+estate.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://swvirginiarealestatecareers.com/" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Coaching/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+key+to+success+in+real+estate.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

The one thing you need to do to be a successful real estate agent is to make sure that you get an education, and I’m not talking about studying for your licensing exam.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Damon Gettier</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

The one thing you need to do to be a successful real estate agent is to make sure that you get an education, and I’m not talking about studying for your licensing exam.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Roanoke Real Estate, Real Estate Careers, Real Estate Professionals, Realtors, Real estate industry, how much do realtors make</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Do You Still Need a Website as an Agent?</title>
        <link>http://swvirginiarealestatecareers.com//do-you-still-need-website-as-agent.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate Coaching</category>
        
        <author>Damon Gettier</author>
        <pubDate>2016-12-01 14:51:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Do+you+even+need+a+website+anymore%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Do you need a website as a real estate agent in this marketplace? Lots of agents I talk to seem to think they don’t need them anymore. Here’s why I think they’re crucial.

Book a FREE Business Strategy Session

As a real estate agent in this market, should you have a website? A lot of agents ask me if anyone even needs a website in this market anymore.

My answer is this: your website is your calling card. It’s where people go to find out whether you’re legitimate or not. They want to see whether you list and sell homes.

I encourage anyone who is serious about the real estate business to either join a team with a great website or a company with a great website. It’s hard to buy a $50 solution to a website and still be seen as legitimate in the marketplace.

“YOUR WEBSITE IS YOUR CALLING CARD.”

In short, when companies like mine spend tens of thousands of dollars every month on websites, it’s hard to compete if you have a cheap, $50 website. Every website manufacturer out there will tell you it’s possible, but it’s simply not.

If you’re going to be a real estate agent and take the job seriously, I suggest you spend the money on the tools to do the job right. If you have any questions about how we do it and who we use or if you’re interested in joining our team, give me a call or send me an email. I hope to hear from you soon!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Do+you+even+need+a+website+anymore%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://swvirginiarealestatecareers.com/" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Do+you+even+need+a+website+anymore%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Do you need a website as a real estate agent in this marketplace? Lots of agents I talk to seem to think they don’t need them anymore. Here’s why I think they’re crucial.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Damon Gettier</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Do you need a website as a real estate agent in this marketplace? Lots of agents I talk to seem to think they don’t need them anymore. Here’s why I think they’re crucial.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Roanoke Real Estate, Real Estate Careers, Real Estate Professionals, Realtors, Real estate industry, how much do realtors make</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Whats Our Secret to Getting New Clients?</title>
        <link>http://swvirginiarealestatecareers.com//whats-our-secret-to-getting-new-clients.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate Coaching</category>
        
        <author>Damon Gettier</author>
        <pubDate>2016-11-15 12:53:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+This+is+how+we+attract+clients.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Our strategy for getting new clients is quite simple. We go out of our way to meet and talk to people we haven’t before.

Book a FREE Business Strategy Session

Today we are excited to discuss with you our strategy to getting more clients. We are in the house selling business, so what do we have to do? Expose ourselves to more and more people every week.

The goal for everyone on our team is to meet 40 new people each week that we have never talked to before. Some people might ask why we are giving away our strategy. Simply put, we don’t believe that our competitors are willing to put in the work we put in to talk to this many new people each week.

“YOU WANT TO MEET MORE AND MORE PEOPLE ALL THE TIME.”

Last year, we talked to 2,000 people we had never talked to before. When you do that, it’s hard not to get new business buying and selling houses. You want to meet more and more people all the time. If you aren’t expanding your network, you won’t succeed in this business.

If you have any questions for us or want to learn more about expanding your list of contacts, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+This+is+how+we+attract+clients.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://swvirginiarealestatecareers.com/" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+This+is+how+we+attract+clients.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Our strategy for getting new clients is quite simple. We go out of our way to meet and talk to people we haven’t before.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Damon Gettier</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Our strategy for getting new clients is quite simple. We go out of our way to meet and talk to people we haven’t before.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Roanoke Real Estate, Real Estate Careers, Real Estate Professionals, Realtors, Real estate industry, how much do realtors make</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How New Agents Can Get Leads</title>
        <link>http://swvirginiarealestatecareers.com//how-new-agents-can-get-leads.html</link>
        
          <category>Coaching</category>
        
        <author>Damon Gettier</author>
        <pubDate>2016-11-01 13:29:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Coaching/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Solving+the+hardest+part+of+your+real+estate+career.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’re new to the business of real estate, the first thing you should do is ask yourself where you’re going to get business from. Getting new leads is the hardest part of real estate.

Book a FREE Business Strategy Session

A lot of agents ask me what I would do if I was first getting into the business, so I wanted to drop by with some important tips for brand-new agents.

If I was entering the business today, the first thing I would do is ask myself where I’m going to get business. If you don’t have a ready answer for that, you need to put things on pause and figure it out.

Getting business and leads is the hardest part of this business.

When I first got into the business, I spent the first month and a half in the phone book calling the A’s and asking if anyone wanted to buy or sell a house. I didn’t sell a house until I got to the B’s! It took a month and a half to get a sale because I had no book of business.

“GETTING LEADS IS THE HARDEST PART OF THIS BUSINESS.”

If you ask yourself where you’re going to get business from and you don’t know the answer, I’d highly recommend investigating a team. On our team, we love new agents because we can teach them. Old agents tend to come with old habits. New agents who have been in the business for less than a couple of years do great on our team and they sell tons of houses, and we love them.

Newer agents are able to sell a ton of houses with us because we have a book of business for them. They walk in and they instantly have leads–which are the hardest thing in this business to get.

If you have any questions about developing business and getting leads, give me a call. I’d love to talk with you and help you advance your career.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Coaching/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Solving+the+hardest+part+of+your+real+estate+career.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://swvirginiarealestatecareers.com/" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Coaching/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Solving+the+hardest+part+of+your+real+estate+career.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you’re new to the business of real estate, the first thing you should do is ask yourself where you’re going to get business from. Getting new leads is the hardest part of real estate.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Damon Gettier</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you’re new to the business of real estate, the first thing you should do is ask yourself where you’re going to get business from. Getting new leads is the hardest part of real estate.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Roanoke Real Estate, Real Estate Careers, Real Estate Professionals, Realtors, Real estate industry, how much do realtors make</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Prepare Your Roanoke Home for Listing Photos</title>
        <link>http://swvirginiarealestatecareers.com//there-are-few-steps-sellers-should-take.html</link>
        
          <category>Photography</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate Coaching</category>
        
        <author>Damon Gettier</author>
        <pubDate>2016-09-09 12:43:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

There are a few steps sellers should take to get their homes ready for listing photos.

First of all, organize and clean the home so it looks spacious and inviting to buyers. You don’t want the home to look sparse, but you do need to declutter. Get everything off the countertops. You can maybe leave a decorative, colorful cannister out, but put the coffeepot and the toaster away.

Now, you don’t necessarily need to have everything hidden away for home showings, but it does have to be like that for the photos. No one likes a photo of themselves, even though it’s a picture of the same person you saw in the mirror this morning. Photos are still, which gives you a chance to examine every detail you don’t like. The same holds true for photos of your home on the MLS.

So, get everything off the top of the fridge, make a nice arrangement on the table, and make sure everything is in its place. If you have to move a bunch of stuff into a separate room to take the photos, go ahead. You can just move everything back later.

“MAKE SURE YOUR HOME LOOKS NICE AND SPACIOUS IN THE PHOTOS.”

Finally, make sure you take photos when the sun is on the front of your house and there are no shadows. Shadows can make a home look sad and dismal. You should also make sure that the front yard looks nice; put down fresh mulch and seal the driveway. Then, your listing photos will be in great shape.

If you have any questions, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://swvirginiarealestatecareers.com/" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

There are a few steps sellers should take to get their homes ready for listing photos.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Damon Gettier</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

There are a few steps sellers should take to get their homes ready for listing photos.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Roanoke Real Estate, Real Estate Careers, Real Estate Professionals, Realtors, Real estate industry, how much do realtors make</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Does a Home Seller Conquer Clutter in Roanoke?</title>
        <link>http://swvirginiarealestatecareers.com//roanoke-real-estate-agent-how-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate Coaching</category>
        
        <author>Damon Gettier</author>
        <pubDate>2016-08-09 13:07:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Looking to improve your real estate career? I’m here to help you make a smart decision when it comes to growing your business, improving your bottom line, and choosing a place to work in real estate sales. If you’d like to learn more about working with Damon Gettier and Associates, contact me at 540-314-1199 or &lt;a href=”mailto:Damon@DamonGettier.com”Damon@DamonGettier.com&lt;/a&gt;.

How do we get a seller to conquer clutter?

What we did recently is had our photographer and one of our assistants go into a $300,000 house, photograph it as is, declutter it, and then re-photograph it the same day. We did that because I don’t like before/after photos - the lighting is different, the house is different, the camera’s different, even the location is different. Our true before and after photos could amply demonstrate that.

We tell sellers all the time that the first thing people do when they decide to sell a car is detail it. The logic is no different with selling a house. If your house is filled to the brim (and most are), then the next potential buyer is going to be discouraged from buying it. That’s why you need to make the house look spacious. It has to feel warm, inviting, and show people there is plenty of room in there to live in and be happy. If it’s cluttered, you’re never going to get that feeling.

“BOX UP ALL THE THINGS YOU DON’T NEED AND STORE THEM ELSEWHERE.”

Therefore, box up everything that you don’t need and ship it out. If it’s spring or summer, get rid of all your winter clothes. If the kids have toys they don’t play with anymore, they go too. If you can’t afford to rent a storage unit or a pod to store it all, that’s fine. Just use your garage or basement. If it has to be the basement, stack your boxes very neatly from floor-to-ceiling so that it takes up the least amount of footprint possible. If you do that, you’re house will appear much more spacious and inviting, and sell faster and for more money.

If you have any questions about staging, decluttering, or joining Roanoke’s #1 team, please reach out to us. We’d be happy to talk to you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://swvirginiarealestatecareers.com/" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Looking to improve your real estate career? I’m here to help you make a smart decision when it comes to growing your business, improving your bottom line, and choosing a place to work in real estate sales. If you’d like to learn more about working with Damon Gettier and Associates, contact me at 540-314-1199 or &lt;a href=”mailto:Damon@DamonGettier.com”Damon@DamonGettier.com&lt;/a&gt;.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Damon Gettier</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Looking to improve your real estate career? I’m here to help you make a smart decision when it comes to growing your business, improving your bottom line, and choosing a place to work in real estate sales. If you’d like to learn more about working with Damon Gettier and Associates, contact me at 540-314-1199 or &lt;a href=”mailto:Damon@DamonGettier.com”Damon@DamonGettier.com&lt;/a&gt;.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Roanoke Real Estate, Real Estate Careers, Real Estate Professionals, Realtors, Real estate industry, how much do realtors make</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Gifts Show Your Clients How Much You Value Them</title>
        <link>http://swvirginiarealestatecareers.com//roanoke-real-estate-agent-give-clients.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate Coaching</category>
        
        <author>Damon Gettier</author>
        <pubDate>2016-07-05 09:43:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Protect+your+rights+as+a+buyer.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Looking to improve your real estate career? I’m here to help you make a smart decision when it comes to growing your business, improving your bottom line, and choosing a place to work in real estate sales. If you’d like to learn more about working with Damon Gettier and Associates, contact me at 540-314-1199 or &lt;a href=”mailto:Damon@DamonGettier.com”Damon@DamonGettier.com&lt;/a&gt;.

Giving gifts is a great way to show clients how much you value them. I wanted to share some of my favorite ideas with you today. Clients appreciate anything of value that you give as a gift with heartfelt sincerity.

We always send a handwritten card to every single client. It’s been a game-changer for us. We also send a handwritten card to every agent we deal with now, and we’ve also started giving a gift card to every agent. The way we see it, we worked a deal with them, and our goal in life is to work a deal with every agent and have everybody come out of it happy. We give every client a gift card as well.

“WE WANT TO GIVE CLIENTS A GIFT THAT PROVIDES VALUE AND STAYS WITH THEM.”

The other thing we do for our clients is give them a Cutco knife. We made an investment of about $20,000 into Cutco last year, and we give one to each client because we value the relationship, and we want to give them something in return that provides value, and stays with them. Some give a gift basket, for example, but that just doesn’t stay with you.

Likewise, a gift card to a restaurant doesn’t last. Right now, if someone buys or sells a house with us, we’re giving them a cruise. They’re spending a lot of money, and it gives them a chance at a vacation after the big transaction. Some can afford vacations and some can’t so we like to give that opportunity to everyone.

If you’re looking for more ideas for gifts, please feel free to give me a call. I’d love to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Protect+your+rights+as+a+buyer.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://swvirginiarealestatecareers.com/" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Protect+your+rights+as+a+buyer.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Looking to improve your real estate career? I’m here to help you make a smart decision when it comes to growing your business, improving your bottom line, and choosing a place to work in real estate sales. If you’d like to learn more about working with Damon Gettier and Associates, contact me at 540-314-1199 or &lt;a href=”mailto:Damon@DamonGettier.com”Damon@DamonGettier.com&lt;/a&gt;.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Damon Gettier</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Looking to improve your real estate career? I’m here to help you make a smart decision when it comes to growing your business, improving your bottom line, and choosing a place to work in real estate sales. If you’d like to learn more about working with Damon Gettier and Associates, contact me at 540-314-1199 or &lt;a href=”mailto:Damon@DamonGettier.com”Damon@DamonGettier.com&lt;/a&gt;.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Roanoke Real Estate, Real Estate Careers, Real Estate Professionals, Realtors, Real estate industry, how much do realtors make</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Effect of Tech on the Roanoke Market</title>
        <link>http://swvirginiarealestatecareers.com//roanoke-real-estate-agent-tech-effect.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate Trends</category>
        
        <author>Damon Gettier</author>
        <pubDate>2016-06-03 13:44:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Damon+Gettier+Tech+Trends.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Looking to improve your real estate career? I’m here to help you make a smart decision when it comes to growing your business, improving your bottom line, and choosing a place to work in real estate sales. If you’d like to learn more about working with Damon Gettier and Associates, contact me at 540-314-1199 or &lt;a href=”mailto:Damon@DamonGettier.com”Damon@DamonGettier.com&lt;/a&gt;.

Did you know that tech trends have an influence on real estate? Some of them may surprise you.

Virtual reality headsets play a part in real estate now with 3D videos that can be used for home tours. You can use the headset to virtually walk through a house! I’ve got friends across the country who are testing this now with clients. It looks like it might be a game changer for showings.

Drone technology has also taken over the world in the last couple years. Now you have to have a pilot license for drones, but there are companies around Roanoke that use drone videos. This will change the way you see a property.

“Virtual reality headsets might be a game changer for showings.”

One of the most intriguing trends we’re seeing is smart homes. Personally I have the Nest thermostat, and I can control my house and my office temperatures from my phone. Video cameras have become much more popular in homes as well, which give you a real-time view of what’s happening during a showing or open house. You can also hear what you’re saying, so we need to be careful about what we do and say in a house.

If you want to learn more about how technology is changing real estate or have any real estate questions, don’t hesitate to call or email us today!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Damon+Gettier+Tech+Trends.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://swvirginiarealestatecareers.com/" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+Damon+Gettier+Tech+Trends.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Looking to improve your real estate career? I’m here to help you make a smart decision when it comes to growing your business, improving your bottom line, and choosing a place to work in real estate sales. If you’d like to learn more about working with Damon Gettier and Associates, contact me at 540-314-1199 or &lt;a href=”mailto:Damon@DamonGettier.com”Damon@DamonGettier.com&lt;/a&gt;.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Damon Gettier</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Looking to improve your real estate career? I’m here to help you make a smart decision when it comes to growing your business, improving your bottom line, and choosing a place to work in real estate sales. If you’d like to learn more about working with Damon Gettier and Associates, contact me at 540-314-1199 or &lt;a href=”mailto:Damon@DamonGettier.com”Damon@DamonGettier.com&lt;/a&gt;.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Roanoke Real Estate, Real Estate Careers, Real Estate Professionals, Realtors, Real estate industry, how much do realtors make</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Our Clients Become Clients for Life</title>
        <link>http://swvirginiarealestatecareers.com//roanoke-real-estate-agent-were-selling.html</link>
        
          <category>Make your clients</category>
        
          <category>clients for life</category>
        
        <author>Damon Gettier</author>
        <pubDate>2016-05-02 12:24:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Looking to improve your real estate career? I’m here to help you make a smart decision when it comes to growing your business, improving your bottom line, and choosing a place to work in real estate sales. If you’d like to learn more about working with Damon Gettier and Associates, contact me at 540-314-1199 or &lt;a href=”mailto:Damon@DamonGettier.com”Damon@DamonGettier.com&lt;/a&gt;.

How do we help clients find a home for life?

The biggest thing we stress on our team is that when we’re selling, the only thing we are selling is our team. We sell houses, but we don’t sell people on houses. We don’t try to convince our clients to buy or not to buy, the selling we do is completely within our team.

That’s why our clients want to do business with us. They see the value and benefits we offer them, and how we can do more for them as a team than any other agent can. That’s what we’re selling.

“We want our buyers to be buyers for life.”

We want our buyers to be buyers for life, so we listen to their needs, assess them, and look for corresponding homes that match. When we show them a house and they try to convince themselves to buy it even though it’s not what they want, we remind them of what they told us they wanted. We want them to be sure they are buying the house that they want.

Another way we help our buyers is by offering a love it or leave it listing guarantee. If they don’t love the home they bought, we will sell it for free for them within the next year. We never want our buyers to feel trapped.

If you have any other questions for us, or want to sit down and talk about your career and how Damon Gettier &amp; Associates can help you, give us a call or send us an email. We’d love to hear from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://swvirginiarealestatecareers.com/" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Looking to improve your real estate career? I’m here to help you make a smart decision when it comes to growing your business, improving your bottom line, and choosing a place to work in real estate sales. If you’d like to learn more about working with Damon Gettier and Associates, contact me at 540-314-1199 or &lt;a href=”mailto:Damon@DamonGettier.com”Damon@DamonGettier.com&lt;/a&gt;.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Damon Gettier</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Looking to improve your real estate career? I’m here to help you make a smart decision when it comes to growing your business, improving your bottom line, and choosing a place to work in real estate sales. If you’d like to learn more about working with Damon Gettier and Associates, contact me at 540-314-1199 or &lt;a href=”mailto:Damon@DamonGettier.com”Damon@DamonGettier.com&lt;/a&gt;.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Roanoke Real Estate, Real Estate Careers, Real Estate Professionals, Realtors, Real estate industry, how much do realtors make</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reaching your Clients through Video</title>
        <link>http://swvirginiarealestatecareers.com//roanoke-virginia-real-estate-coaching.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate Coaching</category>
        
        <author>Damon Gettier</author>
        <pubDate>2014-08-29 12:39:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Coaching/8.15/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+best+way+to+reach+your+clients.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Looking to improve your real estate career? I’m here to help you make a smart decision when it comes to growing your business, improving your bottom line, and choosing a place to work in real estate sales. If you’d like to learn more about working with Damon Gettier and Associates, contact me at 540-314-1199 or &lt;a href=”mailto:Damon@DamonGettier.com”Damon@DamonGettier.com&lt;/a&gt;.

Reaching your Clients through Video

A lot of people ask us, “Why video?” when they find out how we market ourselves to our past, present and future clients. Well, it just so happens that the 2nd most used search engine in the world is a video site. That’s right, we are talking about YouTube. Everybody has got a smart phone now and people like video. Being able to show a house through video can show the property in a much better light than pictures can. With video, you are positioning yourself where the consumer is and where they are looking. Not all video is helpful, however. Consumers enjoy watching videos and TV shows about homes and home improvements, but the information they get from those shows is inaccurate and wrong.

When we do videos with our marketing partner, Vyral Marketing, we are giving out short, educational videos that add value and give information about current events to our clients. Are they going to watch these types of videos every day? No, but when they are thinking of buying or selling, they are going to find these videos. The real point of the videos is to get the message across to the consumer as they are looking, so you can position yourself as an expert in the area.

If you have any questions about how to insert video in your marketing, please give us a call. We’d love to answer any and all questions you might have.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Coaching/8.15/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+best+way+to+reach+your+clients.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://swvirginiarealestatecareers.com/" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Coaching/8.15/Roanoke+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+best+way+to+reach+your+clients.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Looking to improve your real estate career? I’m here to help you make a smart decision when it comes to growing your business, improving your bottom line, and choosing a place to work in real estate sales. If you’d like to learn more about working with Damon Gettier and Associates, contact me at 540-314-1199 or &lt;a href=”mailto:Damon@DamonGettier.com”Damon@DamonGettier.com&lt;/a&gt;.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Damon Gettier</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Looking to improve your real estate career? I’m here to help you make a smart decision when it comes to growing your business, improving your bottom line, and choosing a place to work in real estate sales. If you’d like to learn more about working with Damon Gettier and Associates, contact me at 540-314-1199 or &lt;a href=”mailto:Damon@DamonGettier.com”Damon@DamonGettier.com&lt;/a&gt;.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Roanoke Real Estate, Real Estate Careers, Real Estate Professionals, Realtors, Real estate industry, how much do realtors make</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What does Zillow's buyout of Trulia Mean for You?</title>
        <link>http://swvirginiarealestatecareers.com//roanoke-virginia-real-estate.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate Coaching</category>
        
        <author>Damon Gettier</author>
        <pubDate>2014-08-13 10:53:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Coaching/8.1/Roanoke+VA+Real+Estate+-+The+fate+of+the+real+estate+industry.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Looking to improve your real estate career? I’m here to help you make a smart decision when it comes to growing your business, improving your bottom line, and choosing a place to work in real estate sales. If you’d like to learn more about working with Damon Gettier and Associates, contact me at 540-314-1199 or &lt;a href=”mailto:Damon@DamonGettier.com”Damon@DamonGettier.com&lt;/a&gt;.

What does Zillow’s buyout of Trulia Mean for You?

Today we want to touch on a recent topic that has been in the news. If you have been paying attention to real estate news recently, you already know that internet home search giant Zillow has recently bought out their biggest competitor, Trulia, for $3.5 billion. We know that a lot of people in the real estate world are concerned about this. They know what the internet did to the travel agency business and are afraid that the same thing will happen in real estate with this buyout.

We tell our agents not to worry about this. Real estate is local, travel agencies are not. They were selling trips, not houses. Travel is a hobby, a luxury if you will. Real estate is something that people will always purchase and always need. Real estate agents have that distinct advantage of being local. We have feet on the ground, know the market and inventory. As long as we as professionals know our craft, our inventory, and what we are doing and can do our job in a competent manner, we don’t think any of these sites are a threat. They only become a threat when we don’t know our job and rely on them to do our job for us.

If you have any questions about the buyout or anything else real estate related, please feel free to give us a call. We’d love to sit down with you to discuss your career.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Coaching/8.1/Roanoke+VA+Real+Estate+-+The+fate+of+the+real+estate+industry.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://swvirginiarealestatecareers.com/" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Coaching/8.1/Roanoke+VA+Real+Estate+-+The+fate+of+the+real+estate+industry.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Looking to improve your real estate career? I’m here to help you make a smart decision when it comes to growing your business, improving your bottom line, and choosing a place to work in real estate sales. If you’d like to learn more about working with Damon Gettier and Associates, contact me at 540-314-1199 or &lt;a href=”mailto:Damon@DamonGettier.com”Damon@DamonGettier.com&lt;/a&gt;.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Damon Gettier</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Looking to improve your real estate career? I’m here to help you make a smart decision when it comes to growing your business, improving your bottom line, and choosing a place to work in real estate sales. If you’d like to learn more about working with Damon Gettier and Associates, contact me at 540-314-1199 or &lt;a href=”mailto:Damon@DamonGettier.com”Damon@DamonGettier.com&lt;/a&gt;.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Roanoke Real Estate, Real Estate Careers, Real Estate Professionals, Realtors, Real estate industry, how much do realtors make</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Avoid Becoming Overwhelmed this Selling Season</title>
        <link>http://swvirginiarealestatecareers.com//roanoke-virginia-real-estate-coaching.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Coaching</category>
        
        <author>Damon Gettier</author>
        <pubDate>2014-05-12 16:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Coaching/Roanoke+VA+Real+Estate+-+Are+you+properly+and+effectively+managing+your+leads.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Looking to improve your real estate career? I’m here to help you make a smart decision when it comes to growing your business, improving your bottom line, and choosing a place to work in real estate sales. If you’d like to learn more about working with Damon Gettier and Associates, contact me at 540-314-1199 or &lt;a href=”mailto:Damon@DamonGettier.com”Damon@DamonGettier.com&lt;/a&gt;.

Avoid Becoming Overwhelmed this Selling Season

As real estate agents, we tend to be reactive instead of being proactive. It isn’t until we are buried in leads that we decide to purchase a lead management system. As the market begins to heat up, I encourage you to get your software platforms in place and find out what contact management system you will plan to use.

This allows you to track your leads – the last thing you want is business, which you pay for, coming in with no way to manage it! Hiring help during this influx of business is also a great move. Your first hire should be an administrative assistant – this person will help you bring in the leads, qualify them and find the good from the bad. However if you are unable to pay for additional employees, stop paying for leads. You don’t want to gain the reputation of someone who can’t handle the public’s inquiries.

If you have any questions about team dynamics or lead management, feel free to call or email me. Thanks and have a great day!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Coaching/Roanoke+VA+Real+Estate+-+Are+you+properly+and+effectively+managing+your+leads.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://swvirginiarealestatecareers.com/" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Damon+Gettier/Coaching/Roanoke+VA+Real+Estate+-+Are+you+properly+and+effectively+managing+your+leads.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Looking to improve your real estate career? I’m here to help you make a smart decision when it comes to growing your business, improving your bottom line, and choosing a place to work in real estate sales. If you’d like to learn more about working with Damon Gettier and Associates, contact me at 540-314-1199 or &lt;a href=”mailto:Damon@DamonGettier.com”Damon@DamonGettier.com&lt;/a&gt;.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Damon Gettier</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Looking to improve your real estate career? I’m here to help you make a smart decision when it comes to growing your business, improving your bottom line, and choosing a place to work in real estate sales. If you’d like to learn more about working with Damon Gettier and Associates, contact me at 540-314-1199 or &lt;a href=”mailto:Damon@DamonGettier.com”Damon@DamonGettier.com&lt;/a&gt;.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Roanoke Real Estate, Real Estate Careers, Real Estate Professionals, Realtors, Real estate industry, how much do realtors make</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Focus on What is Most Important by Implementing Systems!</title>
        <link>http://swvirginiarealestatecareers.com//central-virginia-real-estate-systems.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Coaching</category>
        
        <author>Damon Gettier</author>
        <pubDate>2014-04-11 16:16:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Looking to improve your real estate career? I’m here to help you make a smart decision when it comes to growing your business, improving your bottom line, and choosing a place to work in real estate sales. If you’d like to learn more about working with Damon Gettier and Associates, contact me at 540-314-1199 or &lt;a href=”mailto:Damon@DamonGettier.com”Damon@DamonGettier.com&lt;/a&gt;.

To ensure our agents are successful, we have systemized everything – individual agents cannot to do everything, let alone be successful and earn and income.

We have three different internet-based systems that we spend over $5,000 a month for the sole purpose of bringing in internet leads.  We also have an administrative staff that supports our agents. For instance, after we write a contract, the staff takes the contract to closing. There are also three groups of inside sales agents who call our listing prospects, buyer prospects and turn those prospects into viable leads. This allows our agents to focus on writing contracts and showing homes.

If you have any questions about the systems or techniques that we use, feel free to call or email me. Thanks and have a great day!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://swvirginiarealestatecareers.com/" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Looking to improve your real estate career? I’m here to help you make a smart decision when it comes to growing your business, improving your bottom line, and choosing a place to work in real estate sales. If you’d like to learn more about working with Damon Gettier and Associates, contact me at 540-314-1199 or &lt;a href=”mailto:Damon@DamonGettier.com”Damon@DamonGettier.com&lt;/a&gt;.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Damon Gettier</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Looking to improve your real estate career? I’m here to help you make a smart decision when it comes to growing your business, improving your bottom line, and choosing a place to work in real estate sales. If you’d like to learn more about working with Damon Gettier and Associates, contact me at 540-314-1199 or &lt;a href=”mailto:Damon@DamonGettier.com”Damon@DamonGettier.com&lt;/a&gt;.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Roanoke Real Estate, Real Estate Careers, Real Estate Professionals, Realtors, Real estate industry, how much do realtors make</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Damon Gettier</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Damon Gettier</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">A podcast about real estate careers and training in the Roanoke, Virginia area, brought to you by Damon Gettier of Damon Gettier & Associates.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
