<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title> Real Estate Podcast with </title>
    <link>localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Vyral Marketing - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor></managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2018-01-23 17:02:02 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright></media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>allison@getvyral.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name></itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author></itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the  Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Vyral Marketing - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week of 12/04/17</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/week-of-120417.html</link>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2018-01-23 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Holly Mabery - Don’t lose your deal

Bob &amp; Diane Peterson - A Question From a Past Client

Seth &amp; Alyce Dailey - Do You Know About These 4 Additional Costs for Buying a Home?

Nancy Seraphin - How Can You Add Leverage to Your Business?

Brian Lessinger - 2 Services We Provide: Property Management and Referrals

Todd Martin - 	Challenging Clients

Brian Hammond - Holiday fun in Nashville

Jennifer Smith - Britt Schulle

Mario Gigant - A Specific Tax Planning Strategy for You to Consider

Jason Daniels - Watch: Start planning for next year now

Becky Ivins - Join us Dec. 2nd for pictures with Santa

Brian Riolo - Great Feedback From Our Clients

Anastasia Riley - The easiest way to change your life

John Head - Your Outer Banks market update

Tyler Goff - A toast to a great Thanksgiving pie giveaway

Jinger Cutting - How does Zillow work?

Rhonda Sher - Making connections on the go

Haro Setian - “Extraordinary Business Leaders Series: You Don’t Want to Miss this Class

Kati Spaniak - 	What do millennial homebuyers really want?

David Rosen - Should You Consider Buying in a Co-op?

Will Cook - 4 tricks for winning bidding wars

Heather Neidlinger - Work with you

Casey Cooke - Help us bring joy to children in need

Adam Butler - Santa Claus Is Coming to K.C.

Brandon Blackwell - Should you list your home this winter?

Doug Cary - reconnect email

Jon DeHart - What You Need to Know About Closing Costs

Nathan Abbott - Experience Florida at Deer Lake State Park

Jay Heidel - Can you list during the holidays?

David Hamiki - Tell us about your experience

Ed Pluchar - Why Are Home Inspections So Important?

Kevin Smith - Join us for our appreciation event

Brian Canady - Is It Wise to Replace Your Carpet Before Listing Your Home?

Cristina Dougherty - Who Pays Real Estate Commissions in Virginia?

Chad Huebener - Buying in an off-peak market

Dave Knight - Is the Holiday Season a Good Time to Sell Your L.A. Home?

Jason Wilson - 5 Tips For a Successful Sale During the Holidays

Leslie Carver - A Few Helpful Tips if You’re Planning on a Home Purchase Soon

Travis Chatwin - How much should you disclose?

Ashley Carter - Gaining a New Perspective on the Home Buying Process

Jason Baker - It’s a Great Time to Sell in Western Montana

Ryan Butler - Home buyer mistakes

Andy Stavros - Watch: Visit Laguna Canyon Winery

Brandon Montemayor - Advice for Dealing With Lowball Offers

Geradl Durham - 	Don’t Let a Faulty Will Ruin Your Transfer of Property

John Schuster - This holiday, we wish you the best

Lisa Sisko - 3 Tips to Keep Your Home Safe for the Holidays

Sean Zanganeh - 5 Reasons Why the Holiday Season Is a Great Time to Sell Your Home

Jeremy Sisemore - The Top 10 In Demand SAP Skills

Rick Carson &amp; Chuck Korger - The Key to Investment Discipline

Zach Wessolleck - Get a Head Start on Buying a Home in 2018

Melinda Elmer - A few tips to avoid being scammed

Melissa Thompson - The Numbers Are In: Memphis Market Update

Jody Donaldson - How Did the Northern Virginia Real Estate Market Do This October?

Mikki Ramey - Your latest Charleston market update

Robert Mack - 	December 2017 Newsletter

Jeremy Larkin - 8th annual Basket Brigade News Video

Rodney &amp; Jenn Wallner - 6 Ways You Could Be Scaring Off Sellers

Shawn Culhane - Get a Sneak Preview of Our New “Coming Soon” Listing

Bryan &amp; Scott Colemere - Bring Your Kids to See Santa With Us This Year

Marjorie Dick Stuart - Negotiating

Angel Garcia - The Golden Rules of Investing in Flip Properties

Sandie Hea - How Does Earnest Money Function Within a Home Sale?

Kevin Clancy - How and why you should thank past clients

Susan Heller - What’s Happening in Our Southwest Florida Real Estate Market?

Ryan Smith - Thinking About Staging Your Home? Make These 4 Repairs First

Dan Fulkerson - DO YOU NEED AN ATTORNEY IF YOU’RE INJURED IN AN ACCIDENT?

Denise Zirke - 	Homebuyers Are Feeling Optimistic

Kevin Hudoba - 5 Reasons You Need to Hire a Professional Agent to Handle Your Transaction

John Fagan - The Little Gym

Shawn Luong - What’s the Key to Identifying a Great Investment Property?

Nate Martinez - Should You Sell Now or Wait Until After the Holidays?

Nate Martinez - Recruiting - 14 Activities Every Real Estate Agent Should Master: Part Two

Ian Lobas - “The Numbers Don’t Lie—a Shift May Be Happening Soon in Our Market

Gene Agustin - Can you use gifted funds toward a new home?

Karen &amp; Joe Donovan (Long Island) - What Is an Inspection Contingency?

John Schuster - How Can You Increase the Value of Your Home?

Darin Triolo - ROI renovation

Mark Gellman - Your November St. Louis Market Update

Martin Millner - The Latest Bucks County Real Estate Information

Deja Lett - Safety precautions to consider before listing

Mark Benefiel - 4 Tips to Properly Stage Your Home for the Market

Janice Overbeck - Don’t miss these upcoming events

Denise Swick - 3 THINGS THAT CAN DRAMATICALLY AFFECT YOUR HOME SALE

Greg McDaniel - 	What Do You Love Most About the Bay?

Andy Sachs - What Are My Market Predictions for 2018?

Tara Limbird - 	Coffee and home value

Ty Leon Guerrero - The Weather Is Cooler but the Market Is Still on Fire

Marc Smith - May the merry bells keep ringing

Shawn Kriewaldt - 7 Tips to Prepare Your Home for Sale in the Winter

Maggie Harris - Fall 2017 McAllen market update

Lindsey Gudger - #EveryOneGetsAHome

Mario Romero - Can refinancing a mortgage hurt your credit?

Dale Downing - How Much of a Down Payment Do You Need to Buy a House?

Rick Sadle - What Do the Proposed Tax Changes Mean for Our Market?

Mary Peacock - 	Prepare for the New Year and Buy Your Dream Home in 2018

Dan Rochon - Brooke Rivera

Nick Good - Get ready for your 2018 home search

Durwin Cheung - A Year Over Year Breakdown of Our 3rd Quarter Market

Michael Kaim - How to handle early offers?

Ernie Dill - How a Good Agent Can Close a Tricky Transaction

Joy Daniels - Introducing our new HouseekR app

Victoria Sandoval	5 Things to Know Before Buying a Short Sale

Jana and Jason DeLong - Watch: The 7 best things about a fall home purchase

Monique Walker - Having Mortgage Trouble? Don’t Worry - Help Is Available

(ASI) Aesthetic Surgical Images - Dec 1

Dan Hamilton - 	5 reasons to list home this winter

Tracy Venturi - Homebuyer Tip No. 2—Never Pick a Lender Based Solely on Their Rate

Kevin Langan - Why Are Homebuyers Feeling Optimistic?

Clifton Sanders - All text

Ferzoco Group - Prepare Your Home for Winter Weather With These Tips

Anthony Boatner - 6 Tips for Winter Home Sellers

Jeremy Qualley - Ready for winter

Sohail Salahuddin - The Secret to Relisting Your Home

Bret Johnson - 5 Tips for Homebuyers in 2018

Jodie Osofsky - Tinker’s Cafe

Kodi Riddle - Can refinancing a mortgage hurt your credit?

Jason Mitchell - Why are homebuyers suddenly so optimistic?

Todd Martin - Buying in a Seller’s Market

Jeff Cook - Entice homebuyers

Lee Tessier - Is it too late to list?

Alex Tooke - 7 steps to purchasing a home in 2018

Deepak Gupta - Best wishes in the new year

Dar Walden - Selling in the winter

Deepak Gupta - Buying Your First Home? These Programs Can Help

John Teixeira - Mortgage Minute 3: Loan Products for Veterans

Jeffrey Cohn - The Pros and Cons of Buying a Home in Winter

Joe Mendoza - Is Seller Financing Right for You?

Joshua Stern - 	Buyer Obstacles

Deuce Kirk - The Challenges That Plague FSBO Sellers

Ron Cedillo - How Can a Listing Agent Help Sell Your Home?

Kathy Toth - How Do You Know How Much Equity Is in Your Home?

Caleb Pearson - Optimistic buyers

Willie Miranda - Should you list now or wait until spring?

Barker Hedges Group - When Is the Best Time to Buy?

David Robinson - Don’t wait until spring to list your home

Hunter Reynolds - Save on energy bills this winter

Brent Downing - Should you list on your own?

Hunter Reynolds - Should You Consider Refinancing?

Valerie Hunter-Kelly - Buyer Tips

Damon Gettier - Unexpected Home Purchasing Costs, Part III: Taxes

Joe DeSane - Are holiday listings a good idea?

Mike Roth - Full-Service Brokerages vs. Discount Brokers—Which Is Better?

Andrew Ford - Can You Buy a Home Without a Realtor?
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Holly Mabery, Bob & Diane Peterson, Seth & Alyce Dailey, Nancy Seraphin and Brian Lessinger</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Holly Mabery, Bob & Diane Peterson, Seth & Alyce Dailey, Nancy Seraphin and Brian Lessinger</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Week of 11/20/17</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/week-of-112017.html</link>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2017-12-06 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Patricia Kiteke - The Truth About Fast-Cash Buyers
Sent to: 1984 | Opens: 24.5 | Clicks: 2

Tracy Wilson - Meet Michelle
Sent to: 222 | Opens: 23.87 | Clicks: 15.77

Clint Stitser - How Land is Stolen
Sent to: 545 | Opens: 22.94 | Clicks: 5.32

Seth &amp; Alyce Dailey - How Can You Protect Your Credit After the Equifax Hack?
Sent to: 4657 | Opens: 22.5 | Clicks: 0.79

Amy Smits / Kevin Smits - Smits Team 3rd Annual Pie Giveaway!
Sent to: 387 | Opens: 22.22 | Clicks: 8.27



Brian Lessinger - Wishing You a Happy Thanksgiving

Bob &amp; Diane Peterson - Should You Sell Your House Over the Holidays?

Dan Ihara - We’re thankful for you

Sharon Stevens - A Quick Stucco Tutorial

Charlotte Mabry - We’ve Got an Opportunity for Agents Looking to Grow

Ed Pluchar - If You’re Under Contract, Is It Too Late to Back Out?

Leslie Carver - Happy Thanksgiving From Team Carver!

Clint Stitser - How Land is Stolen

Paul Brouillette - What Preliminary Steps Should You Take Before Buying a New Home?

Scott Hardesty - A quick real estate update

Jason Wilson - Taking Time to Reflect This Thanksgiving

Brian Riolo - Happy Thanksgiving From Our Entire Team

Zach Wessolleck - A Great Thanksgiving Recipe to Try

O’Neill Team - BUILDING HOMES FOR THOSE IN NEED WITH SEA ISLAND HABITAT FOR HUMANITY

Anastasia Riley - Home Updates That Bring The Most Value

Clint Stitser - How Land is Stolen

Bo Winn - Looking for a home in 2018?

Chad Hauer - 4 Unexpected Costs First-Time Homebuyers Should Watch out for

Ashley Carter - Plain Text

David Rosen - I Went to War for One of My Clients, and We Won—Here’s How

Jerimiah Taylor - Red light, Green light, and your budget

Sean Hellmann - To Our Friends, Family, and Clients: Thank You

Sandie Hea - Do You Know the Answers to These Common Appraisal Questions?

Chris Heller - 5 ways to add value to your home

Jacob Laffoon - A few Thanksgiving tips

Bryan &amp; Scott Colemere - Listing MistakesYou Should Always Avoid

Gene Agustin - Mortgage do’s and don’ts

Shawn Luong - Plain Text

Max Folkers - What will happen to the housing market?

Jose Morales - Another agent success

Kevin Hudoba - Happy Thanksgiving From My Family to Yours

Dave Silva - What Do Rising Interest Rates Mean for You?

Christy Kimbrel - Should You Hire a Buyer’s Agent to Help You Buy a Home?

Ryan Smith - 6 Tips to Get Your Home Ready for the Holidays

Delane Rouse - Budget season is here

Dave Knight - What Is a 1031 Exchange?

GoVig 1 - How are dating and interviewing similar?

Jason Huerkamp - The 4 Most Important Factors in Buying or Selling a Home

Monica Benevides - Plain Text

Jason Penrose - October 2017 market update

Angel Garcia - Making Your Offer More Attractive

Tiffany Holtz - Should You Put Your Home on the Market This Winter?

Kodi Riddle - Why are homebuyers suddenly so optimistic?

Jan Leasure - How Gratitude Helps Your Business

Alan Kushmakov - What Does The Market Have in Store for Those Who List Now

Earron Shields - What Should Buyers Expect to Pay at the Closing Table?

Charlotte Mabry - Do You Have a Problem With Your Foundation?

John West - Get the best deal for your home now - don’t wait until spring to list

Ferzoco Group - How to Celebrate the Holidays Here on the Jersey Shore

Tim Majka - Imagine Realty Wishes You Happy Thanksgiving

Victoria Sandoval - 3 Key Benefits to Homeownership

Maggie Harris - Plain Text

Jesse Myles - 3 Tips to Increase Your Home Value

Kevin Langan - It’s Time to Reflect on Our Blessings

Joe Mendoza - Thank You All for Your Support

Brent Dildine - Wishing You All a Happy Thanksgiving

Jason Daniels - You Could Afford a Home for Less Down Than You Think

Lisa Blake - What’s the Latest News From Our Denver Market?

Deepak Gupta - Happy Holidays From the Dee Team

Blake Sloan - Your November real estate market update

Dar Walden - Winter is officially here

Jon Carbutti - Plain Text

Tracy Venturi - Don’t Buy a Home Without a Realtor

Mike Quail - 5 ways to add value to your home

Chris Watters - Optimistic Homebuyers Plain Text

Shane Neal - The holidays are a great time to list

Mindy Robbins - How will the Fed’s new move impact real estate?

Shane Roxburgh - This listing method could cost you big time

Kevin Clancy - Could a common, deadly gas be in your home?

Lee Tessier - What Do You Need to Know About Short Sales?

Peter MacIntyre - Toys for Tots

Clayton Gits - Plain Text

Ron Cedillo - Why an Agent Is a Homebuyer’s Best Friend
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Patricia Kiteke, Tracy Wilson, Clint Stitser, Seth & Alyce Dailey, and Kevin & Amy Smitz</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Patricia Kiteke, Tracy Wilson, Clint Stitser, Seth & Alyce Dailey, and Kevin & Amy Smitz</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Week of 11/13/17</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/week-of-111317.html</link>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2017-11-27 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>John Carr and Rosalin Smith Carr - What’s the Latest From Our Toronto Market?
Sent to: 361 | Opens: 34.9 | Clicks: 7.48

Ryan Anderson - Thanksgiving Pie Party
Sent to: 175 | Opens: 28.57 | Clicks: 6.29

Scott Hollinger - Advice for the off-season
Sent to: 1865 | Opens: 27.18 | Clicks: 5.2

Kodi Riddle - Reserve your pumpkin or apple pie
Sent to: 353 | Opens: 24.93 | Clicks: 5.67

Rob Kittle - Let Us Add Something Sweet to Your Table This Thanksgiving
Sent to: 803 | Opens: 21.92 | Clicks: 3.36



Amy Smits / Kevin Smits - Our holiday season pie giveaway is here

Will Cook - 	What’s Going on in Our Market Today?

Joe Sabato - The disappearing deal: foreclosure sales are gone

Sandy King - Are You Interested in Being a Service Technician at Symbiont Service?

Jinger Cutting - Prescott real estate market update

Bob Sokoler - Plain Text

Kari Kohler - 2 Market Secrets to Be Thankful for This Holiday Season

Jennie Wolek - How do you treat your buyer listings?

Tyler Goff - Which home improvements are worth it?

Lisa Sisko - A Day in the Life of Our Administrative Staff

Duke Kimhan - Why Is Loss of Rent Coverage Important for Homeowners?

Becky Ivins - Let us provide the pie this Thanksgiving

Angie Travis Roberts - Beware - I got hacked

Zach Sikes - What We’re Thankful for This Thanksgiving

Jeff Green - Interview With Economist Brian Wesbury: Part 1

John Head - Home inspections vs. appraisals

Ashley Carter - How Short-Term Rentals Can Boost Your Real Estate Investment Strategy

Nathan Abbott - Sitting Down With Mike Ragsdale of 30A.com

Ryan Butler - Trump Tax (All-text)

Dave Nimick - Short-term rental properties

Bill White - How to Prepare Your Home to List This Fall

Kyle Fernandez - Which home repairs actually matter?

Brett Sikora - What Steps Do You Need to Take to Buy a Home in 2018?

Ryan Hummel - Nutrition Talk and Holiday Hours

Rick Carson &amp; Chuck Korger - How Are You Planning for Retirement?

John Schuster - Is Zillow an Accurate Way to Get a Home Value?

Rodney &amp; Jenn Wallner - Holiday Events

Alfie McFadden - Orange County market report

Kevin McCarthy - The Latest Developments From the Sea Casa

Gary Raze - 6 Tips for Homebuyers in 2018

John Mikesh - Watch: How much home can you afford?

Craig Barton - Homebuyers Are Feeling Optimistic

Gerald Durham - Summer Isn’t the Only Good Time to List

Robert Mack - 	November Newsletter

Bob Guest - Our Special Offer Can Set You Up for a Huge Home Sale in 2018

Troy Copeland - Watch: A word about insurance

Lindsey Gudger - The Cost of Waiting

Debbie Spaulder - 	Can You Trust “We Pay Cash for Houses” Signs?

Joe DeSane - Is it possible to juggle 2 transactions?

Dave Hooke - The 3 Steps to Buying and Selling at the Same Time

Darin Triolo - Watch: Is a homeowners association a good fit?

Sandy Blanton - 5 Inexpensive Things You Can Do to Maximize Your Home’s Value

Jeremy Larkin - Help us feed all 265 families!

REOP - Tips for Purchasing a Home During the Holidays

Susanne Casey - Plain Text

Mark Brace - 4 reasons to find a home this fall

Tom Daves - Come Join Us for Music, Fun, and Free Pie

Brad Atkins - Help Others in Burbank Celebrate Thanksgiving

Daniel Dixon - 5 improvement mistakes

Jesse Herfel &amp; Loretta - Three Reasons To Sell Your Home During The Holidays

Dan Jones - Watch: Charlotte’s 4th quarter market update

Ernie Dill - Think You’ve Missed Your Best Chance to Sell Your Home This Year?

Sarita Dua - Are You Asking Agents the Right Questions?

Clifton Sanders - 2 Programs to Help in the Wake of Hurricane Harvey

Scott Lander - What I’m Thankful for This Thanksgiving

Nick Good - School districts and your home price

Kris Miller - How healthy are your spending habits?

Greater Toronto Group (Dijana) - 3 Mistakes to Avoid When Selling Your Home

Aaron Wittenstein - What Low Inventory Means for Our Current Market

Dan Ellison - What Happens During the Inspection Contingency?

Wes Peters - How Does the Cool Kids Campaign Help Children With Cancer?

Dan Hamilton - 	Hot Carolina Neighborhoods

Anthony Boatner - 5 Surprising Benefits of Selling in the Winter

Mary Peacock - 	4 Energy-Efficient Tips for the Winter

Scott English - Happy Holidays From the English Real Estate Group

Shawn Culhane - Why It Makes Sense to List During the Fall

Lenny LaRocca//Tony Cangas - Explaining the Difference Between FHA and Conventional Loans

Christine Browning - How A Home Warranty Will Benefit You

Greater Calgary Group - 4 Tips for Buying in a Seller’s Market

Spalding Pyron - Should You Order a Pre-Listing Inspection?

Andrew Ford - Handling 2 Real Estate Transactions at the Same Time

Sohail Salahuddin - I’d Love to Have Your Help in Growing My Business

Larry Martin - Why Are Homebuyers Feeling Optimistic?

JP Pirtle - Watch: Don’t let hidden contingencies slip by

Marti Hampton - 	How hard is it to get into a home?

Rita Driver - Have a Real Estate Problem? We Can Help

Kathy Toth - Are You Interested in a Career in Real Estate?

Hunter Reynolds - Homebuyers Are Feeling Optimistic
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by John Carr and Rosalin Smith Carr, Ryan Anderson, Scott Hollinger, Kodi Riddle and Rob Kittle</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by John Carr and Rosalin Smith Carr, Ryan Anderson, Scott Hollinger, Kodi Riddle and Rob Kittle</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Week of 11/06/17</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/week-of-11617.html</link>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2017-11-24 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Haro Setian - You're Invited to Our Annual Cheesecake Giveaway
Sent to: 925 | Opens: 32.76 | Clicks: 7.46

Seth &amp; Alyce Dailey - Why It Isn't Too Late to Buy or Sell
Sent to: 4758 | Opens: 29.53 | Clicks: 1.72

Cristina Dougherty - It’s Almost Time for Our Pie Giveaway
Sent to: 187 | Opens: 28.9 | Clicks: 20.32

Holly Mabery - Buy in the fall
Sent to: 104 | Opens: 23.08 | Clicks: 5.77

Brian Lessinger - New vs. Existing Homes
Sent to: 616 | Opens: 22.08 | Clicks: 3.25



Jason Daniels - We Want to Thank You for Giving Us Five-Star Reviews

John Simmonds - Don’t Miss Our 3rd Annual Great American Pie Giveaway

Patricia Kiteke - How Will New Mortgage Rules Impact You?

O’Neill Team - LIST WITH MATT O’NEILL FOR OPTIMAL RESULTS

Gillies Team - 	 A word about the Fed’s recent announcement

Brian Hammond - When Is Reselling a Good Idea?

Marcus Green - A True Story of How Keller Williams Can Transform Brokerages

Alex Mont-Ros - How Does the Development Sector of Real Estate Work?

Tracy Wilson - Is your home wasting energy?

Diva Team - Is Your 2018 Business Plan Ready?

Jessica Sanders - Where Do We Get Our List to Call?

Richard Witt - How Much Does It Cost to Close With Me?

Tom White - San Antonio snapshot

Brian Riolo - What Qualities Do All Great Listing Agents Share?

Anastasia Riley - Listing your home in the fall or winter?

Stephanie Crawford - Knowing the Basics of Title Insurance

Aaron Hendon - The Amazing Story of the Burton Inn

Justin Woodall - What happened to foreclosure deals?

Scott Himelstein - Interest rates

Gary Raze - The Pros and Cons of Buying a New Home

Michael Vernamonti - Home Flipping Tips You Won’t Want to Miss

Mike Roth - Common Basement Concerns for Homebuyers &amp; Homeowners

Angela Fox - Staging your home this fall &amp; winter

Dave Silva - Be Sure to Ask an Agent These Questions

Jon DeHart - Why Fall 2017 Is a Great Time to Buy a Home

Shawn Anderson - The Best Restaurants in Idaho Falls

Andrew Kronenberg - New housing development in Carlisle

David Rosen - Questions You Should Ask Potential Brokers

Rob Spring - What Income Is Considered When Qualifying for a Mortgage?

Kevin Hudoba - How Will the Fed’s Recent Decision Affect You?

Patrick Fitzgerald - What You Need to Know About Property Surveys

Travis Chatwin - 6 ways to build your wealth

Sherry &amp; Angela - 	Don’t Forget to Reserve Your Pie From Us

Jody Donaldson - The 8 Most Common Homebuyer Questions

Jerry Land - What Is Our Approach to Recruiting?

Janice Overbeck - Cobb County market update

Bo Winn - Top 10 reasons to list during the fall

Enrique Medellin - 	5 Questions to Ask Before Moving Into a Homeowners Association

Josh Lioce - What 5 Expenses Do First-Time Homebuyers Often Forget?

Jeremy Larkin - Nominate Families to Receive Thanksgiving NOW!

Melissa Thompson - You’re Invited to Our Annual Pie Giveaway

Dave Knight - What Do Current LA Market Conditions Mean for You?

Gregory Taylo - 	Moving tips Victoria Sandoval	4 Reasons Pre-Approvals Are Essential

Blaine Moore - Things to Know as a Move-Up Buyer

Bryan &amp; Scott Colemere	8 Things You Must Not Overlook When Buying a Home

Don Williams - Busting the Myth That Fall Isn’t a Good Time to Sell

Angel Garcia - The Garcia Team Is Hiring Exceptional Agents

Mike Gray - 	How is our post-Harvey market?

Adam Cohn - Plain text

Nate Martinez - Is Moving Up Right for You?

Rob Ellis - Focus Fridays

Ferzoco Group - A Jersey Shore Market Update

Jan Leasure - How Will the Fed’s New Announcement Impact Your Real Estate Plans?

Patrick O’Sullivan - Sell in the fall

Brian Beatty - What Makes Fall a Great Time to Buy?

Kwasi Bowie - Not all renovations are worth it

Tim Majka - What Does the Fed’s Latest Announcement Mean for You?

Jason Huerkamp - How HOA Homes Can Be Beneficial

Erik Winegarden - Should you list now or wait?

Tiffany Holtz - Is Your Home the Right Size for You?

Christal Johnson - Three Ways to Get Your Offer Accepted in Today’s Competitive Market

Damon Gettier - How to Actively Seek New Business in Real Estate

Jason Penrose - Is the market going to crash?

Jodie Osofsky - What You Should Know About Your Property Taxes

Jesse Myles - 2 Ways You Can Successfully Buy and Sell a Home Simultaneously

Deepak Gupta - Is It a Better Idea to Buy Now or Later?

Jeremy Sisemore - Don’t Make These Mistakes If You’re Hiring During the Holiday Season

Jacob Laffoon - Should you list over the holidays?

Chris Watters - We’re Saying Thanks…With Pie

Craig &amp; Stacey Akers - 5 Ways to Invest in Real Estate

Jason McIntosh - Selling in the off-season

Josh Cooley - Is it too late to list?

Adrienne Lally - Real Estate Agent Gets Surprise Pie In The Face

Matt &amp; Jenn Freda - Meet the Members of teamFREDA

Ana Sarabia - What Makes Fall Such a Great Time to List?

Brent Dildine - The Truth About Zillow’s Estimates

Josh Heneveld - How to Handle Multiple Offer Situations as a Seller

Amy Smits / Kevin Smits - Airbnb Properties vs. Long-Term Rental Properties

Lance Woodley - Plain Text

Patrick Collins - Did You Know That Overpricing Can Reduce Your Home’s Value?

Denise Swick - Shouldn’t wait to list home

Tom Nickley - How Has Our Orlando Market Recovered Since Hurricane Irma?

Deja Lett - How Will the Fed’s Recent Decision Influence the Market?

Goran &amp; Lisa Forss - When to hire a realtor

Brent Drowning - Open House

Joy Daniels - Line your pockets with investment properties

Jack Lehr - How Seller’s Help Affects Buyers and Sellers

Dar Walden - Why fall is a great time to purchase a home

Dave Friedman - The latest in Charleston real estate

Kevin Clancy - How serious is mold?

Julie Baldino - Enter Our Pumpkin Pie Giveaway

Bret Johnson - 	Staging: Get the Most Bang for Your Buck

Jeff Latham - A dream come true: How I learned to fly

Joe Mendoza - How to Have a Major Breakthrough in Real Estate Investing

Deuce Kirk - The Unexpected Costs of Purchasing a Lexington Home

Brian Gubernick - How Do School Districts Impact Your Home’s Value?

Bob Sokoler - A Market Update and a Walk for a Great Cause

Chase Craig - How Can You Win in a Multiple Offer Situation?

Andrew Duncan - Is Your Agent as Good as They Say?
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Hero Setian, Seth & Alyce Dailey, Cristina Dougherty, Holly Mabery and Brian Lessinger</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Hero Setian, Seth & Alyce Dailey, Cristina Dougherty, Holly Mabery and Brian Lessinger</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Week of 10/30/17</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/week-of-103017.html</link>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2017-11-07 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Karlyn Ellis - Have you been to Thatcher?
Sent to: 872 | Opens: 21.9 | Clicks: 3.9

Damon Gettier - Special Announcement for Local Agents
Sent to: 1237 | Opens: 16.25 | Clicks: 8.73

Sandy King - Let Us Help You Inspect Your Damaged Pool Heating Equipment
Sent to: 8032 | Opens: 16 | Clicks: 1

Janet Gresh - What the Fed’s new move means for you
Sent to: 1490 | Opens: 15.77 | Clicks: 1.41

Bob &amp; Diane Peterson - Learn how to make an offer that stands out
Sent to: 2402 | Opens: 15.61 | Clicks: 1.67



Eric Mortimer - 5 Ways to Avoid Buyer’s Remorse

Mario Gigant - Learn how to transition your portfolio for retirement

Wade Betz - 4 Reasons Why Your Lender Matters

Barbara Radke - Why are there so few homes for sale?

Valerie Van de Zilver - Vacation homes and short-term rentals

Chris Hauck - A guide to getting full-price offers

Scott Himelstein - Don’t Miss out

Joe DiRaffaele - Take Time to Enjoy All That Las Vegas Offers

Marcus Green - Teaching the Importance of Managing Money

Duke Kimhan - Did the Recent Equifax Breach Impact Your Credit?

Ed Pluchar - What Are the True Benefits of Buying and Selling in the Fall?

Jason Baker - Can You Take Advantage of Our Current Market?

Kristin Jamieson - How Much Money Down Is Too Much?

Chad Hauer - The Latest News and Numbers for Pierce County

Scott Hardesty - Were you affected by the Equifax hack?

Jerry Land - Are Human Recruiters Being Replaced?

Melinda Elmer - 5 projects that maximize home value

David Rosen - How I Helped Jim Sell His Home for a Record Price

Paul Brouillette - A Few Things Massachusetts Home Sellers Should Know

Nate Martinez  -  Recruiting	We Want to Teach You How to Build Your Wealth

Black Clover Fitness - Low Calorie Drink Options

Sharon Stevens - Where Is the Best Ice Cream in St. Augustine?

Martin Millner - What’s Going on in the Real Estate World of Bucks County?

Sandie Hea - A 3rd Quarter Update for the St. Louis Metro Market

Dave Hooke Recruiting - The 7 Habits of Highly Effective Real Estate Agents

Cristina Dougherty - 3 Home Improvements to Consider When Selling Your Home

Nathan Abbott - What Can the Tortoise Clinic Do for You?

Jay Heidel - Our market is constantly changing

Jason Wilson - 3 Strategies for the Move-Up Buyer

Nate Martinez - Is It Time for You to Downsize?

Adam Butler - Why I Love Arbor Masters

Don Williams - Is Your Home Ready for Trick-or-Treaters?

Sandy Eagon - How You Can Be a Hero Around the Holiday Dinner Table

John West - Which homes have increased in value the most?

Brandon Montemayor - Are Your Affairs in Order?

Doug Leugers - Need Dinner Reservations? Try La Corte Bistro in Cape Coral

Joe DeSane - Big changes are coming to the economy

Lance Woodley - How Your Property Taxes Can Cost You Extra

Dale Downing - Can Buyers or Sellers Cancel the Purchase Agreement Once in Escrow?

Lorie Gould - Plain Text

Monique Walker - Are Cash Offers Always the Best Option?

Leigh Marcus - How we help homebuyers find their dream home

Marcus Vanzant - How Will the Fed’s Recent Decision Influence the Market?

Kevin Hudoba  - Is This Autumn the Time to Sell Your Carmel Home?

Chase Craig - How Can You Win in a Multiple Offer Situation?

Chris Gorman - The hidden benefits of listing in fall

Jesse Herfel &amp; Loretta - What’s the key to a successful listing?

Sandy Blanton - 3 strategies for juggling transactions

Dave Hooke - Should I Buy or Rent?

Greg McDaniel  - Why I chose Real Estate

Blake Sloan - Your October real estate market update

Robert Mack  - What Should Buyers and Sellers Do as We Approach the Holiday Market?

Sean Zanganeh - Don’t Overlook TheseCritical Property Features

Aaron Wittenstein - You’re Invited to Our Next Networking Event

Caleb Pearson - Carleston Events

Brayden Bengtzen - If You’re Thinking of Buying, Now Is the Time

Jana and Jason DeLong - Halloween Safety Tips

Rick Sadle - How Will the Fed Reducing their Balance Sheet Affect Buyers and Sellers?

Sarita Dua - The Inspection Process Is All About Give and Take

Andrew Kent - A Look at Our Market and a Great Local Vendor

Anthony Boatner - 5 Tips to Entice Buyers &amp; Sell Your Home in Record Time

Haro Setian - Prepare for Our Annual Cheesecake Party

Shawn Kriewaldt - 5 Tips for a Safe and Happy Halloween

Ryan Smith - 6 Things to Never Do During the Home Buying Process

Dan Jones - List in the fall

Clifton Sanders - How to Maintain Your Home’s Value

Alan Kushmakov - Plain Text

Pazi D - Can You Qualify for 100% Financing?

Scott English - 4 Reasons to Never List Without an Agent

Mary Peacock  - Watch to learn about unexpected costs

Spalding Pyron - How Important Is the Final Walkthrough of a Home Sale?

Lee Tessier - We Appreciate Your Support, and Now We Need Your Help

Greg Tran - Which improvements aren’t worth it?

Michael Perna - Winter is Coming . . . . don’t get left in the cold!

Clayton Gits - Top 5 Reasons for the Dip in Inventory

Andy Richardson - How to Avoid Getting Spooked on Your Next Home Purchase

Jeff Smith - What’s Been Happening in Our Denver Market Lately?

Thom Dallman Core Group Realty - 6 ways to prepare your home for winter

Gillies Team  -  A word about the Fed’s recent announcement

Spencer Hasch - Answering All the Questions You’re Afraid to Ask During a Home Tour

Diva Team - A Fall Market Update

Ruby Miranda - Why Do Some Agents Ask for Exclusivity?

Julie Baldino - Don’t Let These Extra Costs Surprise You

Justin Udy - Looking for a home? It just got easier

Kevin Yoder - Sell with confidence

Ron Cedillo - 3 Tips for Selling Your House

Andrew Duncan - When Is the Best Time to Put Your Home on the Market?

Debbie Spaulder  -  2 great destinations for fall fun

Zach Wessolleck - 3 Keys to Selling Your Home if You Have Pets

Chad Schwendeman - 7 Reasons to Buy a Home During Fall
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Karlyn Ellis, Damon Gettier, Sandy King, Janet Gresh, and Bob & Diane Peterson</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Karlyn Ellis, Damon Gettier, Sandy King, Janet Gresh, and Bob & Diane Peterson</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Week of 10/23/17</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/week-of-102317.html</link>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-30 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Scott Hollinger - Is history repeating itself in our market?
Sent to: 1831 | Opens: 25.01 | Clicks: 5.95

Greg Flaherty - Is It a Good Time to Buy in San Diego? 
Sent to: 745 | Opens: 24.9 | Clicks: 3.8

Holly Mabery - Home inspections
Sent to: 105 | Opens: 23.81 | Clicks: 5.71

Nancy Seraphin - How The Wilstein Team Uses Leverage
Sent to: 1049 | Opens: 21.93 | Clicks: 3.43

Sandy King - A Message Regarding Hurricane Preparation
Sent to: 8353 | Opens: 17.5 | Clicks: 1.7



Richard Witt - Should You Expect a Secondary Inspection?

Brian Lessinger - Is Your Home Covered if Disaster Strikes?

Jared Chamberlain (Chamberlain Group) - Watch: How to pull off two transactions at once

Justin Woodall - What people forget about downsizing

Brian Riolo - What Should You Expect From Closing Costs?

Leslie Carver - Is Las Vegas Still in a Seller’s Market?

Kari Kohler - Why You Should Consider Buying a New Construction Home

Michael Vernamonti - Snowbird Season Is Upon Us

Angela Fox - A different kind of ghost

Kyle Fernandez - Fall 2017 St. Louis housing update

Jeff Cook - Save the Date for Pie Day!

Anastasia Riley - What will you pay in closing costs?

Gary Raze - All Your Real Estate Questions Answered

Sharon Stevens - Have You Heard of the ZIP System?

Rick Carson &amp; Chuck Korger - Do You Have Enough Saved for Retirement? 71% of Americans Don’t

Chris Heller - Market update for San Diego

Marjorie Dick Stuart - Backup contracts

Bob Guest - October Market Update for the Austin Area

Jody Donaldson - Winter Is Coming. Is Your Home Prepared?

David Rosen - How I Helped Jim Sell His Home for a Record Price

Josh Heneveld - Fall 2017 Salem housing update

Kevin McCarthy - 1031 Exchanges: The Basics

Brandon Brittingham - We’re making property management easy

Daniel Dixon - Meet agent Heather Sowa

Doug Herdahl - Why are there so few homes for sale?

Dave Silva - How to Sell Your Home the Right Way

Josh Pemberton (DiBello Group) - 5 home maintenance tasks to tackle this October

Jon DeHart - Watch to see if Zillow’s Zestimates are accurate

Jennie Wolek - Giving back feels great

Enrique Medellin - 	Buying a Home? Don’t Forget to Budget for These 4 Costs

Jason Daniels Training - What’s the Key to a Successful Open House?

Bryan David - 3 critical home search mistakes

Sean Hellmann - Why Sellers Should Be Excited About Our Current Market

Josh Lioce - 5 Tips for Energy Efficiency in Fall and Winter

Darin Triolo - Watch: How does our market look right now?

Andrew Kronenberg - Fall 2017 Central Pennsylvania housing update

REOP - How Do You Make an Offer in a Competitive Market?

Sherry &amp; Angela - 	Why is Now a Great Time to Sell?

Melissa Thompson - How Can You Protect Yourself Against the Equifax Breach?

Gerald Durham - Home Improvements to Make Before Selling

Sarah/Marty McKay - What Half of Americans Don’t Realize About Purchasing a Home

Susan Heller - Have Storms Affected Our Southwest Florida Market?

Ferzoco Group - What Do the Different Markets Around the Jersey Shore Look Like?

Adam Cohn - Getting a New Home Is Possible, Even With Limited Funds

Rex Jarnagin - Unsure About the Buying Process? We’re Here to Help

Zach Sikes - What Type of Home Is Right for You?

John Schuster - Why home inspections are so crucial

Aaron &amp; Kelly Allen - Recapping the 3rd Quarter of Our East Cobb Market

Mike Duggal - The Controversy of Stigmatized Properties

Shawna Brooks - When and How Do Sellers Pay for Closing Costs?

Bret Johnson - What’s the Latest Word From Our Phoenix Market?

Nick Good - Avoid these 3 home upgrades

Robert &amp; Shannon Rollings - 	October events in CRSA

Delane Rouse - LET US HELP YOU PHOTOGRAPH YOUR OFFICE SPACE

Charlotte Mabry - What Not to Do When Buying a Home

Jeremy Sisemore - What Are Some Common Mistakes Made in the Interview Process?

Ernie Dill - What Does It Actually Cost to Close?

Deepak Gupta - 5 Reasons Now Is the Time to Sell Your Home in Central Florida

Kodi Riddle - Do you know the signs of wire fraud?

Jeff Cook - Is Now a Good Time to Sell in Our Charleston Market?

Shawna Brooks - An Important Reminder in Light of Breast Cancer Awareness Month

Dar Walden - WATCH: Energy efficiencies in your home

Joe Mendoza - What Are the 7 Keys to Investing in Rental Property?

Jason Daniels - Overpricing Your Home Is a Critical Mistake

Josh Cooley - How to list your home for the most money

Matt Templeton - Watch: How to expose your home to millennials

Brent Dildine - Why Are Buyer’s Agents Useful?

SAUL ZENKEVICIUS - Watch: Thoughts about the flipping craze

Rita Driver - What’s the Latest News From Our Memphis Market?

Kevin Smith - Renovations Loans, Explained

Kevin Yoder - Watch: Do relatives and real estate mix?

Wes Peters - My Team Is Putting Our Money Where Our Mouth Is for Our Sellers

Brian Gubernick - 5 Top Tips for Fall and Winter Listings

Hunter Reynolds - Is Fall a Good Time to Put Your Home on the Market?

Kevin Clancy - Our approach to real estate

Jack Lehr - Home Renovation Mortgage

Diva Team - It’s Time for a Look at Our Blooper Reel

Andrew Ford - 3 FAQs About Property Taxes Answered

Kathy Toth - How Do Absorption Rates Impact You?

Matt Barker - Why Green Photos Can Make Or Break A Winter Listing

Damon Gettier - What’s the First Step to Take When Selling Your Home?
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Scott Hollinger, Greg Flaherty, Holly Mabery, Nancy Seraphin and Sandy King</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Scott Hollinger, Greg Flaherty, Holly Mabery, Nancy Seraphin and Sandy King</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Week of 10/16/17</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/week-of-101617.html</link>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-23 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Karlyn Ellis - Fall 2017 Buda/Kyle Texas housing update
Sent to: 879 | Opens: 24.12 | Clicks: 0.57

Seth &amp; Alyce Dailey - 5 Home Staging Tips That Will Have You Cashing in on Your Home Sale
Sent to: 4944 | Opens: 23.34 | Clicks: 3.09

Earron Shields - You're Invited to Our Fall Client Appreciation Event
Sent to: 53 | Opens: 20.75 | Clicks: 9.43

Gretchen Karr - Is Fall a Good Time to Put Your Home on the Market?
Sent to: 1051 | Opens: 18 | Clicks: 2.8

Leslie Carver - Don’t Sell Your Home in Nevada Without Making These Disclosures
Sent to: 854 | Opens: 17.56 | Clicks: 1.76



John Simmonds - How to Maintain Your Pool During the Hurricane

Eric Mortimer - You Latest Calgary Market Snapshot

Mindy Robbins - Fall 2017 Dallas/Ft Worth housing update

Paul Brouillette - Smoke and Carbon Monoxide Requirements When Selling a Home

Dave Nimick - Condo Owner Must Knows

Janet Gresh - Fall 2017 DC Metro area housing update

Alex Lam - 	How was our market this September?

Brian Lessinger - 2 Helpful Books to Jump-Start Your Financial Success

Jessica Sanders - How We Keep Remote Employees Accountable

Philipp Fries - Tour our newest listing

Ed Pluchar - A Quick Tip for Selling Your Home in Today’s Market

Jennie Wolek - How to handle lower offers

Patrick Fitzgerald - Is Using an IRRL a Smart Move for You?

Brian Beatty - Should You Sell in the Fall?

Tim Riordan - Fall 2017 Buffalo Northtowns housing update

Aaron Hendon - A Great New Community Venue Is Coming Soon to Vashon

Alex Mont-Ros - A Conversation With Lloyd Ball of Anomaly Commercial

The Consigliori - The Missing Key Revealed

Spencer Janke - What happened in this bathroom?

Brandon Montemayor - What Does a Recent Change in the Lending World Mean for You?

Jeff Green - Don’t Let Small Obstacles Eclipse Your Long-Term Goals

Sherry &amp; Angela - 	How Does Our 5-Step Buyer System Work?

Clifton Sanders - Work With A Mortgage Team That Truly Cares

Melinda Elmer - Were you impacted by the Equifax data breach?

Lisa Sisko - What Are Your Mortgage and Credit Options?

David Rosen - Property Tax Problems Explained

Ryan Hummel - How to Keep From Getting “Text Neck”

Bill Burns - A Pre-Approval Can Bulk Up Your Offer

Dave Hooke - How Has Our Local Market Changed Since 2016?

Jack Barry - Fall 2017 Philadelphia housing update

Matt Templeton - How Do We Handle a Shifting Market

Adam Bailey - 4 Helpful Halloween Home Tips

Andrew Lamb - Fall 2017 Vacaville housing update

Kwasi Bowie - The myth about down payments debunked

Don Williams - How to Stage Your Home for Success

Christal Johnson - Why Do I Need a Realtor If I Buy New Construction?

Pazi D - You Won’t Believe What’s Possible With Our New Loan Program

Tad Wicker - What makes us stand out compared to other agents?

Jason Bramblett - Fall 2017 Triad Area housing update

Kevin Langan - We’re Bringing Even More Value to Real Estate

Scott Fuller - Watch: What not to overlook when purchasing a home

Patrick O’Sullivan - 3 Reasons You Must Have Professional Photography When Selling

Ferzoco Group - How Are Appraisal Costs Calculated?

Heather Upton - 3 Questions to Ask When Interviewing Listing Agents

Joe Mendoza - Surprise guest for Saturday’s training event

Todd Martin - Fall 2017 Louisville housing update

Don Mowery - How will the Fed’s new move impact real estate? PLAIN TXT

Joy Daniels - Fall 2017 Central Pennsylvania housing update

Clayton Gits - When Are You Committed to a Real Estate Agent?

Jeff Ryder - Why home inspections matter so much

Diane Cardano-Casacio - Homeownership rates are increasing

Kelly Cook - Watch: Should you rent or own a home?

Abel Tejeda - 3 Tips for a Better Credit Score

Aaron Wittenstein - Selling Your Own Home? Take Advantage of the Smart Seller Program

Chris Colgan - How will the Fed’s new move impact real estate?

Jason Mitchell - 5 Things Potential Homebuyers Should Know

Dan Rochon - YOU’RE INVITED TO MY UPCOMING BUSINESS PLANNING CLINIC

JP Pirtle - Watch: We are hiring

Jeff Latham - Fall 2017 Washington housing update

Andrew Duncan - How Irma Affected the Tampa Real Estate Market

Rick Sadle - What Can Staging Do for Your Home?

Joshua Stern  - Market Update

Eric Burch - What to Expect From the Fourth Quarter Real Estate Market

Rob Cedillo - Why Are Pre-Approvals So Important?

Ruby Henderson - Master the Art of Negotiating as a Home Seller

(ASI) Aesthetic Surgical Images - Don’t miss this scary good deal

Robert Mack  - October Newsletter

Delane Rouse - Converting Color Photos to Black &amp; White Is Easy for Us

Chad Schwendeman - These 3 Seller Mistakes Are More Common Than You Think

David Humes - October Market Update

Brent Downing - The basics of working with an agent
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Karlyn Ellis, Seth & Alyce Dailey, Earron Shields, Gretchen Karr, and Leslie Carver</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Karlyn Ellis, Seth & Alyce Dailey, Earron Shields, Gretchen Karr, and Leslie Carver</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Week of 10/9/17</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/weekof10917.html</link>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-19 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Jeffrey Cohn - How Can You Know What Your Home Will Sell for in Omaha?
Sent to: 49722 | Opens: 43.29 | Clicks: 0.38

Scott Hollinger - 3rd Quarter 2017 Waterfront Report
Sent to: 1847 | Opens: 30.86 | Clicks: 15.81

Holly Mabery - Smart home
Sent to: 107 | Opens: 28.97 | Clicks: 7.48

Joe Coimbra - Attorney Newsletter
Sent to: 129 | Opens: 25.58 | Clicks: 4.65

Dan &amp; Connie Couse - Plain Text
Sent to: 1077 | Opens: 24.14 | Clicks: 3.44



Marcus Green - Meet Carolyn Chavez

O’Neill Team - Good Marketing Can Maximize Your Home’s Appeal

John Simmonds - How to Maintain Your Pool During the Hurricane

Richard Wit - 	Are There Any Costs or Obligations to Previewing Your Home?

Duke Kimhan - Owners, Rejoice: We’re Here to Help

Jason Wilson - Reserve Your Spot for Our Pie Giveaway!

Andrew Lamb - What Is an Expansion Team

Scott Himelstein - Market update

Jeremy Qualley - Buyer specialist

Melinda Elmer - What does “pre-foreclosure” mean on Zillow?

Marjorie Dick Stuart - Price reduction

Ashley Carter - You’re Invited to Our Free Pumpkin Giveaway!

Joe Richardson - Ask Joe: Answering Your Real Estate Questions

Chris Colgan - The top 4 negotiation tactics

Shane Neal - Looking for talented individuals

Anastasia Riley - What is a home warranty?

Gary Raze - These Missed Details Could Give You Buyer’s Remorse

Ron Margolis - The only way to get an accurate home value

Brett Sikora - 5 Costs That Shock First-Time Homebuyers

Rob Kittle - Plain Text

Nathan Abbott - Have You Been to the Sunset Bay Cafe?

Daniel Dixon - Appraisal questions and answers

Jeremy Sisemore - 10 Hottest I.T. Skills

Lindsey Gudger - What 4 Tips Can Make or Break Your Listing?

Becky Ivins - Do professional photos matter?

Sandy Eagon - 3 Common Misunderstandings Smart Sellers Still Have

Gillies Team - 	Why is a team better than just 1 agent?

Troy Copeland - List in the fall

Josh Lioce - 8 Tips to Prevent Flood Damage

Anthony Boatner - Why You Should Consider a Backup Offer

Bo Winn - Should you list or remodel your home?

David Rosen - Property Tax Problems Explained

Andrew Kronenberg - I am thinking about selling. Now what?

Bryan David - Why order an inspection before listing?

Jon &amp; Patty Hampton - Feds Plain Text

Jennifer Niederbrach - Can you trust online home value tools?

Melissa Thompson - A Look at Our Market: 2016 vs. Now

Chip Hodgkins - 	You must do this as soon as possible

Nate Martinez - Why Hasn’t Your Home Sold Yet?

Shawn Kriewaldt - Fall 2017 Housing Update

GoVig 1 - Becoming a better leader

Monique Walker - Support The Guerrant Foundation’s Worthwhile Cause

Bob Little - Why hire an agent

Sarah/Marty McKay - 4 Tips to Prepare Your Home to Sell in the Fall &amp; Winter

Aaron &amp; Kelly Allen - The Key to Listing in a Shifting Market

Mike Gray - 	How smart is your home?

Jennifer Smith - List in the fall

Zach Wessolleck - What’s the Best Way to Price Your Home?

Mike Duggal - A Guide to Selling Your Home in the Fall

Ryan Smith - How to Speed up the Selling Process

Mike Tchobanian - When Is the Best Time for Homeownership?

Kevin Clancy - Are you moving forward purposefully?

Dar Walden - Anchorage market overview

Kodi Riddle - Fall 2017 Greater Phoenix housing update

Andrew Kent - Is Fall a Good Time to Sell in Salt Lake City?

Greg Tran - Is the Austin market headed for a bubble?

Jeff Adler - Stand out offer

Rick Sadle - Fall 2017 Portland/Vancouver housing update

Kyle Lancashire - Join Us in Welcoming Brandon to Our Team

Chad Smith - Entice homebuyers

Kris Miller - Our group coaching could unlock your success

Leigh Marcus - Winter is coming! Take your outdoor photos now!

Adrienne Lally - Team Lally Supports Pearlside Boxing

Victoria Sandoval - A Fall Market Update for San Diego Real Estate

Dave Friedman - It’s the great pumpkin giveaway

Jodie Osofsky - Disc golf

Andy Mulholland - What kind of value is most important?

Greater Toronto Group (Dijana) - Don’t Hire an Agent Before Asking Them These 10 Questions First

Durwin Cheung - Why Include a “Love Letter” in Your Offer?

Chris Watters - Fall 2017 Austin housing update

Jerimiah Taylor - Upcoming Market Trends in  Tucson

Bret Johnson - What Happens If You’re Not Happy With Your Home Purchase?

Brandon Brittingham - Help Us Contribute to Breast Cancer Awareness

Saul Zenkevicius - Market update

Brian Gubernick - What Are You Required to Disclose About Your Home?

Spalding Pyron - Can an Agent Help You Purchase a For Sale By Owner Home?

Brent Dildine - Why Listing This Fall Could Be the Right Move for You

Jeff Cook - Rent Holy City

Wes Peters - How Has Technology Changed the World of Lending?

Marti Hampton - 	Fall 2017 Triangle Area housing update

JP Pirtle - Plumber wanted

Greater Calgary Group - A Way to Obtain the Best Rates &amp; Lowest Closing Costs

Maggie Harris - 5 Ways to Invest in Real Estate

Tom Nickley - What’s the Best Way to Stage Your Home?

Spencer Hasch - 8 Things to Avoid After Buying a New Home

Valerie Hunter-Kelly - Why Do You Need a Buyer’s Partner Representing You?

Dan Ellison - 3 Key Tips to Selling Your Home in the Fall

Diva Team - How to Get Your Home Ready Before Winter Strikes

Curtis Johnson - 5 ways to invest in real estate

Misty Soldwisch - We’ve cooked up a fun prize for you
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Jeffrey Cohn, Scott Hollinger, Holly Mabery, Joe Coimbra, and Dan & Connie Couse</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Jeffrey Cohn, Scott Hollinger, Holly Mabery, Joe Coimbra, and Dan & Connie Couse</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Week of 10/2/17</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/week-of-10217.html</link>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-13 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Tracy Wilson - How to purchase a home for next to nothing


  
    
      Sent to 205
      Opens: 25.85%
      Clicks: 4.39%
    
  


Karlyn Ellis - New construction seekers need agents, too


  
    
      Sent to 914
      Opens: 24.8%
      Clicks: 42.30%
    
  


Wade Betz - Things to Know About Flood Insurance


  
    
      Sent to: 5057
      Opens: 21.26%
      Clicks: 2.89%
    
  


Kari Kohler - St. Charles Has Something for Everyone


  
    
      Sent to: 2655
      Opens: 19.5%
      Clicks: 3.5%
    
  


Alex Lam - What could happen if your deal collapses


  
    
      Sent to: 558
      Opens: 17.56%
      Clicks: 4.12%
    
  




John Simmonds - How to Maintain Your Pool During the Hurricane

Janet Gresh - Real estate’s first cryptocurrencies

Max Folkers - Introducing Myself

Jason Daniels - TrainingThe Secret to Organizing Your Database

Casey Cooke - How Does Our Market Look as We Enter Fall?

Chris Hauck - What’s happening in St. Cloud’s market?

Kelly Fischer - Is It Time for You to Downsize?

Kyle Fernandez - You can make a difference for kids in need

Cristina Dougherty - 5 Upgrades That May Not Add Value to Your Home

Ed Pluchar - Answering Your Questions About Homebuyer Etiquette During Showings

Jared Chamberlain (Chamberlain Group) - How Can You Make Your Property Stand out in Today’s Market?

Joe DiRaffaele - How Kindness Can Help Us and Our City Move Forward

Sharon Stevens - My favorite farmer’s market in St. Augustine

Spencer Janke - Are rates changing soon?

Lisa Sisko - Everything You Should Know About Radon

Dave Nimick - How to Navigate Simultaneously Buying and Selling

Mike Roth - Plain Text

Jeff Green - Dealing With the Aftermath of Hurricane Harvey

Joe DeSane - The problem with Zillow’s Zestimates

Karen &amp; Joe Donovan (Long Island) - The Path to Orchestrating Your Own Home Sale

Sandie Hea - These 3 Inspections Could Save You a Lot of Trouble Later On

Adam Bailey - Got Questions You’re Afraid to Ask Your Agent? I’ve Got Answers

Andy Stavros - We’re Excited To Join Forces With Douglas Elliman

Blaine Moore - Plain Text

Mark Gellman - What Should You Do to Prepare Your Home for the Market?

Rex Jarnagin - What You Should Know About Zillow

Chip Hodgkins - Real estate’s first cryptocurrencies

Jason Baker - What’s Wrong With Listing Without an Agent?

Susan Heller - An Update on Southwest Florida’s Hurricane Recovery

Dave Hooke - 3 Reasons Your Home Isn’t Selling

Dave Knight - How to Fix Up Your Home Prior to Selling It

Mark Brace - Can you be exempt from capital gains?

Earron Shields - You’re Invited to Our Fall Client Appreciation Event

Mario Romero - Should you list your home this fall?

Brad Korb - What’s Our Fall Market Outlook?

Mike Quail - September Market Update

Shawn Luong - Plain Text

Lance Woodley - How Being Local Makes a Difference in Real Estate

Jesse Myles - Plain Text

Thom Dallman - Core Group RealtyThe fall Parade of Homes is happening now

Anne Stewart - Our market is changing

Dan Jones - Thinking of Listing on Your Own? You May Want to Reconsider

Matt Templeton - What 3 Challenges Do Homebuyers Most Commonly Face?

Joe Coimbra - How Do I Destroy, Erase or Improve My Criminal Record?

Lisa Blake - What Trends Are Happening in the Market?

GoVig 3 - A 90-day transition plan

Ana Sarabia - The Problem With Zestimates

Haro Setian - Plain Text

John Mikesh - Pick the patch

GoVig 2 - Looking to stand out as a job candidate?

Brayden Bengtzen - What’s Happening in the Salt Lake County Real Estate Market?

Dave Nabity/ Rob - The True Value of Entrepreneurship

Billy/Heidi Phong - What Do You Need to Know About Closing Costs?

Tom Daves - 4 Options for Buying and Selling at the Same Time

David Huffaker - 3 Topics to Consider When Building a New Home

Kodi Riddle - Tips for purchasing new construction

Jason Penrose - Which is the wiser investment?

Joy Daniels - What is Homes for Heroes?

Jason Daniels - Buying a Home for the First Time? Here’s How to Stay Protected

Sarita Dua - 2 Reasons to Get Pre-Approved Before You Look at Homes

Julie Baldino - 5 Unique Home Selling Tips for Fall and Winter

Aaron Wittenstein - 7 Questions to Ask Before Hiring a Listing Agent

Ruby Henderson - What Does Listing For Sale by Owner Truly Cost?

Damon Gettier - Unexpected Costs Could Leave You Reeling

Andrew Ford - The Best Home Search Website Out There

Danny Burks/Ashlee Branch - What Can You Do to Make Your Move as Smooth as Possible?

Bob Sokoler - Plain Text

Kathy Toth - What Is the Homes Sold Guarantee?
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Tracy Wilson, Karlyn Ellis, Wade Betz, Kari Kohler, and Alex Lam</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Tracy Wilson, Karlyn Ellis, Wade Betz, Kari Kohler, and Alex Lam</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Week of 9/25/17</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/week-of-92517.html</link>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-06 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Seth &amp; Alyce Dailey - Helping Those Impacted by Harvey


  
    
      Sent to: 5017
      Open: 32.21
      Click: 1.91
    
  


Breanne Steen - Questions - Plain Text


  
    
      Sent to: 2019
      Open: 26.99
      Click: 0.74
    
  


Justin Udy - 3 Questions to Ask Yourself Before Joining a Team


  
    
      Sent to: 2100
      Open: 25.62
      Click: 3.86
    
  


Scott Hollinger - Hesitating on the right home can be a mistake


  
    
      Sent to: 1863
      Open: 22.28
      Click: 3.27
    
  


Melida Potts - Questions - Plain Text


  
    
      Sent to: 1656
      Open: 19.32
      Click: 0.06
    
  




Melinda Elmer - 5 ways to invest in real estate

David Shutler - Debunking 2 major fitness myths

John Simmonds - How to Maintain Your Pool During the Hurricane

Anne-Marie McCormick - Market Update

Jeremy Larkin - Career Opportunity with The Larkin Group!

Jay White - Market update

Gene Agustin - The difference between pre-approval and pre-qualification

Mike Roth - Should You Trust Zillow With Your Home’s Value?

Blaine Moore - Buying New Home Construction? Beware of These Agent Tricks

Dan Ihara - Helping Those Impacted by Harvey

Bill Black - 770 Acre Dam Site

Aaron Hendon - Is Seattle in a Bubble? Part II

Karen &amp; Joe Donovan (Tampa Bay)

Monique Walker - A New Arcadia-Lite Listing!

David Rosen - What Are the Most Important Elements in a Property?

Christal Johnson - The Tale of 2 Home Inspections

Rodney &amp; Jenn Wallner - Fall/Winter Preperations

Chase Craig - Reconnect - Plain Text

O.K Hogan - What Makes Today’s Market So Great to List In?

Chad Smith - 4 Things to Consider When Buying New Construction

Shannon Rollings - Humanitree Juice Bar

Thom Dallman - Core Group RealtyDon’t miss these fall listing tips

Jesse Myles - Don’t Trust a Zestimate

Tim Majka - 5 Ways to Surge Ahead of Competitors in this Hot Market

Lee Tessier - How Can Renovations Affect Your Home Value?

Chip Glennon - Market Update

Christine Browning - The Role of Appraisals in Home Selling

Jon Carbutti - Don’t Start Your Home Search Without Meeting With a Buyer’s Agent First

Jodie Osofsky - Rounding Out the Top 10 Trends at Salt Lake Creative Homes

Shawn Culhane - The Loan Officer Is Key to Closing on Your Home

Todd Martin - Back-up Offers

(ASI) Aesthetic Surgical Images - Strech marks

Kelly Cook - 5 Ways You Can Invest in Real Estate

Caleb Pearson - 5 Real Estate Investments

Michael Perna - Harvey and Irma Victims still need us!!

Bob Sokoler - How Did Our Market Fare in the Month of August?

Jennifer Niederbrach - Zillow Lawsuit

Jennie Wolek - Grogg’s Green Barn

Christy Morrison - 5 reasons to list your home this fall

Travis Chatwin - Will changes in our local market affect you?

Becky Ivins - Getting your offer accepted

Josh Heneveld - Trusting Zillow could be a mistake

Dave Heeter - Market Update

Philipp Fries - Think twice before skipping flood insurance

Ryan Hummel - Alleviate lower back pain

Erik Winegarden - Who pays the commission?

Jack Barry - Will we see you at any of these events?

Shane Neal - Our Red Relief program is here to help

Art Lickunas - What an agent truly earns

Jason McIntosh - For Sale By Owner

Randy Plaice - Fall is a great time to sell your home

Greg &amp; Wendy Kime - Renting a home vs. owning one

Greg Ismay - The new place you can find our newsletter

Jason Morris - Do you need flood insurance?
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Seth & Alice Dailey, Breanne Steen, Justin Udy, Scott Hollinger, and Melida Potts</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Seth & Alice Dailey, Breanne Steen, Justin Udy, Scott Hollinger, and Melida Potts</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Week of 9/18/17</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/week-of-91817.html</link>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2017-09-25 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Tracy Wilson -	Northern Colorado market insights
Sent to: 208 | Open: 30.77 | Click: 8.17

Rob Kittle -	Listing Flyer
Sent to: 1671 | Open: 26.87 | Click: 3.71

Dan Ihara -	Millionaire Listing
Sent to: 265 | Open: 22.64 | Click: 1.13

Dave Knight -	Questions Plain Text
Sent to: 1389 | Open: 22.53 | Click: 0.14

Chad Huebener -	New inspection contingency changes
Sent to: 3232 | Open: 21.5 | Click: 3.47



Hal Sweasey - 	Meet the Team

John Simmonds -	How to Maintain Your Pool During the Hurricane

Rob Spring -	How Much Do You Really Need for a Down Payment?

Charleston Homes -	Fall home preparation alert

Greg McDaniel - 	Commission Deal

Bo Winn -	Watch to find out the latest market trends

Joe DiRaffaele -	It’s Time for the 3rd Annual Sip, Sail, and Savor

Alfie McFadden -	What’s it like working with us?

Mike Lafido -	2 record-breaking home sales

Dave Friedman -	My recent visit to Real Estate Uncensored

Tina Caul -	5 Ways to Invest in Real Estate

Renae Gibson -	Red Relief—Helping Those Impacted by Harvey and Irma

Ashley Carter -	Helping Those Impacted by Harvey

Jason Shinpaugh -	Hurricane Recovery

Chris Snow -	Praying for Jacksonville

Dave Knight -	What Is the Mills Act?

Dave Nimick -	Local Lender vs Online Mortgage Provider

Jay White -	Is your home priced correctly for the market?

Rob Ellis -	Investing in Columbus

Gloria Buck -	Red Relief—Helping Those Impacted by Harvey and Irma

Lee Tessier -	Questions Plain Text

Lance Woodley -	Happy Fall Plain Text

Lance Woodley -	Recruiting Email

Anastasia Riley -	Interest Rates

Ryan Butler -	Real estate investing all text

Ian Lobas -	The importance of home staging

Mark Brace -	September Market Update

Lisa Treu - 	The victims of Hurricane Irma need our help

Anne-Marie McCormick -	Keep up with San Diego real estate news

Anne Stewart -	An emerging challenge in our market

Ryan Anderson -	How We Make Dreams Come True

Amanda Howard -	Investing in your kid’s college crib

Robert &amp; Shannon Rollings - 	Pricing for new construction &amp; resale homes

Jeff Ryder -	The right color can add thousands in value

Shawn Culhane -	Hurricane Harvey - Plain Text

Jan Leasure -	5 Ways to Invest in Real Estate

Kris Miller -	Where Do I Start My Day?

Jason Penrose -	What made our August market so different?

Jason Bramblett -	Our listing guarantee

(ASI) Aesthetic Surgical Images -	Recovering from a tummy tuck

Ana Sarabia -	Avoid These 5 Listing Mistakes

Diane Cardano-Casacio -	3 tips you’ll learn at my upcoming seminar

Haro Setian -	Red Relief—Helping Those Impacted by Harvey and Irma

Paul Herrick -	Real Estate Myth Busting: Part 2

Monica Benevides -	6 Tips for Successfully Staging Your Kitchen

Greg Tran -	What will the Houston market look like now?

Amy Smits / Kevin Smits -	This new program allows you to refinance quickly

John Hatch - 	Important stats from the Portland market

Peter MacIntyre -	5 Ways to Invest In Real Estate

Curtis Johnson -	3 facts you need to know about the home-flipping craze

Kwasi Bowie -	Is it possible to predict market changes?

Jeff Latham -	My key to financial freedom

Alex Lam - 	How interest rate increases affect you
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Tracy Wilson, Rob Kittle, Dan Ihara, Dave Knight, and Chad Huebener</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Tracy Wilson, Rob Kittle, Dan Ihara, Dave Knight, and Chad Huebener</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Week of 9/11/17</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/week-of-91117.html</link>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2017-09-21 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Tracy Wilson - Costly Mistakes
Sent to: 204 | Opens: 31.37 | Clicks: 8.33

Scott Hollinger - Wildfire Season
Sent to: 1739 | Opens: 27.6 | Clicks: 3.85

Dan Ihara - Do You Have Any Questions?
Sent to: 2190 | Opens: 26.12 | Clicks: 2.28

Eric Vallee - Questions Plain Text
Sent to: 1957 | Opens: 21.67 | Clicks: 0.51

John Head - Answering 2 Questions
Sent to: 1049 | Opens: 19.35 | Clicks: 4.29



Breanne Steen - Are your property taxes going up?

Joe DiRaffaele - Harvey’s Impact on the Las Vegas Market

Christal Johnson - One success story from our mentoring program

Haro Setian - Questions - Plain Text

Aaron Hendon - Is Our Seattle Market in a Bubble?

Brian Hammond - Red Relief—Helping Those Impacted by Harvey and Irma

Michael Kaim - Could things fall apart before closing?

Roshena Chada - Reconnect Plain Text

Melida Potts - What Do You Have to Do to Sell Your Estate Sale?

Mike Roth - 7 Keys to Winning a Multiple Offer Situation in Our Market

Blaine Moore - Is the Fall a Good Time to Buy or Sell a Home?

Gene Agustin - How Divorce Impacts My Current Mortgage

Lee Tessier - Questions Plain Text

Lance Woodley - Plain Text

O.K Hogan - How to prepare for a hurricane

Rob Kittle - Appraisal vs. Inspection: What’s the Difference?

Thom Dallman -Core Group Realty - Mesa Listing

Seth &amp; Alyce Dailey - Why You Should Think Twice Before Trusting a Zestimate

Amy Smits / Kevin Smits - An Exciting New Venture

Greg McDaniel - 	You won’t want to miss our next event

Nick Good - Short Sales

Kevin Clancy - How Does My Team Sell So Many Homes?

Andy Sachs - Your latest fall market update

Amanda Howard - Market Update

Doug Herdahl - Vetting Buyers and Offers

Denise Swick - 5 ways to invest in real estate

Bill Black - Try the Fat Mo challenge

Chip Hodgkins - The best place to get meat in Manlius

Heather Upton - Red Relief—Helping Those Impacted by Harvey and Irma

Shawn Luong - A Look at Our Market From Last Year to Now

Caleb Pearson -  Are you on the fence about moving?

Maggie Harris - Providing disaster relief for hurricane victims

Diane Cardano-Casacio - Market Update

Chad Raney - Red Relief—Helping Those Impacted by Harvey and Irma

Tyler Goff - Is Fall a Good Time to Sell

Kwasi Bowie - Listing in the Fall

Jeffrey Cohn - What Things Need to Change When Transitioning Into a New Home?

Peter Dellane - Enhancing your credit

Chris Gorman - Video guide to a secret real estate resource

Bob Sokoler - A Market Update and Disaster Insurance Tips

David Robinson - New Study

Christy Morrison - Your latest Tahoe-Truckee summer market update

Ron Margolis - Kauai real estate’s latest news

Shane Neal - Could you be our next team member?

Jason Delatte - Are you making any of these mistakes?

Erik Winegarden - Closing cost questions?

Zach Behr - 3 Beautiful Homes That Haven’t Hit the Market Yet

Greg &amp; Wendy Kime - What’s happening with home prices right now?

Jose Morales - Good deals are always out there

Andy Mulholland - Appraisal problem help

Glen Gayden - Hurricane Harvey relief info

Art Lickunas - Can you overcome this real estate disaster?

GoVig 2 - The power of interview scheduling

Dave Friedman - We’ve been noticing some odd changes

Randy Plaice - The latest smart home tech

Greg Ismay - Don’t go into new construction alone

Jerimiah Taylor - The latest numbers from the Tucson market

Jason Morris - The best indicators of our market’s health

David Humes - Monthly Rector-Hayden Market Report
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Tracy Wilson, Scott Hollinger, Dan Ihara, Eric Vallee, and John Head</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Tracy Wilson, Scott Hollinger, Dan Ihara, Eric Vallee, and John Head</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Week of 9/04/17</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/week-of-90417.html</link>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2017-09-12 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Hunter Reynolds  - What Are the Best Benefits of Homeownership?
Sent to: 28721 | Opens: 33.52 | Clicks: 0.1%

Charlotte Mabry - How to Sell Your Home—Agent Secrets Revealed
Sent to: 12607 | Opens: 20.93 | Clicks: 0.79%

Canady and Chase - Earnest Money Explained in Under 90 Seconds
Sent to: 1255 | Opens: 17.77 | Clicks: 3.19

Clayton Gits - The Best Way to Choose a Realtor
Sent to: 15374 | Opens: 17.47 | Clicks: 0.21%

Jody Donaldson - Which Home Upgrades Aren't Worth Making?
Sent to: 3069 | Opens: 16 | Clicks: 3



Robert Little - 5 Ways to Add Value to Your Home

Clifton Saunders - 8 Common Myths About Veteran Financing

Mary Peacock - How to Prepare Your Home for the Market

Paul Brouillette - How Can a Digital Tour of Your Home Attract Buyers?

Vergis Eiland - How to Find the Right Lender

Bill White - Why Can’t You Trust Zillow to Calculate Your Home’s Value?

Christy Kimbrel - What Is Your Home Worth in This Crazy Market?

Will Cook - 6 Types of Disclosures in California

Angel Garcia - Don’t Make These Mistakes When Buying a Home

Mike Tchobanian - Think You Need 20% Down? Not With These Assistance Programs

Bob &amp; Diane Peterson - Reconnect Email

Andrew Ford - Credit Repair Advice From an Expert

Alan Kushmakov - Where Can You Find Properties Besides the MLS?

Paul Herrick - Myth-Busting a Common Real Estate Agent Claim

Ernie Dill - Are You Serious About Buying a Home?

Brayden Bengtzen - To Buy or Not to Buy—That Is the Question

Wes Peters - Great News About Our Zillow Reviews and a Quick Market Update

Matt Fetick - Why a Buyer’s Agent Is So Valuable

Kevin Yoder - Which Role Is Best for You—Buyer’s Agent or Seller’s Agent?

Nick Kellar  - How This Academy Is Using Jiu-Jitsu to Bring Confidence to a Community

Sarita Dua - Why We Don’t Mind Breaking the Deal

Don Vallee - The Best Ways to Make Your Home More Energy Efficient

Tom Nickley - You’re Invited to Pumpkin Chuckin’ with The Nickley Group

Deja Lett - Busting 3 Common Home Buying Myths

Sean Zanganeh - Is It a Wise Move to Invest in an Airbnb Property?

Jana &amp; Jason DeLong - A Few Common Appraisal Questions Answered

Anastasia Riley - How Can You Lessen the Stress &amp; Costs Involved in Your Move?

John Simmonds - How to Maintain Your Pool During the Hurricane
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Hunter Reynolds, Charlotte Mabry, Clayton Gits, Robert Little, and Clifton Saunders.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Hunter Reynolds, Charlotte Mabry, Clayton Gits, Robert Little, and Clifton Saunders.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright></copyright>
    <media:credit role="author"></media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Vyral Marketing - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
