<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Raleigh Real Estate Podcast with Tina Caul</title>
    <link>http://raleighrealestatelife.com</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://raleighrealestatelife.com"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Caul Real Estate Group - your professional Raleigh Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Tina Caul</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2017-09-27 14:49:02 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Tina Caul</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://raleighrealestatelife.com/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Raleigh, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Team@CaulTeam.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Tina Caul</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Tina Caul</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://raleighrealestatelife.com/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Raleigh, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Raleigh Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Caul Real Estate Group - your professional Raleigh Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Ways to Invest in Real Estate</title>
        <link>http://raleighrealestatelife.com/real-estate-investing-is-on-rise.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Tina Caul</author>
        <pubDate>2017-09-15 14:58:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Tina%20Caul/Greater%20Raleigh%20Real%20Estate-%205%20Ways%20to%20Invest%20in%20Real%20Estate.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Real estate investing is on the rise. Here are five different ways you can get involved.

Investing in real estate is no longer restricted to the super wealthy. According to a recent survey, real estate investors now make up 15% of the population. That translates to almost 50 million individuals who invest in at least one property other than their primary residence.

In fact, 89% of U.S. investors are interested in putting their money in real estate because of benefits such as cash flow, tax incentives, leverage, and value appreciation that come with investing in multiple properties.

REAL ESTATE INVESTING IS ON THE RISE. HERE ARE FIVE DIFFERENT WAYS YOU CAN GET INVOLVED.

Are you curious about investing in real estate? If so, here are five different ways you can get started:

1. Buy and rent
This is probably the most traditional way to invest in real estate. It simply involves buying a property and renting it out. Now is a good time for this kind of investing because rental rates are on the rise (8% since last year) but the downside of this investing approach is the time and effort needed to manage and maintain your investment.

2. Buy and sell
Also known as home flipping, this involves buying a property and reselling it soon after for a profit. Home flipping has offered a record-breaking 49% return in 2016.

3. Real estate investment groups
Real estate investment groups are organizations that buy a set of properties and then sell them to individual investors.The main benefit of this approach is that you typically do not need to act as the landlord because the investment group handles property management for you (for a fee of course).

4. Crowdfunding sites
Recently, there’s been an explosion of sites such as Prosper and Lending Club, which allow individuals to invest in various real estate development projects. Through crowdfunding sites, you can be a part of a large-scale property investment while investing only a moderate amount of money. On the other hand, crowdfunding sites act as a middleman and charge fees which can eat into your profits.

5. REITs
Real estate investment trusts (REITs) are like mutual funds for real estate.They typically pay high dividends. However, they also do not offer all of the typical benefits of investing in real estate, such as increased leverage and tax benefits.

Each of these investing approaches offers a tradeoff between possible profits, risks, and costs. The one constant is that you can minimize your risks with due diligence and by consulting with an experienced real estate professional.

If you have any questions for us or you’re interested in investing in real estate yourself, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Tina%20Caul/Greater%20Raleigh%20Real%20Estate-%205%20Ways%20to%20Invest%20in%20Real%20Estate.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://raleighrealestatelife.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Tina%20Caul/Greater%20Raleigh%20Real%20Estate-%205%20Ways%20to%20Invest%20in%20Real%20Estate.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Real estate investing is on the rise. Here are five different ways you can get involved.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Tina Caul</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Real estate investing is on the rise. Here are five different ways you can get involved.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Raleigh, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>You Dont Need a Down Payment</title>
        <link>http://raleighrealestatelife.com/you-dont-need-down-payment.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Tina Caul</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-22 15:42:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Tina%20Caul/Greater%20Raleigh%20Real%20Estate-%20You%20Dont%20Need%20a%20Down%20Payment.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There are a lot of loan options out there with low down payment options. There are even some that don’t require a down payment at all.

What’s the biggest obstacle to homeownership?

According to a recent survey, “saving enough for a down payment” comes at the top of the list. A whopping 55% of prospective homebuyers cited this as their main stumbling block.

And with the continuing growth of home prices, things aren’t getting any easier. In fact, homeownership rates reached a 20-year low last November.

It wasn’t always like this.

A decade ago, many lenders were offering easy, no-money-down mortgages.

However, after the financial crisis, mortgage standards have become more restrictive. A typical mortgage now requires a 20% down payment.

“55% CITED THE LACK OF A DOWN PAYMENT AS THEIR MAIN STUMBLING BLOCK.”

Here’s the good news.

If you have decent credit and a steady income, you might be qualified for a number of specialized programs that require no or very little down payment. Here are a few of the top options.

First, there’s the USDA loan, which is valid for homes in certain regions, such as rural and suburban areas.

With zero money down and lenient credit requirements, the USDA loan can be a great choice for many homeowners.

Second, there’s the VA loan, which you can apply for if you or your spouse served in a branch of the military.

It’s possibly the most generous zero-money-down mortgage because of low-interest rates and low closing costs.

Third, there’s the FHA loan. It does require a 3.5% down payment—still drastically more achievable than the 20% required for a conventional mortgage.

Finally, there are a number credit unions and first-time homebuyer programs that might apply to your particular situation.

There’s one important thing you should know.

If you get one of these no-money-down mortgages, chances are good you will be required to pay private mortgage insurance, which can drive up your monthly payments.

Fortunately, private mortgage insurance will disappear after your mortgage balance is under 80%. Also, the money you do pay will be tax deductible in most cases.

In short, there are lots of options to make owning a home a reality for you, even if you haven’t saved up tens of thousands of dollars.

If you need more advice on getting a no-money-down loan, give me a call. I can put you in touch with some experienced lenders who can answer your questions and help get you started.
</description>
        <enclosure url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Tina%20Caul/Greater%20Raleigh%20Real%20Estate-%20You%20Dont%20Need%20a%20Down%20Payment.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://raleighrealestatelife.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Tina%20Caul/Greater%20Raleigh%20Real%20Estate-%20You%20Dont%20Need%20a%20Down%20Payment.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

There are a lot of loan options out there with low down payment options. There are even some that don’t require a down payment at all.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Tina Caul</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

There are a lot of loan options out there with low down payment options. There are even some that don’t require a down payment at all.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Raleigh, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Fannie Mae Is Relaxing Some Student Loan Policies</title>
        <link>http://raleighrealestatelife.com/fannie-mae-is-relaxing-some-student.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Tina Caul</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-26 15:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Tina%20Caul/Greater%20Raleigh%20Real%20Estate-%20Fannie%20Mae%20Is%20Relaxing%20Some%20Student%20Loan%20Policies.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today, I’d like to share some new Fannie Mae rules that those with student debt may find intriguing.

If you have a student loan or you are a cosigner on one, I have some good news for you.

Fannie Mae, the nation’s largest underwriter of mortgages, recently introduced three new rules that will affect those with student debt.

These new rules can make it easier to get a mortgage, and they can make it easier to pay off your (or your kids’) student loans.

The first change is for those on income-based repayment plans, where having a high debt-to-income ratio is the No. 1 reason for not being approved for a mortgage.

Fannie Mae previously used a very conservative 1% of the total loan instead of the actual monthly payment. This can drastically lower your debt-to-income ratio and give you a much better chance of qualifying for a mortgage.

Some folks are lucky enough to have their student debt paid by their parents or even by their employer. The thing is, Fannie Mae didn’t take this into account when calculating the debt-to-income ratio. That’s the second new change.

If your employer or your parents have been paying off your student debt and you can show evidence of this for the past 12 months, then this debt won’t be counted in your debt-to-income ratio. This makes it more likely you will qualify for a mortgage.

“IF YOU CAN QUALIFY FOR A MORTGAGE RIGHT NOW, YOU DEFINITELY SHOULD.”

If you can qualify for a mortgage right now, you definitely should. Rates are still at a historic low, and lots of great houses have recently come on the Raleigh market.

Fannie Mae also makes it possible to refinance your mortgage for more than the value of your home. Normally, there is a 0.25% fee that applies to any cash you take out in this way.
The third big change is that Fannie Mae will now waive that fee when you use this cash to pay off a student loan.

This applies whether the loan is yours, or you’re a cosigner. If the mortgage rate is significantly lower than the student loan rate, it can make sense to refinance in this way, and the new rule makes it cheaper to do so.

If you need help understanding these new guidelines to see whether they’re right for you, or you have questions about putting them into practice, get in touch with me by phone or email. I’ll be glad to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Tina%20Caul/Greater%20Raleigh%20Real%20Estate-%20Fannie%20Mae%20Is%20Relaxing%20Some%20Student%20Loan%20Policies.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://raleighrealestatelife.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Tina%20Caul/Greater%20Raleigh%20Real%20Estate-%20Fannie%20Mae%20Is%20Relaxing%20Some%20Student%20Loan%20Policies.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today, I’d like to share some new Fannie Mae rules that those with student debt may find intriguing.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Tina Caul</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today, I’d like to share some new Fannie Mae rules that those with student debt may find intriguing.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Raleigh, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3 Things Every First-Time Homebuyer Should Know</title>
        <link>http://raleighrealestatelife.com/3-things-every-first-time-homebuyer.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Tina Caul</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-16 13:22:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Tina%20Caul/Greater%20Raleigh%20Real%20Estate-%203%20Things%20Every%20First-Time%20Homebuyer%20Should%20Know.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I want to share my three top tips to help first-time homebuyers protect themselves during this crucial period.

Buying your first home can be an incredibly exciting time. However, it requires a huge commitment and a sizable investment. That’s why I want to share my three top tips to help first-time homebuyers protect themselves during this crucial period:

1. Know what you can afford

Your mortgage is only a part of what you will need to pay when you buy a home. Homeownership comes with plenty of other expenses, including closing costs, taxes, property insurance, maintenance costs, and homeowner association fees.

Once you have a clear idea of how much all of these items will cost, you can compare it to your current monthly expenses. Then you can figure out the kind of home you can honestly afford without getting carried away and without getting bogged down in debt.

2. Choose your lender wisely

Choosing a lender is not something you should base only on the lowest rate. A competent and trustworthy lender will offer you advice on how to improve your credit and also help you take advantage of special homebuyer programs that might benefit you.

But how do you find the right lender specifically for you? It’s often best to get recommendations from friends who have already worked with a lender or from a real estate agent you trust.

3. Don’t overlook the details

There are many details that go into buying a home, and missing any of them can be a costly mistake. I always advise buyers to get a professional inspection done on their home, separate from the appraisal. An inspection will set you back about $300, but it can save you thousands of dollars down the line, and it can even prevent you from making a decision to buy a home that you would later regret.

A second example is understanding the fine print in the various contracts you will be signing. If there’s anything that isn’t clear to you, talk to your real estate agent and have it spelled out.

The process of buying a home can be intimidating, and that’s why professional real estate agents are there to help. These three quick tips are only the start of the things you need to watch out for when buying your first home.

If you need more advice or you are ready to start looking for a home, get in touch with me. I love working with first-time homebuyers, and I can help you get your perfect new home with minimum hassle.
</description>
        <enclosure url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Tina%20Caul/Greater%20Raleigh%20Real%20Estate-%203%20Things%20Every%20First-Time%20Homebuyer%20Should%20Know.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://raleighrealestatelife.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Tina%20Caul/Greater%20Raleigh%20Real%20Estate-%203%20Things%20Every%20First-Time%20Homebuyer%20Should%20Know.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today I want to share my three top tips to help first-time homebuyers protect themselves during this crucial period.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Tina Caul</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today I want to share my three top tips to help first-time homebuyers protect themselves during this crucial period.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Raleigh, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Have You Heard About This Lawsuit Filed Against Zillow?</title>
        <link>http://raleighrealestatelife.com/friends-and-ive-got-some-breaking-news.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Tina Caul</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-05 11:41:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Friends and Clients —

I’ve got some breaking news to share with you.

In case you haven’t heard already, a woman in Glenview, Illinois has filed a lawsuit against Zillow claiming that her Zestimate repeatedly undervalued her house and created a “tremendous roadblock” to its sale.

The lawsuit was filed in Cook County Circuit Court by real estate lawyer Barbara Andersen. You can get the full story from The Washington Post here, but I’ll summarize the main points for you now.

This suit may be the first of its kind. It says that, despite Zillow’s denial that they don’t offer “appraisals,” the fact that they “are promoted as a tool for potential buyers to use in assessing the market value of a given property,” shows that they meet the definition of an appraisal under Illinois state law.

It argues that Zillow should be licensed to perform appraisals before offering these estimates, while also obtaining “the consent of the homeowner” before they go online.

The Zestimate in question is for Ms. Andersen’s townhouse that she bought for $626,000 in 2009. It overlooks a golf course and is in a prime location, and she listed it on the market for roughly what she payed for it. However, the home’s most recent Zestimate was only $562,000. Ms. Andersen is suing for Zillow to either remove her Zestimate or amend it. She isn’t seeking monetary damages at the time, according to The Washington Post.

Zillow has a different take on the situation. They don’t see their Zestimates as appraisals but rather a tool that utilizes a proprietary formula to assess value, and they say as much on their website.

However, the accuracy of some of these estimates leaves much to be desired. They have a median error rate of 5%, which can translate to a lot of lost money on a home sale or a lot of money left on the table in a home purchase.

It will be interesting to see how this situation plays out. It might be a flash in the pan, but it might just be the start of something else entirely. We’ll be sure to keep you updated.

We also found &lt;a href=”http://abcnews.go.com/GMA/video/zillow-faces-lawsuit-zestimate-tool-47341951” target=”_blank&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; of Shark Tank star and New York real estate mogul Barbara Corcoran giving her thoughts on the lawsuit on “Good Morning America” that we think you might enjoy.

If you have any questions for me about this topic or anything else relating to real estate, give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.

Have a great day,

Tina Caul
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://raleighrealestatelife.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Friends and Clients —

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Tina Caul</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Friends and Clients —

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Raleigh, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Prepare Your Home for Sale With Pets</title>
        <link>http://raleighrealestatelife.com/how-to-prepare-your-home-for-sale-with.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Tina Caul</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-22 16:38:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Tina%20Caul/Greater%20Raleigh%20Real%20Estate-%20How%20to%20Prepare%20Your%20Home%20for%20Sale%20With%20Pets.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today, I’d like to show you a few steps you can take to help sell your home if you are a pet owner.

If you have a pet and you’re looking to sell your home, then read on for some helpful advice.

The good news is, many homebuyers are looking for a pet-friendly home.

Two out of three of us have a pet, and 61% of pet owners say they have trouble finding a home that is a good match for their pet.

In fact, a recent survey estimates that 31% of animal owners frequently don’t put in an offer because a home would not suit their pet.

This means that if your home is a good match for a pet, it will be attractive to a large pool of dedicated animal owners.

On the other hand, 67% of Realtors also estimate that actually having a pet in your home can make it harder for you to sell.

So what can you do? Here are three things I typically recommend:

1. Repair any damage

Floors, walls, doors, the yard — these are some typical areas that pets love to chew, scratch, and dig up.

Repairing this damage is an investment that will pay for itself many times over in terms of a higher selling price.

“PET OWNERS ARE LESS SENSITIVE TO ODORS IN THEIR HOME THAN PROSPECTIVE BUYERS ARE.”

2. Get a professional to remove pet odors

Many pet owners are less sensitive to odors in their home than prospective buyers will be.

That’s why you should hire a professional cleaning crew to clean any carpets, rugs, or upholstery that have absorbed pet odors.

Once you’re done with the cleaning, ask a friend or your Realtor for a sniff assessment to make sure the job is really complete.

3. Take your pet out during showings

Some people are afraid of animals. Others are allergic. And regardless of the time, money, and effort you’ve put in to clean and repair your home, many buyers will be prejudiced by knowing that a pet currently lives there.

That’s why I recommend taking your pet out during showings and also removing any pet objects such as toys, food bowls, or scratching posts.

By following these three simple guidelines, you will be able to sell your home for top dollar, whether the buyer is a pet owner or not.

If you’re curious what you could get for your home in the current market, check out my home value calculator on my site.

And in case you have any questions or concerns about preparing your home for a sale, give me a call. I’m here to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Tina%20Caul/Greater%20Raleigh%20Real%20Estate-%20How%20to%20Prepare%20Your%20Home%20for%20Sale%20With%20Pets.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://raleighrealestatelife.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Tina%20Caul/Greater%20Raleigh%20Real%20Estate-%20How%20to%20Prepare%20Your%20Home%20for%20Sale%20With%20Pets.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today, I’d like to show you a few steps you can take to help sell your home if you are a pet owner.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Tina Caul</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today, I’d like to show you a few steps you can take to help sell your home if you are a pet owner.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Raleigh, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 Ways to Mess Up a Home Purchase</title>
        <link>http://raleighrealestatelife.com/greater-raleigh-real-estate-5-ways-to.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Tina Caul</author>
        <pubDate>2016-09-30 13:46:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Tina%20Caul/Greater%20Raleigh%20Real%20Estate-%205%20Ways%20to%20Mess%20Up%20a%20Home%20Purchase%20%281%29.mp4</guid>
        <description>

A lot can go wrong when purchasing a home. We are giving you these five tips to help you avoid making simple mistakes.

There are so many different things to keep in mind when buying a home that buyers often forget a few of them. We want to help you avoid these if you’re thinking about purchasing, so here are five of the most common oversights we see buyers make:

“THIS IS NOT YOUR DAD’S REAL ESTATE MARKET.”

1. Not considering the home’s resale value. This is not your dad’s real estate market. Our market is transient, and people move in and out very quickly. You want to make sure the home you pick is appealing to a broad range of buyers down the line. Stay away from a home with a sauna or a barn. It may not appeal to the next buyer.

**2. Not factoring in expenses you’ll pay after the home closes.// Everybody is so focused on their monthly payments and closing costs, they forget about the additional costs that will inevitably occur when you move in. You may end up shelling out $10,000 or $15,000 in cash when you could have originally gotten a home that cost $10,000 or $15,000 more and not had to deal with any problems.

3. Not rooting out all restrictions. You want to make sure that you call the local municipalities and see what restrictions there are, if any, on the house.

4. Not checking if past work was up to code. Even if a homeowner has had a basement or attic finished by a professional contractor, they still need to have the proper permits. You don’t want to run into any issues here either.

5. Not getting the scoop on the HOA. Homeowners Associations are there to be supportive, but some are harder to deal with than others. Your agent can help you deal with certain restrictions and investigations.

We have a great team of buyer’s agents that would be happy to help you check off these boxes on your next home purchase. If you have any questions, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Tina%20Caul/Greater%20Raleigh%20Real%20Estate-%205%20Ways%20to%20Mess%20Up%20a%20Home%20Purchase%20%281%29.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://raleighrealestatelife.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Tina%20Caul/Greater%20Raleigh%20Real%20Estate-%205%20Ways%20to%20Mess%20Up%20a%20Home%20Purchase%20%281%29.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

A lot can go wrong when purchasing a home. We are giving you these five tips to help you avoid making simple mistakes.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Tina Caul</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

A lot can go wrong when purchasing a home. We are giving you these five tips to help you avoid making simple mistakes.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Raleigh, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Respond to Low Appraisals in the Raleigh Market</title>
        <link>http://raleighrealestatelife.com/how-to-respond-to-low-appraisals-in.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Tina Caul</author>
        <pubDate>2016-08-29 11:08:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

I wanted to talk today about low appraisals, what they mean, and how you should handle them.

With our market being as strong as it is, we sometimes see appraisals come in low. Since our market is strong, we have certain price points that have houses that receive multiple offers when they go on the market. This drives up the cost of those houses.

“YOU CAN CHALLENGE AN APPRAISAL IF YOUR AGENT BELIEVES IT IS WRONG.”

If the appraisal comes in low, there are four options you have to facilitate the deal:

1. Cancel the deal. Most of the time appraisals come back during your due diligence period, which means you can cancel the deal if the appraisal is shockingly low.

2. Put up more cash. If there were multiple offers on a property and the appraisal comes in $5,000 lower than the sale price and you absolutely still want this home, you can pay the difference in cash if the seller isn’t willing to lower the price.

3. Ask the seller to lower the price. Many times this is what happens in our market - the seller lowers the price because they know that if you don’t buy the house, the next buyer will likely have the same issue of a low appraisal. Similarly, you can change the terms of your loan. For example, maybe you can do a first and second mortgage with your lender, which could offset the difference.

4. Challenge the appraisal. We do this all the time. If the appraisal comes in low, we send it back to the appraiser and request that they look at comparable properties that they may have missed when assigning a value to the property. We’ve done this three times in the last month and got the deal done the way we wanted!

We will see a bit of softening in our market, but it is still a tremendous time to buy or sell. If you have any questions about buying or selling a home in the Raleigh area, give us a call or send us an email. We’d love to help you out.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://raleighrealestatelife.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

I wanted to talk today about low appraisals, what they mean, and how you should handle them.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Tina Caul</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

I wanted to talk today about low appraisals, what they mean, and how you should handle them.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Raleigh, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Four Questions You Should Ask Before Hiring a Raleigh Agent</title>
        <link>http://raleighrealestatelife.com/four-questions-you-should-ask-before.html</link>
        
          <category>Caul Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Tina Caul</author>
        <pubDate>2016-03-07 10:32:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today, I’ll go over four questions you need to ask when interviewing an agent to help you buy or sell a home.

“A good agent is available to their clients at all times.”

1. What is your experience? In the Triangle, we have about 5,000 real estate agents. The average agent sells 6 to 10 homes a year, but many agents sell even less than that. In our market, the top 50 agents sell the majority of homes. Last year, for instance, we sold 200 homes. You don’t want to hire a newer agent who will be practicing their skills on your property. You need an experienced professional to guide you through what is most likely the biggest transaction of your life.

2. What is your communication plan? A good agent is available to their clients at all times via phone, text, or email. Will this agent communicate rapidly with you? We have many references that show how actively we communicate with our clients.

3. Are you an active or passive agent? Active agents are aggressively looking for buyers and sellers each day. An active agent will be able to describe their plan for finding buyers for your property, or if you’re a buyer, they will have a plan to match you with the right property. Passive agents will put a sign in your yard, sit back, and hope and pray that somebody will show up. Don’t settle for a passive agent.

4. Do you have the right tools to sell my home? Do they have systems in place? Can they generate leads? Can the agent bring buyers to the property so that you will get offers? That’s exactly what you need to know. On our team, we have 151 steps from the time we list the home to the closing table that we do for every single one of our clients to ensure their success.

If you have any questions about today’s video, give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://raleighrealestatelife.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today, I’ll go over four questions you need to ask when interviewing an agent to help you buy or sell a home.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Tina Caul</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today, I’ll go over four questions you need to ask when interviewing an agent to help you buy or sell a home.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Raleigh, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Tina Caul</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Tina Caul</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Caul Real Estate Group - your professional Raleigh Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
