<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Greater Philadelphia Real Estate Podcast</title>
    <link>localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Scott Irvin and Associates - your professional Greater Philadelphia Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Scott Irvin</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2017-04-17 13:13:51 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Scott Irvin</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Greater Philadelphia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">News &amp; Politics</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Scott@ScottIrvin.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Scott Irvin</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Scott Irvin</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Greater Philadelphia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Greater Philadelphia Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Scott Irvin and Associates - your professional Greater Philadelphia Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="News &amp; Politics"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Is Our Real Estate Market Changing?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-is-our-real-estate-market-changing.html</link>
        
          <category>Philadelphia Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Scott Irvin</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-28 11:35:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

I’ve got a quick update for you. The spring market is upon us and inventory levels are still very low. That’s driving prices up in certain areas, as well as driving sales down.

From January to February of this year, sales dropped by about 3.7%. However, sale numbers are still 5.4% higher than they were at this point last year. Inventory is 6.4% lower than it was at this time last year.

Right now in the Northeast, we are seeing a sharp 13.8% decline in sales from last year due to this low level of inventory.

“First-time buyers make up a large portion of the market.”

First-time homebuyers make up a large segment of our market. Right now, they make up about 32% of buyers. In the price ranges they are looking in, mostly under $300,000, we are seeing multiple offers and bidding wars because there are not a lot of properties out there for those buyers to choose from.

Last year, we had about 1,600 homes on the market, but only have 1,100 on the market right now. If inventory continues to drop, prices will continue to go up.

If you have any questions for us about the market or about real estate in general, give me a call or send me an email today. I would love to hear from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>A lot can happen in a month in our real estate market, let alone a year. Here’s how things have changed.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Scott Irvin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>A lot can happen in a month in our real estate market, let alone a year. Here’s how things have changed.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Greater Philadelphia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Can You Keep Good Credit Health?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-can-you-keep-good-credit-health.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buying Tips</category>
        
        <author>Scott Irvin</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-13 13:18:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

How is your credit score determined? How can you keep yours healthy?

There are three different agencies that keep track of your credit score: Experian, Equifax, and TransUnion. Your credit score can vary between 300 and 850, which is a big difference in terms of minimum and maximum because each agency has a different minimum and maximum.

There are five different factors these agencies examine in determining your credit:


  Your payment history (if you’re paying on time, how often you pay, etc.).
  Your debt amount.
  The length of your credit history.
  The different types of credit you have.
  Your recent credit application history.


There are two different types of credit pulls you can have done on your credit report: a “hard” pull and a “soft” pull. A hard pull is when you apply for a loan and you have to give agencies permission for the pull. A soft pull is when they don’t need your permission. This leads to you getting solicitations in the mail about credit cards—the agencies do soft pulls to see what your risk factor is.

With a hard pull, if you apply for a car loan or a home mortgage and within a 45-day period have five or six different people pull that credit report on a hard loan, that doesn’t necessarily lower your score. If it does, it’s very minimal because they realize you’re shopping the rate around.

Your score can be different with the three core reporting agencies because not everyone reports to all three different agencies. They also have different algorithms they keep to determine and track your score. To keep good credit health, pay down your debt as much as possible, don’t use more than a third of your revolving credit on your credit cards, and pay on time.

“You should pull your credit report at least once a year.”

It’s always a good idea to pull your credit report at least once a year. It has no detrimental effect on your credit score and it allows you to see if there are any discrepancies on it and dispute them if so. If you elect to dispute any discrepancies, you’ll want to do so not only with the reporting agency but also the person or entity that reported the discrepancy.

If you have any questions about your credit score or have a topic in mind you’d like to see me discuss in a future video, please feel free to give us a call or shoot us an email. We’d be happy to speak with you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here are some facts you need to know about your credit score and how you can keep good credit health.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Scott Irvin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here are some facts you need to know about your credit score and how you can keep good credit health.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Greater Philadelphia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Zillow Can’t Provide an Accurate Home Estimate</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/why-zillow-cant-provide-accurate-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Zillow</category>
        
        <author>Scott Irvin</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-15 14:46:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

If you’re looking to sell your home, it’s important you understand the true value in order to price it for the market. Many people think using Zillow to guide their estimate is a good way to do that. I’ll go over how Zillow determines value and explain why their value estimates are not always realistic.

Zillow takes a computer-generated model and looks at the tax records and recent sales in the area. With that, a value for your home based on your tax records is generated. However, there are a couple flaws in that system.

For example, tax records can be incorrect, directly affecting the value estimate for your home. Additionally, Zillow doesn’t know about any upgrades you have done to your home. So, if you just put in a beautiful $50,000 patio area with a fireplace, Zillow won’t give you credit for that in their estimate.

“Zillow doesn’t take into account any upgrades you’ve done to your home.”

When we come out to take a look at a home, we not only look at the square footage and bedrooms but also at any upgrades that you’ve done. We will also look at if your home backs up to anything desirable like open space, or if you have refinished anything recently.

If you want to know the true value of your home, we can provide that for you. In fact, we have seen online estimates off by as much as 30%.

If you have any other questions or if you’d like us to come out and provide you with the true value of your home, please feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>In order to find the true value of your home, I would recommend skipping a Zillow estimate. Here’s why.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Scott Irvin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>In order to find the true value of your home, I would recommend skipping a Zillow estimate. Here’s why.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Greater Philadelphia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Building Wealth Through Homeownership</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/building-wealth-through-homeownership.html</link>
        
          <category>Homeownership Wealth</category>
        
        <author>Scott Irvin</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-27 13:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today I wanted to take a moment to talk about homeownership and building wealth.

The number one ingredient to this is price appreciation. This past year, we’ve seen about a 5.8% increase in values. Because of this, your home equity gets greater. The second ingredient is paying down your loan. This is done over time as you make payments; part of it goes to principal reduction.

Another way people do this is by refinancing their homes. With the equity built thanks to recent increases in appreciation, many homeowners are refinancing their home and going from a 30-year mortgage to a 15-year mortgage, allowing you to pay off that mortgage much quicker.

“Homeownership is the American dream.”

Homeownership is obviously the number one American Dream. CoreLogic recently did a study showed that any equity that’s 20% or greater equity in a home is significant equity, and the majority of people don’t think they have significant equity in their home. In reality, close to 73% of these people have significant equity in their home.

When necessary, you can use that home equity to take out a home equity line of credit. This is the difference between what is owed on your home and the value of your home—you can use this as a line of credit. You can use this loan for things like home improvements or your kids’ college.

If you’re interested in learning your home’s current value to get a better picture of your equity, give me a call or send me an email soon. I’d be more than happy to help you out in any way I can.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Homeownership is one of the most important tools Americans can use to build wealth. Today we’ll dive a little deeper into the ways you can pull this off.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Scott Irvin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Homeownership is one of the most important tools Americans can use to build wealth. Today we’ll dive a little deeper into the ways you can pull this off.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Greater Philadelphia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Where Is Our Market Heading in 2017?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/where-is-our-market-heading-in-2017.html</link>
        
          <category>Philadelphia Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Scott Irvin</author>
        <pubDate>2016-12-29 11:32:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today I wanted to talk about how our market has performed this year and where I think it’s going in 2017 based on some recent historical data.

The first statistic we look at is the average sale price. Year to date, our average sale price is $332,000. At the same point in 2015, that number was $327,000. Going all the way back to 2011, it was $311,000. As you can see, we’ve had some appreciation in this case, which is no surprise considering how good our market has been this year.

The next statistic we examine is our average days on market (or average days to sell). Currently, we’re running at about 67 days on market. In 2015, we were running at 71 days on market. In 2011, there were 99 days on market. This number continues to trend downward the further removed we get from the crash of 2008 and 2009.

Next, we look at months of inventory. This is what’s driving our prices and our interest rates. Currently, we only have three months of inventory, which is not a lot. In 2015, we had seven months of inventory. In 2011, we had a whole year’s worth.

Next, we look at sales. Year to date, we’ve had 7,398 homes sell, with about 466 to 500 pending sales, giving us an estimated final number of 7,844. In 2015, we had a total of about 7,689 sales. In 2011, there were 4,948 sales.

So, what do these disparities mean? Where are we going in 2017?

As we all know, the Federal Reserve met earlier in the month and increased interest rates again, so we should continue to see that number trend upward. Mortgage rates have risen from a low of about 3.5% earlier in the year to 4.25% now. That increase should balance out our inventory levels. If our inventory levels don’t increase, we’ll continue to see that price appreciation.

“Expect a slowdown in the year to come.”

However, next year, I think we’ll see a general slowdown in the market. We simply can’t continue at the pace we’ve gone over the past year. If you’re thinking about making a move in our market, now would be a good time to get ready for that.

If you’re thinking about buying or selling a home, we’d love for you to email us or give us a call so we can help you. In the meantime, have a happy holiday season and I hope we talk soon!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>In looking ahead to what our market holds for 2017, today I wanted to review our final year-end statistics and how they compare to years past.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Scott Irvin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>In looking ahead to what our market holds for 2017, today I wanted to review our final year-end statistics and how they compare to years past.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Greater Philadelphia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Benefits of Home Warranties</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/the-benefits-of-home-warranties.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Warranties</category>
        
        <author>Scott Irvin</author>
        <pubDate>2016-12-16 11:13:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Whether we’re representing buyers or sellers during a transaction, we always recommend getting a home warranty because it benefits both parties.

One of the biggest benefits for buyers is that it gives you peace of mind for that first year of homeownership. After that first year, whether you want to renew it or not is up to you. Rest assured, though, that if something goes wrong, if it’s covered under the home warranty (which a lot of things are), you’re going to be able to budget for it because you’ll only need to pay the deductible.

The benefits for sellers are more numerous. For one thing, getting a home warranty guarantees that the buyer isn’t going to come back and try to pawn off another repair cost after they’ve already settled on the home. They can also purchase a home warranty for the buyer if it’s negotiated that way.

In addition, home warranties are a great selling point because buyers don’t have to purchase one on their own. Sellers can then opt to have coverage during the time period between when they go under contract to when they close if anything should go wrong then.

“Home warranties are both a selling point and a negotiating tool.”

Finally, home warranties are a great negotiating tool. If the inspection is done and the inspector declares that some appliance is at the end of its useful life, for example, you can offer the buyer a home warranty instead of negotiating a price for that item.

Though there are many different companies throughout the U.S. that offer home warranties, each company only covers certain regions or states. Only certain warranties can be bought in particular states. In our area, the primary home warranty companies are First American and American Home Shield. Both of them have their advantages and disadvantages. Which company is best for you depends on what type of coverage you’re looking for and the price and value you want to get out of that.

If you’re thinking about buying or selling a home, please call or email me today for a free real estate consultation. I look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Home warranties are beneficial to both buyers and sellers because they guarantee many things.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Scott Irvin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Home warranties are beneficial to both buyers and sellers because they guarantee many things.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Greater Philadelphia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Can You Reduce Your Mortgage Term?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-can-you-reduce-your-mortgage-term.html</link>
        
          <category>Reducing a Mortgage Term</category>
        
        <author>Scott Irvin</author>
        <pubDate>2016-12-05 10:32:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Everyone wants to know what the rate of a mortgage is and what the terms of that mortgage would be when purchasing a home. However, there are some things you can look at after you buy a home and consider before getting that mortgage.

One of these things is the length of the mortgage. Most buyers opt for a 30-year mortgage because of the cheaper payments. The other option is a 15-year mortgage, which you could pay off in half the time, but that would require much higher payments to do so.

How can you split the difference and reduce the length of a 30-year mortgage down to 22 years?

One simple way of doing it is making one extra payment per year. If you’re making 12 monthly payments, then, you would make 13 for the year. You can also divide those payments over 12 months. For example, if your mortgage is $2,400 a month, you’re going to need to pay an extra $2,400 for the year, so each month would require an extra $200.

“You will save thousands of dollars in the long run.”

This will make a significant difference and save you tens of thousands of dollars in the long run. If you don’t have it in your budget to spare the extra payment for a particular month, you could always just make it up the next month. You’re not obligated to make those payments like you would be in a 15-year mortgage.

If you have any questions on this topic, please feel free to give me a call or shoot me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>You can reduce a 30-year mortgage term down to 22 years without using a lender. All you have to do is make one extra payment per year.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Scott Irvin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>You can reduce a 30-year mortgage term down to 22 years without using a lender. All you have to do is make one extra payment per year.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Greater Philadelphia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Fall Is Actually a Great Time to Sell</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/why-fall-is-actually-great-time-to-sell.html</link>
        
          <category>Selling in the Fall</category>
        
        <author>Scott Irvin</author>
        <pubDate>2016-11-10 12:22:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

The number one question I get from potential sellers this time of year is, “Should I list my home?” It’s a very good question from sellers who are considering selling in the fall but aren’t sure about the time of year. A lot of sellers want to wait until spring because they believe it’s a better time to sell.

If we look at inventory levels over the year, spring has the highest level of inventory and the most homes sold. However, if we look at the number of homes sold versus the number of homes on the market, both fall and winter are very good times to sell. If you wait until spring, you’re just like everyone else waiting until spring. When that spring market comes around, there is a lot of competition on the market.

You have to look at your own personal situation and decide what works best for you. The best thing about the fall market is that there is less inventory, so there is less competition. Also remember that if you’re selling in the wintertime, you want to have someone come out and take photographs of your home ahead of time so you don’t have to worry about it in the winter. You don’t want snow on the ground in your photos, but you do want the beautiful leaves and colors that you can get this time of year.

Timing the housing market is just like timing the financial market–usually it doesn’t work. Buying low and selling high is not something most people can do outside of a few professionals who do it day in and day out. The same goes for housing, which is why you really need to look at what works best for your situation. If now is the time to do that, know that during this time of the year, you’ll be facing less competition.

“Ultimately, you have to look at your own personal situation.”

The other good thing about selling this time of year is that the buyers out looking right now are much more serious buyers. In the spring market, we get a lot of buyers out kicking tires, so you get a higher quantity of showings, but not as high of quality of showings like you do this time of year.

It’s a good time to put your house on the market not just because of the decreased competition, but also because the numbers show that houses sell for a very good price.

If you have any questions about buying or selling a home this time of year or you’re not sure whether your situation merits looking into selling in the fall, give me a call or send me an email. I’d love to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>A lot of sellers out there have been asking me whether it's wise to sell a house during the fall and winter months. Today we're talking about why it might be a great option.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Scott Irvin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>A lot of sellers out there have been asking me whether it's wise to sell a house during the fall and winter months. Today we're talking about why it might be a great option.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Greater Philadelphia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Your Resource for Real Estate Needs</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/your-resource-for-real-estate-needs.html</link>
        
          <category>real estate</category>
        
        <author>Scott Irvin</author>
        <pubDate>2016-10-11 18:56:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

On my blog &amp; YouTube channel, you’ll find tips for both buyers and sellers in the real estate market, as well as updates on what’s happening in our local market. The real estate market affects all of us!

I really want this page to be a valuable resource for you. If you have any questions about our market or about real estate in general, send me an email. Odds are good that if you have a question about a topic, someone else does as well, so send your questions my way and we’ll make an educational video.

Take a look around - I look forward to hearing from you soon!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>I’d like to welcome you to my new YouTube Channel.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Scott Irvin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>I’d like to welcome you to my new YouTube Channel.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Greater Philadelphia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Scott Irvin</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Scott Irvin</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Scott Irvin and Associates - your professional Greater Philadelphia Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
