<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Greater Toronto Group - Podcast about Real Estate</title>
    <link>http://yyzrealestateblog.com</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://yyzrealestateblog.com"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Greater Toronto Group - your professional Toronto Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>David Morrell</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2017-04-27 16:47:47 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>David Morrell</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://yyzrealestateblog.com/img/Toronto_podcast.png"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Toronto, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">News &amp; Politics</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>office@greatertorontogroup.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>David Morrell</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>David Morrell</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://yyzrealestateblog.com/img/Toronto_podcast.png"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Toronto, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Toronto Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Greater Toronto Group - your professional Toronto Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="News &amp; Politics"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>This Program Will Assist You With Your Down Payment</title>
        <link>http://yyzrealestateblog.com/this-program-will-assist-you-with-your-down-payment.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>David Morrell</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-11 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greater+Toronto+Group/Greater+Toronto+Group-+Great+news+for+would-be+homebuyers.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Are you one of the many people putting off buying a home due to the lack of finances for a down payment? If so, I have some great news.

There’s a new program designed to assist buyers by getting them into a home for little to no money down.

There’s actually a new report that details exactly how this program will help you buy a home called “How to Buy a Home With Little or No Money Down.”

“There’s great news for would-be homebuyers who lack the funds for a down payment.”

To get all the details on this program and find out how you can purchase a home without a large down payment, order a copy of the report today by going to www.littleornocashdown.com

If you have any other questions, please don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greater+Toronto+Group/Greater+Toronto+Group-+Great+news+for+would-be+homebuyers.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://yyzrealestateblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greater+Toronto+Group/Greater+Toronto+Group-+Great+news+for+would-be+homebuyers.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you lack the funds for a down payment but still want to buy a home, I’ve got some great news.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>David Morrell</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you lack the funds for a down payment but still want to buy a home, I’ve got some great news.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Toronto, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Should You Buy a New Home or an Existing Property?</title>
        <link>http://yyzrealestateblog.com/should-you-buy-a-new-home-or-an-existing-property.html</link>
        
          <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>David Morrell</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-16 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greater+Toronto+Group/Greater+Toronto+Group-+Should+You+Buy+a+New+Home+or+an+Existing+Property.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Are you considering buying a home? If so, you might be trying to decide between buying a new home or a resale home. Luckily, there are 10 secrets to homebuying that will help you make a decision. 

Most homes on the market are resales, but one out of every four homebuyers chooses to purchase a new home. Both new homes and resale homes offer different advantages. 

Resale homes are often cheaper and are already in established neighborhoods. New homes offer modern energy efficiency, innovative uses of space, and different options for upgrades. Everything is new, including the neighbors. 

“The 10 secrets every new homebuyer should know will help you decide which type of home is right for you.”

Determining which choice is best for you will depend on many factors including your taste, your family, and your finances. 

Fortunately, a new, special report has just been released identifying 10 secrets every new homebuyer should know. The report includes little-known buyer advantages that most builders won’t divulge unless pressed. You can order the report and be on your way to deciding if a new or resale home is right for you by clicking here.  

If you are looking to buy or sell a home, or if you have any other real estate questions, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you! 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greater+Toronto+Group/Greater+Toronto+Group-+Should+You+Buy+a+New+Home+or+an+Existing+Property.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://yyzrealestateblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greater+Toronto+Group/Greater+Toronto+Group-+Should+You+Buy+a+New+Home+or+an+Existing+Property.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re looking to purchase a home, you might be wondering if you should buy new or go with a resale home. There’s actually a special report that will help you make that decision.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>David Morrell</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re looking to purchase a home, you might be wondering if you should buy new or go with a resale home. There’s actually a special report that will help you make that decision.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Toronto, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Our Hot List for First-Time Homebuyers</title>
        <link>http://yyzrealestateblog.com/our-hot-list-for-first-time-homebuyers.html</link>
        
          <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>David Morrell</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-01 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greater+Toronto+Group/Greater+Toronto+Group-+How+our+hot+list+can+improve+your+home+search.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Are you a first-time homebuyer?

You’ve probably noticed that affordable homes in desirable neighborhoods sell very quickly. Timing is incredibly important. If you want to buy your first home, then you need to be ready to act right away, especially in this market.

Our hot list of first-time buyer homes will give you the advanced information that you need to be prepared.

“The hot list gives you a huge advantage over other buyers in the market.”

You will receive a free report with photos which identifies the best buys on the market for first-time buyers. The list will feature homes in your desired price range and location.

The hot list uses a simple, efficient format to provide you key information at no extra cost or obligation. This list will give you a huge advantage over other buyers in the market.

To get your list, go to buyershotlist.net and enter your criteria.

If you have any questions, please don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greater+Toronto+Group/Greater+Toronto+Group-+How+our+hot+list+can+improve+your+home+search.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://yyzrealestateblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greater+Toronto+Group/Greater+Toronto+Group-+How+our+hot+list+can+improve+your+home+search.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you are a first-time homebuyer, the current market might seem intimidating, as homes are selling quickly. We have a tool to help you be successful in this competitive market.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>David Morrell</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you are a first-time homebuyer, the current market might seem intimidating, as homes are selling quickly. We have a tool to help you be successful in this competitive market.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Toronto, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Get Your Agent Working 2x Harder</title>
        <link>http://yyzrealestateblog.com/how-to-get-your-agent-working-2x-harder.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>David Morrell</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-06 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greater+Toronto+Group/Greater+Toronto+Group-+The+advantages+of+a+real+estate+team.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The fact is, there isn’t much more to the average agent than the agent themselves. Most agents operate a one-person show and they are probably breaking their backs trying to do a good job for their clients. Most agents couldn’t work harder than they already are.

Sometimes, clients can actually suffer from their agent’s good intentions. The fact is, you may be sympathetic to the fact that your agent is working as hard as humanly possible, but if the quality and profitability of your home sale suffers as a result of them trying to do everything themselves, you have the right to feel cheated.

The simple explanation is that we have built a team of professionals to help us be in 10 places at once, greatly enhancing the quality of service we can deliver to our clients. This is how other professionals like your banks and lawyers run their businesses. On top of that, we have used cutting-edge technology to dramatically improve the speed, efficiency, and innovative capabilities of every part of the service we deliver.

“Our team sells a lot of homes.”

We don’t expect you to care about the fine details of the inner-workings of our office. What you should care about is simply that because of the highly unique way we have structured our real estate office, our clients’ homes sell for more money in less time.

Our team sells a lot of homes. We have extensive home selling experience that puts more money in our clients’ pockets. To find out more about how our team approach can make you more successful in the real estate market, simply visit www.getmorewithus.ca and fill out the form. We’ll be in touch!

If you have any questions for us, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We would love to hear from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greater+Toronto+Group/Greater+Toronto+Group-+The+advantages+of+a+real+estate+team.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://yyzrealestateblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greater+Toronto+Group/Greater+Toronto+Group-+The+advantages+of+a+real+estate+team.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>How do we sell our clients’ homes for more money than the average agent? It all comes down to our team structure.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>David Morrell</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>How do we sell our clients’ homes for more money than the average agent? It all comes down to our team structure.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Toronto, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mortgage Brokers vs. Bank Mortgages</title>
        <link>http://yyzrealestateblog.com/mortgage-brokers-vs-bank-mortgages.html</link>
        
          <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>David Morrell</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-10 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greater+Toronto+Group/Greater+Toronto+Group%3D+Are+mortgages+better+from+a+bank+or+a+broker.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What’s the difference between obtaining your mortgage through a mortgage broker and getting a mortgage through your bank?

Getting approved and getting the best possible mortgage is a large component of buying real estate, and I find that many people don’t know the difference between these two. I wanted to clear the air for you on this topic today.

What is a mortgage broker? Here at the Greater Toronto Group, we have partnered with specific mortgage brokers who are the in the top 1% in Canada. These are people we know we can trust who can provide some very specific products to our clients. They have strategic wholesale lending rates, which can save you thousands of dollars. Additionally, they are not owned by the lenders they represent. This means they represent you specifically and are in your corner during the process.

Another cool fact about these lenders is that they have special software that allows them to scan all the lenders for the best rates and terms for you, the buyer. In seconds, they can shop for the best mortgage opportunity for you without you having to do any extra work.

“Brokers can scan all lenders in seconds to find you the best rate possible.”

I also have clients who decide to work with their bank, and I get that. It can be convenient to have all of your accounts and mortgage at one branch. However, be aware that your bank can only provide you mortgage options that they already offer. In fact, I once had a mortgage broker assist my client, and the broker got them a better mortgage than the client themselves could get at their own bank

It’s kind of silly, but it’s important to see all options rather than just one.

I like to think of the difference between getting a mortgage from a mortgage broker and a bank this way: a mortgage broker is a huge wine store with every brand and type of wine selection available and a staff that gives opinions, insight, and recommendations, as well as points out which ones are on sale or are of good value. A bank, in this example, would be like going to a wine store with just one wine available. The horror! Then, they try to convince you that this one kind of wine is the best and that you should buy it.

If you have any questions or you’re interested in meeting with a mortgage broker, contact me to speak with one of these amazing individuals. Remember to do your homework and get all information before making any decision.

If you have any questions about the home buying process, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greater+Toronto+Group/Greater+Toronto+Group%3D+Are+mortgages+better+from+a+bank+or+a+broker.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://yyzrealestateblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greater+Toronto+Group/Greater+Toronto+Group%3D+Are+mortgages+better+from+a+bank+or+a+broker.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today we’re breaking down the difference between getting a mortgage through a broker versus getting one through your local bank.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>David Morrell</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today we’re breaking down the difference between getting a mortgage through a broker versus getting one through your local bank.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Toronto, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Get the Highest Sale Price for Your Toronto Home</title>
        <link>http://yyzrealestateblog.com/how-to-get-the-highest-sale-price-for-your-toronto-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>David Morrell</author>
        <pubDate>2016-11-30 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greater+Toronto+Group/Greater+Toronto+Group-How+to+negotiate+your+home%E2%80%99s+best+price.mp4</guid>
        <description>

For most people, “getting top dollar” is number one on their list of goals when selling their home. These same people, however, feel ill-equipped to achieve this goal. Since various market factors can cause large swings, pricing a home is an imperfect science to begin with, and the skill of the person responsible for negotiating for the home can also impact the outcome of the transaction.

However, negotiating effectively doesn’t have to be as difficult or scary as you would expect. Like anything else, if you have a proven system to follow and know the signals and language, you can successfully turn the tables in your favor. Who better to borrow these skills from than professional negotiators who daily sit across the table to try to out-bargain their opponents?

“The art of negotiation doesn’t have to be difficult or scary.”

The system we follow as professionals is outlined in a new, free special report for home sellers that explains the four most common mistakes sellers make when negotiating the sale price of their home. One local area resident credits the knowledge gained from the information revealed in this free special report with netting thousands more than their original asking price.

To get this report, visit www.mostmoney.ca and find out how you can get the highest possible price when you sell your home.

If you’re thinking of buying or selling a home, call us, email us, or visit our website today. Remember—if real estate is an art, we’re Banksy!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greater+Toronto+Group/Greater+Toronto+Group-How+to+negotiate+your+home%E2%80%99s+best+price.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://yyzrealestateblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greater+Toronto+Group/Greater+Toronto+Group-How+to+negotiate+your+home%E2%80%99s+best+price.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Negotiating the highest possible sale price for your home isn’t as difficult as you think. We have a proven system to share with you that can help you achieve this goal.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>David Morrell</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Negotiating the highest possible sale price for your home isn’t as difficult as you think. We have a proven system to share with you that can help you achieve this goal.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Toronto, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>David Morrell</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">David Morrell</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Greater Toronto Group - your professional Toronto Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
