<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Mansfield Real Estate Video Blog</title>
    <link>localhost:5000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="localhost:5000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Teixeira Realty Group - your professional Mansfield Area Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>John Teixeira</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2016-11-23 13:49:27 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>John Teixeira</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="localhost:5000"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">News &amp; Politics</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>northtexasre@sbcglobal.net</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>John Teixeira</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>John Teixeira</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="localhost:5000"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Mansfield Area Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Teixeira Realty Group - your professional Mansfield Area Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="News &amp; Politics"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>Don’t Wait Until After the Election to Sell</title>
        <link>localhost:5000/6-reasons-to-consider-selling-now-27.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Updates</category>
        
        <author>John Teixeira</author>
        <pubDate>2016-10-05 12:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Many potential home sellers have been worried about the uncertainties in the housing market in the face of the upcoming presidential election.

A lot of them want to wait until the election is over to sell, but that would be a mistake. It’s a great time to sell right now because of all the advantages in the marketplace. Here are six reasons why you shouldn’t wait until after the election to sell:


  
    It doesn’t matter who the next president is. What I mean by this is that the world will continue to spin and people will continue to buy and sell real estate regardless of who is elected to office.
  
  Real estate will still be one of the best ways to build wealth. Again, this is true no matter who wins the election. Real estate is always going to be one of the wisest investments to make.
“No matter who wins, the world will keep turning.”
  
    Inventory will continue to constrict because of uncertainty. Most people will decide to take their homes off the market until after the election. This will help you stand out more if you list your home right now. There is a higher concentration of serious buyers in the market who will see your home.
  
  
    Serious buyers want to move before the holidays. A lot of buyers in the market right now have been looking for months. Many weren’t able to get a home in the highly competitive market this spring and summer, so they have a sense of urgency in wanting to get a deal done.
  
  
    Many relocation buyers are looking now. Most corporate relocations take place at the beginning of the year. The families that are being relocated are looking for homes right now and checking out the areas that they want to live in. This is another pool of buyers that will see your home stand out.
  
  Interest rates are at historic lows. You’re probably sick of hearing it at this point, but it’s still true. Interest rates can only go up now, and we want you to be able to capture the buyers that are out there right now.


If you have any questions for us or are interested in buying or selling a home, we would love to hear from you. It’s a good time to make a move right now.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:5000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Mansfield Area Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>John Teixeira</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Many home sellers are waiting until after the presidential election to list. By selling now, you can take advantage of the trends they are missing out on.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Mortgage Rates Are So Low Right Now</title>
        <link>localhost:5000/why-mortgage-rates-are-so-low-right-now-26.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>John Teixeira</author>
        <pubDate>2016-09-15 14:16:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

It’s not very nice to profit from your neighbors’ troubles. Sometimes, though, there’s simply nothing you can do to stop it.

At the beginning of the summer, as I’m sure you have heard, the UK voted to leave the EU. This became known as “Brexit,” and it has created heaps of uncertainty and worry for our neighbors across the Atlantic.

Here in the U.S., though, Brexit has been nothing but good news for the real estate market. Because of Brexit, investors all over the world wanted a safer place to invest, and this pushed already low mortgage rates down even further to almost unseen lows.

In fact, we are now in the middle of the second-longest run of cheap mortgage rates in history. The 30-year fixed rate mortgage is 3.46%; this is only a few points above its all-time low of 3.31%.

What does this mean for you?

First, if you are looking to buy a home, now is an unusually good time to do so because these low rates mean you will be paying less. As an example, taking out a 30-year, $250,000 mortgage today versus a year ago (when the rate was 3.91%) would mean that you would save more than $25,000 over the lifetime of the loan.

The other way to look at it is that at today’s rates, you can afford a more luxurious home without paying more. For example, if you were to take out a 30-year mortgage, you could now afford $15,000 more for a home than a year ago while keeping the same monthly payments.

Clearly, this is a great opportunity.
“Here in the U.S., Brexit has been nothing but good news for mrtgage rates.”
Now, if you are looking to sell rather than buy, these low rates also benefit you big time. The more the mortgage rates drop, the more buyers there are, and the greater the demand is for homes.

This healthy demand keeps up the price of your home and ensures your home will get sold quickly. Not surprisingly, pending home sales are up by 1.3% this summer and are now at the second-highest level in over a decade.

As you can imagine, these ultra-low mortgage rates won’t last forever and will rise sooner or later.

If you are looking to take advantage of this unique situation while it lasts, give me a call or send me an email. I’m always here to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:5000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Mansfield Area Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>John Teixeira</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Why are interest rates so low right now? Global economics have made American real estate a great haven for investments, so rates have dropped.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Fall Is a Great Time to Sell in Mansfield</title>
        <link>localhost:5000/why-fall-is-great-time-to-sell-home-25.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>John Teixeira</author>
        <pubDate>2016-09-15 14:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today I wanted to talk about why the fall is such a great time to sell your home.

Sometimes, it really pays to go against the crowd.

As you probably know, spring is the season when most people around Mansfield put their homes on the market. Summer is the high season, and it’s when most homes get sold. And yet, there are a few powerful reasons why fall might actually be a better time than either spring or summer to sell your home.

It makes perfect sense when you think about it.

By the fall, the bulk of spring listings are expiring. As a result, there is less competition, particularly when you consider the NEW label and the fewer days on the market that your listing will boast. Also, home buyers in the fall are more serious. They have been looking at listings for months, and they are eager to conclude their search and move in comfortably before the holidays.

“It makes perfect sense when you think about it.”

When you put those two things together, you get that homes listed in the fall sell more quickly and often command a higher price. In fact, fall is the season with the highest percentage of sold listings, beating out summer by 1%.

Now, if you are thinking of selling your home this fall, there are a few things you have to do differently.

First, you have to prepare your home to account for the particular fall conditions. For example, you need to check the HVAC system and replace your furnace filter so your home will be warm and smell fresh. Also, make sure to turn on all the lights; you’ve got to compensate for the shorter, cloudier days. Cleaning up the yard is also a must.

The second thing you need to do is price your home appropriately. To get started, check out the value calculator I created that takes into account recent Mansfield sales to give you an idea of what your home is worth right now.

Once you have an idea of what your home is worth, how should you price it? On the one hand, the fall is not a good time to start with a sky-high price. If you don’t sell right away, you might not have time to adjust the price because of the smaller number of buyers and the shorter selling period (nobody wants to move over Christmas).

On the other hand, those serious buyers I mentioned earlier might be willing to pay more simply because they’ve been looking longer and are more eager to buy.

It’s a balancing act. It’s also something I can definitely help you with. Give me a call if you are considering selling this fall, and I’ll give you my recommendations on how to price your home based on current conditions in Mansfield.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:5000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Mansfield Area Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>John Teixeira</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Contrary to popular belief, the fall is actually a great time to sell a home. You may not see as many buyers as you would in the spring and summer, but you can be sure that fall buyers are more serious.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Which Updates Will Help Sell Your Mansfield Home? </title>
        <link>localhost:5000/the-dos-and-donts-of-home-renovations-24.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>John Teixeira</author>
        <pubDate>2016-09-08 11:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

If you are considering selling your home in the near future, you are probably planning on making a few renovations. However, some renovations are more appealing to buyers than others.

These improvements will actually deter buyers when it comes time to sell your home:


  Too much wallpaper. Buyers don’t want to tear down a bunch of wallpaper in order to paint; they want the walls ready for painting when they move in.
  Lavish lighting fixtures. You might have a different sense of style than the buyers, so keep it simple when it comes to the lighting fixtures.
  Textured walls, wall coverings, and ceilings. Many times, people think they are adding value with different DIY textures when, really, they put up too much. You should also avoid murals, permanent wall coverings, or cute ceiling decals that may damage the walls.
  The wrong kind of flooring. Flooring is expensive to replace and the wrong kind of flooring will be detrimental to your home sale. Buyers want plain, neutral decor when they move in.
  Too much carpet. Carpet holds dirt and shows traffic patterns. Most buyers do not want to see that everywhere.
  Bold wall colors. Remember, bright, loud colors are bad; neutral, soft colors are good.
  
    Swimming pools and hot tubs. You may enjoy a pool or hot tub but most buyers don’t want to deal with or pay for the maintenance.
“Keep the decor light, soft, and neutral.”
That said, other renovations will add value to your home and net you more money when it comes time to sell. The top four renovations to make when selling your home are:
  
  Renovating your kitchen. Buyers love to see updated kitchens. However, keep in mind that if you spend more than $20,000 on the renovation, you’re not likely to get all of that money back.
  Bathroom renovations. Everyone likes to have a large, luxurious master bathroom, and buyers will pay extra for an updated bathroom.
  New flooring. You probably can’t clean your carpet well enough to make people think that it’s new; instead, bring in new carpeting or tile. New flooring is a great way to add value and that new carpet smell will give buyers peace of mind.
  Curb appeal. When buyers drive past your home, you need to make sure your property makes a good first impression. Plant flowers, trim bushes, and pull weeds. The more organized and orderly your lawn is, the more appealing your home will be to buyers.


Now, this one is not on the list, but it’s incredibly important not to forget the backyard.

People want to see a yard that they can entertain friends in. A cluttered and unkempt backyard tells the buyer that you don’t take care of your home; a well-cared for backyard with trimmed trees, weeded flower beds, and trimmed grass tells buyers the opposite.

If you have any questions about getting your home ready for the market or about real estate in general, give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:5000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Mansfield Area Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>John Teixeira</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you are considering selling your home in the near future, you are probably planning on making a few renovations. However, some renovations are more appealing to buyers than others.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>8 Inexpensive Tips to Add Value to Your Bathroom</title>
        <link>localhost:5000/tips-for-updating-your-bathroom-23.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>John Teixeira</author>
        <pubDate>2016-08-11 11:58:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

It’s commonly known that kitchens and bathrooms sell homes. Making improvements to your bathroom, therefore, is one of the best ways to create value to your home if you’re considering selling in the future. Here are eight inexpensive ways to do just that:


  Paint: As is the case with any room in the house, painting is the best way to update your bathroom. Due to the room’s small space, it’s important to use a neutral color.
  Paint the vanity mirror. If nothing else needs to be painted, you might consider painting the vanity mirror to contrast the rest of the room.
  Replace the vanity mirror.
  Update the flooring. Stay away from carpet and laminate floors. If you’re going to do it yourself, there are some great products out there with vinyl flooring that are easy enough to install, but please at least consider hiring a professional for the job. Adding a rug can also accent the room well.
  Change the showerhead. If you haven’t modernized the showerhead in some time, go down to your local home improvement store and consider the variety of inexpensive options you can choose from.
  Add shelving. If there is any place to add shelving, especially if there is storage needed, don’t hesitate to do so. It’s a nice place to put colorful towels, baskets, and other accents to the room as a whole.
  Cover any problem walls. If you have areas on any wall that are showing past damage, or or just have too many white walls, find a solution for them. Even if you have to hire a contractor to come out and retexture, it will be worth it.
  Change the lighting. Much like the showerheads, you have a surplus of options in how you would like to replace and update your bathroom’s lighting fixtures. Make sure you choose the right bulbs so the light works well with however much natural light you have coming in already.


If you have any questions, or have plans to buy or sell a home in the near future, please don’t hesitate to give us a call or send an email.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:5000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Mansfield Area Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>John Teixeira</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

It’s commonly known that kitchens and bathrooms sell homes. Making improvements to your bathroom, therefore, is one of the best ways to create value to your home if you’re considering selling in the future. Here are eight inexpensive ways to do just that:

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>An Update on the Summer Real Estate Market in Mansfield</title>
        <link>localhost:5000/this-is-what-were-seeing-in-mansfield-22.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>John Teixeira</author>
        <pubDate>2016-08-11 11:16:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

The latest numbers are in for the Mansfield real estate market, so we wanted to share them with you. We’ll compare them to the figures we saw at this time last year to show how the market has changed in the past year.

The median house price in Mansfield has remained the same since June 2015 at $247,500. When we look at homes that were listed on the market, 25% of homes were listed under $200,000, 72% of homes were listed between $200,000 and $500,000. The rest of them were over $500,000.
“Demand is strong in our market.”
Active listings in Mansfield are down 12.3% from last year, which doesn’t help our inventory problem. Despite that, the number of homes sold is up 21.7% over last year, which shows strong demand in our market.
DEMAND IS STRONG IN OUR MARKET.
Our average days on market are 26 days, six days fewer than last year. We have only 1.8 months of inventory, down from 2.3 months last year.

If you have any questions for us or are considering buying or selling a home, give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help in any way we can.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:5000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Mansfield Area Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>John Teixeira</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

The latest numbers are in for the Mansfield real estate market, so we wanted to share them with you. We’ll compare them to the figures we saw at this time last year to show how the market has changed in the past year.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Arlington Real Estate Market Update</title>
        <link>localhost:5000/arlington-real-estate-market-update-21.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>John Teixeira</author>
        <pubDate>2016-08-11 10:52:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Let’s review some numbers from June 2016 and see how they compare to June 2015:


  In that time, the median home price has gone up 8% to $178,000.
  Much like our surrounding areas, our active listings in the area are down 15.4%.
  With 443 homes sold, our active listings are up 5%.
  The average days on market is 26 days, a decrease of two from last year.
  Our inventory level has gone down from 1.8 months to 1.4 months.


“The median home price has gome up 8% to $178,000.”
That’s it for our Arlington housing report. If you have any questions about real estate, or are looking to buy or sell a home, give us a call soon. We guarantee service, experience, and teamwork.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:5000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Mansfield Area Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>John Teixeira</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Let’s review some numbers from June 2016 and see how they compare to June 2015:

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Introducing Our Newest Listing With Some Free Tacos</title>
        <link>localhost:5000/open-house-featuring-free-tacos-20.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>John Teixeira</author>
        <pubDate>2016-08-05 12:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

We’re here today to introduce our newest listing at 4407 Meadow Knoll Lane in Mansfield, Texas. It’s a beautiful home featuring four bedrooms, three living rooms, and three full bathrooms built inside its nearly 3,100 sq ft area. Tucked within the Meadow Glen subdivision, the neighborhood is great for raising a family. Nearby you can find community parks, pools, playgrounds, and Lake Ridge High School.

“The neighborhood is great for raising a family in.”

We’d love to have you come check it out for yourself at our open house this Saturday, August 6th, from 1 p.m. to 3 p.m. Since we ran out of pizza, this time we’ll be serving free tacos. Who doesn’t like free tacos?
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:5000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Mansfield Area Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>John Teixeira</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

We’re here today to introduce our newest listing at 4407 Meadow Knoll Lane in Mansfield, Texas. It’s a beautiful home featuring four bedrooms, three living rooms, and three full bathrooms built inside its nearly 3,100 sq ft area. Tucked within the Meadow Glen subdivision, the neighborhood is great for raising a family. Nearby you can find community parks, pools, playgrounds, and Lake Ridge High School.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Introducing Our Newest Listing in South Arlington</title>
        <link>localhost:5000/open-house-in-south-arlington-19.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>John Teixeira</author>
        <pubDate>2016-08-01 13:02:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today we want to introduce our newest listing here at 6406 Berlinetta Drive. It’s a beautiful corner lot with a 3-bedroom home in South Arlington measuring almost 1,900 square feet.

“At a price of $170,000 in South Arlington, you can’t beat that deal.”
 The location falls under the esteemed jurisdiction of the Mansfield school district. The outside features an enormous backyard that’s adjoined by a covered patio. The inside features a floor plan that is somewhat open with a large living space that leads into a spacious dining room. It’s a house that’s great for entertaining guests, and for the price of $175,000 in South Arlington, you can’t beat that deal.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:5000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Mansfield Area Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>John Teixeira</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today we want to introduce our newest listing here at 6406 Berlinetta Drive. It’s a beautiful corner lot with a 3-bedroom home in South Arlington measuring almost 1,900 square feet.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Don’t Miss This Beautiful Listing in Mira Lagos</title>
        <link>localhost:5000/get-sneak-peek-before-next-open-house-18.html</link>
        
        <author>John Teixeira</author>
        <pubDate>2016-07-21 14:24:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

We’re here at our new listing, 2927 Mirado Drive. Located in Mira Lagos, this beautiful, 3,100 square foot home features four bedrooms, two bedrooms, a game room, and a gorgeous open floor plan.

There are also great schools nearby, such as ISD, Cora Spencer, Mary Lillard, and Danny Jones. The property is also close to Lake Ridge High School, which is the most requested school district in Mansfield right now.

Mira Lagos is a beautiful community complete with walking trails, community fishing ponds, a clubhouse with a swimming pool, playgrounds, soccer fields - everything you want in a master plan community is here. Joe Pool Lake is nearby as well, so your family will never run out of fun activities to do!

“Mira Lagos is a beautiful community filled with great activities for your family.”

We are having an open house this Saturday from 1 to 3 p.m. Come take a look at this property and get acquainted with Mira Lagos.

To get a quick preview, watch the video above for a tour of the home. The master suite is one of my favorite rooms in the house. It has plenty of open space so you have a lot of options - you can have a nursery, exercise space, or home office in the master suite, depending on what you need.

The kitchen features gorgeous granite counter tops and opens up to a breakfast area and family room. You will also see the formal living room, the dining room, and more.

Again, don’t miss the open house this Saturday at 2927 Mirado Drive from 1 to 3 p.m. If you have any questions about the property, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email in the meantime. We look forward to seeing you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:5000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Mansfield Area Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>John Teixeira</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

We’re here at our new listing, 2927 Mirado Drive. Located in Mira Lagos, this beautiful, 3,100 square foot home features four bedrooms, two bedrooms, a game room, and a gorgeous open floor plan.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Now on the Market: This Arlington Oasis</title>
        <link>localhost:5000/a-great-conversation-with-our-home-17.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>John Teixeira</author>
        <pubDate>2016-06-21 12:19:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

We’re very excited to talk about a special home that has just been listed on the market. The home is located at 9321 Marble Falls in the Southwind subdivision in the southernmost part of Arlington. At 2,230 sq. ft. with four bedrooms, granite counters, and wood floors, this home has just been put on the market for $240,000. The home’s owner, Carol, is here today to discuss her home, why she’s selling, and why she will be sad to leave it.

Carol is actually the original owner of the home, and had it built on-site just over nine years ago. The most important part of the build, to her, was making sure there was plenty of room for family and friends to feel welcome and invited. The open floor plan has helped her achieve this and as recently as two weeks ago, Carol was able to seat 40 people for dinner.

“Southwind is a friendly and quiet community.”

The master bedroom in the home is large enough to have its own living room, and Carol has even been able to do workout programs like P90x in it without running out of space. The dining room comfortably holds 10 seats, with another eight spots in the kitchen, and four more at the bar.

The community of Southwind is very unique. All the schools in the area are within a 5-10 minute drive, and Carol describes the community as “very friendly and very quiet.” This is never more evident than when looking at the backyard. This home’s backyard opens up to a green space with hiking and running trails, with a creek bed on the opposite side.

Although Carol is selling because she is semi-retired and choosing to move out to her lake house, she’s sad to see this home go. She’s been very happy with her energy bills at this home, mostly because she had the builder put a radiant barrier on it.

We really appreciate Carol taking time out of her day to join us and talk about her beautiful home. If you have any questions for us or if you’d like to see the home in person, give us a call or send us an email. We would love to hear from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:5000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Mansfield Area Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>John Teixeira</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

We’re very excited to talk about a special home that has just been listed on the market. The home is located at 9321 Marble Falls in the Southwind subdivision in the southernmost part of Arlington. At 2,230 sq. ft. with four bedrooms, granite counters, and wood floors, this home has just been put on the market for $240,000. The home’s owner, Carol, is here today to discuss her home, why she’s selling, and why she will be sad to leave it.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Don’t Miss Out on the Mansfield Shootout</title>
        <link>localhost:5000/coming-to-shootout-16.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>John Teixeira</author>
        <pubDate>2016-06-13 10:14:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today I’m with a sponsor for the Mansfield Shootout, Dr. Bobbit with Mansfield Chiropractic. Dr. Bobbit loves to help out the community, and he is eager to help us, as all of our donations will go to Habitat for Humanity to help build homes for those in need.

Dr. Bobbit’s desire to help people has guided him throughout his life, and that’s why he now owns his own chiropractic clinic. He is dedicated to helping people through a natural process. One of his recent innovations has to do with spinal decompression, but he also offers massages, chiropractic work, and nutritional advice.
“We’re still looking for sponsors!”
Last but not least, we are still looking for sponsors for our event. For just $100 we will put your business’ sign on one of eight shooting greens. It’s a great way to get your business seen.

Also, if you’ve never shot a gun, this tournament is a great place to start. The event will be taking place on June 18th at the Alpine Shooting Range at 5482 Shelby Rd. in Fort Worth. It’s $100 for one shooter or $385 for four. All proceeds are going to benefit the Trinity Habitat for Humanity.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:5000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Mansfield Area Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>John Teixeira</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today I’m with a sponsor for the Mansfield Shootout, Dr. Bobbit with Mansfield Chiropractic. Dr. Bobbit loves to help out the community, and he is eager to help us, as all of our donations will go to Habitat for Humanity to help build homes for those in need.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Price Your Mansfield Home in Today’s Market</title>
        <link>localhost:5000/mansfield-real-estate-agent-accurately-15.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>John Teixeira</author>
        <pubDate>2016-04-26 15:57:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Setting the right sales price is incredibly important before you list your property. You don’t want to price your home too low or too high. Today, we’ll go over how to set your price so you can net the most money for your home.

The first step is to hire an experienced real estate agent who will provide market comparables in your neighborhood. You can see what homes like yours are selling for in the current market.

When you evaluate those comparables, you should price your home somewhere right in the middle. We are in a seller’s market, and by pricing your home in the middle, you will generate a lot of competition, showings, and offers for your home. Since so many people will want to buy your home, that competition will drive your home to the highest price you can get.
“Price your home right in the middle.”
A lot of people are tempted to price their home based off the highest priced comparable. Some people even think that, since prices are rising, they can price over what the highest comparable sold for. If you do that, you will price yourself out of the market. When buyers do their searches using price ranges, they will not even see your home.

Ultimately, price your home appropriately. Don’t go too high and you will wind up being at the top of the market in your neighborhood.

If you have any questions, give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:5000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Mansfield Area Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>John Teixeira</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Setting the right sales price is incredibly important before you list your property. You don’t want to price your home too low or too high. Today, we’ll go over how to set your price so you can net the most money for your home.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Should You Buy a Mansfield Home Without an Inspection?</title>
        <link>localhost:5000/mansfield-real-estate-agent-should-you-14.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>John Teixeira</author>
        <pubDate>2016-04-22 08:46:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today, we’ll talk about buying a home with a professional inspection. What should you do in this particular situation in Mansfield?

As a local real estate expert, I always recommend a home inspection. Never buy a home without one! There are a lot of things inside a home an inspector can identity that you cannot. A private contractor will review all the systems in a home, including plumbing and electricity, in addition to checking appliances. There are so many aspects an inspector takes into account when they go through your property.

When you walk through your own home, you won’t be able to detect any problems. Some buyers have more expertise in building and repairing a home. However, the inspector you hire will definitely have that expertise, so you can fix repairs and add upgrades before you even accept an offer. They will always find more than you will just by looking. This is a serious and wise investment that I recommend to anyone selling their home.
“I always build in an option period for my buyers.”
I always build in an option period for my buyers. During this period, and inspection will happen along with any negotiations for potential repairs, and the contract can be terminated if necessary. I like to use a seven to ten day period, but ultimately, it’s for your protection. You want to be clear about what you want in the beginning, so there are no surprises later on.

If you’re thinking about buying or selling a home in the surrounding area, give me a call or send me an email at your earliest convenience. I’d be happy to help you with any questions you might have!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:5000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Mansfield Area Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>John Teixeira</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today, we’ll talk about buying a home with a professional inspection. What should you do in this particular situation in Mansfield?

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Is the Mansfield Market Performing this Spring?</title>
        <link>localhost:5000/mansfield-real-estate-agent-mansfields-13.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Updates</category>
        
        <author>John Teixeira</author>
        <pubDate>2016-03-28 15:29:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today we are going to be discussing the current market here in Mansfield. A lot of people have been asking us about the market’s current stats, and we’re here to share an update with you.

Right now, we have roughly 130 active homes on the market and 160 pending listings. That gives us less than a one-month supply of homes! This low-inventory is likely to continue for the foreseeable future.

Coming out of the holiday and winter months, we have seen a huge rise in activity, going from 77 sold properties over the last 30 days, to the current 160 pending sales. This is typical of a normal yearly cycle. But what does it mean for buyers, sellers, and investors?

For buyers, there are still homes on the market, but you’re going to have to compete for the best homes. For every good home, we have 10 to 20 buyers looking at it. If you’re buying, you need to be pre-approved, have a real estate agent working hard for you, and be ready to act quickly when the right property comes up.

“We have 10 to 20 buyers looking at every good home.”

For sellers, you have to get the condition of your home right and price it right. If you do these things, you are in great position to sell your home for more money than you could in the past.

For investors, there is a lot of competition out there, just as there is for regular buyers. If you’re investing in this market, you need to align yourself with a great agent who understands your goals and can work with you to help you achieve them.

If you have any questions, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I’d love to hear from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:5000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Mansfield Area Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>John Teixeira</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today we are going to be discussing the current market here in Mansfield. A lot of people have been asking us about the market’s current stats, and we’re here to share an update with you.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Avoid These 4 Mistakes When Selling in Mansfield</title>
        <link>localhost:5000/mansfield-real-estate-agent-avoid-these-12.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>John Teixeira</author>
        <pubDate>2016-03-23 10:38:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

As an experienced Mansfield Realtor, I oftentimes identify common mistakes within the local marketplace. It’s mind-boggling! Today, we’ll review the four most common mistakes, so you can avoid them when selling your home.

The first mistake people make is trying to sell their home themselves. One of the biggest reasons to hire a real estate professional is they can market to a wider net of people than you can. You also have limited knowledge of the real estate market. Real estate agents are working in the market all day, every day. We have a level of real estate expertise that you cannot reach and learn on your own. We can help you negotiate contracts and sell for the most money. Don’t miss out on maximizing profit from your property!

The second mistake people make is overpricing their home. Everybody wants to get the most money they possibly can for their home. People have a tendency to think their home is worth  more than it actually is. A real estate agent will examine comparable sales in your area so you know what your home is worth in today’s market. By accurately pricing your home, you will sell faster and for more money than you would if your home was overpriced.

“Pricing your home correctly will net you more money!”

The third mistake is using poor quality photos. Just because your phone has a camera doesn’t mean you should use your iPhone to take pictures for the MLS! Professional photographs will make your home shine, and a real estate agent will make sure that the MLS does not distort the size of your photographs.

The final mistake is forgetting about the backyard. We all tend to focus on curb appeal and cleaning the interior of the home but run out of steam when it’s time to take care of the backyard. The backyard matters to buyers, so make sure you get everything neat and tidy.

If you have any questions, give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:5000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Mansfield Area Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>John Teixeira</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

As an experienced Mansfield Realtor, I oftentimes identify common mistakes within the local marketplace. It’s mind-boggling! Today, we’ll review the four most common mistakes, so you can avoid them when selling your home.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Introducing Our Newest Team Member</title>
        <link>localhost:5000/mansfield-real-estate-agent-introducing-11.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>John Teixeira</author>
        <pubDate>2016-01-22 13:57:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

I hope you are all enjoying a great start to the new year. Today we are very excited to introduce you to the newest member of our team!

April Parr is our newest buyer’s agent, and is really enjoying what she is doing. She is fast becoming an important member of our team.
“You can see why we are so excited to have her with us.”
April’s passion has always been to help others, which she has done for the past 10 years as an educator in Mansfield. She is looking forward to helping families with their home search in any way she can. You can see why we are so excited to have her with us.

If you or anyone you know is looking to buy or sell, don’t forget us! We will use our passion, experience, and teamwork to serve you and your referrals to the best of our ability. Give us a call or send us a quick email to get in touch!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:5000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Mansfield Area Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>John Teixeira</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

I hope you are all enjoying a great start to the new year. Today we are very excited to introduce you to the newest member of our team!

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Happy Holidays, Mansfield!</title>
        <link>localhost:5000/mansfield-real-estate-agent-happy-10.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>John Teixeira</author>
        <pubDate>2015-12-14 17:16:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today, we thank everyone for your continual support and endless referrals. You’re so important to us. We hope you enjoy the holiday season with your family.

“Happy Holidays!”

Please continue to remember us as our team grows and the market remains hot in 2016! We wish you all happy holidays! We wish you a successful new year.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:5000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Mansfield Area Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>John Teixeira</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today, we thank everyone for your continual support and endless referrals. You’re so important to us. We hope you enjoy the holiday season with your family.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Important Is the Age of a Home When Buying?</title>
        <link>localhost:5000/mansfield-real-estate-agent-old-vs-new-9.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>John Teixeira</author>
        <pubDate>2015-10-01 13:47:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today, we’ll talk about the importance of the age of your home when buying. You may not want an older home because you are looking for a newer neighborhood, or you may prefer an older neighborhood with mature trees. Older homes also have different character than newer homes.

First, you need to know that the age of the home doesn’t affect its appreciation. You may find a neighborhood that is depreciating rapidly, but those neighborhoods are far and few between.

Next, any home you buy, you can upgrade. You may need to make changes for energy efficiency, layout, or other updates. I have seen older homes updated with new windows or roofs to make them more energy efficient. Sometimes making these upgrades yourself makes your property more energy efficient than new construction homes.
“You can change almost anything in a home, no matter how old.”
Regardless of the age of the home, you need to get an inspection. The inspector will be able to tell you about all the idiosyncrasies in the home so you have a clear idea of what’s going on with the house from the foundation to the roof.

My appeal to you is to go with what suits your personality. Don’t let the fact that a home is 50 years old keep you from buying it. The neighborhood should play a bigger factor in your decision than the age of the home.

If you have any questions, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:5000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Mansfield Area Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>John Teixeira</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today, we’ll talk about the importance of the age of your home when buying. You may not want an older home because you are looking for a newer neighborhood, or you may prefer an older neighborhood with mature trees. Older homes also have different character than newer homes.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Build Wealth from Real Estate</title>
        <link>localhost:5000/mansfield-arlington-real-estate-agent-8.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>John Teixeira</author>
        <pubDate>2015-09-09 15:06:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Real estate is a fantastic way to build wealth. People have been doing it forever, and real estate investments are actually some of the best long-term investments that you can make.

One of the first steps you need to take is to own the home you live in. Once you pay off your mortgage, you’ll be in great position to invest in another property. Interest rates are incredibly low right now, so this would be a very good time to invest in a home.

If you’re worried about being in debt because of a new home purchase, I wouldn’t think about it too much. Mortgage debt is the only good debt that you can have. Homes do appreciate, so you can bank on that if you’re worried about stepping too deep into mortgage debt.
“Real Estate is the best long-term investment you can make.”
Equity can be built pretty quickly after you have purchased a home. It can take five or maybe six years, but after this you can ride a nice wave of appreciation.

If you don’t own a home, I would contact a lender and forge out a path for home-ownership. It’s an incredible way to stabilize your family’s financial future.

My partner, Trever Kerr, is an excellent lender in the area. You can call him at (972) 822-7408. He is extremely consultative, and he can show you exactly what you need to do in order to purchase a home.

If you own a home right now, I invite you to give me a call to talk about investing in more real estate. Interest rates are low right now, so waiting to buy will cut into your purchasing power significantly.

Please don’t hesitate to contact me in regard to Mansfield real estate. I look forward to speaking with you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:5000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Mansfield Area Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>John Teixeira</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Real estate is a fantastic way to build wealth. People have been doing it forever, and real estate investments are actually some of the best long-term investments that you can make.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What's Happening with Mansfield's Inventory Levels?</title>
        <link>localhost:5000/mansfield-real-estate-agent-inventory-7.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Updates</category>
        
        <author>John Teixeira</author>
        <pubDate>2015-07-22 16:19:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Lately, I’ve found myself explaining real estate inventory levels to many people. Our market is crazy right now, and it seems like there are 10 buyers for each house on the market. Guess what? That’s because there is! Right now, there is a supply and demand problem that primarily affects buyers. Essentially, that problem exists because we have not been fulfilling our industry inventory levels since 2008.

Before 2008, builders were putting up new homes constantly. Whenever you walked down a street, it seemed like there was a new subdivision. Builders were also putting up spec homes so that people who were unwilling to wait the six to eight months still had inventory to look at. For most of those buyers, the financing has not come around for them to do that anymore. Plus, many builders are still a little gun-shy, as they were stuck with extra inventory back in 2008.

On top of all of that, we have an entire generation of millennials entering the market and looking for starter homes. Our inventory just started approaching industry levels this year, and I don’t think the supply and demand issue will be neutral for another three to five years.
“Here in the South, we’re supplying 30% more than demand.”
It’s different all across the country. In the Northeast, they still aren’t building enough for demand. The West is barely getting there. Here in the South, we’re doing better than anybody else. We’re supplying about 30% more than demand. However, we still have a lot of catching up to do, and while we’re catching up, more and more buyers are coming onto the market.

If you have any further questions, please feel free to reach out to me. If you’re thinking of buying or selling a home, call or email me today for a free consultation.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:5000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Mansfield Area Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>John Teixeira</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Lately, I’ve found myself explaining real estate inventory levels to many people. Our market is crazy right now, and it seems like there are 10 buyers for each house on the market. Guess what? That’s because there is! Right now, there is a supply and demand problem that primarily affects buyers. Essentially, that problem exists because we have not been fulfilling our industry inventory levels since 2008.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What's the First Move Before Buying a Home?</title>
        <link>localhost:5000/mansfield-real-estate-agent-lender-6.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>John Teixeira</author>
        <pubDate>2015-07-09 11:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Welcome back. Today we are asking one of the most common questions we get asked, “What is the first step in the real estate process in Mansfield?”

My answer is almost always the same. Unless you are paying cash, call a lender. It’s a really important step for us to know how we can help you and what you can afford. There are a lot of steps involved in the process and the more you can anticipate, the easier and more stress-free it will be.

Even if you’re not a first-time buyer, finding a good lender is still essential to your transaction. They will let you know exactly what you can afford and what type of home you can purchase.
“”
Lending guidelines are constantly changing, so it’s important you are working with someone who is always up to date on the latest changes. If you are looking for a good lender, we always recommend asking a good agent. If they are a good agent, they will have a preferred lending partner.

We have a lender that we refer all our clients to, and that is Trevor Kerr at Gateway Mortgage, who you can contact at (972)-822-7408. There is no one else I would refer my clients to.

If you have any questions for us, or are looking to buy or sell a home in Mansfield, give us a call or send us an email! We would love to hear from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:5000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Mansfield Area Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>John Teixeira</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Welcome back. Today we are asking one of the most common questions we get asked, “What is the first step in the real estate process in Mansfield?”

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Pros and Cons of Building a New Home</title>
        <link>localhost:5000/mansfield-real-estate-agent-build-home-4.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>John Teixeira</author>
        <pubDate>2015-05-29 16:35:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

There comes a point in time when people need to move into bigger, better homes. Whether it’s because of a growing family or simply a wish to invest in a better property, people do this all of the time.

Usually move up buyers have to find a home to move into before they can sell, and vice versa, so sometimes the transactions can get dicey. However, I have a lot of experience helping move up buyers, and there are a few things that can be done to have a seamless transaction.

My advice to you right now is to focus on the purchase because inventory is low right now, so selling your home will be the easy part.
“Focus on finding a home before selling.”
In a normal market, you could use contingencies to sell your home, but right now, because of the low inventory, this may not work.

Another option is to build a new home, so then you can have a slow move in and have plenty of time to sell your home.

If you’re interested in moving up, please contact me and ask about my move up discount. I’d love to help you out!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:5000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Mansfield Area Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>John Teixeira</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

There comes a point in time when people need to move into bigger, better homes. Whether it’s because of a growing family or simply a wish to invest in a better property, people do this all of the time.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Have You Been Thinking of Buying a Better Home?</title>
        <link>localhost:5000/mansfield-real-estate-agent-move-up-5.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>John Teixeira</author>
        <pubDate>2015-05-29 16:10:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

There are a lot of benefits to building a new home in Mansfield, especially right now when we have low inventory.

Instead of waiting around to find the perfect home, you could build your own custom dream home! However, it does take 4-8 months to build a home, so if you’re in a hurry, it may not be your ideal option.

When you buy a pre-owned home, it is a lot more cost-effective because you get a lot more home in terms of cost per sq. ft. New homes are often more expensive, but you have total control over the price when you’re picking materials and amenities.

“Building a new home requires a lot of time and money.”

However, sometimes with resale properties, the previous owners have already customized the home and barred the expense, so you have to pay nothing for those upgrades!

If you’re thinking of building a new home, I would advise you to use a Realtor when you’re working with a builder, and I would be glad to represent you.

As always, if you have any questions or concerns, please don’t hesitate to contact me in regards to Mansfield real estate.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:5000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Mansfield Area Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>John Teixeira</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

There are a lot of benefits to building a new home in Mansfield, especially right now when we have low inventory.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Are the Hottest Neighborhoods in Mansfield?</title>
        <link>localhost:5000/mansfield-real-estate-agent-hot-spots-3.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>John Teixeira</author>
        <pubDate>2015-05-15 10:33:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today I wanted to discuss some of the more popular neighborhoods in Mansfield. Now is a great time to buy, so these are some of the neighborhoods that you might want to investigate:


  The Trails
  Walnut Creek Country Club
  Dover Heights


A majority of the new building is occurring in the Lake Ridge High School District, but there are some other wonderful new communities forming in Garden Heights, Bower Ranch, Las Brisas, and the D.R. Horton neighborhood. I think a majority of the growth in Mansfield will be happening in the southeast corner for the near future.
“Mansfield is becoming a hot spot to live.”
In the future, I expect growth will happen more out to the west of town. The city is really beginning to manage development out in those areas.

Overall, Mansfield is becoming a hot spot to live, so if you plan on buying in the near future, please don’t hesitate to contact me and I can help you to find a great place to settle into.

I look forward to speaking with you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:5000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Mansfield Area Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>John Teixeira</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today I wanted to discuss some of the more popular neighborhoods in Mansfield. Now is a great time to buy, so these are some of the neighborhoods that you might want to investigate:

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Do You Know How to Handle Multiple Offer Situations?</title>
        <link>localhost:5000/mansfield-real-estate-multiple-offers-2.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>John Teixeira</author>
        <pubDate>2015-05-14 09:26:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

The market here in Mansfield is extremely active and we’re seeing a lot of multiple offers happening. This is why I thought I would shed some light on this topic, as a lot of my clients have been asking about it. There are different strategies that buyers and sellers can take when faced with this problem, and I’m here to tell you about them.

“Sometimes the best offer is the one that has the highest likelihood of closing.”
The important thing to know as a buyer is that your competition will be fierce, but this doesn’t mean that you don’t stand a chance. Sometimes a personalized offer can help push you to the top of the list. Sellers are always more comfortable choosing a buyer that they can relate to, and one that they know will be taking good care of their home. Writing a note to them explaining why you want the property can help a lot, but I’ve also filmed videos with families, and that can be helpful too.

If you’re a seller in a multiple offer situation, it’s important to have patience as we expose your property to a large audience of buyers. When you do get multiple offers, you want to ensure that the offers are from pre-qualified buyers, because they’re serious about purchasing a home. Cash offers are also good, but you just want to see proof of funds. However, sometimes cash is not the most important, sometimes the best offer is the one that has the highest likelihood of closing. Every seller has a different motivation, so sometimes it’s also just a matter of what works f
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:5000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Mansfield Area Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>John Teixeira</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

The market here in Mansfield is extremely active and we’re seeing a lot of multiple offers happening. This is why I thought I would shed some light on this topic, as a lot of my clients have been asking about it. There are different strategies that buyers and sellers can take when faced with this problem, and I’m here to tell you about them.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Can You Take Advantage of Mansfield Real Estate?</title>
        <link>localhost:5000/mansfield-real-estate-market-update-1.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Updates</category>
        
        <author>John Teixeira</author>
        <pubDate>2015-05-07 15:38:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

People always ask me how the local real estate market is performing, and the answer always depends on whether you’re buying, selling, or investing.

If you’re a seller, you’ll find that now is a great time to put your home on the market. Buyer demand is high and inventory is low, so you stand to make a good profit if you get your home on the market now. Just remember, it needs to be priced correctly and in good condition.

If you’re looking to buy a home, now is also a good time to do so. Interest rates are at historic lows (below 4%) and there are a lot of excellent loan products available. It’s more affordable to buy a home right now than it has been in a very long time. It’s a lot cheaper to pay a mortgage right now than it is to pay monthly rent, so if you’ve thought about purchasing a home, then now may be the time to pull the trigger. This is also true because interest rates are currently on the rise, so your affordability may drop if you wait to buy.
“You have a really great opportunity to capitalize on a move-up home sale.”
Investors will have a little tougher time flipping homes, but rental rates are increasing so you may find comfort in that fact. I would recommend investing in rental homes over properties that you’re just going to flip.

Overall, inventory is extremely low in our area. If your home is worth more than $200K, there is only about 1 month supply of inventory. If your home is worth less than $200K then you will find that there is only 1-2 weeks worth of inventory. This means that you have a really great opportunity to capitalize on a move-up home sale.

If you’d like any assistance buying, selling, or investing in a new home, then please don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I would be very happy to assist you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:5000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Mansfield Area Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>John Teixeira</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

People always ask me how the local real estate market is performing, and the answer always depends on whether you’re buying, selling, or investing.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>John Teixeira</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">John Teixeira</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Teixeira Realty Group - your professional Mansfield Area Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
