<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>North Carolina Real Estate Podcast with Patty Gillepsie</title>
    <link>http://www.pattytalks.com</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://www.pattytalks.com"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Patty Sells NC Team - your professional Raleigh Real Estate Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Patty Gillepsie</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2017-07-21 09:54:01 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Patty Gillepsie</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://i.imgur.com/xwMWat6.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Raleigh Real Estate, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>info@pattysellsnc.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Patty Gillepsie</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Patty Gillepsie</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://i.imgur.com/xwMWat6.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Raleigh Real Estate, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Raleigh Real Estate Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Patty Sells NC Team - your professional Raleigh Real Estate Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Properly Stage Your Home</title>
        <link>http://www.pattytalks.com/how-to-properly-stage-your-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Patty Gillepsie</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-06 08:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patty+Sells+NC/Email+Assets/++Videos/2017/July/Patty+Sells+NC-+How+to+Properly+Stage+Your+Home.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Some homeowners will need to stage their home for showings while they’re still living in the property. Today I’ve listed a few tips to help make the staging process easier.

1. Remove all signs of personalization. A homebuyer should be able to envision themselves in the home through its design, and if too many personal items are around, they won’t be able to do that.

“A homebuyer should be able to envision themselves in the home.”

2. Re-define each room’s purpose. Adjusting the use of converted spaces back to their original purpose will help you get the home sold.

3. Make use of a storage unit. Investing in a storage unit close to your home will give you quick access to items that you may need, while still allowing you to remove some items so that sellers can see the entire space without clutter.

If you have any questions or you’d like to schedule a free in-home consultation with our team stager, give us a call. We’d be happy to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patty+Sells+NC/Email+Assets/++Videos/2017/July/Patty+Sells+NC-+How+to+Properly+Stage+Your+Home.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.pattytalks.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patty+Sells+NC/Email+Assets/++Videos/2017/July/Patty+Sells+NC-+How+to+Properly+Stage+Your+Home.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I wanted to talk to you about how to stage your home for showings while you’re still living in it.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patty Gillepsie</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I wanted to talk to you about how to stage your home for showings while you’re still living in it.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Raleigh Real Estate, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 Home Maintenance Tasks for the Summer</title>
        <link>http://www.pattytalks.com/5-home-maintenance-tasks-for-the-summer.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Patty Gillepsie</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-22 08:23:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patty+Sells+NC/Patty+Sells+NC-+Get+your+home+ready+for+summer+fun.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There are five home maintenance tasks you should definitely tackle this June:

1. Inspect brick or stone patios and walkways. Freezing temperatures can wreak havoc on hardscape surfaces made of loose, unmortared brick, stone, concrete, or other paving materials. If frost heave and erosion have caused pavers to shift, rise, or sink, you’ll want to fix any unevenness for safety and aesthetic reasons.

2. Feed your lawn. After a wet spring, your lawn may look very nice and lush. Since Mother Nature did all the hard work, you can relax now, right? Unfortunately, no. Grass loves nutrients. Now is a great time to add a high nitrogen fertilizer to help suppress weeds and keep your lawn looking great for the summer.

“Fix uneven areas in your patio to stay safe this summer.”

3. Repair wooden fences and gates. Cycles of cold and wet weather can cause wood to move, twist, and warp. Garden gates can fall out of alignment and fence pickets can become loose or fall off. Check for any loose fencing and fix sagging gate areas.

4. Mulch your flower and vegetable beds. Insulate your planting beds with two to five inches of mulch to prevent evaporation and keep weeds in check.

5. Get your grill in gear. Nobody wants a rack of ribs with last year’s grill gunk on them, so make sure your grill is clean and that the gas hoses and connections are tight and secure.

If you take care of these items on our “check yourself” list, then your house is ready for another great summer season. If you have any questions about home maintenance or if you are interested in our current real estate market, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!

</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patty+Sells+NC/Patty+Sells+NC-+Get+your+home+ready+for+summer+fun.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.pattytalks.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patty+Sells+NC/Patty+Sells+NC-+Get+your+home+ready+for+summer+fun.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today, I’ll go over five home maintenance tips you should do this June in order to prepare your home for another summer season.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patty Gillepsie</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today, I’ll go over five home maintenance tips you should do this June in order to prepare your home for another summer season.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Raleigh Real Estate, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Key to Finding the Perfect Neighborhood</title>
        <link>http://www.pattytalks.com/the-key-to-finding-the-perfect-neighborhood.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Patty Gillepsie</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-07 08:31:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patty+Sells+NC/The+Patty+Sells+NC+Team-+Finding+the+perfect+neighborhood.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you want to ensure your new home is in a neighborhood you will absolutely love, I’ve got just the checklist for you.

1. Check the list! Google the best places to live in the Triangle or a specific city in the Triangle that’s of interest to you. You’ll get pages of options to sift through. The websites and news outlets have done a lot of the legwork for you, and they will provide you with data and statistics that will help you quickly see where you might want to concentrate your search. At the very least, they will provide you with a good starting point that will allow you to do further research.

2. Consider the value. There are countless ways to look at the value of an area, but one of the strongest indicators of growth in neighborhoods today is what can be found around it. For example, a popular coffee shop. Proximity to a coffee shop has a very real and positive effect on home values. In fact, in the 17 years leading up to 2014, homes adjacent to a Starbucks almost doubled in value up to 96%. Those further out appreciated by 65% over the same period.

“Test run your work commute from each neighborhood.”

3. Make the drive. Commuting is a big deal for everyone, and if you have a limit to how much time you want to spend in the car, it makes sense to drive from any of the neighborhoods you like to work and back during rush hour. You might find that the drive from one of those neighborhoods is too long, so you can eliminate it as an option.

4. Spend as much time as possible in the area. This will tell you if it’s a good fit. Make a list of your needs and figure out if that area will meet them.

If you have any questions about finding the perfect neighborhood, or if you are looking to buy or sell a home, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to speaking with you soon!

</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patty+Sells+NC/The+Patty+Sells+NC+Team-+Finding+the+perfect+neighborhood.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.pattytalks.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patty+Sells+NC/The+Patty+Sells+NC+Team-+Finding+the+perfect+neighborhood.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I want to share my foolproof checklist for finding the perfect neighborhood to purchase your new home in.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patty Gillepsie</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I want to share my foolproof checklist for finding the perfect neighborhood to purchase your new home in.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Raleigh Real Estate, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Patty Gillepsie</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Patty Gillepsie</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Patty Sells NC Team - your professional Raleigh Real Estate Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
