<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Cleveland Park Real Estate Podcast with Marjorie Dick Stuart</title>
    <link>http://marjoriedickstuart.tv</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://marjoriedickstuart.tv"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from W.C. & A.N. Miller Realtors - your professional Cleveland Park Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Marjorie Dick Stuart</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2017-08-24 17:07:08 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Marjorie Dick Stuart</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Cleveland Park, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>marjorie@marjoriedickstuart.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Marjorie Dick Stuart</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Marjorie Dick Stuart</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Cleveland Park, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Cleveland Park Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from W.C. & A.N. Miller Realtors - your professional Cleveland Park Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>What's Working Now! - Why Home Staging Works for Home Sellers</title>
        <link>http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/whats-working-now-why-home-staging-works-for-home-sellers.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Marjorie Dick Stuart</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-22 11:24:52 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marjorie+Dick+Stuart/2017/Cleveland+Park+Real+Estate-+Home+Selling+Story.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Welcome to another episode of “What’s Working Now!”

Today, I’m reporting to you live from my new listing at 3201 Garfield Street NW on the edge of Cleveland Park. This home is on the market for $1.795 million.

You all know how I feel about staging, and something happened at the Garfield house that demonstrates exactly how important staging is.

In many cases, home staging has helped my sellers net an extra $100,000. Sometimes, though, a motivated buyer will get a sneak preview before the house is ready.

I invited an agent and her prospective buyers over to the Garfield house. She was working with a family of four. They came into the dining room. The sellers had their wedding guest list on the wall. The agent noticed it and couldn’t take her eyes off of it, and she told her buyers, “Come over here and see who’s invited to the wedding.”

“Make sure you pack away personal items before listing your home for sale.”

There were also a number of personal photos and other wedding memorabilia in the dining room. It turns out that the buyers were so distracted by all of these personal items that they never really looked at the house.

After that, we came in and made sure to pack away all personal photos that were in that dining room. The kitchen walls were brown and covered in pictures as well, so we cleared everything away, opened up the windows, and made the house clean and shiny.

As you can see, staging your home makes a huge difference.

To learn more about the value of preparing your home for the market, you can sign up here to watch our Seller Half Hour seminar online. Remember, you can learn everything you need to know about selling a home in just 30 minutes.

If you would like a tour of my new listing, click here for a tour from the seller.

Thank you for watching “What’s Working Now!”Be sure to tune in next time, when I’ll discuss a breakthrough in technology that may actually be a step backward.

In the meantime, if you have any other questions about real estate or the current market, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marjorie+Dick+Stuart/2017/Cleveland+Park+Real+Estate-+Home+Selling+Story.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://marjoriedickstuart.tv" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marjorie+Dick+Stuart/2017/Cleveland+Park+Real+Estate-+Home+Selling+Story.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Home staging is incredibly important, and our latest listing at 3201 Garfield Street proves that.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Marjorie Dick Stuart</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Home staging is incredibly important, and our latest listing at 3201 Garfield Street proves that.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Cleveland Park, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Marjorie Dick Stuart</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Marjorie Dick Stuart</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from W.C. & A.N. Miller Realtors - your professional Cleveland Park Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
