<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title> Real Estate Podcast with Patrick Fitzgerald</title>
    <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://www.thevaloanguy.com"/>
    <description>Patrick Fitzgerald, the VA Loan Guy, is located in San Antonio, Texas and is a true “One Stop Lender”. We originate, underwrite, and close all types of loans. We offer Texas Vet, Veterans, FHA, Conventional, Jumbo, Adjustable Rate, and Investment products.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Patrick Fitzgerald</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2018-03-15 15:28:10 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Patrick Fitzgerald</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://www.thevaloanguy.com/img/podcast.png"/>
    <media:keywords>Texas Veteran Loans, VA Loans, The VA Loan Guy, Loans for Active Military, Mortgage Banking Firm, Mortgage Banking in Texas, VA Mortgages</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>pfitzgerald@peopleshomeequity.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://www.thevaloanguy.com/img/podcast.png"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Texas Veteran Loans, VA Loans, The VA Loan Guy, Loans for Active Military, Mortgage Banking Firm, Mortgage Banking in Texas, VA Mortgages</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Get the answers to the most popular questions for you and to get the necessary tools to make a proper decision on a Home Loan using the Texas Veterans Land Board Program.</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>Patrick Fitzgerald, the VA Loan Guy, is located in San Antonio, Texas and is a true “One Stop Lender”. We originate, underwrite, and close all types of loans. We offer Texas Vet, Veterans, FHA, Conventional, Jumbo, Adjustable Rate, and Investment products.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>Is Your Future Property Located in a Flood Zone?</title>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/is-your-future-property-located-in-a-flood-zone.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2018-03-12 14:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/Videos/2018/March/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Is+Your+Future+Property+Located+in+a+Flood+Zone%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Why is it crucial when buying a property that you check if it’s located in a flood zone? Let me tell you a quick story.

I’m doing a loan for a couple who bought a 12-acre property awhile back but didn’t know that part of the property was in a flood zone. Since they only recently learned about this and we’ve pulled a flood certificate, they now have to pay between $100 and $200 a month extra for the entire life of their loan.

If you use a Realtor to buy a property, make sure they work hard to check for this kind of information. Most of the time, if a property is located within a flood zone, that fact will be listed in the seller’s disclosure.Some sellers themselves don’t even know if their property is located in a flood zone, though. This could be because they inherited the property, bought it at an auction, or the land was split off from another parcel. Sometimes, unfortunately, they can also be dishonest and just not tell you about it.

“You should always research if a property is located within a flood zone before you buy it.”

That’s why, again, you should always research if a property is located within a flood zone before you buy it. If you’re using a mortgage to finance the purchase, ask your lender to run what’s called a “flood cert” (or flood certificate), where they reach out to FEMA and FEMA reports back to them whether the property is located either partially or wholly within a flood zone.

Once you have that flood certificate, it will put your home into a certain category. You can then give this information to your insurance agent and they can tell you to what extent your flood insurance will cost you.

If the property is only located partially within a flood zone, you can ask a surveyor to provide an elevation certificate, which may show that the home site where you plan on building is not in a flood zone.

If you have any other questions about flood insurance or there’s anything else I can help you with, don’t hesitate to give me a call. As always, it doesn’t cost a penny to talk.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/Videos/2018/March/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Is+Your+Future+Property+Located+in+a+Flood+Zone%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.thevaloanguy.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/Videos/2018/March/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Is+Your+Future+Property+Located+in+a+Flood+Zone%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Not checking if a property you want to buy is located within a flood zone can end up costing you.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Not checking if a property you want to buy is located within a flood zone can end up costing you.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Texas Veteran Loans, VA Loans, The VA Loan Guy, Loans for Active Military, Mortgage Banking Firm, Mortgage Banking in Texas, VA Mortgages</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Should You Work With My Own Realtor</title>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/why-should-you-work-with-my-own-realtor.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2018-02-15 13:57:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/Videos/2018/February/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Why+Should+You+Work+With+My+Own+Realtor%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today, we’re going to talk about why you need your own Realtor.

When driving around looking for a home, you might come across a house you like with a yard sign featuring a phone number.

Most people are tempted to pick up the phone and call, but you need to know that the number on the sign is for a Realtor who represents the seller. They have a signed contract with that homeowner, meaning that they’re not financially obligated to represent your interests, and don’t have to inform you about any known issues in the house. They have no fiduciary responsibility to you as a buyer.

“A buyer’s agent will represent you and only you.”

This is why it’s important for you to have your own Realtor. When you have your own representation, it doesn’t cost you anything because the selling fees are paid for by the seller of the property.A buyer’s agent will represent you and only you. They’re obligated to protect your interests. Your Realtor will work in conjunction with the seller’s agent to negotiate the best deal for you.

If you have any questions, feel free to reach out to me. Remember, it doesn’t cost a penny to talk.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/Videos/2018/February/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Why+Should+You+Work+With+My+Own+Realtor%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.thevaloanguy.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/Videos/2018/February/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Why+Should+You+Work+With+My+Own+Realtor%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Having your own representation in real estate matters. Here’s why.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Having your own representation in real estate matters. Here’s why.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Texas Veteran Loans, VA Loans, The VA Loan Guy, Loans for Active Military, Mortgage Banking Firm, Mortgage Banking in Texas, VA Mortgages</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What’s the Difference Between an Inspection and an Appraisal?</title>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/whats-the-difference-between-an-inspection-and-an-appraisal.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2018-02-01 09:46:59 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/Videos/2018/February/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Whats+the+Difference+Between+an+Inspection+and+an+Appraisal%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What is the difference between an inspection and an appraisal? Today, I’d like to clear up some key differences.

Many veterans call me believing that the VA is going to do an inspection on their home, when in fact, that’s not really the case. The VA will appraise a home, not inspect it.

An appraiser is there to view the property, measure it for square footage, take pictures of the home, and study the property as a whole to determine its value. This is done by comparing it to other properties with similar square footage and amenities that have sold in the area.

“The VA does not require a veteran to get an inspection of the home they’re buying.”

An inspector, on the other hand, couldn’t care less about the value of the property. Inspectors are there to measure the home’s functionality. In other words, the inspector’s goal is to make sure that the air conditioning and heating system is working, any appliances are fully functional, the electrical framework is up to scratch, and that there are no safety issues in the house. The inspector will generate a 35- to 40-page document with pictures of anything of interest found that needs to be addressed.

To be clear, the VA does not require a veteran to get an inspection of the home they’re buying. Personally, I would never buy a house without an inspection, but under the terms of the VA loan, they’re not necessary.

If you have any questions, it doesn’t cost a penny to talk to me. Feel free to give me a call and I’d be happy to answer all of your questions.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/Videos/2018/February/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Whats+the+Difference+Between+an+Inspection+and+an+Appraisal%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.thevaloanguy.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/Videos/2018/February/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Whats+the+Difference+Between+an+Inspection+and+an+Appraisal%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What is the difference between an inspection and an appraisal? Today, I’ll explain how they differ.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What is the difference between an inspection and an appraisal? Today, I’ll explain how they differ.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Texas Veteran Loans, VA Loans, The VA Loan Guy, Loans for Active Military, Mortgage Banking Firm, Mortgage Banking in Texas, VA Mortgages</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mortgage Loan Rules for Moving a Manufactured Home</title>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/mortgage-loan-rules-for-moving-a-manufactured-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2018-01-08 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/Videos/2018/January/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Moving+a+Manufactured+Home.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I wanted to clarify the rules on moving a manufactured home. A lot of people don’t know this, but there are some very, very specific rules regarding this topic and there’s a lot of confusion about it.

Why is this so important?

A lender may not be able to do one of the top three loans—FHA, conventional, or VA loan—on a manufactured home if it’s been moved. FHA and conventional loans don’t allow a home to be moved or reinstalled once it has been in installed in its original location. Only VA loans, the loan option for veterans, allow the option to move a home once after its initial installation.

Does the trip from the manufacturer to the location count as a move?No, it doesn’t count as a move. But here’s what you need to know: If the owner sells the home or has been foreclosed upon, if the home is moved from where it was installed to another location after having been sold, then that is considered a move.

“Only VA loans, the loan option for veterans, allow the option to move a home once after its initial installation.”

Where do we get all this information?

You can visit the Texas Department of Housing website at www.TDHCA.state.tx.us for records on every installation of manufactured homes. A manufactured home installer is licensed and by law they must log on to that site, enter their license number, then tag numbers of the manufactured home and the serial numbers and declare that they installed a specific home with both the date and location of that installation. This site is how lenders find out if a home has been moved.

This is critical information no matter if you’re on the buyer’s or seller’s side because some lenders don’t even know how to do this. You should want to know in advance if you’re wasting your time.

If you have any questions about this, feel free to give me a call or send an email. I’ll answer all of your questions, and after all, it doesn’t cost a penny to talk.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/Videos/2018/January/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Moving+a+Manufactured+Home.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.thevaloanguy.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/Videos/2018/January/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Moving+a+Manufactured+Home.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There are specific rules regarding the moving and re-installation of manufactured homes that many don’t know about. Learn about them here.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There are specific rules regarding the moving and re-installation of manufactured homes that many don’t know about. Learn about them here.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Texas Veteran Loans, VA Loans, The VA Loan Guy, Loans for Active Military, Mortgage Banking Firm, Mortgage Banking in Texas, VA Mortgages</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Where Can Veterans Get a Home Improvement Loan?</title>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/where-can-veterans-get-a-home-improvement-loan.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2017-12-21 07:10:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/Videos/2017/December/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Where+Can+Veterans+Get+a+Home+Improvement+Loan%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’re a veteran looking for a home improvement loan to make some upgrades to your home, I have good news and bad news.

The bad news is the VA doesn’t offer any loans for this purpose. The good news is the Texas Veterans Land Board does, and they recently doubled the amount they’re willing to loan to a veteran—$50,000.

There are a couple very favorable terms to this loan. Not only will they go up to 20 years on the loan at below market rate, but you don’t have to provide a down payment either.

“You don’t even need a down payment with this loan.”

To apply for this loan, just go online at www.texasveterans.com. From there, they’ll contact you to get the ball rolling.

One of the requirements for this loan is you need to gather two bids for the work you want to be done—they won’t allow you to do it yourself. After they underwrite and approve the loan, the work will begin. Typically, they’ll send the money to a local title company in your area. As soon as the work is done, they’ll send an inspector to your home to ensure the work has been done satisfactorily and you’re happy with it. After that, they’ll fund the work and make sure the suppliers get paid.

There are home improvement loans available for non-veterans too. They’re typically done by most banks or federal credit unions, and most of them are underwritten by HUD. If you’d like to know more about these, ask your local bank or credit union.

If you have any more questions about home improvement loans, don’t hesitate to give me a call. As always, it doesn’t cost a penny to talk, and I’d love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/Videos/2017/December/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Where+Can+Veterans+Get+a+Home+Improvement+Loan%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.thevaloanguy.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/Videos/2017/December/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Where+Can+Veterans+Get+a+Home+Improvement+Loan%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Need a home improvement loan to make some upgrades? I know where you can get one.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Need a home improvement loan to make some upgrades? I know where you can get one.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Texas Veteran Loans, VA Loans, The VA Loan Guy, Loans for Active Military, Mortgage Banking Firm, Mortgage Banking in Texas, VA Mortgages</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Unique Opportunity for Veteran Homebuyers</title>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/a-unique-opportunity-for-veteran-homebuyers.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2017-11-28 07:04:36 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/Videos/2017/November/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+A+Unique+Opportunity+for+Veteran+Homebuyers.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Did you know that you can not only use VA financing to buy a home with 0% down, but you can also use VA financing to buy a multi-family property? If you set things up right, the home will essentially pay for itself. Here’s what I mean.

You are allowed to use a VA loan to purchase a multi-family property, but there are a few caveats. First, you must occupy the property as a primary residence within 60 days of closing on the property. That’s a very important rule to remember.

“This is a smart investment strategy.”

When it comes to multi-family properties, you can actually use the projected rent from the other units in the home to count towards your qualifying number. Because of this, you will be able to qualify for a home with a much higher price. You’ll also have the opportunity to make passive income through rent as you own the home.

If you have VA disability, you will also have a reduction in your property taxes. If you are 100% service-connected disabled, there are no property taxes whatsoever on the entire complex.

There are a lot of ways we can make this work, even if you don’t have any prior experience as a landlord.

If you have any questions about this program or about anything else, give me a call or send me an email today. It doesn’t cost a penny to talk. I look forward to hearing from you soon!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/Videos/2017/November/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+A+Unique+Opportunity+for+Veteran+Homebuyers.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.thevaloanguy.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/Videos/2017/November/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+A+Unique+Opportunity+for+Veteran+Homebuyers.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>How can you use your loan to buy a multi-family home? Here’s what you need to know.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>How can you use your loan to buy a multi-family home? Here’s what you need to know.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Texas Veteran Loans, VA Loans, The VA Loan Guy, Loans for Active Military, Mortgage Banking Firm, Mortgage Banking in Texas, VA Mortgages</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What You Need to Know About Property Surveys</title>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/what-you-need-to-know-about-property-surveys.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2017-11-08 06:50:42 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/Videos/2017/November/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+What+You+Need+to+Know+About+Property+Surveys.mp4</guid>
        <description>

A property survey is a very important document in a real estate transaction. What is a property survey, though? What do you need to know about them?

When a mortgage company finances the property in question of a real estate transaction, they’ll require a property survey.This survey shows several key things. Most importantly, it shows where the house will sit on that property. It also shows the legal description of the property— which is important for recording ownership—and where the exact property lines are and where the fences are. If the property doesn’t have a fence and you’re thinking of putting one in, that will show the fence contractors where to put it on the property line.

The property survey will also note the locations of any pools, outbuildings, or driveways, and where those are in reference to any legal setbacks. Legal setbacks are the dimensions that the city or county requires you not to encroach upon when building your house. There is no set amount of space in this regard, but if you’re thinking about building a swimming pool in the backyard, you don’t want to build it within the utility easement.

“Property surveys show several important things.”

This information is important not only if you’re building a home, but if you’re buying an existing home as well. If your property is encroaching on your neighbor’s, for example, you need to know that up front so it can be remedied.

In the state of Texas, a property survey can be reused. A lot of people don’t recommend that, but our position is as long as it’s legible and the engineer’s stamp can be read, there’s no reason you can’t reuse it.

Reusing a survey, however, means that it may not show any changes that have been made in utility easements. This doesn’t happen very often, but it’s why some real estate companies require the prospective buyer to always get a new survey. That’s a decision you and your Realtor can make.

As always, it doesn’t cost a penny to talk, so if you have any more questions about property surveys, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/Videos/2017/November/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+What+You+Need+to+Know+About+Property+Surveys.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.thevaloanguy.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/Videos/2017/November/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+What+You+Need+to+Know+About+Property+Surveys.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Property surveys are used by mortgage companies to list and record key details of a property that’s being bought or built.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Property surveys are used by mortgage companies to list and record key details of a property that’s being bought or built.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Texas Veteran Loans, VA Loans, The VA Loan Guy, Loans for Active Military, Mortgage Banking Firm, Mortgage Banking in Texas, VA Mortgages</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Is Using an IRRL a Smart Move for You?</title>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/is-using-an-irrl-a-smart-move-for-you.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-16 08:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/Videos/2017/October/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Is+Using+an+IRRL+a+Smart+Move+for+You%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

“Pat, I just closed my VA loan with you. Within two weeks, I’m starting to get letters every week offering me to refinance my home loan. How do they even know I did a loan with you? Why am I getting these offers right off the bat?”

This is a question I get asked a lot and a scenario I encounter quite often. We didn’t sell your loan or your information to anybody, but in the state of Texas, whenever someone buys a home, it’s public information if there’s a loan put on it at the courthouse. No other information is recorded—it just denotes that the person bought a home and used a VA loan to do so

There are people who sell that information and there are certain mortgage companies who focus solely on an interest rate reduction refinance, or IRRL. This is a product that the VA allows that, in my opinion, got completely out of hand. The VA’s position on it, however, is if the veteran can benefit from a reduced house payment, they see no issue.

“In my opinion, these fast and low refinance offers very rarely make sense to pursue.”

How does this product work?

There are some nice things about it. It greatly reduces paperwork, and in most cases, it doesn’t require another appraisal, any paycheck stubs, or even bank statements. The VA also allows the closing costs to be put into the new loan. We do have to verify in the credit report that the payments have been made on time and for at least the last 12 months. In most cases, you can come to closing with nothing but a pen in hand and can get a lower house payment.

So, the payment is lowered, and there are other advantages, but at what cost? In order to get that lower rate, these mortgage companies force you to buy points. This means that once you do the closing, the balance on the rate begins to grow.

Let me give you an example of a situation like this I dealt with a few months ago. One of these mortgage companies came to one of my clients that had closed on a home two months prior and offered him a 2.99% rate to refinance a loan that had a $200,000 balance. When I asked him to give me a copy of the good faith estimate, I found that they had $17,000 worth of points and other associated fees to buy that loan down.

Did they give him a lower house payment? Yes—it was about $137 per month. The problem, though, was when he came away from closing, he owed $217,000 on the home instead of $200,000.

This kind of situation can spell trouble for you if and when you sell your home. In many cases, you have to come to closing with money in order to get out from under the loan. Let’s not forget, in most cases when you sell a home, you’ll also have about 6% in real estate fees. If you tack that onto the extra $17,000, you’ve got a really difficult situation.

Do these fast and low refinance offers make sense to pursue? In my opinion, very rarely.

If you have any questions about IRRLs, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/Videos/2017/October/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Is+Using+an+IRRL+a+Smart+Move+for+You%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.thevaloanguy.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/Videos/2017/October/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Is+Using+an+IRRL+a+Smart+Move+for+You%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Interest rate reduction refinances can offer you a reduced house payment, but they also come with serious downsides.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Interest rate reduction refinances can offer you a reduced house payment, but they also come with serious downsides.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Texas Veteran Loans, VA Loans, The VA Loan Guy, Loans for Active Military, Mortgage Banking Firm, Mortgage Banking in Texas, VA Mortgages</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>If a Storm Hits, Do You Have Coverage?</title>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/if-a-storm-hits-do-you-have-coverage.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2017-09-25 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/Videos/2017/September/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+If+a+Storm+Hits%252C+Do+You+Have+Coverage%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The terrible situations that have unfolded in Texas, Florida, and elsewhere are still fresh in our minds, and for good reason. People have been flooded out of their homes, and it has been absolutely heartbreaking to watch.

So today, I wanted to talk about what flood insurance is and why it can be helpful in situations like these.

The most important thing I want you to know is that homeowners insurance does not cover rising water. If water happens to come in from the roof, it will be covered under homeowners insurance. If it comes from beneath and rises into your home, however, it is simply not covered.

Of the approximately 185,000 homes that were flooded in Houston, 80% of them did not have flood insurance. Flood insurance is its own separate policy, meaning that you will need to call and request this specific type of coverage.

“Don’t wait until you see the hurricane coming before you think about your coverage.”

It’s important to be aware that flooding can still occur in non-flood zones. If you do happen to live in a non-flood zone, the government caps the price of coverage at $410. Here’s something else you need to know: Because flood insurance is a separate policy, it covers just $250,000 on the dwelling regardless of the value of the home.

There is also an additional $100,000 worth of coverage for the contents of your home, such as furniture and other personal effects. Keep in mind that both of these figures are the maximum amount of coverage provided and may not always be what is given in the event of a flood.

You should also realize that flood insurance does not go into effect for 30 days after purchase. For this reason, you don’t want to wait until you see the hurricane coming before you think about your coverage. For $30 or so a month, I find the coverage to be well worth it. After everything that happened, I’ve definitely purchased flood insurance, myself.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/Videos/2017/September/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+If+a+Storm+Hits%252C+Do+You+Have+Coverage%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.thevaloanguy.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/Videos/2017/September/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+If+a+Storm+Hits%252C+Do+You+Have+Coverage%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>As many people in the wake of these recent hurricanes found out, flood insurance is a separate policy from homeowners insurance. Here’s what you need to know.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>As many people in the wake of these recent hurricanes found out, flood insurance is a separate policy from homeowners insurance. Here’s what you need to know.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Texas Veteran Loans, VA Loans, The VA Loan Guy, Loans for Active Military, Mortgage Banking Firm, Mortgage Banking in Texas, VA Mortgages</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Can You Build With the VA Loan?</title>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/can-you-build-with-the-va-loan.html</link>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-24 13:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/Videos/2017/August/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Can+You+Build+With+the+VA+Loan%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>
Can you use a VA loan to build on land you own? Of course you can.

It doesn’t cost a penny to talk….so call me right now and I will answer your questions!

Apply Now

If you’ve got land, can you use your VA loan to build on it?

The answer is: of course you can.

Now that you know this is a possibility, there are a few things you need to consider before you can make it happen. The first step is to have your home designed.

After you’ve met with an architect to do this, you’ll need to generate the blueprints and specifications.

The next step is to determine what costs will be associated with this process. That cost includes the price of building the home itself, site preparation, and other factors as well.

All of this information that you’ve gathered until this point will then need to be presented to an appraiser. Requesting a VA construction appraisal is different from the normal appraisal process because in this case, the appraiser has no house to look at.

“THE FUNDS FROM THIS 30-YEAR VA LOAN WILL PAY OFF THE CONSTRUCTION LOAN.”

Instead, the appraiser will visit and photograph the site, look at the plans for your home, and find comparable properties in the area.

Within a couple of weeks, the appraiser will determine an approximation of the home’s value upon completion. Having this value from the start is a great way to prevent any unsavory surprises down the road.

After this, you’re finally ready to get a construction loan. If you happen to owe money on the land, the first draw of the construction loan will pay that cost off, as well.

At various points throughout the process, the builder will take draws—with the final draw coming once the house is completed. It is at this point, during the final phase of construction, that your VA loan will be put together.

The funds from this 30-year VA loan will pay off the construction loan. It’s really that simple.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, remember that it costs nothing to talk. Feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/Videos/2017/August/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Can+You+Build+With+the+VA+Loan%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.thevaloanguy.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/Videos/2017/August/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Can+You+Build+With+the+VA+Loan%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
Can you use a VA loan to build on land you own? Of course you can.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
Can you use a VA loan to build on land you own? Of course you can.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Texas Veteran Loans, VA Loans, The VA Loan Guy, Loans for Active Military, Mortgage Banking Firm, Mortgage Banking in Texas, VA Mortgages</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Are VA Appraisals Any Different from Conventional Ones?</title>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/are-va-appraisals-any-different-from-conventional-ones.html</link>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-11 15:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>
Today I wanted to talk about VA appraisals and how they differ from conventional appraisals.

It doesn’t cost a penny to talk….so call me right now and I will answer your questions!

Apply Now

I get a lot of calls about this with lots of questions about the VA appraisal and how it’s different from conventional appraisals. An appraisal is an estimated value of a property done by a licensed appraiser. One thing to remember is that VA appraisals are not that much different from a conventional appraisal.

The appraiser will first visit the property and measure the square footage of the home, take photos of all sides of the home’s exterior, and then photograph of each room inside the home. The appraiser will then take note of any amenities in the home that might affect the value—such as updated kitchens or bathrooms.

If the home has any damage, then it will be noted as a repair on the appraisal. They will take note of any damage to the interior or exterior that can decrease the value of the home—like rotting wood and cracked or peeling paint. If there are any serious matters that need to be addressed, the appraiser will put it in the report given to you and your Realtor.

You need to write up any needed repairs the appraiser sees. This is a VA requirement. The VA doesn’t necessarily need a brand new home, but they want to make sure that the home is in sound condition and that the veteran is not buying a problematic home.

“THE VA DOESN’T NECESSARILY NEED A BRAND NEW HOME, BUT THEY WANT TO MAKE SURE THAT THE HOME IS IN SOUND CONDITION FOR THE VETERAN.”

Once the appraiser finishes the inspection, they will then take pictures of other comparable homes in the neighborhood and with that information, head back to the office to calculate the value of the home. Once the value is determined, it is forwarded to the mortgage company and we have a dollar value for the house that we can work with.

If there are any repairs that were noted on the appraisal, both Realtors are notified that those repairs need to be made in order to close on a VA loan.

If there’s a problem with the value, under the VA loan process we have an opportunity to appeal the value and bring additional comparables to the attention of the appraiser in order to get the value changed.

If you have any additional questions about VA appraisals or any other VA loan-related topic, please give me a call. I’d be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.thevaloanguy.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
Today I wanted to talk about VA appraisals and how they differ from conventional appraisals.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
Today I wanted to talk about VA appraisals and how they differ from conventional appraisals.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Texas Veteran Loans, VA Loans, The VA Loan Guy, Loans for Active Military, Mortgage Banking Firm, Mortgage Banking in Texas, VA Mortgages</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Taxes and Insurance Figure into VA Loans</title>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/how-taxes-and-insurance-figure-into-va-loans.html</link>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-28 10:37:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/Videos/2017/July/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Taxes%252C+VA+loans%252C+Insurance+July+1.mp4</guid>
        <description>
Today I wanted to talk a bit more in-depth about how property taxes and homeowners insurance figure into the VA loan process.

It doesn’t cost a penny to talk….so call me right now and I will answer your questions!

Apply Now

Today I wanted to talk about taxes and insurance and how they figure into a VA loan. I get this question from both veterans and real estate agents alike.

In most areas, real estate taxes are comprised of state, local, city, and school taxes. They are all figured in by the local appraisal district, who then sets the value of the home. Then those taxes are set based on a percentage

The monthly house payments figures into an escrow account that not only includes principal and interest, but also 1/12th of the property taxes that will be due at the end of the year as well as 1/12th of the insurance. In the state of Texas, veterans who are 100% disabled pay absolutely no property taxes whatsoever. The doesn’t happen automatically, however. They have to fill out the appropriate form and send a copy of that to the lender that is holding the loan in order to stop collection of the taxes.

Now I wanted to talk a little bit about homeowners insurance. Homeowners insurance has nothing to do with life insurance or private mortgage insurance. Homeowners insurance covers fire, liability, weather-related issues, but does not cover the home from a flood. Rising water is not covered by regular homeowner’s insurance.

“RISING WATER IS NOT COVERED BY REGULAR HOMEOWNERS INSURANCE.”

Recently I’ve been asked why insurance rates are all over the board, so I did a little digging and contacted three separate insurance agents that I do business with to get an answer. The general consensus is that homeowner’s insurance is based on the size and age of the property. The older a home is, the more claims there can be on it, which will affect your rates.

Insurance rates are also affected by claim history on the home if it’s pre-owned, and the insurance claim history of the buyer themself. Insurance companies also factor in your credit score to determine rates. Generally, there are more claims on insurance policies owned by individuals with lower credit scores. Additionally, the location of the home can affect rates as well.

Something interesting to note is that insurance agents won’t insure individuals who own dogs that are pit bulls or dobermans or similar dog breeds. This is because they have seen a spike in claims related to dog bites, and don’t want to undertake that liability.

I would advise you to bundle your insurance if you can. If you combine your homeowners insurance with your car insurance, you could get up to a 20% reduction in the overall rate.

Like I always say, it doesn’t cost a penny to talk, so if you have any questions at all, give me a call. I’d be happy to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/Videos/2017/July/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Taxes%252C+VA+loans%252C+Insurance+July+1.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.thevaloanguy.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/Videos/2017/July/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Taxes%252C+VA+loans%252C+Insurance+July+1.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
Today I wanted to talk a bit more in-depth about how property taxes and homeowners insurance figure into the VA loan process.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
Today I wanted to talk a bit more in-depth about how property taxes and homeowners insurance figure into the VA loan process.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Texas Veteran Loans, VA Loans, The VA Loan Guy, Loans for Active Military, Mortgage Banking Firm, Mortgage Banking in Texas, VA Mortgages</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Manufactured Homes Made Simple</title>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/manufactured-homes-made-simple.html</link>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-03 13:49:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/Videos/2017/July/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Manufactured+Homes+Made+Simple.mp4</guid>
        <description>
There are a few key rules you should know about in order to get a VA loan under a manufactured home.

It doesn’t cost a penny to talk….so call me right now and I will answer your questions!

Apply Now

If you’re considering using a VA Loan on a manufactured home, I have some information that you’ll need to know.

To begin, you should know that you are, in fact, allowed to have a VA loan under a manufactured home. However, this can be difficult in certain cases. Though VA loans are technically allowed on both double-wide as well as single-wide homes, you will experience a great deal of difficulty in finding a lender who will do a VA loan for you on a single-wide home.

Along with this, there are some other rules. For example, a manufactured home needs to be compliant with any foundation requirements—the home must have a foundation that is attached to the ground, called a HUD-style foundation. Luckily, an engineer can inspect and retrofit this style of foundation on homes that don’t already have one.

Additionally, any wheels or axles must be removed from the home. This is because, from a title standpoint, the home must be considered permanently one with the land.

Speaking of mobility, in order to get a VA loan under a manufactured home, the home must have been moved one or fewer times since its original installment.

“THE VA WANTS BUYERS TO BE SAFE AND HEALTHY WITHIN THEIR HOMES.”

To ensure that these requisites have been met, the home must go through a number of inspections, including a septic inspection, termite inspection, and, if there is one present on the property, a well inspection and water quality test.

While they are negotiable between the buyer and seller, the seller is no longer required to provide funds for these inspections so the impetus falls largely on the buyer to ensure that these inspections are carried out and paid for.

A final rule to keep in mind is that the home must be a 1976 or newer model.

This may seem like a lot, but all of the inspections and regulations required are for the benefit of the veteran—as the VA wants buyers to be safe and healthy within their homes.

Also, while many may say that acreages are not allowed under a VA loan with a manufactured home, this is not the case.

If you want more information on VA loans and manufactured homes, or if I can answer any other questions for you, feel free to get in touch by giving me a call or sending me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/Videos/2017/July/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Manufactured+Homes+Made+Simple.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.thevaloanguy.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/Videos/2017/July/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Manufactured+Homes+Made+Simple.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
There are a few key rules you should know about in order to get a VA loan under a manufactured home.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
There are a few key rules you should know about in order to get a VA loan under a manufactured home.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Texas Veteran Loans, VA Loans, The VA Loan Guy, Loans for Active Military, Mortgage Banking Firm, Mortgage Banking in Texas, VA Mortgages</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Is the Anatomy of a VA Loan?</title>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/what-is-the-anatomy-of-a-va-loan.html</link>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-12 11:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+How+veterans+financing+works.mp4</guid>
        <description>
If you’re thinking of applying for a VA loan, here’s what you should know about them.

It doesn’t cost a penny to talk….so call me right now and I will answer your questions!

Apply Now

The anatomy of a VA loan features four components: principal, interest, property taxes, and homeowners insurance.

In January 2017, the U.S. Department of Veteran Affairs increased the loan amount on a VA loan to $424,100. That’s called the “conforming limit,”  and it means in most states around the country, a veteran can borrow up to $424,100 with no down payment. In other areas of the country where housing is dramatically more expensive (Alaska, Hawaii, California, New York, etc.), the conforming limit is much higher than that.

VA loans don’t require any PMI (private mortgage insurance), but property taxes and insurance must be included with it. The Department of Veteran Affairs has compensated for the rise in home prices by offering jumbo loans or high-balance loans that go above the $424,100 limit. However, that’s also where the no down payment portion ends.

“A VA LOAN ALLOWS YOU TO BORROW UP TO $424,000 WITH NO DOWN PAYMENT.”

If the purchase price of the home is above $424,100, you would have to pay 25% of the overage. For example, if a home is priced at $524,000—which is $100,000 over the limit—that means you’d pay $25,000. There is no limit as to how high you can purchase as you pay 25% of the overage

If you have any questions about the anatomy of a VA loan, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. As I always say, it doesn’t cost a penny to talk. Just give me a call and I’d be happy to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+How+veterans+financing+works.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.thevaloanguy.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+How+veterans+financing+works.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
If you’re thinking of applying for a VA loan, here’s what you should know about them.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
If you’re thinking of applying for a VA loan, here’s what you should know about them.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Texas Veteran Loans, VA Loans, The VA Loan Guy, Loans for Active Military, Mortgage Banking Firm, Mortgage Banking in Texas, VA Mortgages</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Types of Property You Can Buy With VA Financing</title>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/types-of-property-you-can-buy-with-va-financing.html</link>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-22 11:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+The+kinds+of+properties+you+can+purchase.mp4</guid>
        <description>
VA loans allow you to buy a wide variety of properties.

It doesn’t cost a penny to talk….so call me right now and I will answer your questions!

Apply Now

If you plan to use a VA loan, you might be wondering what types of properties you can use your VA loan for.

The most popular use is for a single-family residence, but you can also use a VA loan on a multi-family property like a duplex or triplex, but you can’t go higher than four units in one building. To use it on a multi-family home, the cardinal rule is that the veteran must occupy one of the units as their primary residence. You can also use a VA loan for a condo if it’s on the list of VA-approved condo associations, which I can send you.

You can use a VA loan for a townhouse, and it doesn’t have to be on any list. You can also use it on manufactured homes that are 1976 or newer. It’s allowed for single-wide or double-wide manufactured homes, but it’s almost impossible to find a lender who will offer a loan on a single-wide. Manufactured homes must also be properly attached to the ground with a HUD-style foundation—it can’t just be tied down sitting on concrete blocks.

“YOU CAN BUY MULTI-FAMILY PROPERTIES UP TO FOUR UNITS WITH A VA LOAN.”

You can also use VA loans for modular homes, which are growing in popularity.

I get a lot of questions about using VA loans on acreages as well. Many lenders will tell you that you can’t use it on a property with 20 or 30 acres, but that’s simply not true. VA loans do not have a limit on acreage; it just has to make sense. More importantly, they want to know the use of the land because they don’t want to finance a home if the veteran is going to use it for a for-profit use.

Finally, you can, in fact, use a VA loan for a home with an agricultural tax exemption. You can’t use it to buy raw land, however.

If you have any other questions about the types of property you can buy with a VA loan, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. Like I always say, it doesn’t cost a penny to talk.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+The+kinds+of+properties+you+can+purchase.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.thevaloanguy.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+The+kinds+of+properties+you+can+purchase.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
VA loans allow you to buy a wide variety of properties.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
VA loans allow you to buy a wide variety of properties.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Texas Veteran Loans, VA Loans, The VA Loan Guy, Loans for Active Military, Mortgage Banking Firm, Mortgage Banking in Texas, VA Mortgages</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Can You Still Get a VA Loan Post-Bankruptcy?</title>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/can-you-still-get-a-va-loan-post-bankruptcy.html</link>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-05 15:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Veterans+financing+post-bankruptcy.mp4</guid>
        <description>
If you had a bankruptcy in the past and it involved a home that you used a VA loan to purchase, you haven’t lost your eligibility. Here’s the situation you’ll face instead.

It doesn’t cost a penny to talk….so call me right now and I will answer your questions!

Apply Now

If you’ve had a bankruptcy in the past and it involved a home you used a VA loan to finance—have you lost your eligibility?

No, you haven’t. The Department of Veterans Affairs has a heart. They’ll always note that they lost money in that situation, but they have a non-collection policy.

“YOU ARE STILL ELIGIBLE FOR A VA LOAN, BUT ONLY AFTER A CERTAIN AMOUNT OF TIME HAS PASSED.”

Instead, they will send you a new certificate of eligibility request, note how much they lost on the home, and deduct that amount from your eligibility. You still have eligibility and you can still get another VA loan just as long as at least two years have passed since the bankruptcy.

Remember, if you have any questions about this or any other subject, feel free to give me a call. I’d be happy to talk to you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Veterans+financing+post-bankruptcy.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.thevaloanguy.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Veterans+financing+post-bankruptcy.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
If you had a bankruptcy in the past and it involved a home that you used a VA loan to purchase, you haven’t lost your eligibility. Here’s the situation you’ll face instead.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
If you had a bankruptcy in the past and it involved a home that you used a VA loan to purchase, you haven’t lost your eligibility. Here’s the situation you’ll face instead.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Texas Veteran Loans, VA Loans, The VA Loan Guy, Loans for Active Military, Mortgage Banking Firm, Mortgage Banking in Texas, VA Mortgages</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Who Qualifies for VA Loans?</title>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/who-qualifies-for-va-loans.html</link>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-24 14:54:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Who+Qualifies+for+a+VA+Loan%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>
Who can qualify for a VA loan? Do you have to have military benefits? I’ll go over the answers to those questions today.

It doesn’t cost a penny to talk….so call me right now and I will answer your questions!

Apply Now

Who qualifies for a VA loan? I get asked this question quite often, and I’ll go over the details behind qualifying today.

It’s true that in order to qualify for a VA loan, you have to be a veteran. However, a lot of veterans have spouses that are not associated with the military. Can they both qualify if that’s the case? The answer is yes.

Fiances are another story. If you are not married, your fiance would also have to have military benefits in order for you to both qualify. If the fiance of a spouse does not have military benefits, they would not qualify for the loan.

“THE SPOUSE OF A VETERAN CAN QUALIFY FOR A VA LOAN.”

The main thing that the VA wants to achieve is making sure the people taking advantage of VA loans are actually living in the home purchased with one. Gone are the days when people could co-sign for a VA loan. Again, a spouse can certainly co-sign and qualify for a VA loan but don’t plan on having a fiance do that unless they qualify on their own.

If you have any other questions please feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Who+Qualifies+for+a+VA+Loan%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.thevaloanguy.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Who+Qualifies+for+a+VA+Loan%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
Who can qualify for a VA loan? Do you have to have military benefits? I’ll go over the answers to those questions today.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
Who can qualify for a VA loan? Do you have to have military benefits? I’ll go over the answers to those questions today.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Texas Veteran Loans, VA Loans, The VA Loan Guy, Loans for Active Military, Mortgage Banking Firm, Mortgage Banking in Texas, VA Mortgages</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Answering Some Common VA Loan Questions</title>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/answering-some-common-va-loan-questions.html</link>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-06 14:49:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Can+You+Have+Two+VA+Loans+at+Once%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>
I get a lot of questions about VA loans and the eligibility restrictions. Can you use a second VA loan? Can you rent a home purchased with a VA loan? Find out here.

It doesn’t cost a penny to talk….so call me right now and I will answer your questions!

Apply Now

I’ve been getting a lot of questions lately from people, which is great. I wanted to answer a few of them today. One of the most common questions I get asked about VA loans goes like this: “Pat, I have used my VA loan to buy a home in the past, can I use it again?”

The simple answer is absolutely yes. All veterans and active military have the benefit of using VA eligibility to buy a home. When someone uses it the first time, all they have to do is pay off the house or sell their current home, and it will free up their eligibility.

“THE SIMPLE ANSWER IS ABSOLUTELY YES.”

The other question I often get goes like this: “I already have a home with a VA loan on it, and I have been renting that home out. Can I buy another house with a VA loan as well?”

Yes, you can have two VA loans at once, but there are some restrictions. You will have to fill out a form for us, and then we can insert those numbers and tell you how much more you can borrow on another VA loan in addition to your first.

If you have any questions about this topic or any mortgage needs, give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to helping you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Can+You+Have+Two+VA+Loans+at+Once%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.thevaloanguy.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Can+You+Have+Two+VA+Loans+at+Once%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
I get a lot of questions about VA loans and the eligibility restrictions. Can you use a second VA loan? Can you rent a home purchased with a VA loan? Find out here.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
I get a lot of questions about VA loans and the eligibility restrictions. Can you use a second VA loan? Can you rent a home purchased with a VA loan? Find out here.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Texas Veteran Loans, VA Loans, The VA Loan Guy, Loans for Active Military, Mortgage Banking Firm, Mortgage Banking in Texas, VA Mortgages</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>I Specialize in Working with Military Clients</title>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/i-specialize-in-working-with-military-clients.html</link>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-16 13:31:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+My+specialty+is+military+loans.mp4</guid>
        <description>
I offer all types of mortgages, but my specialty is making sure military personnel can buy their dream homes.

It doesn’t cost a penny to talk….so call me right now and I will answer your questions!

Apply Now

I’m a loan officer here at Guild Mortgage in San Antonio and a mortgage expert. Although I do offer conventional, FHA, and all other different types of loans, my specialty is helping military personnel with their home loan needs. I’ve been doing this for the past 15 years.

One of the unique things I do is meet with my clients in person. A lot of our competition doesn’t do this anymore, but I think it’s important to be able to talk to someone in person when going through the home buying process. There are a lot of options to choose from and a lot of paperwork needed to determine what you qualify for.

“IT DOESN’T COST A THING TO TALK TO ME ON THE PHONE.”

If you have any questions for me, I would be glad to answer them. I’m here six days a week in my office and when you dial me, you will talk to me. I don’t have a receptionist or assistant answering my calls for me. I’m here for you, so don’t hesitate to give me a call. It doesn’t cost a thing to talk to me on the phone. I look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+My+specialty+is+military+loans.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.thevaloanguy.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Patrick+Fitzgerald/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+My+specialty+is+military+loans.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
I offer all types of mortgages, but my specialty is making sure military personnel can buy their dream homes.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
I offer all types of mortgages, but my specialty is making sure military personnel can buy their dream homes.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Texas Veteran Loans, VA Loans, The VA Loan Guy, Loans for Active Military, Mortgage Banking Firm, Mortgage Banking in Texas, VA Mortgages</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Patrick Fitzgerald</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Patrick Fitzgerald</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">Patrick Fitzgerald, the VA Loan Guy, is located in San Antonio, Texas and is a true “One Stop Lender”. We originate, underwrite, and close all types of loans. We offer Texas Vet, Veterans, FHA, Conventional, Jumbo, Adjustable Rate, and Investment products.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
