<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Memphis Real Estate Podcast with Melissa Thompson</title>
    <link>localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Your Key To Memphis - your professional Memphis Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Melissa Thompson</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2017-07-26 13:12:32 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Melissa Thompson</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Melissa@YourKeyToMemphis.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Melissa Thompson</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Memphis Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Your Key To Memphis - your professional Memphis Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>101 Things To Do In Memphis #76: The Bar-B-Q Shop</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/101-things-to-do-in-memphis-76-bar-b-q.html</link>
        
          <category>101 Things to do in Memphis</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-26 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>
The Bar-B-Q Shop, voted #1 ribs in America by the Food Network’s “Top Five Restaurants”, located in the heart of Midtown, less than a mile from the Overton Square Entertainment District, is a local Memphis barbecue eatery that opened in November of 1987. It is a place known for real-pit barbecue with old fashioned barbecue sauces and cole slaw that are made from scratch.

The unique taste of The Bar-B-Q Shop’s gourmet award winning sauces has always been something that has set The Bar-B-Q Shop off from other barbeque restaurants. The recipes for our gourmet sauces have been around for over fifty years.

The Original (mild) Sauce provides a thickness that can be used to baste, marinade, or provide flavoring for your meat of choice.

Our Hot Sauce also provides the same level of thickness but with a little warmth behind it. Our Hot Sauce does an excellent job of providing your meat with a hot flavor without taking away from the barbeque, smokey flavor itself.

The Bar-B-Q Shop’s Dry Seasoning was created later by Frank Vernon in the mid eighties. Our Dry Seasoning is an extraordinary seasoning because it can be used to season anything from chicken breasts, hamburger steaks, salmon or fillet catfish, to even a beef roast. The seasoning can be used with a marinade while prepping your food item, or it can be applied when your food comes out of the oven.

1782 Madison Ave, Memphis, TN 38104
Restaurant: 901.272.1277
Sauce Order: 888.372.8237

By and photo credit: The Bar-B-Q Shop
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
The Bar-B-Q Shop, voted #1 ribs in America by the Food Network’s “Top Five Restaurants”, located in the heart of Midtown, less than a mile from the Overton Square Entertainment District, is a local Memphis barbecue eatery that opened in November of 1987. It is a place known for real-pit barbecue with old fashioned barbecue sauces and cole slaw that are made from scratch.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
The Bar-B-Q Shop, voted #1 ribs in America by the Food Network’s “Top Five Restaurants”, located in the heart of Midtown, less than a mile from the Overton Square Entertainment District, is a local Memphis barbecue eatery that opened in November of 1987. It is a place known for real-pit barbecue with old fashioned barbecue sauces and cole slaw that are made from scratch.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>101 Things To Do In Memphis #76: The Bar-B-Q Shop</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/singles-are-falling-for-their-dream.html</link>
        
          <category>101 Things to do in Memphis</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-26 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>
Some Highlights:

-According to NAR’s Profile of Home Buyers &amp; Sellers, the share of recent homebuyers who were single at the time of purchase held steady at 24% last year.

-The percentage of first-time buyers who were single females rose to 17% (up from 16%), as the share of single men dropped from 11% to 8%.

-The primary reason for buying a home amongst singles was the desire to own a home of their own (38% for women and 37% for men).
​
​Contact your local expert’s at The Melissa Thompson Team 901-729-9526 to find out if you qualify to buy your dream home!

By: KCM Crew
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
Some Highlights:

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
Some Highlights:

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Luxurious Laundry Rooms</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/luxurious-laundry-rooms.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Improvement</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-24 11:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>The laundry room is probably not the first space you think of when you hear the word luxurious.  But it is a room you spend a lot of time in.  Doing laundry is a necessary part of life, so why not make it more appealing by creating a comfortable, practical and pretty environment that will make it feel less like a chore and more like a pleasant task. You don’t have to spend a lot of money to make your laundry room a calm and soothing work space.  There are opulent touches you can add that will improve your disposition while performing the essential duties of washing, drying, folding and ironing.
*Paint the room in a soft, neutral color - choose from greens, blues or yellow.

-Hang some art on the walls.  Pick pieces that you love or are meaningful to you. You don’t have to spend a lot of money…just choose paintings or pictures that bring you joy.



-If you lack storage in your laundry room, add some simple shelves with clean lines.  Get some clear containers for your detergent, fabric softener sheets, clothes pins etc. so you can dispose of the unsightly bags and boxes they come in.

-Use baskets or bins to pre-sort clothes into whites, colors, sheets, towels etc.

-If your laundry room is spacious, create a folding area.  You can have a table or if you are using front loading machines, design a counter to go on top of them.



-Add a small, wall-mounted television and a comfy chair, and folding clothes won’t seem so boring anymore.

-Add a small vase with fresh flowers.  Being amidst the beauty of nature will make you feel better about being stuck indoors doing laundry!

Remember, guests are not likely to see your laundry room, so make it all about YOU.  Be funky and unique with your décor and have fun with it!  Before you know it, you will look forward to doing all that washing, drying and folding.  Ok…maybe you won’t look forward to it, but at least you won’t dread it!

More Resources:
Quick Fix Tricks to Make Your House Sparkling Clean
Top Home Renovations for Maximum ROI
Clearing the Clutter
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>The laundry room is probably not the first space you think of when you hear the word luxurious.  But it is a room you spend a lot of time in.  Doing laundry is a necessary part of life, so why not make it more appealing by creating a comfortable, practical and pretty environment that will make it feel less like a chore and more like a pleasant task. You don’t have to spend a lot of money to make your laundry room a calm and soothing work space.  There are opulent touches you can add that will improve your disposition while performing the essential duties of washing, drying, folding and ironing.
*Paint the room in a soft, neutral color - choose from greens, blues or yellow.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>The laundry room is probably not the first space you think of when you hear the word luxurious.  But it is a room you spend a lot of time in.  Doing laundry is a necessary part of life, so why not make it more appealing by creating a comfortable, practical and pretty environment that will make it feel less like a chore and more like a pleasant task. You don’t have to spend a lot of money to make your laundry room a calm and soothing work space.  There are opulent touches you can add that will improve your disposition while performing the essential duties of washing, drying, folding and ironing.
*Paint the room in a soft, neutral color - choose from greens, blues or yellow.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>101 Things To Do In Memphis #75: 29th Annual WEVL Blues on the Bluff</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/101-things-to-do-in-memphis-75-29th.html</link>
        
          <category>101 Things to do in Memphis</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-19 13:52:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>
Bring your chairs and blankets and celebrate 29 years of fun on the bluffs of the Mississippi River in a beautiful park-like setting on the grounds of The Metal Museum.
Giant shady oaks, cool river breezes, the smell of BBQ, fantastic music, and absolutely the best view of the Mississippi in the entire mid-South!

Details:
Schlafly Beer is the beer sponsor.
Beer, wine and non-alcoholic drinks being sold
Award-winning BBQ and more from Central BBQ Food Truck being sold
No pets or outside food or beverage permitted
Kids welcome when accompanied by watchful parents
Silent auction
WEVL Merchandise and Blues on the Bluff posters for sale
Free guarded parking

The line-up:
The MD’s
6:30 p.m.
The Ghost Town Blues Band
8 p.m.
Marcella &amp; Her Lovers
9:35 p.m.

Admission is $20 in advance, $25 at the gate
Kids 11 and under are $12 at the gate

Saturday, July 22nd
Gates open at 6 p.m.

By and photo credit: http://wevl.org/bob
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
Bring your chairs and blankets and celebrate 29 years of fun on the bluffs of the Mississippi River in a beautiful park-like setting on the grounds of The Metal Museum.
Giant shady oaks, cool river breezes, the smell of BBQ, fantastic music, and absolutely the best view of the Mississippi in the entire mid-South!

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
Bring your chairs and blankets and celebrate 29 years of fun on the bluffs of the Mississippi River in a beautiful park-like setting on the grounds of The Metal Museum.
Giant shady oaks, cool river breezes, the smell of BBQ, fantastic music, and absolutely the best view of the Mississippi in the entire mid-South!

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 Important Things to Fix Before Putting Your House on the Market</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/5-important-things-to-fix-before.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Improvement</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-17 14:13:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>
If you want the best price for your house, you may have to do some repairs before selling it. Potential buyers will be willing to spend more for a home that doesn’t need a lot of work.  Here are 5 important things to fix before selling:


  
    Exterior - When was the last time the exterior of your house was painted?  Is the paint faded and chipping?  Is wood rotting around the windows?  Is your front door dingy?  First impressions matter when it comes to selling your home and buyers will get their first impression when they see the outside of your house whether in pictures or in person.  Don’t forget the landscaping.  A well-kept lawn and simple, but clean flower beds will go a long way toward creating an enticing aesthetic for your property.
  
  
    Interior Paint - If the walls are looking a bit shabby and the trim a bit grimy, painting is a quick and easy fix.  The same applies if you went through a crazy color phase a few years back and decorated with hues that might not appeal to everyone.  Choose neutral colors that will allow buyers to focus on the spaces without being distracted.
  
  
    Kitchen - The kitchen is one of the most important rooms that buyers focus on when looking at a house.  So, if yours is looking run-down you will want to update it.  It will be worth the investment to replace appliances that are on their last legs or putting in a new granite counter.  Or it might be as simple as repainting cabinets and adding shiny, new handles.
  
  
    Bathroom - Nothing turns buyers off faster than an unsightly bathroom.  Sparkling, clean fixtures and a fresh coat of paint will go a long way toward impressing someone searching for their dream home.  Inexpensive touches like a decorative mirror or a lovely picture on the wall will add to the ambiance without breaking the bank.
  
  
    Flooring - If your carpets are stained or thread bare, it is worth your while to replace them.  Otherwise, buyers may ask for a carpet allowance when they make an offer on your house.  The same applies if your vinyl floors are in bad shape.  Hardwoods are always popular, but you may want to consider getting them refinished if they are looking old and scruffy.
  


It may seem counter intuitive to spend money on repairing or fixing up a house you are getting ready to sell, but at the end of the day, it will not only help you sell your house faster, but you will get a better price for it too.

More Resources:
Quick Fix Tricks to Make Your House Sparkling
Tips for Showing Your Home to Potential Buyers
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
If you want the best price for your house, you may have to do some repairs before selling it. Potential buyers will be willing to spend more for a home that doesn’t need a lot of work.  Here are 5 important things to fix before selling:

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
If you want the best price for your house, you may have to do some repairs before selling it. Potential buyers will be willing to spend more for a home that doesn’t need a lot of work.  Here are 5 important things to fix before selling:

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3 Tips to Protect First-Time Homebuyers</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/3-tips-to-protect-first-time-homebuyers.html</link>
        
          <category>Buying a House</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-12 12:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2017/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+3+Tips+to+Protect+First-Time+Homebuyers.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you or someone you know is considering buying a home for the first time, there are a few things you need to be aware of. Here are our top three tips to protect first-time homebuyers:


  Know what you can afford. This doesn’t just include your mortgage payment. You need to make sure you can afford that in addition to property taxes, utilities, and various other maintenance fees.


“HOME VALUES HAVE BEEN INCREASING YEAR BY YEAR IN MEMPHIS.”


  
    Choose your lender wisely. Online lenders aren’t always the best option, even if they advertise the lowest rate. You should really get a recommendation from a Realtor or some other person you trust. Local lenders tend to work best in terms of being able to close on time.
  
  
    Don’t overlook the details. Purchase contracts have a lot of them. Take your time to read through it carefully and don’t hesitate to ask your Realtor any questions you have.
  


These are just three tips for successfully buying a home for the first time. If you would like some more tips or just have a question, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2017/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+3+Tips+to+Protect+First-Time+Homebuyers.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2017/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+3+Tips+to+Protect+First-Time+Homebuyers.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you or someone you know is considering buying a home for the first time, there are a few things you need to be aware of. Here are our top three tips to protect first-time homebuyers:

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you or someone you know is considering buying a home for the first time, there are a few things you need to be aware of. Here are our top three tips to protect first-time homebuyers:

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Promising Numbers From Our Memphis Market</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/promising-numbers-from-our-memphis.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-23 08:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+Your+latest+Memphis+market+update.mp4</guid>
        <description>

How do the numbers from our current market compare to where we were at this time last year?

The number of units sold has risen 9% from 1,625 to 1,771, which is good. Home values have been increasing year by year in the Memphis area as a whole, and the median sale price is up to $165,000. The number of home sales above $500,000 has increased 32%.

“HOME VALUES HAVE BEEN INCREASING YEAR BY YEAR IN MEMPHIS.”

On a related note, I’d like to remind you that we’re donating the commission of our 100th home sale to a local charity, and you have the opportunity to vote on this website for who wins. The candidates are HopeWorks, Youth Villages, and the Bartlett Animal Shelter.

If you have any questions about our market, you’d like to know what your home is worth, or you’re thinking about buying or selling a home, feel free to reach out to me. I’d be happy to assist you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+Your+latest+Memphis+market+update.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+Your+latest+Memphis+market+update.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

How do the numbers from our current market compare to where we were at this time last year?

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

How do the numbers from our current market compare to where we were at this time last year?

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Make Your Offer on a Memphis Home Stand Out</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-to-make-your-offer-on-memphis-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-13 13:36:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-How+to+win+a+multiple+offer+situation.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’re looking to buy a home here in Memphis, you might have to compete against other offers for a home you like.

For starters, remember that no other buyers know what the offers are, so you don’t have to worry about your offer being revealed. However, you can do a few things to make your offer better.

First, put down as much earnest money as possible. This speaks volumes to the seller about your interest level in the home and that you can follow through with the loan process. Putting down a small amount means you don’t have any skin in the game, and the seller might not see your offer as worth it at that point.

Secondly, show the seller that you are qualified for a home loan. Get fully pre-approved for a loan instead of just getting pre-qualified, which carries less weight. An offer with a pre-approval is akin to a cash offer for a seller.

“SHOW THE SELLER THAT YOU ARE QUALIFIED FOR A HOME LOAN.”

You can also give the seller extra time to move. Call the listing agent and ask them what’s important to their seller, because it’s not always all about money. For example, I recently worked with a seller who needed to rent the house back for a couple months after closing because they have a handicapped child. There are many situations going on in people’s lives, and accommodating them can help you win the home.

Finally, add a personal touch by writing a letter telling the seller why you love the home. Also be aware of what you’re willing to pay for the home.

If you have any questions about multiple offer situations when buying a home, give us a call or send us an email soon. We’d be more than happy to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-How+to+win+a+multiple+offer+situation.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-How+to+win+a+multiple+offer+situation.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you’re looking to buy a home here in Memphis, you might have to compete against other offers for a home you like.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you’re looking to buy a home here in Memphis, you might have to compete against other offers for a home you like.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Get the Best Possible Credit When Applying for a Home Loan</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-to-get-best-possible-credit-when.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-24 13:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+get+your+credit+mortgage+loan+ready.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’re thinking about buying a home, you need to start preparing to have the best possible credit when applying for a mortgage loan.

First, pay attention to your accounts. Don’t close any accounts or open any new ones when preparing to buy a home. Also, make sure your credit to debt ratio looks good on all your open accounts. If you have a $500 limit, don’t let the balance sit at $495.

Next, don’t switch jobs. If you do need to switch, try to stay in the same field so lenders have information about the switch. They want to see some job security, so if you’ve hopped around a lot that can be a problem.

“DON’T CLOSE ANY ACCOUNTS OR OPEN ANY NEW ONES WHEN PREPARING TO BUY A HOME.”

Pay attention to your balances. If you have a high limit and you’ve maxed that out, it won’t look good to lenders. On the other hand, if you had a credit card that you use and pay off regularly, lenders will love that.

Finally, don’t make any big purchases until after closing on a home. After you’ve got the keys to your new home, feel free to get that new furniture, just hold off until then.

If you have any questions or are looking to buy or sell a home, please feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I’m always happy to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+get+your+credit+mortgage+loan+ready.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+get+your+credit+mortgage+loan+ready.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you’re thinking about buying a home, you need to start preparing to have the best possible credit when applying for a mortgage loan.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you’re thinking about buying a home, you need to start preparing to have the best possible credit when applying for a mortgage loan.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Homeowners & Homebuyers Need to Know About Taxes</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/what-homeowners-homebuyers-need-to-know.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-20 12:39:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today I’m here with Wendy Thompson of the Wendy Thompson Lending Team to talk about your tax appraisal. Unless you live in the downtown area, you should have received your appraisal by now.

If you disagree with your appraisal, you can go to the Shelby County tax assessor site and fill out an informal request for a reassessment. You don’t have to provide a lot of documentation for an informal request, so it is a fairly easy process. That said, there is a short time frame for informal requests. Beginning on May 1st, you can make a formal request. That is a much more involved process.

“MAKE SURE YOUR LENDER IS USING THE CORRECT TAX ASSESSMENT.”

If you are selling your house and your taxes have gone up, this could impact you. Since taxes are divided between you and your potential buyer at closing, the buyer could come to you and ask for additional taxes since your appraisal went up.

If you are a buyer and you are currently under contract to purchase a home, make sure that your lender is using the correct tax assessment. Unfortunately, in some instances even a slight increase in monthly taxes can make a huge difference between getting approved for a loan or not.

As always, if you have any questions about this topic, just give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+Is+your+tax+appraisal+too+high%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today I’m here with Wendy Thompson of the Wendy Thompson Lending Team to talk about your tax appraisal. Unless you live in the downtown area, you should have received your appraisal by now.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today I’m here with Wendy Thompson of the Wendy Thompson Lending Team to talk about your tax appraisal. Unless you live in the downtown area, you should have received your appraisal by now.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Will Recent Interest Rate Changes Affect You?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-will-recent-interest-rate-changes.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-06 13:03:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+recent+interest+rate+changes+affect+you.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Interest rates have been a hot topic recently, so today, I’ve brought in Wendy Thompson with the Wendy Thompson Lending Team of Bank of England Mortgage to help me explain.

The Federal Reserve raised interest rates by 0.25% last week, and the market actually responded very positively. Rates had been rising before, but we’ve actually settled with rates at about 4.25% with FHA, VA, and USDA interest rates at 4%. The Federal Reserve anticipates two more rate increases of 0.25% this year as well.

The good thing is that despite the recent rise, rates are still very low. If you’re thinking about buying a new home, it’s better to act sooner than later.

Rates have been so low for so long that it’s actually better for the economy for them to go up now. After all, we all want our retirement funds and investments to do well also. The impact of rising rates on your costs isn’t substantial either. For a $200,000 home, a 0.25% increase in rates only equates to about $25 more per month. Historically speaking, having rates this low is great compared to the 18% I saw when I started in real estate.

“RATES HAVE BEEN SO LOW FOR SO LONG THAT IT’S ACTUALLY BETTER FOR THE ECONOMY FOR THEM TO GO UP NOW.”

Many people don’t know that mortgage-backed securities control mortgage rates. That’s why it’s important to work with a mortgage lender who follows rate changes daily. As Wendy says, it’s a bit volatile right now because things outside of the country can even have an effect on rates, so they can change on a dime. Having a knowledgeable lender is more important in these conditions.

If you have any questions for Wendy about rates or getting approved for a home loan, you can reach her at Wendy@TheWendyThompsonTeam.com or give her a call at 901-461-8858.

As always, if you have any questions about our market or you’re thinking about buying or selling a home, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I’d be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+recent+interest+rate+changes+affect+you.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+recent+interest+rate+changes+affect+you.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Interest rates have been a hot topic recently, so today, I’ve brought in Wendy Thompson with the Wendy Thompson Lending Team of Bank of England Mortgage to help me explain.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Interest rates have been a hot topic recently, so today, I’ve brought in Wendy Thompson with the Wendy Thompson Lending Team of Bank of England Mortgage to help me explain.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Dont Let Your Pets Mess up Your Home Sale</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/dont-let-your-pets-mess-up-your-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-04 12:02:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+ways+Fido+can+ruin+your+home+showings.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I have a pet and I love animals but, unfortunately, pets can mess up your home sale. After all, the way we live in our home every day is different from the way we live in it after it has been on the market. Here are five things you need to pay attention to when selling a home with pets:


  
    Tufts of fur: If you have a cat or dog that sheds, you need to clean up the extra fur that gathers around the house so that your home doesn’t look messy.
  
  
    Floor stains: Redo your hardwood floors if need be and make sure that any pet stains are cleaned out of the carpet.
  


“CLEAN UP ANY PET STAINS TO THE BEST OF YOUR ABILITY.”


  
    Pet odors: You can get used to the smell when you live there, but you don’t want buyers to walk in and think your house smells like wet dog. Pet stores sell products, like candles, that will cover up pet odors without being too overwhelming.
  
  
    Scratches and dings: Puppies love to chew and scratch at things. If you have marks on your furniture, there are special pens out there that can cover those up. Pay attention to your windowsills and doors, as dogs tend to scratch on those as well.
  
  
    Bowls, pet beds, and litter boxes: Put away all of the pet paraphernalia that you can and make sure that the litter box is clean; buyers don’t want to see or smell that.
  


Take care of these five things so that your home shows well. If you have any other questions about selling with pets or about the home-selling process in general, give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+ways+Fido+can+ruin+your+home+showings.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+ways+Fido+can+ruin+your+home+showings.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

I have a pet and I love animals but, unfortunately, pets can mess up your home sale. After all, the way we live in our home every day is different from the way we live in it after it has been on the market. Here are five things you need to pay attention to when selling a home with pets:

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

I have a pet and I love animals but, unfortunately, pets can mess up your home sale. After all, the way we live in our home every day is different from the way we live in it after it has been on the market. Here are five things you need to pay attention to when selling a home with pets:

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Selling in 2017? Start Your Renovations Now</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/selling-in-2017-start-your-renovations.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-20 10:04:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+Why+Make+Those+Pre-List+Renovations+Now%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There are a few good reasons to do some renovations in your home, especially if you plan to sell this year.

For one, if you renovate now, you get to enjoy the new stuff! There are plenty of things you may have put off, like new appliances or granite countertops, so why not enjoy them a bit before selling your house? Give yourself a chance to cook with those new appliances first.

The second reason to start renovations early is that they always take longer than you expect. If you get an estimated timeline of six weeks, plan on 12 weeks. It’s just the nature of the beast. If you plan for this, you won’t have to be stressed about getting your house finished and on the market in a certain amount of time.

Thirdly, you might run into issues that you’re not aware of. A big part of my job is going to potential listings early to get a look at things that might need to be done. We often uncover issues that you never notice because you live in the home every day.

“YOUR RENOVATIONS DON’T HAVE TO BE MASSIVE.”

Your renovations don’t have to be huge. I’m not talking about taking things down to the studs for a renovation. In fact, that’s not beneficial in many cases. **My goal is to get you $3 in return for every $1 you spend. **

The fifth reason is that in this competitive market, you simply might need renovations. With the popularity of HGTV in the last few years, we see that buyers simply want what they want. As an agent, I know these things that buyers want to see in a home and will get you more money for your home in the long run.

Finally, if you make the right renovations, you’ll see a good return on your investment. Again, we want to get $3 in return for every $1 you spend on these renovations. My main job is to identify the best ways to do this ahead of time.

If you’re thinking about selling your house this year and you’d like to know more about the smart renovations that will increase your net sales price, give me a call or send me an email. I’d be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+Why+Make+Those+Pre-List+Renovations+Now%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+Why+Make+Those+Pre-List+Renovations+Now%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

There are a few good reasons to do some renovations in your home, especially if you plan to sell this year.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

There are a few good reasons to do some renovations in your home, especially if you plan to sell this year.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Get Pre-Approved Before You Start Your Home Search</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/get-pre-approved-before-you-start-your.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-02 16:28:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Before you start your home search, it is incredibly important that you get pre-approved for a mortgage. There are many reasons why, but Fannie Mae recently released an article about the four C’s:


  
    Capacity: This refers to your current and future ability to make your house payments. What do you want to spend? You don’t want all of your money to go to house payments or you will end up house poor.
  
  
    Capital or cash reserves: How much money do you have available? What do you want to put down in order to get the home?
  
  
    Collateral: What type of home do you want? What size should the home be?
  
  
    Credit history: The lender will look at your credit score and your credit history.
  


“WHAT DO YOU WANT TO SPEND ON YOUR MONTHLY HOUSE PAYMENTS?”

We have several great lenders that can help you get pre-approved before you start looking at homes. If you would like more information, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Before you start your home search, it is incredibly important that you get pre-approved for a mortgage. There are many reasons why, but Fannie Mae recently released an article about the four C’s:

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Before you start your home search, it is incredibly important that you get pre-approved for a mortgage. There are many reasons why, but Fannie Mae recently released an article about the four C’s:

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Can You Expect When Hiring a Home Inspector?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/what-can-you-expect-when-hiring-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-16 10:56:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+can+you+expect+from+home+inspectors%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Once you’re under contract for a home and you’ve hired a home inspector to do an inspection, what can you expect from them? What does a home inspector do, exactly?

During their inspection, inspectors aren’t looking for cosmetic concerns like whether or not to repaint the bathroom or whether the wallpaper should come off. Instead, they’re looking for things of importance like heating, electrical, cooking, and other systems vital to the integrity of the house.

“INSPECTORS ARE LOOKING FOR WHAT’S IMPORTANT—NOT ANY COSMETIC FLAWS.”

After they’re done inspecting those items, they’ll give you a report on the house. As the buyer, this report goes to you only. It doesn’t go to the seller unless their agent requests it. After you receive this report, it’s up to you to look through it, see what’s important to you, and negotiate with the seller going forward.

If you have any questions about this topic or are looking to buy or sell a home in our market, please feel free to give me a call or shoot me an email. I’d be happy to speak with you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+can+you+expect+from+home+inspectors%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+can+you+expect+from+home+inspectors%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Once you’re under contract for a home and you’ve hired a home inspector to do an inspection, what can you expect from them? What does a home inspector do, exactly?

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Once you’re under contract for a home and you’ve hired a home inspector to do an inspection, what can you expect from them? What does a home inspector do, exactly?

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Do You Need to Know About TRID?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/what-do-you-need-to-know-about-trid.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-19 14:02:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+does+TRID+do%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

You may have heard the acronym TRID before, but you also may not be totally clear about what it is and how it can affect you.

If you’re a buyer or under contract, you’ve already heard, but here are the basics. TRID was put into effect in October 2015 to protect buyers. TRID allows buyers to have three days prior to closing to look at all your documents as a buyer.

“TRID IS IN PLACE TO HELP BUYERS.”

As a seller, you have a closing date and a possession date which is however many days after the closing date. The three-day TRID window takes place in that time period. We do the best we can, but we are at the mercy of the lenders most of the time. TRID is a good thing and it helps protect consumers, but things can get awfully hairy if you’re in a rush.

Make sure your lender gets it out in time because although we will do everything we can to have this not affect your closing, it still can. If you have any questions, don’t hesitate to reach out and give me a call or send me an email. We look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+does+TRID+do%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+does+TRID+do%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

You may have heard the acronym TRID before, but you also may not be totally clear about what it is and how it can affect you.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

You may have heard the acronym TRID before, but you also may not be totally clear about what it is and how it can affect you.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Is Winter a Good Time to Sell Your House?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/why-is-winter-good-time-to-sell-your.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-06 10:25:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+Why+winter+is+a+great+time+to+sell+your+house.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Is winter a good time to put your home on the market? It’s actually the second best time to sell a home, just behind springtime. Why?

There is less inventory on the market for buyers to choose from, and those buyers out looking in the winter are great buyers. These buyers are moving for a reason; they’re not the semi-serious tire kickers that you see looking at houses in the spring and summer.

“WINTER IS STILL A GREAT TIME TO SELL YOUR HOUSE.”

Interest rates went up a little bit after the election, but they are still very low. These low rates have been the tipping point for some buyers who have been on the fence.

If you have any questions about selling during the winter or you’re thinking about buying or selling a house, give me a call or send me an email soon. I’d be happy to help in any way I can!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+Why+winter+is+a+great+time+to+sell+your+house.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+Why+winter+is+a+great+time+to+sell+your+house.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Is winter a good time to put your home on the market? It’s actually the second best time to sell a home, just behind springtime. Why?

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Is winter a good time to put your home on the market? It’s actually the second best time to sell a home, just behind springtime. Why?

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Melissa Thompson</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Melissa Thompson</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Your Key To Memphis - your professional Memphis Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
