<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Florida's Emerald Coast Real Estate Podcast with Nathan Abbott</title>
    <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://ownemeraldcoast.com"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Nathan Abbott Team - your professional Florida's Emerald Coast Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Nathan Abbott</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2017-06-20 13:06:10 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Nathan Abbott</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://ownemeraldcoast.com/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Florida's Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">News &amp; Politics</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Nathan@NathanAbbottTeam.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Nathan Abbott</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Nathan Abbott</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://ownemeraldcoast.com/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Florida's Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Florida's Emerald Coast Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Nathan Abbott Team - your professional Florida's Emerald Coast Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="News &amp; Politics"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>Exploring the Beautiful Waterways of the Emerald Coast</title>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/exploring-the-beautiful-waterways-of-the-emerald-coast.html</link>
        
          <category>Venue Reviews</category>
        
        <author>Nathan Abbott</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-14 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Cruising+the+Emerald+Coast+waterways.mp4</guid>
        <description>

One of the first things people think of when they visit the Destin area is our white sand beaches and the Gulf of Mexico, but this is also a boater’s dream with plenty of places to explore throughout all of our coastal waterways. There are so many wonderful places to explore by water to create memories that last forever.

Recently I visited the Fort Walton Beach sound on the west side of Mary Esther to do a little boating on the adjoining intercoastal waterway and along the Destin harbor. There are many beaches like the one I’m standing on in the video above scattered up and down the coastline, and we’re fortunate to live in such a beautiful area.

“We’d be honored to give you a private tour of waterfront properties if you want.”

Destin’s original tag line was “The World’s Luckiest Fishing Village” due to our vast variety of fish, but we’re now also recognized as one of the top coastal vacation destinations in the country.

We live this lifestyle and if you ever want to explore waterfront real estate opportunities by boat, we would be honored to give you a private tour. Looking at real estate and our area by water gives you a much different perspective than by land.

If you have any questions or you think you might like to take a ride to look at some waterfront properties, don’t hesitate to give me a call. You don’t have to twist my arm to get me out of the office.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Cruising+the+Emerald+Coast+waterways.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://ownemeraldcoast.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Cruising+the+Emerald+Coast+waterways.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>One of the first things people think of when they visit the Destin area is our white sand beaches and the Gulf of Mexico, but this is also a boater's dream with plenty of places to explore throughout all of our coastal waterways.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nathan Abbott</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>One of the first things people think of when they visit the Destin area is our white sand beaches and the Gulf of Mexico, but this is also a boater's dream with plenty of places to explore throughout all of our coastal waterways.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Florida's Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Should You Seek Out Low Condo Association Fees?</title>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/should-you-seek-out-low-condo-association-fees.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Nathan Abbott</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-15 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+The+pros+and+cons+of+condo+association+fees.mp4</guid>
        <description>

More often than not, whenever we have people looking for a resort condominium project to buy, the first thing they desire is low condo association fees. Is it a good idea to seek out low condo association fees, though?

No, it’s not. This is the wrong mentality to have because it could negatively affect you in the long run. When these fees are too low, the property typically isn’t being properly maintained, no reserves are being built for future replacements or improvements, and there’s not enough staff to properly run the HOA. Without these things, the building usually falls into disarray and ages much quicker.

I prefer to see a see a building that has great financials in place, whose budget is being met, and for which a constant reserve is being built for future improvements of the building. When a reserve isn’t being built, that’s when you get popped with an unexpected fee that’s a much larger amount in one bulk fee versus one that’s dispersed over time.

“You can see the difference between a building that’s being properly funded and one that isn’t.”

Condo association fees also cover a lot of items in the building. They cover all of your utilities except for the electric and all of your exterior insurance—the only other insurance policy you’ll usually have to get is a contents policy, which costs about $1,200 a year. They also cover liability insurance for the common areas and the maintenance for the common areas. You can really see the difference in a building that’s being properly funded and one whose fees are too low.

If you consider what those fees are compared to an individual home’s costs, it’s usually a wash. When it comes to an individual home, you pay your fees in smaller increments. For instance, if you pay an $800 per month fee for a condo as part of the association, think about what you’d pay in a home at times. You might need to shell out $150 for the landscaping, $150 for the pool maintenance, and pay for all the exterior maintenance and insurance to boot. These costs can amount to more than the condo fee itself. Condos are more convenient because they charge a flat fee and you don’t have to keep up with all the bills.

Condos also offer a great way of life down here. They allow you to be closer to the Gulf or right on the beach at an affordable price. Overall, there’s less maintenance and you can come and go as you please.

We’re extremely knowledgeable on every condominium from Fort Walton beach to Panama City Beach and everything in between, so if you’re looking for a condominium or you have any other questions, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love the opportunity to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+The+pros+and+cons+of+condo+association+fees.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://ownemeraldcoast.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+The+pros+and+cons+of+condo+association+fees.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>More often than not, whenever we have people looking for a resort condominium project to buy, the first thing they desire is low condo association fees. Is it a good idea to seek out low condo association fees, though?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nathan Abbott</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>More often than not, whenever we have people looking for a resort condominium project to buy, the first thing they desire is low condo association fees. Is it a good idea to seek out low condo association fees, though?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Florida's Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Taste Some Great Wine & Food at Vin’tij Wine Boutique & Bistro</title>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/taste-some-great-wine-food-at-vintij-wine-boutique-bistro.html</link>
        
          <category>Venue Reviews</category>
        
        <author>Nathan Abbott</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-10 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Find+great+wine+and+food+at+VinTij.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Have you been to Vin’tij Wine Boutique &amp; Bistro yet? We recently sat down with owner Todd Reber to give you a taste of what you’re missing in our latest local venue spotlight.

Todd got started in the restaurant industry through a series of jobs he held in college. That experience led him to decide that the marriage of food and wine seemed like a great lifestyle. He gravitated toward it because he enjoyed the camaraderie of restaurant tours and the crowds that came through. When he graduated from Florida State, he discovered he actually made more money in the restaurant industry than he could in a professional field. He decided to challenge himself and open up Vin’tij.

“It’s been a good run for the last 17 years,” Todd says.

He chose Destin as his location because Miramar Beach was close to his home and it was a big destination for outlet stores, which allowed him to use that synergy to test out his concept. 15 years ago, all of the fine wines were earmarked for restaurants. According to Todd, if you wanted a fine wine to take home and enjoy with your friends, you had very few choices. His idea was to find boutique wines and offer them at a reasonable price that you could either enjoy at the restaurant or take home with you.

“We always feel welcome at Vin’tij, and the food is superb.”

In his opinion, the people make Vin’tij stand apart from the competition. He also noted Chef John and his fare, which is fresh and consistently good, and the employees that work there, who are all lifers and have helped to create a family atmosphere.

“We try to welcome everybody that walks in the door,” he says. “We know we’ve got only this moment to make it well and make it right, and that’s what we focus on. We don’t focus on what happened yesterday or what’s going to happen tomorrow—we’re in the now.”

He prefers guests’ experience to be simple. He knows they’re there to have a great meal, and their goal is to help them do so.

This is a place our team loves to go to, and it’s one of the top-rated restaurants in town. We always feel welcome there, the food is always superb, and they support the local residents. We highly recommend you try the experience for yourself.

We want to thank Todd for sitting down to talk with us. If you’d like to know more about Vin’tij, visit their website at www.Vintij.com.

If you have any other questions for us, feel free to give us a call or shoot us an email. We’d be happy to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Find+great+wine+and+food+at+VinTij.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://ownemeraldcoast.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Find+great+wine+and+food+at+VinTij.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Have you been to Vin’tij Wine Boutique & Bistro yet? We recently sat down with owner Todd Reber to give you a taste of what you’re missing in our latest local venue spotlight.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nathan Abbott</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Have you been to Vin’tij Wine Boutique & Bistro yet? We recently sat down with owner Todd Reber to give you a taste of what you’re missing in our latest local venue spotlight.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Florida's Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Pedego Bikes</title>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/pedego-bikes.html</link>
        
          <category>Venue Reviews</category>
        
        <author>Nathan Abbott</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-09 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Have+You+Been+to+Pedego+Bikes%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

We’re at Pedego Bikes, one of my favorite spots. They rent and sell electric bikes here, and I actually bought one for Christmas. It’s been a ton of fun for me and my family. It lets us explore 30A without having to pedal up any steep hills.

We were delighted to be joined by Pedego Bikes owner Jason Medina. He recently retired from the Coast Guard after 22 years and created this store in part to get through some of the congestion and parking issues he faced. Jason says electric bikes are the best way to get around 30A, and I agree. They offer sales and rentals to get the whole family out there cruising around.

“Electric bikes are the best way to get around 30A.”

They are located at 174 Watercolor Way in Santa Rosa, right next door to Publix and the UPS Store. I encourage you to come check out some of these bikes and take one for a test drive yourself.

If you have any questions for me about Pedego or about real estate, give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Have+You+Been+to+Pedego+Bikes%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://ownemeraldcoast.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Have+You+Been+to+Pedego+Bikes%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>We’re at Pedego Bikes, one of my favorite spots. They rent and sell electric bikes here, and I actually bought one for Christmas.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nathan Abbott</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We’re at Pedego Bikes, one of my favorite spots. They rent and sell electric bikes here, and I actually bought one for Christmas.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Florida's Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Lulu's</title>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/lulus.html</link>
        
          <category>Venue Reviews</category>
        
        <author>Nathan Abbott</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-09 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+A+Beachside+Retreat+Fit+for+a+Feast.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I’m here today to talk to you about one of my favorite places in the area that you may not know about. We’re visiting today, and I’m excited to show you around.

This is Lulu’s, a restaurant in Destin right by the Mid-Bay Bridge. They have a big outdoor beach, lots of great seating, and all kinds of activities and events for kids. It has beautiful views of the ocean with both outdoor and indoor seating.

If you have any questions for me about Lulu’s or about real estate, give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+A+Beachside+Retreat+Fit+for+a+Feast.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://ownemeraldcoast.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+A+Beachside+Retreat+Fit+for+a+Feast.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>I’m here today to talk to you about one of my favorite places in the area that you may not know about. We're visiting today, and I’m excited to show you around.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nathan Abbott</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>I’m here today to talk to you about one of my favorite places in the area that you may not know about. We're visiting today, and I’m excited to show you around.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Florida's Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Take a Look at This Beautiful Coastal Park</title>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/take-a-look-at-this-beautiful-coastal-park.html</link>
        
          <category>Venue Reviews</category>
        
        <author>Nathan Abbott</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-17 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/videoplayback.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I’m coming to you from the beautiful Emerald Coast. My son and I are at Topsail State Park, one of our favorite state parks in Florida. It has the most beautiful trails and it really sets your mind free to be here. It’s a spot to really think about the important things in life.

Topsail State Park is just one of the many parks throughout 30a, and we can help you discover all of the great parks Florida has to offer.

If you have any questions, please feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!

Get directions to or learn more about Topsail Gulf Front State Park.


</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/videoplayback.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://ownemeraldcoast.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/videoplayback.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I’m coming to you from the beautiful Emerald Coast.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nathan Abbott</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I’m coming to you from the beautiful Emerald Coast.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Florida's Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Find What You’re Looking for at Not Too Shabby Boutique</title>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/find-what-youre-looking-for-at-not-too-shabby-boutique.html</link>
        
          <category>Venue Reviews</category>
        
        <author>Nathan Abbott</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-07 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Find+unique+items+at+Not+Too+Shabby+Boutique.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I’m here at the Not Too Shabby Boutique, owned by Tony and Marisol Gullo. Marisol was recently chosen as the 2017 Artist of the Year! You can find Marisol’s artwork at the boutique along with many unique pieces.

“We are a one-stop shop,” says Tony. Tony and Marisol make custom pieces that you can’t get anywhere else. They use reclaimed wood for their pieces and sell upholstery by Four Seasons. You can also find Bella Notte Linens, pieces by Regina Andrew, and more from Aidan Gray Home.

“Not Too Shabby is a one-stop shop.”

Although Not Too Shabby has been around for 17 years, they moved into this plaza five years ago. You can find the Not Too Shabby Boutique at 3906 Hwy 98 West.

If you need to furnish your new home or if you need furniture for a rental property, make sure you check out Not Too Shabby. You will be amazed at the variety of furniture and art pieces here that you can use to create a unique look.

If you have any questions for Tony or Marisol, you can contact them here. As always, if you have any real estate questions, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Find+unique+items+at+Not+Too+Shabby+Boutique.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://ownemeraldcoast.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Find+unique+items+at+Not+Too+Shabby+Boutique.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I’m here at the Not Too Shabby Boutique, owned by Tony and Marisol Gullo. Marisol was recently chosen as the 2017 Artist of the Year! You can find Marisol’s artwork at the boutique along with many unique pieces.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nathan Abbott</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I’m here at the Not Too Shabby Boutique, owned by Tony and Marisol Gullo. Marisol was recently chosen as the 2017 Artist of the Year! You can find Marisol’s artwork at the boutique along with many unique pieces.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Florida's Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Top 5 Tips for Scoring a Great Deal on Your Dream Property</title>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/top-5-tips-for-scoring-a-great-deal-on-your-dream-property.html</link>
        
          <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Nathan Abbott</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-23 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+5+tips+to+get+a+great+deal+on+your+dream+home.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Here are five creative tips that will help you get a great deal on the perfect property.

1. Be very specific about what you want. The more you share with us, the easier it will be to find that dream property. Don’t be afraid to let us know what you would be uncomfortable with spending, either. Everything you tell us will help us find the right pool of options that perfectly align with your needs.

2. Be financially well documented. If you’re taking out a loan, make sure you are pre-approved and have that pre-approval letter before you start looking at homes. If you’re a cash buyer, you’ll still want to have some form of financial verification to present to the seller. Having that paperwork presents you as a serious buyer. We’ll align you with the best lender for your needs that is already familiar with properties in our area.

“The more you share with us, the easier it will be to find that dream property.”

3. Act quickly. We’ll be sending you properties as soon as they hit the market, so when you see one that checks off all the boxes, be ready to see it and possibly make an offer. Chances are, you’ll be one of six or seven people also looking at that same home, so be prepared to pounce.

4. Come in with a market-appropriate offer. Don’t try to undercut the sellers. A low offer could cause the seller to reach out to other interested parties, creating a bidding war and ultimately driving up the price. If you present a great offer right off the bat, the seller will only be focused on yours so you can avoid that competition.

5. Minimize contingencies. If you write in a bunch of ways in which you can get out of or cancel a contract, a seller isn’t going to take you very seriously. You want to include some contingencies to make sure you’re protected, but limit the amount to show you are serious about closing on that property.

If you have any questions or need any help buying or selling your home, please don’t hesitate to give us a call. We’re here to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+5+tips+to+get+a+great+deal+on+your+dream+home.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://ownemeraldcoast.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+5+tips+to+get+a+great+deal+on+your+dream+home.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I want to give you some creative buyer tips to get a great deal on the perfect property.  1. Be very specific about what you want. The more you share with us, the easier it will be to find that dream property.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nathan Abbott</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I want to give you some creative buyer tips to get a great deal on the perfect property.  1. Be very specific about what you want. The more you share with us, the easier it will be to find that dream property.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Florida's Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>If You Try Sushimoto, I Guarantee You'll Be Back</title>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/if-you-try-sushimoto-i-guarantee-youll-be-back.html</link>
        
          <category>Venue Reviews</category>
        
        <author>Nathan Abbott</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-09 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Best+sushi+in+town.mp4</guid>
        <description>

This week I’m honored to feature Sushimoto, one of our favorite local restaurants here on the Emerald Coast.

My wife and I absolutely love coming here for sushi that’s extremely fresh and hot dishes that are great. In fact, Emeril Lagasse himself recently featured Sushimoto as one of his favorite restaurants! Owners Andy and Sophia are great people and good friends that provide the best customer service.

“If you mention the Nathan Abbott Team, you’ll get a hot sake on the house.”

Andy wanted a way to feature local seafood and our beautiful beaches drew him here. He loves having a local spot and seeing so many new faces come try his food.

If you mention the Nathan Abbott Team, they’ll even give you a hot sake on the house.

I encourage you to check out Sushimoto because if you come once, I’m sure you’ll be back. You won’t be disappointed!

Until then, give me a call or send me an email with any questions about our local real estate market. I’d be happy to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Best+sushi+in+town.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://ownemeraldcoast.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Best+sushi+in+town.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>This week I'm honored to feature Sushimoto, one of our favorite local restaurants here on the Emerald Coast.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nathan Abbott</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>This week I'm honored to feature Sushimoto, one of our favorite local restaurants here on the Emerald Coast.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Florida's Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Prepare Your Home for the Market</title>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/prepare-your-home-for-the-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Nathan Abbott</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-06 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+How+to+prepare+your+home+for+the+market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

As a home seller, what can you do to get your home ready for the photo shoot, the market, and for buyer showings?

When potential buyers pull up to your house, the outside needs to be just as inviting as the inside. This means having your bushes trimmed back, your driveway and home pressure washed, fresh light bulbs, and maybe some fresh cut flowers. If the exterior of your home is in disarray, that buyer may just keep driving because they got a bad first impression of your home.

As they walk through your front door, it’s important to have all of your carpets vacuumed and your home smelling clean and fresh.

You should also make sure that your home is free of all personal items. Take down family photos and make sure that there aren’t any books stacked on the counter or above cabinets. You want the buyer to feel like this can be their home, and if your personal stuff is lying around everywhere, they will feel like they are intruding in someone else’s home.

“A few small fixes can go a long way.”

It’s important to have all of the smaller items in your home functioning correctly. Check on cabinet hinges, sliding glass doors, and more.

During the showing, we recommend that you have jazz music playing or cookies baking. Doing so will show buyers that you have pride in homeownership. We provide a professional stager to all of our clients. The stager will come in and let you know what you need to do to make showings fantastic. Sometimes just switching out the comforters on the beds or adding a new lamp makes all the difference. Little changes go a long way; you don’t have to spend a lot of money to make your home more appealing to buyers.

Hopefully some of these tips will help you sell your home faster and maximize your price. It’s all about the little touches and the experience the buyer has from the moment they pull up in front of your home. If you have any questions, give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+How+to+prepare+your+home+for+the+market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://ownemeraldcoast.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+How+to+prepare+your+home+for+the+market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Now is the time to prepare your home for the spring real estate market. I’ll give you a few tips on how to create an enjoyable showing experience for potential buyers.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nathan Abbott</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Now is the time to prepare your home for the spring real estate market. I’ll give you a few tips on how to create an enjoyable showing experience for potential buyers.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Florida's Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Where Is the Emerald Coast Real Estate Market Trending?</title>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/where-is-the-emerald-coast-real-estate-market-trending.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Nathan Abbott</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-03 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Hows+the+Emerald+Coast+housing+market+doing%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What’s happening in our local real estate market?

As a whole, our market is very healthy right now. There are indications that it’s converting into a buyer’s market but some of that is due to December being a traditionally slow month for a vacation market, such as ours.

We are in one of the fastest-growing areas in the country for primary residents, and we’re being discovered on a national level. Growing up in this area, I can tell you that, historically, most of our real estate traffic has come from the Southeast region. Now, though, we have residents coming from as far away as California.

“Our area is being discovered on a national level.”

In the past, whenever we had a rise or fall in the market, there was so much speculation in our area that a lot of people who bought properties didn’t have the holding power to keep them and shouldn’t have been buying those properties on the level that they were. Today, there isn’t nearly as much speculation. The activity in our market now is based more on our exposure and people wanting to live in our area.

If you get a loan, lenders are very strict right now about who they’re lending to. There is a lot of cash entering our market, and that’s a strong indication of longevity. Another indicator I always look at in gauging market strength is how the commercial growth is happening in that area, and our commercial growth has been great lately. We have a brand-new 5-star hotel, a new Whole Foods, and plenty of new shopping centers up and down Highway 98. These property developments are all signs of a strengthening market.

Shopping and Entertainment, Brand New and Expansions:

Destin Commons

Pier Park

Pier Park North

The HUB

30 Avenue

New Hotels:

The Henderson (5 star)

The Pearl of Rosemary

The Hampton Inn

If you have any questions about our market or if there’s anything I can assist you with, please feel free to give me a ring or shoot me an email. I would love the opportunity to serve you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Hows+the+Emerald+Coast+housing+market+doing%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://ownemeraldcoast.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nathan+Abbott/Nathan+Abbott+Team-+Hows+the+Emerald+Coast+housing+market+doing%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Thanks to a growing national exposure and a windfall of commercial development, our real estate market is very healthy.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nathan Abbott</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Thanks to a growing national exposure and a windfall of commercial development, our real estate market is very healthy.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Florida's Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Nathan Abbott</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Nathan Abbott</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Nathan Abbott Team - your professional Florida's Emerald Coast Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
