<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="localhost:4000"/>
    <description>A Podcast about Houston Metro Area Real Estate; It's industry, and the people working in it. Whether you're just starting out, aspiring to begin, or been working in the field for a few years, tune in to get updates, tips, tricks and more!</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Frank Gray</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2018-03-12 11:55:51 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Frank Gray</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Houston Metro Area Real Estate, Real Estate Careers, Real Estate Professionals, Realtors, Real estate industry, how much do realtors make</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>frank@frankgray.net</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Frank Gray</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Frank Gray</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Houston Metro Area Real Estate, Real Estate Careers, Real Estate Professionals, Realtors, Real estate industry, how much do realtors make</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Boost your Career with Veteran Real Estate Agent -- CLIENT NAME --</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>A Podcast about Houston Metro Area Real Estate; It's industry, and the people working in it. Whether you're just starting out, aspiring to begin, or been working in the field for a few years, tune in to get updates, tips, tricks and more!</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Our Compensation Plan Can Benefit You</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-our-compensation-plan-can-benefit-you.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Frank Gray</author>
        <pubDate>2018-03-01 21:45:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Frank+Gray/Compensation+Plan+Edited.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Here at Abby Realty, we have by far one of the best compensation plans you’ll hear about in the real estate industry.

The plan is a 90/10 split with a $10,000 cap and a $100 transaction fee. If you’re new to real estate, this means when you have a closing, you keep 90% of your commission. Once the 10% reaches $10,000, you keep 100% of the commission until your anniversary day with Abby Realty. The fine print behind this plan is there are no monthly fees or hidden charges whatsoever, and the company pays for CSS and BackAgent.

Why have we put together such an agent-friendly compensation plan? For many years, I was a recruiter at a big international franchise that was well-known for helping agents achieve very high levels of productivity. The challenge, though, was that the fees were so high (monthly and annually) and took such a big chunk out of the split that many agents were either never able to join the company or weren’t able to get traction in their careers. It just cost too much.

“My passion is helping agents achieve any level of aspiration.”

When I left to start my own company, I was determined to lower the bar of entry so that people who had the inner drive, talent, and personality to succeed would not be put aside because of high fees.

If you want to launch a real estate career and you’re committed to doing it on a full-time basis, we have an opportunity for you. Once you start making money in this business, you’ll keep the bulk of it for yourself. We enable agents to achieve higher and higher levels of aspiration. When you keep your own money, you have more to invest back into your own business and grow that business.

If you’re interested in this opportunity, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to sit down with you and share more ideas on how to spark your real estate career.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Frank+Gray/Compensation+Plan+Edited.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Frank+Gray/Compensation+Plan+Edited.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I want to share with you the compensation plan our agents enjoy and why we put it together the way we did. Quite frankly, it’s one of the best compensation plans in the business. You keep the majority of the commission without any monthly fees or hidden charges. We created such an agent-friendly plan because I believe in helping agents reach their highest levels of success. To learn more about this plan and how it can benefit you, watch our latest video.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Frank Gray</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I want to share with you the compensation plan our agents enjoy and why we put it together the way we did. Quite frankly, it’s one of the best compensation plans in the business. You keep the majority of the commission without any monthly fees or hidden charges. We created such an agent-friendly plan because I believe in helping agents reach their highest levels of success. To learn more about this plan and how it can benefit you, watch our latest video.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Houston Metro Area Real Estate, Real Estate Careers, Real Estate Professionals, Realtors, Real estate industry, how much do realtors make</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Is the Customer Always Right?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/is-the-customer-always-right.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Frank Gray</author>
        <pubDate>2018-02-28 08:35:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Frank+Gray/Abby+Realty-+Is+the+Customer+Always+Right%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

You’ve heard that the customer is always right, but does that hold true in the world of real estate?

If you’ve been in this business for a while, you’ve come across people who are rude, demanding, and, sometimes, a little bit crazy. What happens when you are working with one of these difficult customers?

First of all, I would say that you should always be professional. Don’t sink down to their level. Be very careful with your attitude and vocabulary. Maintain a professional stance at all times.

You may also want to keep your communication in writing. Explain to the client that because there have been some difficulties in communication and you want to be very clear going forward, you’re going to communicate primarily by email. If things really do go south, you now have a written record of everything that transpired.

“Referring a client to your broker is far better than losing the client entirely.”

Finally, if you just can’t handle the client, ask your broker for assistance or ask another agent to take over the client. Make sure that you compensate them with some type of referral fee. Referring a client to your broker is far better than losing the client entirely.

So, is the customer always right? Of course not, but as real estate professionals, we can always handle them in the right way.

I specialize in helping agents take their business to the next level. If you have any other questions about dealing with difficult customers or how to grow your business, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Frank+Gray/Abby+Realty-+Is+the+Customer+Always+Right%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Frank+Gray/Abby+Realty-+Is+the+Customer+Always+Right%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Everyone knows the old adage, “The customer is always right.” If you’ve been in real estate for a while, though, you have probably encountered some rude, demanding, or difficult customers. What can you do in this situation? I have three tips to help you today. To learn more, watch this short video.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Frank Gray</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Everyone knows the old adage, “The customer is always right.” If you’ve been in real estate for a while, though, you have probably encountered some rude, demanding, or difficult customers. What can you do in this situation? I have three tips to help you today. To learn more, watch this short video.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Houston Metro Area Real Estate, Real Estate Careers, Real Estate Professionals, Realtors, Real estate industry, how much do realtors make</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Abby Realty Is One of the Fastest-Growing Brokerages in Houston</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/why-abby-realty-is-one-of-the-fastest-growing-brokerages-in-houston.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Frank Gray</author>
        <pubDate>2018-02-22 11:04:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Frank+Gray/How+Abby+Realty+differs+from+other+real+estate+companies.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Abby Realty is the fastest-growing real estate brokerage here in the Houston metro area. Because we’re so new, many of you might not have heard of us before. I’m Frank Gray, and today, I want to explain where we came from, where we’re at, and where we’re going.

I spent over 20 years in the real estate industry with a large Houston area home builder and then an internationally recognized franchise organization as a business coach and consultant. On November 15, 2017, myself and four courageous agents left to form Abby Realty.

Since then, we have continued to grow at the rate of two to three agents a week. Here we are in mid-February with 30+ agents, but we are in a race to get to 100 as soon as we can.

Why? Once we reach 100 agents, we’re going to get our first brick-and-mortar office so that we have a place to land whenever we need to. Right now, we are utilizing the brick-and-mortar spaces of our mortgage and title partners.

We do offer a live family reunion training event every Monday at 10 a.m. at our mortgage partner, SWBC Mortgage. You are welcome to join us at 26503 Oakridge Drive. This training is a great opportunity to test-drive the type of culture we’re building at Abby Realty.

In case you haven’t heard, it’s a productivity culture, where we help agents achieve their aspirations, and a camaraderie culture, where we know, like, and support each other along the journey.

“Our goal is to have 50 agents at Abby Realty by April 30.”

As of January 30, we had 25 agents. Our goal is to be at 50 agents by April 30. As a way of saying thank you to the agents who are coming along in these early days of Abby Realty, all agents who join us in that 90-day period are eligible for a drawing. The winner will get a cruise for two, anywhere you want to go, up to a $2,000 value.

Also, whoever referred that winning agent to Abby Realty will also get a cruise for two up to a $2,000 value! Whether you are a mortgage professional, title professional, or client who knows a great agent, send them our way for a chance to win.

Obviously, you’re not going to join a real estate company just because of the chance to win a cruise. This is just my way of sharing the excitement of what we’re doing at Abby Realty.

You’re probably wondering about our compensation plan. It’s very simple: Our agents get a 90/10 split that caps at $10,000, and there’s a $100 transaction fee. That’s it. There’s no monthly fees, annual dues, or hidden charges. I even pay for CSS and BackAgent.

My intent is to make Abby Realty a company where agents can join without the fear of high monthly fees. When you do have a closing, you get to keep the bulk of your commission (90%).

If you are at all intrigued by our company, just give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Frank+Gray/How+Abby+Realty+differs+from+other+real+estate+companies.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Frank+Gray/How+Abby+Realty+differs+from+other+real+estate+companies.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Abby Realty is a new real estate brokerage. Today, I’ll go over where we came from, where we’re at, and where we’re going—and why you should join us.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Frank Gray</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Abby Realty is a new real estate brokerage. Today, I’ll go over where we came from, where we’re at, and where we’re going—and why you should join us.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Houston Metro Area Real Estate, Real Estate Careers, Real Estate Professionals, Realtors, Real estate industry, how much do realtors make</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Frank Gray</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Frank Gray</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">A Podcast about Houston Metro Area Real Estate; It's industry, and the people working in it. Whether you're just starting out, aspiring to begin, or been working in the field for a few years, tune in to get updates, tips, tricks and more!</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
