<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Central Iowa Real Estate Careers and Training Podcast with Misty Soldwisch</title>
    <link>http://bebetterdsm.com</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://bebetterdsm.com"/>
    <description>A Podcast about Central Iowa Real Estate; It's industry, and the people working in it. Whether you're just starting out, aspiring to begin, or been working in the field for a few years, tune in to get updates, tips, tricks and more!</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Misty SOLDwisch</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2017-12-12 13:16:19 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Misty SOLDwisch</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://bebetterdsm.com/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Central Iowa Real Estate, Real Estate Careers, Real Estate Professionals, Realtors, Real estate industry, how much do realtors make</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Misty@BHGInnovations.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Misty SOLDwisch</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Misty SOLDwisch</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://bebetterdsm.com/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Central Iowa Real Estate, Real Estate Careers, Real Estate Professionals, Realtors, Real estate industry, how much do realtors make</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Boost your Career with Veteran Real Estate Agent Misty Soldwisch</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>A Podcast about Central Iowa Real Estate; It's industry, and the people working in it. Whether you're just starting out, aspiring to begin, or been working in the field for a few years, tune in to get updates, tips, tricks and more!</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>Need to Meet Your Continuing Education Requirements? This Resource Can Help</title>
        <link>http://bebetterdsm.com/need-to-meet-your-continuing-education-requirements-this-resource-can-help.html</link>
        
        <author>Misty SOLDwisch</author>
        <pubDate>2017-12-06 11:37:17 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Toward the end of the year, I always notice that many agents are scrambling to get their continuing education requirements in for their license renewal.

In the state of Iowa, agents are required to take 36 hours of continuing education every three years, with those hours due by December 31 of the year your license expires.

This education includes eight hours of law updates, four hours of ethics, and 24 hours of electives.

Real estate is a complex industry, so continuing education is extremely important. Knowing industry standards, new laws, and other information helps us, as agents, be the best professionals we can.

But let’s be honest: it can be difficult to find time for that education when you’re keeping such a busy schedule yourself.

As real estate professionals, we’ve got very unpredictable schedules. Fortunately, there is an alternative in Iowa to in-classroom learning.** In Iowa, up to 24 hours of your continuing education can be done online.**

“I was able to schedule my continuing education around my life, instead of scheduling my life around my continuing education.”

This is why I’ve found www.RealEstateCE.com to be an amazing resource. It’s very easy to sign up and is full of informational classes relevant to things I experience in my business. Also, it’s inexpensive.

The best part of taking classes through this website, though, is that it helped me control my time. I was able to schedule my continuing education around my life, instead of scheduling my life around my continuing education.

Additionally, there is an amazing discount available to Iowa licensees through www.RealEstateCE.com that you can find here.

So if you’re busy, want to learn, and would like to save money, I definitely recommend checking it out.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://bebetterdsm.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>How can we as agents possibly set aside time for continuing education with the busy schedules we maintain? Today, I’d like to share a great resource that can help.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Misty SOLDwisch</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>How can we as agents possibly set aside time for continuing education with the busy schedules we maintain? Today, I’d like to share a great resource that can help.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Central Iowa Real Estate, Real Estate Careers, Real Estate Professionals, Realtors, Real estate industry, how much do realtors make</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Misty SOLDwisch</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Misty SOLDwisch</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">A Podcast about Central Iowa Real Estate; It's industry, and the people working in it. Whether you're just starting out, aspiring to begin, or been working in the field for a few years, tune in to get updates, tips, tricks and more!</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
