<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Orlando Real Estate Podcast with Chris Myers</title>
    <link>http://floridapropertygroup.com/</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://floridapropertygroup.com/"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Orlando Property Group - your professional Orlando Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Chris Myers</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2017-06-05 15:23:53 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Chris Myers</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://floridapropertygroup.com//img/Podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orlando, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">News &amp; Politics</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Chris@OrlandoPropertyGroup.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Chris Myers</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Chris Myers</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://floridapropertygroup.com//img/Podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orlando, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Orlando Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Orlando Property Group - your professional Orlando Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="News &amp; Politics"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Truth About Zillow’s Zestimate</title>
        <link>http://floridapropertygroup.com//the-truth-about-zillows-zestimate.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Chris Myers</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-31 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Chris+Myers/Orlando+Property+Group+Zestimates.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Can you really trust Zillow’s Zestimate tool? 
 
Let me start with a story: A couple of years ago, the CEO of Zillow sold his property. The Zestimate said his property was worth $1.75 million. However, the final sales price was only $1.05 million. That’s a $700,000 difference. Do you think he should have trusted that Zestimate? Obviously not!
 
Zillow’s Zestimate tool gives you a general idea of what your property is worth. The problem is, those Zestimates are extremely inaccurate. 
 
According to Zillow’s own website, a Zestimate is a starting point in determining a home’s value. It’s not an appraisal. The Zestimate is based on public and user-submitted data. Unfortunately, user-submitted data can create big discrepancies. 
 
If you want to sell your house and you know that buyers are going to look at that Zestimate, you might want to beef up that number, right? You may be tempted to embellish a little on the upgrades you’ve done, the size of the house, or the size of the lot. Zillow allows you to change that data. 
 
As a consumer, this is where you have to be careful. Zillow can be manipulated by an owner or an agent. Your own home’s value can be inaccurate depending on how honest your neighbors were when they submitted data to Zillow. 
 
Zillow encourages homeowners to supplement the Zestimate by speaking with a real estate professional to get a comparative market analysis or having an appraiser visit your house. After all, Zillow has never been to your house and has no idea how your home stacks up against the other properties on the market. 

“User-submitted data can really throw off your Zestimate.”
 
If you live in a neighborhood with similar homes, there is a lot of similar data for Zillow to go off of, so the Zestimate can be more accurate in those areas. However, if you live in a rural or more eclectic area, like Winter Park, College Park, or downtown Orlando, the types of homes can vary greatly, and your Zestimate is more likely to be off the mark. 
 
Zillow even admits that more than 90% of the homes in the Orlando area have Zestimates that are only within 20% of the final sales price. That means if you have a $400,000 house, your Zestimate could be $80,000 higher or lower than it should be. 
 
This is why you need to get in touch with a local expert, like myself, to get the most accurate comparative market analysis possible. 

Ultimately, Zillow is like WebMD. If you’re curious about an illness you think you might have, then you will probably go to WebMD to research the symptoms. However, you’re going to go to a real doctor to get a diagnosis and treatment. 
 
If you just want to look at home values, then Zillow is fine. If you plan on selling your home, then you need to talk to a professional. 
 
If you have any questions about selling in our current market or would like to know what your home is worth, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Chris+Myers/Orlando+Property+Group+Zestimates.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://floridapropertygroup.com/" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Chris+Myers/Orlando+Property+Group+Zestimates.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Can you rely on Zillow to determine the value of your home? The answer is no, and there are a few reasons why.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Chris Myers</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Can you rely on Zillow to determine the value of your home? The answer is no, and there are a few reasons why.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orlando, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Iron Is Hot in Our Market, but for Whom?</title>
        <link>http://floridapropertygroup.com//the-iron-is-hot-in-our-market-but-for-whom.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Chris Myers</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-17 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Chris+Myers/Orlando+Property+Group+Market+Update+(2).mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’re thinking of selling your house, now is the perfect time to do it. Why?

Not many people are aware of this, but our Orlando market has a shortage of inventory. For example, we recently listed a property in the Hunter’s Creek area that received six offers in seven days. Our biggest fear with this property was that we listed it at $260,000, which was the very peak of where it would appraise. 

“If you’re thinking about selling your house, now’s the time to do it.”

Some of the offers, however, went above our asking price, and the home ended up selling for a $266,000 all-cash offer. For that neighborhood, I netted my seller $12,000 more than the next highest sale and did it 63 days faster than the neighborhood’s average days on market. 

If you’re thinking of putting your house on the market or you’re interested in buying a home, feel free to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Chris+Myers/Orlando+Property+Group+Market+Update+(2).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://floridapropertygroup.com/" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Chris+Myers/Orlando+Property+Group+Market+Update+(2).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Our Orlando market has a shortage of inventory, meaning now is the time to make your move if you’re a seller.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Chris Myers</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Our Orlando market has a shortage of inventory, meaning now is the time to make your move if you’re a seller.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orlando, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>K1 Speed Will Give Anyone Their Adrenaline Fix</title>
        <link>http://floridapropertygroup.com//k1-speed-will-give-anyone-their-adrenaline-fix.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Chris Myers</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-05 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Chris+Myers/Orlando+Property+Group+Visit+to+K1+Speed.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Orlando is an entertainment capital, so what better way to spend a Friday night than some indoor go-karting? Today I’m coming to you on location at K1 Speed with Ryan Hawkins to give you an inside look at the fast lane.

As Ryan says, K1 Speeds provides you with all the adrenaline you need. Ryan can set you up with any kind of race package you need, but they specialize in corporate events, team building events, and race packages for parties, to name a few. 

Click below for more info on:


  Team building
  Room rental
  Race packages


If you’d like to set up a race, a team building event, or just a good time with some friends at K1 Speed, you can contact Ryan at (407) 434-7500. You can also check out the video above to get an up close and personal look at what it’s like to race here at K1 Speed. You’ve got to try this place out!

“K1 Speed provides you with all the adrenaline you need.”

In the meantime, give me a call or send me an email if you have any questions about buying or selling a home here in Orlando. I’m happy to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Chris+Myers/Orlando+Property+Group+Visit+to+K1+Speed.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://floridapropertygroup.com/" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Chris+Myers/Orlando+Property+Group+Visit+to+K1+Speed.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you need a spot for a team building exercise, a corporate event, or just a competitive and adrenaline-pumping atmosphere with some friends, K1 Speed is your place.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Chris Myers</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you need a spot for a team building exercise, a corporate event, or just a competitive and adrenaline-pumping atmosphere with some friends, K1 Speed is your place.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orlando, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>An Update on Mortgage Interest Rates</title>
        <link>http://floridapropertygroup.com//an-update-on-mortgage-interest-rates.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Chris Myers</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-20 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Chris+Myers/Orlando+Property+Group+Interest+Rates.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There has been a lot of talk lately about mortgage interest rates, including where they’re at and where they’re headed. I was recently joined by Sandra Lyons of The Mortgage Firm, one of the best loan officers I’ve ever worked with, to discuss the topic.

We are seeing an increase in rates right now, and they’re up between 4% and 4.5% for the most part. However, this hasn’t really affected our seller’s market so far. Our inventory is only at about three months, which puts sellers in a pretty good spot. The power is in their hands, and a lot of them are seeing multiple offers and offers above asking price as a result.

Interest rates are expected to creep up even further, possibly even by a full 1% this year alone. As rates go up, things will shift more toward buyers. A downward pressure on prices would make more homes available for buyers to choose from. As that happens, we will see a shift in the market toward buyers.

“You can maximize your sale price now.”

Right now, you have a great opportunity to buy and sell in this market. By selling, you can maximize your sale price because of the limited inventory. Then you can buy while rates are still relatively low and lock in a rate before they go up even higher. For every 1% that interest rates go up, buying power decreases by 10%.

Your interest rate is affected by things like your credit score, your income, and your down payment. If you can’t afford to buy now, it doesn’t mean you couldn’t afford it in a few months with the help of someone like Sandra. If you have any questions for her or want to get pre-qualified for a mortgage, give her a call at (407)-902-4297 or send her an email to SLyons@TheMortgageFirm.com.

If you have any other questions for us, don’t hesitate to reach out by phone or email. We would love to hear from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Chris+Myers/Orlando+Property+Group+Interest+Rates.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://floridapropertygroup.com/" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Chris+Myers/Orlando+Property+Group+Interest+Rates.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>You have a great opportunity to buy and sell in this market. It all comes back to interest rates.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Chris Myers</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>You have a great opportunity to buy and sell in this market. It all comes back to interest rates.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orlando, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Own a Vacation Home and Have Someone Else Pay the Mortgage</title>
        <link>http://floridapropertygroup.com//how-to-own-a-vacation-home-and-have-someone-else-pay-the-mortgage.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Chris Myers</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-09 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Chris+Myers/Orlando+Property+Group+Vacation+Homes.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The question I’m addressing today isn’t one I receive often, but I think it’s an important one to answer: “How can I get someone to pay for my vacation home?”

The answer is actually pretty simple. Here in Orlando, we have some communities that are zoned for short-term vacation rentals. If you own a property, you can rent it out for a day, a week, or a month to vacationers. There are great property management companies that will do all the work for you, and you can even buy these properties fully furnished.

The area I want to focus on today is Compass Bay, just minutes from Disney. It’s also near The Loop, one of my favorite shopping centers with shops, restaurants, and movies theaters. Downtown Orlando is also close by.

If you got a mortgage on a Compass Bay townhome and rented it out 75% of the time, your return would be about 6%. That’s fantastic when you consider the fact that a normal, full-time rental here in the Orlando market typically has a 6% return. Another great part of a short-term rental is that you get to enjoy it with your family about 24% of the time, too.

“Where else can you get a free vacation home your family can actually use?”

If you paid cash, your rate of return goes up to about 10%. If you want to use the home a little more than 24% of the time, that’s fine too—you’ll just make a little bit less of a return. Even if you use it enough to only break even, you still get a free vacation home! Where else can you get a free vacation home?

If you’d like to know more about Compass Bay or any of the many other short-term rental communities here in the Orlando area, just give me a call or send me an email. I’d be happy to help you in any way I can!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Chris+Myers/Orlando+Property+Group+Vacation+Homes.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://floridapropertygroup.com/" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Chris+Myers/Orlando+Property+Group+Vacation+Homes.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>How can you get someone to pay for your vacation home? This is a question people don’t ask enough, but should.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Chris Myers</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>How can you get someone to pay for your vacation home? This is a question people don’t ask enough, but should.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orlando, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Holy Cow! Multiple Offers Batman! What Now?</title>
        <link>http://floridapropertygroup.com//holy-cow-multiple-offers-batman-what-now.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Chris Myers</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-31 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Chris+Myers/Holy+Cow!+Multiple+Offers+Batman!+What+Now-+Orlando+Property+Group.mp4</guid>
        <description>

We’re currently in a low inventory market with high demand, which is great if you’re thinking about selling your home. However, this does not mean getting a high price for your home will be easy!

We spend over $10,000 a month on marketing, and we put that to work for our clients. The average agent’s marketing budget is only the size of a car payment! The bottom line is, we get more people looking at your home than the average agent. Who wouldn’t want that?

When you list with us, we make recommendations on what you can do to maximize value. Because of our experience of selling over 100 homes a year, we know exactly what buyers want. Our marketing, plus a low inventory situation, will get your home maximum exposure - and more exposure means a better chance of generating multiple offers!

Once you generate multiple offers, you need to prioritize them by superiority. Remember, the offer with the highest price is not always the superior offer; the amount of money down, financing, and other terms can be just as important! Here are some tips on how to review an offer:

Is the Buyer Pre-approved or Pre-qualified for a Mortgage?
Contrary to popular belief, a seller with a pre-qualification is simply not as good as one that has been pre-approved. It is an important thing to consider when looking at an offer and the difference can easily make or break your transaction. When a buyer has been pre-approved, the lender has reviewed and verified all the important aspects of the financial transaction.

“Once you generate multiple offers, you need to prioritize them by superiority.”

How Much Money Are They Bringing to the Closing Table?
As our marketplace leans heavier and heavier toward a seller-centric environment, the issue of how much down payment they will be able to make will come up more and more. When a buyer has more money down on their purchase, it is definitely a stronger offer than one where the buyers have less at stake. Look for a letter or statement from the bank demonstrating their ability to cover the funds promised as a down payment.

Is There a Contingency To Sell Another Home First?
Many buyers have a home to sell first before they can move forward with a new purchase. In the offer you receive from these buyers, you will likely see a contingency upon the sale of their home. When comparing multiple offers, if one buyer is able to buy your home without needing to sell their home – the chance of other problems or mistakes will reduce significantly.

How Far Out Is the Closing Date?
The ideal closing date is about 30 days from the date of accepted agreement. When you start getting into closing dates that go out two months or more, there tend to be more problems. A lot can happen in that much time, whether a job change, life change or even a change of heart – so if there is an offer with a closer closing date, that would definitely be the stronger choice.

We hope you found some of this information helpful. As always, we look forward to assisting you with all your real estate needs and, in the interim, if you would like to learn more about today’s hot real estate topics, call us at 877-586-2636 or email us at Info@OrlandoPropertyGroup.com. We look forward to hearing from you soon!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Chris+Myers/Holy+Cow!+Multiple+Offers+Batman!+What+Now-+Orlando+Property+Group.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://floridapropertygroup.com/" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Chris+Myers/Holy+Cow!+Multiple+Offers+Batman!+What+Now-+Orlando+Property+Group.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>When you list with us, we make recommendations on what you can do to maximize value. Because of our experience of selling over 100 homes a year, we know exactly what buyers want.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Chris Myers</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>When you list with us, we make recommendations on what you can do to maximize value. Because of our experience of selling over 100 homes a year, we know exactly what buyers want.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orlando, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to My Orlando Real Estate Video Blog</title>
        <link>http://floridapropertygroup.com//welcome-to-my-orlando-real-estate-video-blog.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Chris Myers</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-03 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Chris+Myers/Orlando+Property+Group+Welcome+to+My+Real+Estate+Video+Blog.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Welcome to my YouTube channel! Here, you can find seller tips, buyer tips, and market updates. I want this to be a resource for all of your real estate needs. If you would like to know more about a specific topic, please let me know and I’ll answer your question with a video. To learn more about my channel, watch this short video.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Chris+Myers/Orlando+Property+Group+Welcome+to+My+Real+Estate+Video+Blog.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://floridapropertygroup.com/" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Chris+Myers/Orlando+Property+Group+Welcome+to+My+Real+Estate+Video+Blog.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Welcome to my YouTube channel! Here, you can find seller tips, buyer tips, and market updates. I want this to be a resource for all of your real estate needs.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Chris Myers</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Welcome to my YouTube channel! Here, you can find seller tips, buyer tips, and market updates. I want this to be a resource for all of your real estate needs.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orlando, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Will the Orlando Real Estate Market Change in 2017?</title>
        <link>http://floridapropertygroup.com//how-will-the-orlando-real-estate-market-change-in-2017.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Chris Myers</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-03 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Chris+Myers/Orlando+Property+Group+Market+Update.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What is the Orlando real estate market like? Today, I’ll go over the latest market update as well as what you can expect from the market in 2017. 

Right now, there is a shortage of inventory on the market, which creates a huge opportunity for sellers. There is less competition among people looking to sell their home, but demand is still incredibly high. There are many buyers in the market right now, and that heavy competition is expected to continue throughout 2017. 

Due to low inventory, it’s fairly common to see bidding wars and multiple offers on the same property. Buyers have to go in strong with their offer price and move very quickly in our current market. 

Throughout 2017, we expect to see an influx of millennial home buyers in the market. These first-time home buyers will create even more demand. 

Right after the election, we saw a dramatic increase in mortgage interest rates. Rates had been in the mid-threes throughout 2016. Now, rates range from 4.25% to 4.85%, and they are expected to rise to 5% or even higher by the end of 2017. 

“Interest rates should surpass 5% by the end of 2017.”

Those rising interest rates will put downward pressure on pricing and impact inventory even more. People who want to move up into a larger home may get priced out of the market thanks to those higher interest rates. Buyers may stay in lower-priced homes to avoid paying a higher mortgage rate. 

The good news is that Orlando is one of the top 10 growing real estate markets in the country. Next year, we can expect another 5% to 6% increase in home prices, so there are lots of opportunities for buyers and sellers. 

That said, considering that prices and interest rates will both go up in 2017, now is the time to get off the fence and start your home search. If you have any questions about the buying process or would like to learn more details about our current market, give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Chris+Myers/Orlando+Property+Group+Market+Update.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://floridapropertygroup.com/" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Chris+Myers/Orlando+Property+Group+Market+Update.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What is happening in the Orlando real estate market? I’ll go over the latest market update today, as well as my predictions for the 2017 real estate market.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Chris Myers</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What is happening in the Orlando real estate market? I’ll go over the latest market update today, as well as my predictions for the 2017 real estate market.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orlando, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Chris Myers</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Chris Myers</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Orlando Property Group - your professional Orlando Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
