<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title> Real Estate Podcast with </title>
    <link>localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Vyral Marketing - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor></managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2018-03-14 11:25:25 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright></media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>allison@getvyral.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name></itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author></itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the  Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Vyral Marketing - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week of 3/5/18</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/week-of-030518.html</link>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2018-03-05 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Frank Gray - Why our compensation plan is the best in the business

John Hatch - 	Save the date: Casino night on March 24

Shawneequa Badger -	ACTION REQUIRED: Sign up for my newsletter!

Janice Overbeck - Rising Interest Rates- Plus a fun fact at the end

Shawneequa Badger - Do you have any real estate questions?

Chad Huebener - Standard closing costs

Sandy King - How Can Heating and Cooling Benefit Pools?

Gene Agustin - A question about homeowners policy coverage

Todd Martin - 6 ways to be more productive in 2018

Will Cook - Be smart: Don’t test the market

Mario Giganti	Mario Giganti - Are your employees retirement-ready?

Dave Heeter - Impending interest rate news

Nick Shivers - Can we still expect multiple offers?

Scott Irvin - 	5 Things Every Seller Should Demand of Their Agent

Thomas Scott - What is wage garinshment?

Kory Prince - How to Tell if We’re in a Buyer’s or Seller’s Market

Ben Parojcic - What do my clients really think?

Charleston Homes - Now is the time to build

Don Williams - Are You Ready to Enter the Spring Market?

KWEV - How Knowing Your “Why” Can Improve Your Business

Amanda Howard - Getting your home ready to put on the market

Bill Black - The spring market is coming

Brad Brethouwer - Expert home search tips

John Schuster - The Twin Cities market is red-hot

Amanda Howard - Learn how to cut down your workweek

Jay White - Our value to you after the home sale

Nick Kellar - 7 Simple Tips for a Quick Sale

Denise Swick - What’s really happening in our market

Ryan Butler	What’s the best month to sell your home?

Lisa Treu - 	How do our home values compare to the rest of the world?

Robert &amp; Shannon Rollings - 	What should you avoid sayng when visiting a home?

Ron Cedillo - What You Need to Know About Home Inspections

(ASI) Aesthetic Surgical Images - The most effective loose skin treatment 
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Frank Gray, John Hatch, Shawneequa Badger, Janice Overbeck, Shawneequa Badger</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Frank Gray, John Hatch, Shawneequa Badger, Janice Overbeck, Shawneequa Badger</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Week of 2/26/18</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/week-of-022618.html</link>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2018-02-26 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Andy Sachs - A recent NAR study found that…

Brett Jennings - 	Hi, it’s Amber Deleare

Nancy Seraphin - Increasing Your Stream of Income: Part 2

Paul Campbell - 	Exciting news! (ppc)

Brandon Blackwell - Introducing our new agent

Ryan Anderson - 8 home repairs you need to keep up with

Gavin Shnieder - How can you generate leads at open houses?

Mark Brace - Your Grand Rapids spring market update

Chris Hauck - How to prepare your home for the market

Michael Vernamonti - What Is the Best Way to Find and Buy New Construction?

O’Neill Team - What Will Happen to Charleston Home Prices in 2018?

Kevin Jimeno - Keeping Your Ducks in a Row This Tax Season

Angela Fox - 5 ways to prepare to list

Amanda Howard - Save the date: Power Workshop on March 7th

Bob &amp; Diane Peterson - 3 mistakes first-time listers should avoid

Kris Miller - Stop your negative financial chatter

Peter Dellane - Why should you work with AMG?

Rob Bowerman - Hiring a Specialized Search Firm Makes a Difference

Andrew Duncan - Have You Filed Your Homestead Exemption? The Deadline Is 3/1!

Nick Good - 4 surprising factors that can up your home’s value

Sherry &amp; Angela - 	Proof Our Certified Pre-Owned Program Really Works

Tom White - 3 home seller mistakes to avoid

Ryan Butler	3 exciting announcements from my team

John Head - Reflecting on 2017

Kevin McCarthy - Check Out Our New North Austin Project 

Brian Riolo - What Homebuyers and Sellers Need to Know About Bidding Wars

Doug Cary - What Is Radon and Could It Be in Your Home?

Janice MacMilian - Don’t make an offer before asking this

Jordan Matin - What Do You Want to Learn About Oregon  and Southwest Washington Real Estate?

Maynard Wagner - How to beat 14 offers in our crazy market

Mike Quail - Are you caught in the rental trap?

Mikki Ramey - The millionaire investor

Nick McLean - What’s the best week of the year to list your home?

Paul Brouillette - Answering common appraisal questions

Tina Beliveau - How can you make the most of your database?

Anastasia Riley - 5 benefits of purchasing new construction

Black Clover Fitness - How to use a treadmill and not hurt your knees

Paul Campbell - 	Exciting news! (non ppc)

Bryan &amp; Scott Colemere - Dealing With Low Appraisals: Part 1

Aaron Wittenstein - Don’t Miss Out on Our Next Rockstar Connect Networking Event

Brandie Mathison Klein - 	What to Do Before You List

David Robinson - How to combat a challenging buyer’s market

Deepak Gupta - Now is the time to make your move

Ian Lobas - We want to give back to the community

Lisa Sisko - Bring Your Home Up-To-Date With Smart Technology

Angel Garcia - 3 Tips to Boost Your Home’s Value

Dave Hooke - 4 Ways to Determine Home Value

Dar Walden - Final Reminder: 2018 home seller’s seminar

Darren James - What Are Home Inspectors Looking for?

Kevin Smith - Now is the time to list

Richard Witt - How My Guaranteed Sale Program Works

Sandy Blanton - You can’t have it both ways

Todd Martin - What must you avoid during your home search?

Marcus Vanzant - Monthly housing costs are going up in 2018…don’t wait to buy

Rick Carson &amp; Chuck Korger - Should You Be Worried About a Volatile Market?

Joshua Stern - 	Our latest exciting endorsement

Robert &amp; Shannon Rollings - 	 Homebuyers need to understand this

Susanne Casey - How To Get Your Offer Accepted EVERY Time!

(ASI) Aesthetic Surgical Images - Come work with us

Anthony Boatner - How to Sell Your Home Even if It Needs a Lot of Work

Caleb Pearson - Rental rates are rising

Clifton Sanders - Tips for self-employed borrowers

Ferzoco Group - A Look at the Jersey Shore Market Statistics

Shawn O’Neill - What Sets Our Team Apart?

Clayton Gits - The perfect time to enter the market

Larry Martin - Our agents go the extra mile for you

Mary Peacock - 	How do we make listings stand out?

Julie Baldino - 6 Bad Habits That Stand Between You and Homeownership

Ruby Miranda - 6 things to know about new construction

(ASI) Aesthetic Surgical Images - What to expect after breast augmentation 

Brian Gagnon - What do prices look like in our area?

Brian Canady - Brushing Up On the Basics: Chimney Care

Chad Schwendeman - Interest Rates Will Be Rising Soon

Deja Lett - How are interest rates driving the market?

Victoria Sandoval - 10 Terms That All Homebuyers Should Know
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Danny Sarch, Joshua Stern, Frank Gray, Brian Lessinger, and Scott Hollinger</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Danny Sarch, Joshua Stern, Frank Gray, Brian Lessinger, and Scott Hollinger</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Week of 2/19/18</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/week-of-021918.html</link>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2018-02-19 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Joshua Stern - 	Impending interest rate news

Danny Sarch - What to do after your firm has left the recruiting protocol?

Frank Gray - What makes Abby Realty different?

Brian Lessinger - An Invitation and an Update From the Lessinger Team

Scott Hollinger - The check’s in the mail?

Tyler Goff - Client Stories: Fostering with Kate Telkamp

Gary Raze - A Few Tips and Tricks to Save for a Down Payment

Gene Agustin - What determines the cost of home insurance?

Jeremy Sisemore - What Value Do Search Firms Bring?

Kwasi Bowie - Your latest King County market update

Betsy Sarcone - Are You Prepared for the Spring Real Estate Market?

Dave Nimick - The truth about new construction

Graham MacKenzie - Tips for homebuyers in a competitive market

Barbara Radke - The role of title insurance

Brett Sikora - How to prepare your home for the spring real estate market

Jay Heidel - Who can afford a home?

Ben Parojcic - Your 2018 market outlook

David Rosen - The Key to Adding Value Is Making Buyers Fall in Love

Denny Robert - 3 Market Predictions for 2018

Micah Munro - Always avoid these 3 home search mistakes

KWEV - Leveraging Your Listings to Get More Business

Patrick Fitzgerald - Why Should You Work With My Own Realtor

Brandon Blackwell - 5 real estate lessons from 2017

Danielle Py-Salas - 	We’ve Cracked the Code and We Want to Share It With You

Dar Walden - Action Required: 2018 home seller’s seminar

Kori Prince - Should You Rent or Should You Buy a Home?

Rex Jarnagin - Which Is Better: a Real Estate Team or an Individual Agent?

Brad Brethouwer - Do you have any real estate questions?

Charleston Home - 	Important dryer maintenance tips

Jeremy Larkin - YOU’RE INVITED: Home Buyer Seminar

Peter Dellane - Tips for veterans post-bankruptcy

Amanda Howard - An in-depth look at the Storm Tracker

Diane Cardano-Casacio - How did this couple save $10,000?

Greg McDaniel - 	Stop earning a paycheck and build wealth

Jerry Land - What Are Companies Looking For When Hiring Salespeople?

Lindsey Gudger - Use This Right to Win!

Nate Martinez - How Can You Beat the Competition in This Scorching Hot Market?

Trae Dauby - 	What Should Buyers and Sellers Know About Inspections?

Zach Sikes - How Are Appraisals and Inspections Different?

Amanda Howard - Should you tap into your home equity?

Kevin Clancy - SOI	Why your home doesn’t get any offers

Monique Walker - Do You Want to Buy or Sell Outside of Arizona?

Nick Kellar - Coffee and Conversations: Disney World Edition

Robert Mack - 	How Supply and Demand Will Impact the Spring &amp; Summer Selling Season

Susan Heller - Now May Be the Time to Downsize

Ryan Butler - Should you tap into your home’s equity?

Joe Mendoza - Which Is Right for You: Self-Managing or Hiring an Expert?

Andrew Kent - Is It Better to Rent or to Own?

Kevin Clancy - How to make more money in real estate

Robert &amp; Shannon Rollings - 	Preparing for a home inspection

Chip Glennon - 	The key to attracting online homebuyers

Ron Cedillo - When Keep Your Home California Fails, Call Us

Gavin Shnieder - Which 3 listing mistakes must you avoid?

Greg Tran - Your latest Austin market update

(ASI) Aesthetic Surgical Images - What to expect after a tummy tuck

Adam Stary - February market update

Kathy Toth - When Should I Sell My Ann Arbor Home?

Hunter Reynolds - Why Tap Into Your Home’s Equity Now?
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Danny Sarch, Joshua Stern, Frank Gray, Brian Lessinger, and Scott Hollinger</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Danny Sarch, Joshua Stern, Frank Gray, Brian Lessinger, and Scott Hollinger</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Week of 2/12/18</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/week-of-021218.html</link>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2018-02-12 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Holly Mabery - Challenging your notification of value

Kwaku Mitchell - The Latest News From Our Economy and Housing Market 

Andy Sachs - What do our clients think about us?

Tom White Rec - The culture of the Tom White Group

Ben Parojcic - Are we headed for another market crash? (extra list)

Hal Sweasey - 	January 2018 real estate market update

Gavin Shnieder - 4 tips for increasing review feedback

Rob Bowerman - Why Are Happy Candidates Usually the Best Ones?

David Van Noy - 	4 Traits You Should Look for in an Agent

Bret Johnson - 6 Unexpected Closing Costs You Shouldn’t Forget About

Nancy Seraphin - How to Create Consistent Revenue in Your Business

Oggie Penev - Do you have any real estate questions?

Tom White - SOI	Suburban vs. downtown living

Brian Riolo - What’s Happening in the Hoboken Real Estate Market?

Anne-Marie McCormick - How is the 2018 San Diego market doing?

Kevin McCarthy - The Sea Casa Is Open for Business

Marcus Green - How Keller Williams Turned Shea Kopecky’s Career Around

Doug Cary - How Can Buyers and Sellers Take Advantage of Our Current Market?

Nick McLean - 	How will tax changes impact our market?

Scott Himelstein - Watch: How tax reform impacts our market

Sherry &amp; Angela - 	Listing a Commercial Property vs. Listing a Residential Property

Andrew Duncan - Should You Buy a New Home Before Selling Your Current One?

Angie Cole - Do you have any real estate questions?

Chad Huebener - What’s in store for our early spring market?

Thomas Scott - How do liens and levies work?

Willie Miranda - The network that lets us help around the world

Dar Walden - Home Seller’s Seminar

Kris Miller - How to create a long-term life plan

Lenny LaRocca//Tony Cangas - How Is the 2018 Real Estate Market?

Richard Witt - Need to Close on Your Home Quickly?

Jay White - Are you guilty of these listing mistakes?

Joshua Stern - 	The science of success

Dan Rochon - How can staging enhance your listing?

Victoria Sandoval - 5 Ways to Save for Your Down Payment

Patrick Collins - What’s the Difference Between a Pre-Qualification and a Pre-Approval? 

Robert &amp; Shannon Rollings - 	The top 5 renovation projects for home sellers

(ASI) Aesthetic Surgical Images - Tummy tuck tips

Chris Craddock - Only 30 spots left: Invest for Success seminar with Dr. Chris Craddock

Eric Burch - Watch: Vendor spotlight: You Lucky Dog

Tiffany Johannes - Saving for a Down Payment Made Simple

Matt &amp; Jenn Freda - How Rising Interest Rates Impact Your Plans to Buy

Valerie Hunter-Kelly - How to Get Your Offer Accepted as a Homebuyer

Jeff Smith - Don’t Let Your Home Sale Leave You Homeless

Zach Wessolleck - 4 Must-Visit Breweries in Northern Virginia

Jared Chamberlain (Chamberlain Group) - Should you tap into your home equity?

Donald Payne - 	How to Care for Your Aging Parents
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Holly Mabery, Kwaku Mitchell, Andy Sachs, Tom White Rec, and Ben Parojcic</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Holly Mabery, Kwaku Mitchell, Andy Sachs, Tom White Rec, and Ben Parojcic</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Week of 2/5/18</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/week-of-020518.html</link>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2018-02-05 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Denny Robert - Let’s Help Each Other With Our Goals This Year

Scott Hollinger - Seismic activity in Montana

Andrew Bolton - Breaking Down the Numbers From the 2017 Market

Jeremy Mellick - 2017 market recap and 2018 projections

Kristin Jamieson - Avoid this mistake before closing

Janice Overbeck - Once upon a time…

Dan Fulkerson - WI KÖNNEN WIR IHNEN HELFEN? (HOW CAN WE HELP YOU?)

Graham MacKenzie - Why you shouldn’t wait until spring to list?

Amy Smits / Kevin Smits - 2018 Summit County market predictions

Brian Lessinger - More of Your Real Estate Questions Answered

Rob Spring - Waiting to purchase vs. purchasing now

Angela Fox - 7 signs it’s time to move

Brandie Mathison Klein - 	You Still Have Time to File Your Homestead Exemption

Jay Heidel - Make your move before it’s too late

O’Neill Team - 2017 MARKET REVIEW AND 2018 PREDICTIONS

Seth &amp; Alyce Dailey - Simple Steps to Creating a Zen Bedroom

Alex Tooke - Busting 3 real estate myths

Brett Sikora - What’s Happening So Far in the Spring Real Estate Market? 

Chris Hauck - What can we learn from 2017?

Eric Mortimer - Are Home Assessments the Same Thing as Home Value?

Patricia Kiteke - Can You Take Advantage of the Winter Market By Selling Now?

Rob Bowerman - A Few Tips on How to Make Your Resume Shine

Barbara Radke - Thank you for a great 2017

Chris Heller - Important tips for pet owners

Christal Johnson - Turning your primary home to into an investment property

Dave Knight - Save money on your property taxes

Dave Nimick - How our 2018 market will be different

Gary Raze - The Reality of Life Insurance and Its Benefits

Bill White - Know your down payments

Greg McDaniel - 	A major announcement

Mario Giganti - What is asset allocation and why is it important?

Willie Miranda - Learn how to execute your goals

Aaron &amp; Kelly Allen - What Can Buyers and Sellers Expect at Closing?

Jennifer Smith - 3 things to know about insurance this year

Leslie Carver - What Dave Ramsey Recommends to Save for a Home Purchase

Jeff Green - Check out My Recent Interview on “The Price of Business”

Mikki Ramey - Why should you work with us?

Ben Parojcic - Are we headed for another market crash?

David Robinson - Rates won’t stay put for long

David Rosen - Don’t Choose Just Anyone to Be Your Real Estate Attorney

Jon DeHart - It’s Time for a Market Update

Lindsey Gudger - The State of the Market in 2018

Alexis Weigand - Pre-listing: a safe route for future homebuyers

Brandon Blackwell - Get those ducks in a row

Clifton Sanders - A Foreclosure Starts With a Missed Payment

Maria Hoffman - The final 2017 real estate numbers are in 

Maynard Wagner - How is the Seattle market doing?

Alfie McFadden - Answering your real estate questions

Black Clover Fitness - Should you work out when sick?

Brandon Montemayor - What Should You Do If Your Property Taxes Are Too High? 

Charleston Homes - How cold weather affects new homes

Danielle Py-Salas - 	4 Questions to Ask a Potential Real Estate Agent

Jason Secor - What to expect from the 2018 market

Ryan Anderson - 3 steps to boost your home’s appeal

Scott Irvin - 	What Has Tax Reform Done to Our Market?

Adrienne Lally - Cupcakes Are the Key to Happiness—Grumps Hate Them

Amanda Howard - 10 tips on looking for a Florida home near water

Bret Johnson - 8 Small Things That Make Your Home Look Like a Big Mess

Brian Riolo - 10 Ways to Save for Your Down Payment

Dan Rochon - Set yourself up for your best day

Dar Walden - YOU’RE INVITED: Home Seller’s Seminar

Kevin Langan - What You Need to Know About Renting a Home

Lisa Sisko - Take Advantage of the Market Right Now

Patrick Fitzgerald - What’s the Difference Between an Inspection and an Appraisal?

Diane Cardano-Casacio - 3 crucial, avoidable mistakes

Lee Tessier - The impact of the new tax laws

Mike Quail - 5 Important Things You Should Do To Your Home After You Buy

Nick Good - Send us your real estate questions

Kevin Clancy - What’s your marketing budget?

Monique Walker - The 2018 Market Is Already Full of Opportunities

Patrick Southern - A perfect approach to listing in our current market

Tom Daves - Why Is Now the Best Time to Sell?

Trae Dauby - 	The Best Time to Get Your Home on the Market

Ryan Butler - How to purchase and fix a home at the same time

Anastasia Riley - Is your roof protected?

Dave Hooke - What Does the Housing Shortage Mean to Buyers and Sellers?

Kevin Clancy - SOI	Answering 2 common questions

Melissa Thompson - A Look Back at the 2017 Market

Chase Craig - 3 top tips for 2018 homebuyers

Darren James - Is Your Home Priced Correctly?

Jeff Cook - 4 things to consider before you move

Jerry Land - How Do You Deal With Failure? Do You React or Respond?

Marcus Vanzant - HIre a proven agent

Richard Witt - The Benefits of Selling to a Cash Buyer

Todd Martin - The hidden benefits of winter listings

Amanda Howard - Is it a good idea to list in winter?

Brett Jennings - 	How to get more out of your house’s value-Part 2

Charlotte Mabry - How Can Remodeling Decrease Home Value?

Don Williams - 5 Things a VA Loan Can Do for You

Earron Shields - 8 Reasons You Should Always Use a Realtor When Purchasing a Home

Erin Caraway Gregory - Watch: How to select the right agent

Joe Mendoza - Are You Joining Us on June 16th?

Lisa Treu - 	What are the top 3 ways to become a better leader?

Zach Sikes - What Happens During the Home Buying Process?

Anthony Boatner - 4 Bathroom Upgrades That Won’t Cost an Arm and a Leg

Bill Black - Have you heard of SAT-7?

Caleb Pearson - The Mt. Pleasant market numbers are in

Dan Jones - 3 mistakes that ruin home sales

Pazi D - Breathing Life Back into an Unsuccessful Listing

Scott English - 4 emotional reasons to purchase a home

Shawn O’Neill - Why Smart Sellers Are Listing Now

Dan Hamilton - 	3 reasons your home is stuck on the market

Denise Swick - 2 options for empty nesters

Gavin Shnieder - 3 things you must ask any agent

Kyle Lancashire - The Homestead Exemption Can Save You Money

Michael Kaim - An update on the winter market

Robert &amp; Shannon Rollings - 	Which is the better move: buying or renting?

Ruby Miranda - Got a question that needs answering?

Diva Team - 5 Reasons Using a Real Estate Professional Benefits You

Kevin Jimeno - Avoid This Major Mistake When Filing Your Taxes

Wes Peters - We Have Investors That Will Buy Your House As-Is, Cash, No Commission or Expenses to Sell 

Ferzoco Group - Don’t Forget About These Costs When Selling Your Home

Abel Tejeda - 8 Questions You Should Always Ask Your Lender

Scott Lander - Arizona Winters and Your Home

(ASI) Aesthetic Surgical Images - How to chose the right rhinoplasty surgeon

Damon Gettier - The Unexpected Costs of Buying a Home, Part 5: Homeowners Insurance

Donald Payne - 	Reviewing the Market: 2017 vs. 2018

Misty Soldwisch - Don’t let this luxury home pass you by

Zach Wessolleck - How to Save for Your Down Payment on Your Next Home 

Jason McIntosh - Come work with the McIntosh Team

Deja Lett - How can you set your listing up for success?
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Denny Robert, Scott Hollinger, Andrew Bolton, Jeremy Mellick, and Kristin Jamieson</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Denny Robert, Scott Hollinger, Andrew Bolton, Jeremy Mellick, and Kristin Jamieson</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Week of 1/29/18</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/week-of-012918.html</link>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2018-01-29 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Mikki Ramey - Calling all homeowners

Ed Pluchar - How Important Is Price Per Square Foot in Terms of Home Value?

Andy Sachs - Why hire a tech-savy agent? 

Alex Mont-Ros - An Interview With Mike Dorman From Eclipse BMS

Angela Fox - 5 kitchen trends with staying power

Chris Hauck - How is our 2018 market shaping up so far?

Nancy Seraphin - How Can You Attain the Mindset of a Trusted Advisor?

Sandy Eagon - Don’t Get Your Real Estate Information From the News 

Kevin Hudoba - How the Tax Overhaul Will Affect Real Estate?

Rob Spring - Waiting to purchase vs. purchasing now

Ana Sarabia - Take advantage of our market now

Greg Flaherty - Buy, Rent &amp; Retire with San Diego Real Estate

Patricia Kiteke - Can You Take Advantage of the Winter Market By Selling Now?

Rob Bowerman - A Few Tips on How to Make Your Resume Shine

Bill White - Know your down payments

Mario Giganti - What is asset allocation and why is it important?

Cristina Dougherty - What Can Your Child Learn at Primrose School of Chantilly?

Tina Beliveau - The lead generation model

Duke Kimhan - WHY DO WE REQUIRE TENANTS TO FILL OUT A PROPERTY CONDITION FORM?

John Head - How can our newest agent serve you?

Brandie Mathison Klein - 	How to Set and Reach Your Goals for 2018

Nick McLean - Make these quick fixes before listing

Nick Shivers - Should you make your home purchase in 2018?

Tom White - 9 home repairs you shouldn’t put off

Nico &amp; Pasquale - My Greatest Work – The Great Debate Part 2

Anastasia Riley - Some motivation to start your new year right

Andrew Duncan - Join Us on March 11 for Our Client Appreciation Party

Michael Vernamonti - How Can You Make Money Through Real Estate Investing?

Adrienne Lally - Cupcakes Are the Key to Happiness—Grumps Hate Them

Bret Johnson - 8 Small Things That Make Your Home Look Like a Big Mess

Brian Riolo - 10 Ways to Save for Your Down Payment

Sandie Hea - See How Realtors Are Getting Rich Off of You! 

Kevin McCarthy - A Virtual Tour of a Property We Transformed

Willie Miranda - What 2018 holds for our markets

Karen &amp; Joe Donovan (Tampa) - What Happens When the Market Favors Sellers?

Kris Miller - Have you taught your kids this vital skill?

Nick Kellar - So You’ve Successfully Closed on Your House: What’s Next?

Chip Glennon - 	An update on the winter market

Darren James - Is Your Home Priced Correctly?

Justin Udy - What Can You Expect From a Home Inspection?

Marcus Vanzant - HIre a proven agent

Richard Witt - The Benefits of Selling to a Cash Buyer

Tim &amp; Jennifer Cowan - Common Real Estate Scams to Avoid

Todd Martin - The hidden benefits of winter listings

Bill Black - Our fresh new look

Bill Burns - 3 Common Myths About Reverse Mortgages

Jay White - What do homebuyers want to know?

Karen &amp; Joe Donovan (Long Island) - What Happens When the Market Favors Sellers?

Lisa Blake/Katie Kaven - A Virtual Tour of a Truly Fabulous Listing

Robert &amp; Shannon Rollings - 	Visiting Mary Beth photography

Susan Heller - Things You Should Know About Upsizing

Andy Richardson - List Now, Beat the Competition, and Get a Better Deal

Dar Walden - 3 deal-killing mistakes

Joshua Stern - 	Wasatch Front real estate tips

Patrick Collins - A Few Ways to Increase Your Home’s Value

Pazi D - Breathing Life Back into an Unsuccessful Listing

Kyle Lancashire - The Homestead Exemption Can Save You Money

Lisa Treu - 	What are 3 big mistakes that will keep you from getting your dream home?

Ruby Miranda - Got a question that needs answering?

Kevin Jimeno - Avoid This Major Mistake When Filing Your Taxes

Wes Peters - We Have Investors That Will Buy Your House As-Is, Cash, No Commission or Expenses to Sell 

Ferzoco Group - Don’t Forget About These Costs When Selling Your Home

Greg Tran - How to flip a house pt. 1

(ASI) Aesthetic Surgical Images - How long is the recovery process

Scott Lander - Arizona Winters and Your Home

Jeff Smith - 3 Ways to Resolve any Home Inspection Issues

Andrew Kent - Common Home Buying Misconceptions

Delane Rouse - 5 reasons to get a professional headshot

Zach Wessolleck - How to Save for Your Down Payment on Your Next Home 

Jason McIntosh - We’ll see you on Sunday for the big game
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Mikki Ramey, Ed Pluchar, Andy Sachs, Alex Mont-Ros, and Angela Fox</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Mikki Ramey, Ed Pluchar, Andy Sachs, Alex Mont-Ros, and Angela Fox</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Week of 1/22/18</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/week-of-012218.html</link>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2018-01-22 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Wade Betz - Tax code changes to know

Tara Limbird - 	A special message for you and yours

Jeremy Mellick - Do you have any real estate questions?

Blaine Moore - What can you expect from our 2018 market?

Leslie Carver - A Final Market Report for 2017

Mike Roth - Basement excavation repair

Tina Caul - Winter 2018 Raleigh home price update

David Van Noy - 	Food For Thoughts for Buyers and Sellers 

Joe DiRaffaele - CES smart home rundown

Dan Fulkerson - 5 SAN DIEGO CHARITIES WE PROUDLY SUPPORT

Micah Munro - Winter 2018 Toronto home price update

Rhonda Sher - You need to have an updated LinkedIn

Melida Potts - Are you listing your home this winter?

Shawn Culhane - It’s time to file for homestead exemption

Todd Martin - 	4 tips for successful marketing

Chad Huebener - What is your home’s value

David Rosen - How to Buy and Sell at the Same Time

Thomas Scott - Consequences of tax debt

Bryan &amp; Scott Colemere - What Can You Expect From the 2018 Real Estate Market in Utah?

Jason Will - Join Us for Our KOER Parade Party

Lisa Treu - 	Can exceeding expectations grow you as a leader?

Rob Kittle - Will we see you at our bowling party?

Troy Hansford/Courtney Vance - An Exciting Program to Crowdfund Your Next Home

Amanda Howard - Winter 2018 Jupiter home price update

Lee Tessier

Nate Martinez - Why You Should Consider Listing Now

Scott Irvin - 	Save Money on Your Energy Bill With These 5 Tips

Sean Zanganeh - Important Mortgage Information for Millennial Homebuyers

Danny Sarch - Why are firms leaving protocol?

Jay White - Winter 2018 Charlotte home price update

Lisa Sisko - Increase Your Home’s Value With These 5 Home Improvements

Martin Millner - The Major Impacts We Expect From the New Tax Bill

Shawn Kriewaldt - 4 Simple Upgrades to Completely Transform Your Bathroom

Aaron &amp; Kelly Allen - Know This Before You Search!

Aaron Hendon - What’s going on in the King County Real Estate Market?

Aaron Wittenstein - Network With a Myriad of Professionals at Rockstar Connect

Gary Raze - Looking Back on Our 2017 Market and Making a Few Predictions for 2018

Maggie Harris - Benefits of winterizing your home

Trae Dauby - 	How Housing Inventory Can Affect Your Home’s Value

Amanda Howard - The 2017 real estate market in retrospect

Bob Guest - 5 Ways We Can Help You Get a Great Deal

Brett Sikora - 5 Mistakes Investors Should Avoid When Renovating a Property

Cristina Dougherty - Do You Have Water and Sewer Line Insurance?

Diane Cardano-Casacio - How the new tax bill will impact our market

Earron Shields - Are You Ready? The Spring Market Is Already Here

Melissa Thompson - How Does the New Tax Reform Bill Impact Real Estate?

Ryan Butler - Winter 2018 DC Metro home price update

Danielle Py Salas - 	7 Tips for a Successful Home Buying Process

Dave Hooke - 3 Things You Can Control to Make Your House Saleable

Ian Lobas - How to find the right home inspector for you

Michael Perna - Potentially Lower Your Property Taxes! Watch to Learn!!

Nick Good - Can a home warranty help your listing?

Ryan Anderson - Why do we charge commission?

Diva Team - How Did We Simplify the New Construction Process?

Thom Dallman - Core Group Realty If you aren’t tuning in, you’re missing out

Zach Sikes - What’s the Difference Between a Foreclosure and a Short Sale?

Dave Nimick - You should expect more from your agent

Lindsey Gudger - We Are Excited to Launch Every Door Real Estate

Marcus Green - Forget FAQs, You Need to Ask the SAQs

Denise Swick - Tax reform and real estate

Jason Huerkamp - We Don’t Mind Breaking a Deal to Protect Your Best Interests

Robert &amp; Shannon Rollings

Anthony Boatner - 5 Important Steps in the Home Selling Process

Brayden Bengtzen - These Things Could Be Sabotaging How Your Home Looks to Buyers

Caleb Pearson - 3 factors to consider when making an offer

Michael Kaim - We make sure your listing is seen

Fred &amp; Tami Holmes - What’s the Key to Making Your Home Look Its Best in Winter?

Jeffrey Cohn - Find out your home’s value

Joe Mendoza - What’s Keeping You From Investing in Real Estate?

Kevin Clancy - What motivates you?

Ron Cedillo - What You Should Know About the New Tax Law?

Tom Nickley - What Is the Easiest Way to Organize and Manage Leads?

Valerie Hunter-Kelly - Great News for Veteran Homebuyers!

Jack Lehr - How to Achieve a Warmer, Energy-Efficient Home

(ASI) Aesthetic Surgical Images - A few post-surgery makeup tips

Julie Baldino - Make Your Move Hassle-Free With These 4 Tips

Kevin Clancy - Trust our perspective and experience

Damon Gettier - What to Do With Excess Paper in Your Home

John Hatch - 	Caribbean real estate investment

Kathy Toth - Pre-Approval vs. Pre-Qualification: Which Is Better?

Dave Heeter - Winter 2018 southern New Hampshire home price update

Donald Payne - 	3 Key Questions to Ask Yourself Before Listing Your Home
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Wade Betz, Tara Limbird, Jeremy Mellick, Blaine Moore, Leslie Carter</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Wade Betz, Tara Limbird, Jeremy Mellick, Blaine Moore, Leslie Carter</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Week of 1/15/18</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/week-of-011518.html</link>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2018-01-15 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Casey Cooke - Pocket listing tips

Kristin Jamieson - Your employment status and your application

Andrew Ford - What the Past Market Tells Us About the Future

Earron Shields - You’re Invited To Come &amp; Learn

Brian Hammond - Review of the Nashville housing market

Tyler Goff - What’s it like working with us?

Stacy Esser - Plain text

Jay Heidel - A unique investment opportunity

Jeff Quintin - 	Winter 2018 home price update

John Simmonds - What’s Going in the 2018 Market?

Adrienne Lally - Meet Our Buyer’s Agent: Yana Novikov

Angela Fox - What can we learn from the 2017 market?

O’Neill Team - LET THE TOP AGENT IN CHARLESTON HELP YOU WITH YOUR REAL ESTATE NEEDS

Peter Dellane - Peter Dellane-How the new tax bil impacts real estate

Ben Parojcic - Are Winter listings a bad idea?

Jason Daniels Training - Great Leads vs. Not-So-Great Leads: a Definitive Ranking

Kari Kohler - Changes in the St. Charles Market You Should Know About

Tina Beliveau - Preparing your 2018 business plan

Sherry &amp; Angela - 	Save $1,000’s! Don’t Forget to File Your Homestead Exemption

Joshua Stern - 	Thank you for coming

Seth &amp; Alyce Dailey - Credit advice for potential homebuyers

Brian Canady - 3 Renovations to Help Sell Your Colorado Springs Home

Charleston Homes - How ice melt damages your driveway

Dave Hooke Recruiting - How Has the Bright MLS Changed the Way We Work?

Duke Kimhan - How to Handle Satellite Dishes and Your Property

Ed Pluchar - How to Make an Offer on an Older Listing

Zach Wessolleck - Looking Back on Our 2017 Market and Looking Ahead to 2018

Anne-Marie McCormick - Winter San Diego home price update

Brandie Mathison Klein - Where Has the Market Been and Where Will It Go?

Brian Riolo - Have Your Best Year Ever in 2018

Alex Mont-Ros - What Can Streamlined Business Solutions Do For You?

Michael Vernamonti - What Are Aged REOs and Why Are They Great for Flippers?

Brian Gagnon - A look back at 2017’s market

Chase Craig - A few tips for Idaho real estate transactions

Don Williams - 3 Reasons to Have a Pre-Listing Home Inspection

Josh Pemberton (DiBello Group) - 5 mistakes to avoid if you want to list your home in 2018

Nick McLean - Improve your home owner experience

Black Clover Fitness - Can coffee be good for you?

Chad Hauer - You Can Always Expect These 4 Things From the Right Agent

Kevin McCarthy - How Did We Manage to Fix This Property?

Andy Sachs - A special benefit to working with us

Jay White - 4 tips for homebuyers in 2018

Justin Udy - What’s Causing Buyers to Be So Optimistic Right Now?

Forth Hoyt - Happy New Year! Do Prices Have You Concerned for 2018?  

Monique Walker - How will tax reform impact real estate?

Christal Johnson - “Getting into” the real estate business

Rex Jarnagin - Things You Should Know About the Buying Process

Caleb Pearson - Winter 2018 Mount Pleasant home price update

Greg McDaniel - 	10 terms first-time homebuyers should know

Patrick Collins - What Comes After the Home Inspection?

Ryan Butler -2017 market recap and 2018 predictions

Brent Dildine - Are You Thinking of Buying a New Construction Home in Our Market?

Chip Glennon - 	Should you hire your friend as your Realtor?

Denise Swick - Why isn’t your listing moving off the market?

Joe Coimbra - A friend of mine just got arrested…

Pazi D - FHA Loan Credit Requirements You Should Know

Kevin Hudoba - Benefits and Disadvantages of Paying Your Mortgage Off Early

Misty Soldwisch - What sets our real estate team apart?

Robert &amp; Shannon Rollings - 	Avoid these 3 moving mistakes

Valerie Hunter-Kelly - A Review of Our Past and Present Real Estate Market

Bret Johnson - 2017 Market Recap and 2018 Real Estate Predictions 

Scott Lander - 6 Things to Avoid When Buying a Home in 2018

Ferzoco Group - 9 Tips to Help You Save for Your Down Payment

(ASI) Aesthetic Surgical Images - How to preserve breast size during a lift
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Casey Cooke, Kristin Jamieson, Andrew Ford, Earron Shields, and Brian Hammond</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Casey Cooke, Kristin Jamieson, Andrew Ford, Earron Shields, and Brian Hammond</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Week of 1/8/18</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/week-of-010818.html</link>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2018-01-08 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Andrew Bolton - Retrofit Your House With the Green On Program

Graham Mackenzie - Do you have any real estate questons?

Amanda Howard - Tax Reminder from Amanda Howard real estate

Hal Sweasey - 	Do the new tax laws hurts our real estate market?

Tanya Stevenson - What Can You Expect From Our Colorado Springs Market in 2018?

Chris Hauck - A hidden opportunity for the new year

Micah Munro - 3 projexts to prepare your home from winter

Dan Fulkerson - WHAT MAKES BATTA FULKERSON STAND OUT?

Blaine Moore - Upcoming changes in home affordability

Brian Lessinger - Why Work With the Lessinger Team?

Danielle Salas - 	3 Easy Steps for Selling Your Home

Lance Woodley - Meet our newest agent-in-training

Marcus Green - How Has KW Helped Kaelee Miller’s Career?

Aaron Hendon - Why you need to do the math

David Rosen - How to Win a Multiple Offer Situation

Anastasia Riley - How to price your home correctly

Jeff Green - What Should You Do When the Market Reaches New Highs?

Patrick Fitzgerald - Mortgage Loan Rules for Moving a Manufactured Home

Tim Majka - Important tax code changes to be aware of

Alfie McFadden - A guide to reaching your goals for 2018

Nick Shivers - Should you list your home in 2018?

Pasqualle Scopelliti - Debating My Greatest Work With My Punk Kid

Cristina Dougherty - 5 Reasons That You Shouldn’t Wait to List Your Home

Jay White - How will tax reform impact real estate?

Nate Martinez - The Loan Limit Has Been Raised—What Does This Mean for You?

Treasure Davis - How Using a Team Approach Is Better for Our Clients

Zach Sikes - Thank You for an Amazing 2017

Ben Parojcic - Do you have any real estate questions?

Bryan &amp; Scott Colemere - How Did the Market Do in 2017?

Jesse Herfel &amp; Loretta - How will the upcoming tax reform impact real estate?

Lisa Sisko - 5 Home Improvement Resolutions for 2018

Lisa Treu - 	Want to vacation everday?

Nancy Seraphin - How Does Julie Hopkins Design a Results-Driven Marketing Program?

Ryan Butler - How the new tax plan impacts you

Adrienne Lally - To Bitcoin or Not to Bitcoin - That Is the Question

Dave Hooke - What Does a Day in the Life of a Real Estate Agent Look Like?

Greg McDaniel - 	How will tax reform impact real estate?

Ian Lobas - Winter 2018 Baltimore home price update

Jerry Land - Who Has the Upper Hand in Recruitment, Candidates or Hiring Companies?

Kwaku Mitchell - These 3 Trends Will Cause Prices to Rise in 2018

Mike Quail - 7 tips for purchasing in 2018

Chris Norcross - Preparing to purchase in 2018

Chris Snow - 3 Updates 2018 homebuyers are looking for

Richard Witt - What Will It Cost You to Sell Your Home?

Robert &amp; Shannon Rollings - 	Come see us this weekend

Sandy Eagon - Does Your Home Work for You in 2018?

Sarita Dua - For Any Question Big or Small: Ask Sarita

Amanda Howard - Make you next move simple-Jupiter

Denise Swick - Winter 2018 Ohio home price update

Denise Zirker - Benefits of winterizing your home

Kevin Jimeno - Numbers Don’t Lie: Don’t Wait to Purchase Your Home

Melissa Thompson - A Look Back at Our November 2017 Market

(ASI) Aesthetic Surgical Images - Facelifts and chip liposuction: What to expect

Bill Black - Guiding you through the home buying process

David Robinson - How did our 2017 market shape up?

Kurt Duffeck - Open Saturday, January 13th, 11AM to 2PM.

Christine Browning - Plain Text

Anthony Boatner - 5 Things Homebuyers Should Know in 2018

Brayden Bengtzen - A Year-End Market Wrap Up

Janice Overbeck - Is this new home buying program too good to be true?

Amanda Howard - Make you next move simple-Huntsville

Chad Huebener - What is the home buying process like?

Joshua Stern - 	Winter 2018 Salt Lake City home price update

Kevin Clancy - My challenge to you in 2018

Kris Miller - What are you waiting for?

Lee Tessier - Tips for winterizing your vacant property

Nick Good - 4 things your real estate agent must do

Shawn Luong - Homebuying assistance for seniors

Shawn O’Neill - Do you have any real estate questions?

Tom Nickley Training - 4 Strategies to Take Your Open House to the Next Level

John Schuster - Why Is a Buyer’s Consultation Important?

Andrew Kent - Which Is Better: Renting or Buying?

Aaron Wittenstein - Why Is January the Time to List in Westchester?

Durwin Cheung - What Price Should You Offer on a Home?

Ruby Miranda - Reduce your debt and raise equity

Julie Baldino - How to Take Care of Your Home This Winter

Ruby Henderson	How Can You Be Sure Your Next Home Is Pet-Friendly?

Abel Tejeda - How Do Interest Rate Increases Affect Your Pockets?

Deuce Kirk - Why get a pre-listing inspection?

Jeff Smith - What Type of Home Inspection Repairs Can Homebuyers Ask for?

Kathy Toth - Our Global Reach Helps Sell Luxury Homes

Damon Gettier - Unexpected Buying Costs: Utilities

Diva Team - We Can Help You Buy and Sell Real Estate Anywhere

Thom Dallman Core Group Realty - Why hire Core Group Realty?

Brian Gagnon - Winter 2018 Boston home price update

Brent Downing - Taking a look back at 2017

Donald Payne - 	5 Ways to Dress Your Home for Success

Bob Sokoler	Market predictions for 2018
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Andrew Bolton, Graham Mackenzie, Amanda Howard, Hal Sweasey, and Tanya Stevenson</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Andrew Bolton, Graham Mackenzie, Amanda Howard, Hal Sweasey, and Tanya Stevenson</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Week of 1/1/18</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/week-of-010118.html</link>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2018-01-01 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Seth &amp; Alyce Dailey - Should You Consider Refinancing?

Michael Vernamonti - Looking Back on 2017 and Forward to 2018

Duke Kimhan - Don’t skip this critical process

Mike Roth - My Predictions for the 2018 Real Estate Market

Eric Vallee - A Snapshot of Our Metro Vancouver Market

Cristina Dougherty - How Can Snap Fitness Help You Reach Your Fitness Goals?

Doug Cary - What’s the Latest Word From Our Wasatch Front Market?

Rosalin Smith-Carr - The Best Thing to Do Before You Move

Dan Ihara - Your Winter 2018 Honolulu home price update

Ed Pluchar - 5 Easy Fixes to Solve the Problem of a Messy Home

Nathan Abbott - How to Prepare for Unexpected Costs After Closing

Danny Sarch - A personal message

Bill Burns - A Great New Loan Program for First-Time Homebuyers

Bryan &amp; Scott Colemere - How Did the Market Do in 2017?

Chris Snow - Winter 2018 Northeast Florida home price update

O’Neill Team - WHY DOES GLENN BECK TRUST OUR TEAM?

Brandie Mathison- Klein - 	HOW A BUYER SPECIALIST CAN HELP YOU PURCHASE A NEW CONSTRUCTION HOME

Adam Butler - A Quick Tip on Patching Your Walls

Melida Potts - Do You Have Doubts About Selling This Winter?

Brian Riolo - Make Sure You Ask These 3 Questions Before Buying a Home

Casey Cooke - Why It’s Never too Early to Talk to a Real Estate Agent

Thomas Scott - Tax mistakes to avoid completely

Jason Daniels - You’re Invited to Our Networking Mixer

Jason McIntosh - Winter 2018 Savannah home price update

Josh Pemberton (DiBello Group) - Winter 2018 Seattle home price update

Justin Udy - Is the History of Our Market Bound to Repeat Itself?

Jon &amp; Patty Hampton - How to Have a Winning Winter Listing

Jason Daniels - Why Hire a Realtor When Buying a Home?

Chad Hauer - Your 2017 Market Overview for Pierce County

Kevin Hudoba - December Market Snapshot

Mikki Ramey - Expert tips for real estate investors

Sherry &amp; Angela - 	2017 Housing Stats… Looking Forward to the 2018 Metro Atlanta Market!

Tom White - Get your home sold in 2018

Zach Wessolleck - Getting a New Construction Home? You Need a Realtor’s Help

Kevin McCarthy - A Year-End Review of 2017

Jesse Myles - How to Come out on Top in a Multiple Offer Situation

Delane Rouse - We work around the globe

Ryan Anderson - Can you list on your own?

Aaron &amp; Kelly Allen - So You’re Under Contract. Now What?

Robert &amp; Shannon Rollings - 	3 resolutions for homeowners

Ty Leon Guerrero - Probate Referee Appraisals vs. Normal Appraisals—What’s the Difference?

Joshua Stern - 	Take your real estate career up a notch

(ASI) Aesthetic Surgical Images - Breast reduction recovery

O.K Hogan - Tackling Tricky Scenarios in the Real Estate Process

Scott Lander - An Exciting Opportunity for Investors

Patrick Collins - 3 Tips for Negotiating a Home Sale

Kevin Langan - 3 Ways to Get Your Home Ready to List

Haro Setian - Meet Our Newest Addition: Brad Carper, Professional Photographer

Jon Carbutti - How Investors Can Take Advantage of this Market

Susan Heller - 3 Tips for a Stress-Free Move

Brent Dildine - New Year, New Market?

Ferzoco Group - 10 Things That Make Your House Look Messier Than It Is

Goran &amp; Lisa Forss - A message from Shark Tank’s Barbara Corcoran

Bret Johnson - What 3 Questions Should First-Time Homebuyers Ask When Making an Offer?

Joe Mendoza - Let’s Make 2018 Our Best Year Yet
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Seth & Alyce Dailey, Michael Vernamonti, Duke Kimhan, Mike Roth, and Eric Vallee</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Seth & Alyce Dailey, Michael Vernamonti, Duke Kimhan, Mike Roth, and Eric Vallee</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Week of 12/25/17</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/week-of-122517.html</link>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2017-12-25 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Nick McLean - VIP program 

Angela Fox - Professional Move in 2018 for Angela Fox

Tom White - Make more money with us

Scott Hardesty - May the merry bells keep ringing

Alexis Weigand - Thanks for your support

Alex Mont-Ros - How Justin Richards Built His Real Estate Team

Amanda Howard - Merry Christmas Jupiter

Angie Travis Roberts - Wishing you a Merry Christmas and a Happy New Year

Eric Mortimer - The Benefits of Using Clay Walls in Your Home

Chris Heller - Moving made easy

Anastasia Riley - Shining a light on down payments

Richard Witt - What Should You Expect From Construction Costs?

Scott Himelstein - Build or buy

Chris Norcross - My holiday e-greeting to you

Patrick Fitzgerald - Where Can Veterans Get a Home Improvement Loan?

Brett Sikora - Looking Back on 2017 and Forward to 2018

John Fagan - Watch: An important 2018 ballot initiative

Becky Ivins - We wish you a merry Christmas

Amy Smits - Your 2017 real estate recap

Aaron Hendon - How Will the New Tax Plan Impact the Seattle Market? 

Black Clover Fitness - Don’t wait to start your new workout routine

Trae Dauby - Looking Back on 2017 &amp; What to Expect in 2018

Josh Lioce - 5 Tips to Make Sure Your New Home Fits Your Pet

Brian Canady - 2018 Is Going to Be a Great Year for Real Estate

Gene Agustin - Different income types that will qualify you

Rob Kittle - Is it safe to purchase a home in northern CO?

Patrick Southern - Who knew?

Christal Johnson - What’s the Latest From The Lakeridge Real Estate Market?

Mike Gray - 	Answering one final question this year

Sean Zanganeh - Watch: 3 secrets to finding the right home

Frank Del Rio - 3 little-known energy-saving tips for winter 2018

Amanda Howard - Merry Christmas Huntsville 

Wes Peters - Looking for a Career Change in 2018?

Brandon Montemayor - Best holiday lights in Santa Clarita

Mario Romero - Happy holidays from me to you

Monique Walker - Homes Are More Affordable Now in Phoenix

Aaron Wittenstein - Wishing You a Happy New Year!

Leigh Marcus - Happy Holidays from our family to yours!

Brandon Brittingham - May the merry bells keep ringing

Tiffany Johannes - 7 Mistakes You Must Avoid When Listing Your Home
Ryan Smith - 7 Tips to Help You Make Sure Your New Home Is Pet-Friendly

Dave Hooke - How Should You Budget Your Monthly Housing Allowance?

Ernie Dill - Closing cost basics

Jan Leasure - Thank You for Your Support in 2018

Dave Knight - All About Reverse Mortgages

Joe DeSane - May the merry bells keep ringing

Marcus Vanzant - Why is now such a great time to sell a home?

Jeremy Qualley - Watch: Wishing you a merry Christmas

Jesse Herfel &amp; Loretta - Happy holidays, from our family to yours

Ana Sarabia - 2 Game-Changing Topics in the Real Estate Industry

Sean Hellmann - Happy Holidays!

Mike Quail - Is the real estate bubble about to burst?

Shawn Culhane - Which Home Improvements Bring the Best Return on Your Investment?

Tiffany Holtz - 4 tips for listing in the winter market

Josh Cooley - Should you trust Zestimates?

Chip Glennon - 	Zestimates

Martin Millner - Start Preparing for Your 2018 Home Purchase Today

Tom Nickley Training - Are Expensive Internet Leads Worth It?

(ASI) Aesthetic Surgical Images - How to sleep after a tummy tuck

Mindy Robbins - How can you make a difference in our community?

Andy Stavros - Watch: A Holiday Message For You

Kwasi Bowie - 3 tips for 2018 homebuyers

Larry Martin - Season’s greetings

Earron Shields - What Closing Costs Do Sellers Have to Pay?

Diane Cardano-Casacio - Hot off the presses: December 2017

Dan Hamilton - 	What will happen to our market in 2018?

Kris Miller - Where does true wealth lie?

Billy/Heidi Phong - Does Your Home Insurance Policy Cover Everything It Needs to?

John Teixeira - WATCH: How to start investing in rental properties

Caleb Pearson

Ruby Miranda - Make your home more energy efficient / Save more energy this winter

Ron Cedillo - What Happened in 2017 and What Can You Expect From the 2018 Market?

Julie Baldino - How to Choose the Right Home for You and Your Pets

Ruby Henderson - 8 Tips to Prepare Your Home for the Winter Market

Valerie Hunter-Kelly - A Year-Over-Year Snapshot of Our Latest Market Statistics

Chris Colgan - Market update

Jason Secor - 3 steps 2018 homebuyers can take today

Zach Sikes - Can You Sell Your Home in Winter?

Kathy Toth - Monday Morning Coffee
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Nick McLean, Angela Fox, Tom White, Scott Hardesty, and Alexis Weigand</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Nick McLean, Angela Fox, Tom White, Scott Hardesty, and Alexis Weigand</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Week of 12/18/17</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/week-of-121817.html</link>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2017-12-18 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>John Carr and Rosalin Smith Carr - New Mortgage Guidelines Being Rolled Out in Canada

Seth &amp; Alyce Dailey - 3 Facts You Need to Know About the Home Flipping Craze

Andrew Ford - Which 3 Loan Programs Require Zero Money Down?

Tracy Wilson - Northern Colorado holiday events

Wade Betz - This New Change Will Be Advantageous to Borrowers

Dan Ihara - Plain Text

Scott Hollinger - Seller home inspections

Holly Mabery - Wire fraud

Patricia Kiteke - 6 Things That Make Your Home Look Messier Than It Is

Brian Hammond - This Christmas, Head on Down to the Gaylord Opryland Resort

Nancy Seraphin - An Expert’s Take on the Art of Time Management

Brian Lessinger - 2017 Was a Great Year Thanks to You

Justin Udy - What Should You Do If Your Client Wants to Wait?

Kati Spaniak - The right timing is key

Dan Fulkerson - DID YOU KNOW THIS ABOUT HEALTH INSURANCE?

Breanne Steen - Happy Holidays!

Bob &amp; Diane Peterson - A Great Tip for Keeping Your Utility Costs Low This Winter

Brandie Mathison - 	4 PROACTIVE STEPS TO BUYING IN 2018

O’Neill Team - THE MATT O’NEILL TEAM HAS BARBARA CORCORAN’S SEAL OF APPROVAL

Marcus Green - 	A Quick Q&amp;A With Joe Reardon

Brian Gagnon - It’s the most wonderful time of the year

David Rosen - Our Team Is a Top-Tier Team You Can Depend On

Richard Witt - A Tried and True Method to Resolve Your Property Tax Lien

Chad Huebener - Happy Holidays

John Head - Merry Christmas and happy New Year

Michael Vernamonti - From Us to You: Happy Holidays

Alfie McFadden - I want to wish you a merry Christmas

Ryan Butler - Holiday Brunch Video

Gillies Team - 	Your database is an essential tool

Donald Payne - 	Wishing You a Very Merry Holiday Season

Chris Hauck - Have a happy holiday season

Valerie Van de Zilver - Why are homebuyers suddenly so optimistic?

Chris Gorman - Do you know your “why?”

Jon DeHart - Merry Christmas and happy holidays

Jennie Wolek - Self-mastery is the path to growth

Rob Spring - Do You Have Questions About Down Payments? We’ve Got Answers

Zach Wessolleck - Check Out the Best Light Displays in Northern Virginia and D.C.

Treasure Davis - 3 home winterization projects

Jason Daniels Training - Recruiting Books That Can Change Your Real Estate Career

Kelly Fischer - A Christmastime Market Update

Dave Nimick - How are you celebrating the holidays?

Sherry &amp; Angela - 	We Wish You the Happiest Holiday Season

Barbara Radke - How is Manna making a difference?

Becky Ivins - How to increase your value

Nick Shivers - Thank you and happy holidays

Jay White - Keep your home warm and cozy

Carbutti Coaching - Wrapping Up 2017 and Looking Forward to 2018

Mary Peacock - 	Thanks for Everything This Year

Vergis Eiland - Dec 1 Happy Holidays 2017

Joe Sabato - Why are homebuyers suddenly so optimistic?

Jody Donaldson - A Little Kindness Can Go a Long Way This Holiday Season

Sandy Eagon - What We’re Grateful for This Christmas

Misty Soldwisch - Education for agents just got easier

Angela Fox - Don’t let sticker shock steer you away

Tome White - Have a great holiday season

Mindy Robbins - Taking our service to the next level

Nick Leyendecker - December Market update

Ana Sarabia - Wishing You a Happy Holidays

Lisa Treu - 	Working on your business

Chris Snow - Merry Holiday

Jeremy Sisemore - Thank You and Happy Holidays from ASAP Talent Services

Jason Wilson - 5 Tips for Pet Owners to Think About When Looking to Move

Bill Black - Logan

Jesse Myles - Wishing You Happy Holidays

Bob Guest - Should You Sell Your Home This Winter?

Melissa Thompson - How to Choose the Right Home Inspector

Brad Korb - From Our Family to Yours, Happy Holidays

Don Williams - Do You Need a Real Estate Agent When Buying New Construction?

Andrew Kronenberg - 3 home winterization projects with the highest ROI

Chad Hauer - Get Ahead of the Home Buying Game With These 7 Tips

Deja Lett - Happy Holidays!

Bill Burns - How the Most Recent Change in Conforming Limits Impacts You

Adam Butler - Why Do You Need to Cover Your Home’s Spigots During the Winter?

Mikki Ramey - 3 tips for homebuyers

Ian Lobas - Are you making any of these listing mistakes?

Shawn Luong - 2017 Has Been a Good Year for Real Estate

Kevin Hudoba - The Real Reasons Behind Buyer Optimism

Brad Korb - What Does the Fed’s Recent Interest Rate Hike Mean for You?

Chase Craig - We Wish You the Best in the New Year

Alan Kushmakov - An update on Phoenix real estate

Adrienne Lally - Give the Present of Presence This Christmas

Aaron &amp; Kelly Allen - Happy Holidays

Ryan Anderson - Need To List Before You Purchase?

Ty Leon Guerrero - Tips for Handling Real Estate During Probate

Darin Triolo - December 1 Short-term rentals

Andy Sachs - Future real estate marketing

Susan Heller - Reasons to list your home during the holidays - plain txt

Danielle Py-Salas - Happy Holidays From All of Us at the Salas Team

Jason Daniels - Are You the Winner of Our Review Contest?

Monica Benevides - Happy Holidays, and May 2018 Bring Peace, Joy, and Laughter

Dan Rochon - 2017 WAS A SUCCESS THANKS TO YOU

Robert &amp; Shannon Rollings - 	Happy Holidays!

Tad Wicker - You’ll love our online tools

Rex Jarnagin - The Holidays Can Be a Most Wonderful Time to Sell: Part 2

Greg Tran - Looking forward to another great year

David Huffaker - Happy Holidays

Susanne Casey - Get the best homeowners insurance possible

Lenny LaRocca//Tony Cangas - 3 home winterizations projects

(ASI) Aesthetic Surgical Images - Caring for blepharoplasty incisions

Anthony Boatner - 3 Common Moving Mistakes to Avoid

Tim Majka - 	This Recent Announcement Will Save Home Buyers a Lot of Money

Philipp Fries - Why are homebuyers suddenly so optimistic?

Daniel Dixon - 3 little-known energy-saving tips for winter 2018

Glenda Williamson - Thank You For Our Best Year Ever

Brian Canady - Happy Holidays!

Sandy Blanton - We Can Help You Sell Your Expired Listings

Jason Mitchell - The Mitchell Group Has a Special Holiday Message for You

Greg McDaniel - 	Starbucks and your home value

Blake Sloan - Your December real estate market update

Chip Hodgkins - 	Home remodeling projects with the best ROI

Jon Carbutti - We Hope You’re Enjoying the Holiday Season

Craig &amp; Stacey Akers - Searching for the perfect holiday gift?

Tracy Venturi - Don’t Underestimate Your Budget

Brent Dildine - We Wish You a Merry Christmas and a Happy New Year

Jason Shinpaugh - Holidays

Denise Swick - 3 reasons FSBOs fail

John Hatch - 	Listing in the winter

Tim Majka - 	Happy Holidays From Imagine Realty

Joshua Stern - 	holiday message

Rick Sadle - Tax Changes Part 2: Capital Gains Exemption

Joe Coimbra - Think about your loved ones - plain txt

Janice Overbeck - Should you hire an agent to list your home?

Kodi Riddle - How will the Fed’s new move impact real estate?

Diva Team - Happy Holidays From the Mountain Coast Group

Todd Martin - holidays

Andy Richardson - Enjoy This Holiday Season

Nick Good - Optimistic homebuyers are plentiful

Scott English - Is your home safe this holiday season?

Ferzoco Group - What Makes Now a Great Opportunity to Buy and Sell?

Andrew Kent - Why you NEED a Trusted Advisor

Karen &amp; Joe Donovan (Long Island) - Check Out This New Music Video Featuring the Donovan 3

Jeff Cook - Dec 2 Merry Christmas 2017

Jean Shine - 3 little-known energy-saving tips for winter 2018

Kevin Langan - 3 Projects to Help Your Home This Winter

Kevin Clancy - How will President Trump’s tax cuts affect you?

Tiffany Johannes - HAPPY HOLIDAYS!

Joe Mendoza - We’re Hosting a Holiday Food Drive

Deepak Gupta - Best wishes in the new year

Joy Daniels - Ready to serve you in 2018

Jodie Osofsky - Dec 2 Sugar house

Michael Kaim - Why I’m in this business

Jack Lehr - Why You Should Prepare Now for Your 2018 Home Purchase

Chris Watters - plain text

Ruby Henderson - We’d Like to Help You Sell Your Own Home

Eric Burch - Merry Christmas

Deuce Kirk - Happy Holidays!

Brent Downing - The latest numbers in Columbia

Lee Tessier - Happy Holidays!

Bret Johnson - 6 Mistakes to Avoid When Upsizing Your Home

Matt Barker - Happy Holidays From The Barker Hedges Group

Cristina Dougherty - What Is Actually Covered by Your Condo’s Master Policy?

Sohail Salahuddin - Happy holidays from the entire team
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by John Carr & Rosalin Smith Carr, Seth & Alyce Dailey, Andrew Ford, Tracy Wilson, and Wade Betz</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by John Carr & Rosalin Smith Carr, Seth & Alyce Dailey, Andrew Ford, Tracy Wilson, and Wade Betz</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Week of 12/11/17</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/week-of-121117.html</link>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2017-12-11 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Haro Setian - The Winner of Our Amazon Gift Card Drawing Is…

Tracy Wilson - Meet Amy Lane

Karlyn Ellis - Have you visited our gallery?

Brandon Montemayor - How Does the Santa Clarita Market Look as 2017 Draws to a Close?

Maria Hoffman - Plain text

O’Neill Team - OUR FANTASTIC GROWTH IS THANKS TO YOU

Sandy King - Happy Holidays From Our Symbiont Family

Chris Hauck - 2017 market update

Will Cook -  How Can You Prepare for Your 2018 Home Search?

Alex Mont-Ros - Continuing Our Talk With Attorney Vincent Humphrey

Justin Woodall - Are pre-listing home improvements worth it?

Kari Kohler - How Do You Compete When the Market Heats Up?

Dan Ihara - How Our Team Trainings Benefit You

Scott Himelstein - WiseOceans

Paul Brouillette - If Your Debt Has Become Too Much, a Short Sale May Be the Answer

Michael Vernamonti - The Trouble With Getting Fixer-Upper Financing

Eric Mortimer - Should You Buy or Sell First? A Story of Heartache 

Janet Gresh - A few tips if you’re considering refinancing

Melida Potts - An End-Of-The-Year Recap for 2017

Chris Heller - WATCH: 4 dream-killing mistakes

Chris Norcross - Listing in 2018? You need to prepare now

Kristin Jamieson - Credit Advice for Prospective Mortgage Purchasers

Kevin McCarthy - Can We Get 3 Different Investment Properties Ready for the Market?

Cristina Dougherty - Let Total Wine Help You Celebrate the Holidays in Style

Tom White - What you should know about Zestimates

KWEV - How Can You Prepare Yourself for Changes in Our Market?

Brett Sikora - 4 Demands Every Homebuyer Should Make of Their Agent

Jennie Wolek - How has the world of insurance changed?

Amanda Howard - Real Estate Market Report for November 2017

Kelly Fischer - Homestead exemption

Dave Nimick - Don’t fall victim to this fraud

Robert Mack - 	Strategies for Moving Forward in December

Brandon Blackwell - What to look for during your home search

Jerry Land - What Type of Culture Are We Creating?

Patrick O’Sullivan - Determining Cap Rates for Multi-Family Properties

Jason Duraj - What Is Happening in Our Market?

Enrique Medellin - 	How Can the New Tax Reform Vote Affect You?

David Hamiki - Denver’s Amazing new Lease with the Option to Buy program!

Josh Lioce - Winter Selling

Christal Johnson - The Northern Virginia Market Is Slowing Down

Adam Cohn - Homeownership options for veterans/Financing options for veteran

Marcus Vanzant - What Should You Expect From Your Home Inspection?

Rex Jarnagin - The Holidays Can Be a Most Wonderful Time to Sell: Part 1

Lance Woodley - Unique Challenges of Winter Listings

O.K Hogan - Reflecting on the 2017 Real Estate Market

Christy Kimbrel - Agents duke it out in winter’s hottest sport

Sherry &amp; Angela - 	7 Key Terms in the Commercial Real Estate World

Shane Roxburgh - Tips for new homebuyers

Wes Peters - What’s Happening in the Baltimore Real Estate Market?

Rodney &amp; Jenn Wallner - Homebuyers Are Feeling Optimistic

Dave Hooke - Equifax

Bryan David - Military relocation professionals

Charlotte Mabry - A Few Tips for Buying a New Construction Home

Sarita Dua - A Holiday Message From Our Team to You

Earron Shields - The True Meaning of P.R.I.D.E.

Bob Little - Market update

Tiffany Holtz - Have you been listening to my new show?

Aaron Hendon - 3 Winter Projects to Help Your Home This Winter

Mark Brace - Tips for first-time homebuyers

Tom Nickley Training - 4 Tips That Will Help You Maximize Your Productivity as an Agent

Jesse Herfel &amp; Loretta - All text

Aaron &amp; Kelly Allen - Get Ready to Sell Your Home in 2018

Chip Free - River Run: The Diamond of Davidson

Jeff Adler - Tech upgrades

Josh Cooley - How was our market in 2017?

Craig Barton - Save on energy bills this winter

Danielle Py-Salas - Which Method of Property Valuation Is Best?

David Huffaker - Bent Creek

Fred &amp; Tami Holmes - Your Credit Score and Your First Home

Scott Lander - 6 Small Things That Make Your House Look Messy

Dan Jones - Buyer expectations

Kyle Lancashire - How Do Capital Gains Tax Exemptions Work?

Tiffany Johannes - Despite the Season, Our Market Is Still Active

Kwasi Bowie - Wishing you a merry Christmas

Thom Dallman Core Group Realty - An update on Boise real estate

Greg Taylor - Invest in real estate

Billy/Heidi Phong - 4 Ways to Make the Home Selling Process Faster and Easier

Brent Dildine - What Does an Agent Do Once Your Home Gets Put on the Market?

Chip Glennon - 	4 Reasons Winter Is the Prime Time to Buy

Zach Sikes - 3 Strategies for Investing in Real Estate

Kris Miller - Save now, spend later

Chris Craddock - Home decor

Larry Martin - Save on energy bills this winter

Chase Craig - Why Wait? The 4 Reasons Why Selling Now Is a Good Idea

Jason Secor - A word on thankfulness

Kevin Smith - 8 Great Tips for Listing During the Wintertime

Ruby Miranda - All text

John Mikesh - Living in a listing

SAUL ZENKEVICIUS - How to Know if a Home Improvement Is Worth It

JP Pirtle - Copy of Oct 2 Join our team (3)

Bob Sokoler - Don’t Wait! Take Advantage of Our Hot Market and Sell Now

Julie Baldino - Answering Questions From Home Sellers

Clayton Gits - The Truth Behind Rising Home Prices

Mike Quail - Don’t wait until spring to list your home

Jeff Smith - Does the Current Market Favor Buyers or Sellers?

Delane Rouse - Portraits vs. headshots

Greg Sisson - A Discussion About Will Preparation With Kathryn Sligh

Jason McIntosh - Why You Should Consider Refinancing
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Hero Setian, Tracy Wilson, Karlyn Ellis, Brandon Montemayor, and Maria Hoffman</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Hero Setian, Tracy Wilson, Karlyn Ellis, Brandon Montemayor, and Maria Hoffman</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Week of 12/04/17</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/week-of-120417.html</link>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2017-12-04 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Holly Mabery - Don’t lose your deal

Bob &amp; Diane Peterson - A Question From a Past Client

Seth &amp; Alyce Dailey - Do You Know About These 4 Additional Costs for Buying a Home?

Nancy Seraphin - How Can You Add Leverage to Your Business?

Brian Lessinger - 2 Services We Provide: Property Management and Referrals

Todd Martin - 	Challenging Clients

Brian Hammond - Holiday fun in Nashville

Jennifer Smith - Britt Schulle

Mario Gigant - A Specific Tax Planning Strategy for You to Consider

Jason Daniels - Watch: Start planning for next year now

Becky Ivins - Join us Dec. 2nd for pictures with Santa

Brian Riolo - Great Feedback From Our Clients

Anastasia Riley - The easiest way to change your life

John Head - Your Outer Banks market update

Tyler Goff - A toast to a great Thanksgiving pie giveaway

Jinger Cutting - How does Zillow work?

Rhonda Sher - Making connections on the go

Haro Setian - “Extraordinary Business Leaders Series: You Don’t Want to Miss this Class

Kati Spaniak - 	What do millennial homebuyers really want?

David Rosen - Should You Consider Buying in a Co-op?

Will Cook - 4 tricks for winning bidding wars

Heather Neidlinger - Work with you

Casey Cooke - Help us bring joy to children in need

Adam Butler - Santa Claus Is Coming to K.C.

Brandon Blackwell - Should you list your home this winter?

Doug Cary - reconnect email

Jon DeHart - What You Need to Know About Closing Costs

Nathan Abbott - Experience Florida at Deer Lake State Park

Jay Heidel - Can you list during the holidays?

David Hamiki - Tell us about your experience

Ed Pluchar - Why Are Home Inspections So Important?

Kevin Smith - Join us for our appreciation event

Brian Canady - Is It Wise to Replace Your Carpet Before Listing Your Home?

Cristina Dougherty - Who Pays Real Estate Commissions in Virginia?

Chad Huebener - Buying in an off-peak market

Dave Knight - Is the Holiday Season a Good Time to Sell Your L.A. Home?

Jason Wilson - 5 Tips For a Successful Sale During the Holidays

Leslie Carver - A Few Helpful Tips if You’re Planning on a Home Purchase Soon

Travis Chatwin - How much should you disclose?

Ashley Carter - Gaining a New Perspective on the Home Buying Process

Jason Baker - It’s a Great Time to Sell in Western Montana

Ryan Butler - Home buyer mistakes

Andy Stavros - Watch: Visit Laguna Canyon Winery

Brandon Montemayor - Advice for Dealing With Lowball Offers

Geradl Durham - 	Don’t Let a Faulty Will Ruin Your Transfer of Property

John Schuster - This holiday, we wish you the best

Lisa Sisko - 3 Tips to Keep Your Home Safe for the Holidays

Sean Zanganeh - 5 Reasons Why the Holiday Season Is a Great Time to Sell Your Home

Jeremy Sisemore - The Top 10 In Demand SAP Skills

Rick Carson &amp; Chuck Korger - The Key to Investment Discipline

Zach Wessolleck - Get a Head Start on Buying a Home in 2018

Melinda Elmer - A few tips to avoid being scammed

Melissa Thompson - The Numbers Are In: Memphis Market Update

Jody Donaldson - How Did the Northern Virginia Real Estate Market Do This October?

Mikki Ramey - Your latest Charleston market update

Robert Mack - 	December 2017 Newsletter

Jeremy Larkin - 8th annual Basket Brigade News Video

Rodney &amp; Jenn Wallner - 6 Ways You Could Be Scaring Off Sellers

Shawn Culhane - Get a Sneak Preview of Our New “Coming Soon” Listing

Bryan &amp; Scott Colemere - Bring Your Kids to See Santa With Us This Year

Marjorie Dick Stuart - Negotiating

Angel Garcia - The Golden Rules of Investing in Flip Properties

Sandie Hea - How Does Earnest Money Function Within a Home Sale?

Kevin Clancy - How and why you should thank past clients

Susan Heller - What’s Happening in Our Southwest Florida Real Estate Market?

Ryan Smith - Thinking About Staging Your Home? Make These 4 Repairs First

Dan Fulkerson - DO YOU NEED AN ATTORNEY IF YOU’RE INJURED IN AN ACCIDENT?

Denise Zirke - 	Homebuyers Are Feeling Optimistic

Kevin Hudoba - 5 Reasons You Need to Hire a Professional Agent to Handle Your Transaction

John Fagan - The Little Gym

Shawn Luong - What’s the Key to Identifying a Great Investment Property?

Nate Martinez - Should You Sell Now or Wait Until After the Holidays?

Nate Martinez - Recruiting - 14 Activities Every Real Estate Agent Should Master: Part Two

Ian Lobas - “The Numbers Don’t Lie—a Shift May Be Happening Soon in Our Market

Gene Agustin - Can you use gifted funds toward a new home?

Karen &amp; Joe Donovan (Long Island) - What Is an Inspection Contingency?

John Schuster - How Can You Increase the Value of Your Home?

Darin Triolo - ROI renovation

Mark Gellman - Your November St. Louis Market Update

Martin Millner - The Latest Bucks County Real Estate Information

Deja Lett - Safety precautions to consider before listing

Mark Benefiel - 4 Tips to Properly Stage Your Home for the Market

Janice Overbeck - Don’t miss these upcoming events

Denise Swick - 3 THINGS THAT CAN DRAMATICALLY AFFECT YOUR HOME SALE

Greg McDaniel - 	What Do You Love Most About the Bay?

Andy Sachs - What Are My Market Predictions for 2018?

Tara Limbird - 	Coffee and home value

Ty Leon Guerrero - The Weather Is Cooler but the Market Is Still on Fire

Marc Smith - May the merry bells keep ringing

Shawn Kriewaldt - 7 Tips to Prepare Your Home for Sale in the Winter

Maggie Harris - Fall 2017 McAllen market update

Lindsey Gudger - #EveryOneGetsAHome

Mario Romero - Can refinancing a mortgage hurt your credit?

Dale Downing - How Much of a Down Payment Do You Need to Buy a House?

Rick Sadle - What Do the Proposed Tax Changes Mean for Our Market?

Mary Peacock - 	Prepare for the New Year and Buy Your Dream Home in 2018

Dan Rochon - Brooke Rivera

Nick Good - Get ready for your 2018 home search

Durwin Cheung - A Year Over Year Breakdown of Our 3rd Quarter Market

Michael Kaim - How to handle early offers?

Ernie Dill - How a Good Agent Can Close a Tricky Transaction

Joy Daniels - Introducing our new HouseekR app

Victoria Sandoval	5 Things to Know Before Buying a Short Sale

Jana and Jason DeLong - Watch: The 7 best things about a fall home purchase

Monique Walker - Having Mortgage Trouble? Don’t Worry - Help Is Available

(ASI) Aesthetic Surgical Images - Dec 1

Dan Hamilton - 	5 reasons to list home this winter

Tracy Venturi - Homebuyer Tip No. 2—Never Pick a Lender Based Solely on Their Rate

Kevin Langan - Why Are Homebuyers Feeling Optimistic?

Clifton Sanders - All text

Ferzoco Group - Prepare Your Home for Winter Weather With These Tips

Anthony Boatner - 6 Tips for Winter Home Sellers

Jeremy Qualley - Ready for winter

Sohail Salahuddin - The Secret to Relisting Your Home

Bret Johnson - 5 Tips for Homebuyers in 2018

Jodie Osofsky - Tinker’s Cafe

Kodi Riddle - Can refinancing a mortgage hurt your credit?

Jason Mitchell - Why are homebuyers suddenly so optimistic?

Todd Martin - Buying in a Seller’s Market

Jeff Cook - Entice homebuyers

Lee Tessier - Is it too late to list?

Alex Tooke - 7 steps to purchasing a home in 2018

Deepak Gupta - Best wishes in the new year

Dar Walden - Selling in the winter

Deepak Gupta - Buying Your First Home? These Programs Can Help

John Teixeira - Mortgage Minute 3: Loan Products for Veterans

Jeffrey Cohn - The Pros and Cons of Buying a Home in Winter

Joe Mendoza - Is Seller Financing Right for You?

Joshua Stern - 	Buyer Obstacles

Deuce Kirk - The Challenges That Plague FSBO Sellers

Ron Cedillo - How Can a Listing Agent Help Sell Your Home?

Kathy Toth - How Do You Know How Much Equity Is in Your Home?

Caleb Pearson - Optimistic buyers

Willie Miranda - Should you list now or wait until spring?

Barker Hedges Group - When Is the Best Time to Buy?

David Robinson - Don’t wait until spring to list your home

Hunter Reynolds - Save on energy bills this winter

Brent Downing - Should you list on your own?

Hunter Reynolds - Should You Consider Refinancing?

Valerie Hunter-Kelly - Buyer Tips

Damon Gettier - Unexpected Home Purchasing Costs, Part III: Taxes

Joe DeSane - Are holiday listings a good idea?

Mike Roth - Full-Service Brokerages vs. Discount Brokers—Which Is Better?

Andrew Ford - Can You Buy a Home Without a Realtor?
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Holly Mabery, Bob & Diane Peterson, Seth & Alyce Dailey, Nancy Seraphin and Brian Lessinger</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Holly Mabery, Bob & Diane Peterson, Seth & Alyce Dailey, Nancy Seraphin and Brian Lessinger</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Week of 11/27/17</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/week-of-112717.html</link>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2017-11-27 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>John Carr and Rosalin Smith Carr - How to Navigate a Competitive Market as a Buyer

Kati Spaniak - 	Video: Skyrocketing Illinois property tax

Brett Sikora - You’re Invited to Our 3rd Annual Client Appreciation Party

Scott Hollinger - Should you trust Zillow?

Eric Vallee - October Housing Market Update for the Vancouver Metro Area

Justin Woodall - A Thanksgiving message from us to you

Breanne Steen - Real Estate vs. The Stock Market: Which Should You Invest In?

Brian Hammond - Visiting a Great Local Business: CrossFit Mt. Juliet

Joe DiRaffaele - Las Vegas as You’ve Never Seen It Before

Eric Mortimer - 7 Signs It’s Time to Move

David Shutler - Are you getting enough protein?

Aaron Hendon - Did You Get a Copy of My New Book?

Jerry Land - Learning From the Challenges in Our Past

Sean Zanganeh - Purchasing a second home in San Diego

Patrick Fitzgerald - A Unique Opportunity for Veteran Homebuyers

Jennie Wolek - Holiday gift ideas and more with Candra at Saks

Jeff Green - Interview with Brian Wesbury: Part 2

Casey Cooke - The Benefits of Holiday Listings

Karlyn Ellis - Listing in 2018? Start preparing now

Marcus Green - Is Analysis Paralysis Keeping You Stuck in Place?

Rob Spring - How Can You Improve Your Credit Score?

Kristin Jamieson - Why Is It a Bad Idea to Cosign on a Loan During the Mortgage Process?

Janet Gresh - 3 reasons homebuyers are optimistic

Richard Witt - Should You Work With a Traditional Agent for Probate and Estate Sales?

KWEV - What Are Your Goals for 2018?

John Simmonds - Where to Find the Best Tea on Prince Edward Island

Michael Vernamonti - 4 Things Sellers Can’t Afford to Slack On

Lisa Treu - What makes someone a leader

Tom White - Is San Antonio in a bubble?

Dave Nimick - The best time to put your home on the market

Mike Gray - 	Wishing you a happy Thanksgiving

Gary Raze - Have Your Property Taxes Skyrocketed? Try an Appeal

Blaine Moore - What Items Will You Need to Get Pre-Approved?

Josh Cooley - Wishing you a happy Thanksgiving

Kyle Lancashire - A Beautiful Eastside Austin Home for Sale

Don Vallee - Market Update

Melinda Elmer - A Thanksgiving message from our team

Ryan Butler - Energy Tips

Mindy Robbins - Can refinancing a mortgage hurt your credit?

Chris Gorman - Watch out for these 3 home features

Melida Potts - 3 Tips on How to Maximize Your Fall Sale

Ryan Anderson - Hard questions, simple answers

Chad Hauer - Selling in 2018? These 5 Tips Can Help

Joe DeSane - Wishing you a happy Thanksgiving

Danielle Py- Salas - 	Is There a “Right” Time to Put Your Home on the Market?

Aaron &amp; Kelly Allen - 3 Tips to Get a Head Start on Buying in 2018

Angela Fox - 5 terms to help homebuyers

Erik Winegarden - 2018 homebuyer advice

Doug Herdahl - These 5 things can ruin any listing

Gillies Team - 	Are you and your home truly protected?

Greg Taylor - Market Update

Christal Johnson - Pricing and Condition are Key to Selling Your Home

Brian Beatty - The Shortcomings of Purchasing a Home Without an Agent

Bryan David - Lending for renovations

Greg McDaniel - Reconnect

Rob Kittle - The difference that staging makes

Adam Cohn - If You’re Feeling Stuck With Your Monthly Payments, You’ve Got Options

Chris Norcross - Plain Text

Rodney &amp; Jenn Wallner	Refinanciang (Reid Video)

Chris Snow - Limiting Your Home Search

Don Williams

Bill Black - New loan program

Philipp Fries - Can refinancing a mortgage hurt your credit?

Kwasi Bowie - Prepare your home for winter weather

Andrew Kronenberg - Is a new construction home right for you?

Chase Craig - Sellers: Watch Out for Making These Mistakes

Craig Barton - Should You Consider Refinancing?

Zach Sikes - It’s Time for a Market Update

Ana Sarabia - Buying a Resale Home vs. A Newly Constructed Home

Josh Heneveld - Video: The key to a competitive offer

Janice Overbeck - 3 ways to increase home value

Susanne Casey - Plain Text

Lenny LaRocca//Tony Cangas - Is a Market Shift on the Horizon in South Bay?

Diva Team - How Do Our Latest Market Numbers Stack Up?

Sarita Dua - Should You Inspect Your Home Before You List It?

Craig &amp; Stacey Akers - Why Homebuyers Are So Optimistic About Our Market

Fred &amp; Tami Holmes - The Numbers Are In: It’s a Great Time For Sellers

Joy Daniels - Investment properties are a smart buy

Robert &amp; Shannon Rollings - 	Drone tours

Andrew Kent - 3 Reasons Homebuyers Are So Optimistic About Our Market

Patrick Collins - How to Master the Psychology of Home Showings

Heather Upton - Should You Sell Your Home During the Fall and Winter?

Ruby Henderson - A Fantastic Organization to Consider Giving Back to

Jason Daniels - What’s the Best Home Search Site for the Colorado Springs Area?

Kris Miller - Seeking purpose and making money

Ruby Miranda - 4 Costs Homebuyers Often Forget About

Kevin Smith - How Can You Prepare for Your Next Home Purchase?

Spalding Pyron - Pre-qualified or Pre-approved: What’s the Difference?

Greater Calgary Group - What Not to Do When Listing Your Home

Jason Shinpaugh - Why do you need a pre-approval?

Thom Dallman Core Group Realty - 5 helpful holiday safety tips

Jack Lehr - Exciting Changes Are Coming to Our Team

Greg Tran - Purchasing raw land vs. a home

Larry Martin - Should You Consider Refinancing?

(ASI) Aesthetic Surgical Images - Late management of nasal fractures Caleb Pearson	Refinancing

Julie Baldino - Sell Your Home Quickly and for Top Dollar With Our W.I.S.E. Program

Andrew Duncan - Why We’re the Right Team to Sell Your Home

Jason Secor - How to get top dollar from today’s market

Jeff Smith - Why Should You Put Your Home on the Market This Fall?

Lindsey Springsteen - Busting 3 Common Home Buying Myths

Jason McIntosh - Holiday events

Chad Schwendeman - 3 Questions to Ask Before Hiring a Realtor

Andrew Lamb - Does your offer stand out?
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by John Carr & Rosalin Smith Carr, Kati Spaniak, Brett Sikora, Scott Hollinger, and Eric Vallee</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by John Carr & Rosalin Smith Carr, Kati Spaniak, Brett Sikora, Scott Hollinger, and Eric Vallee</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Week of 11/20/17</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/week-of-112017.html</link>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2017-11-20 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Patricia Kiteke - The Truth About Fast-Cash Buyers

Tracy Wilson - Meet Michelle

Clint Stitser - How Land is Stolen

Seth &amp; Alyce Dailey - How Can You Protect Your Credit After the Equifax Hack?

Amy Smits / Kevin Smits - Smits Team 3rd Annual Pie Giveaway!

Brian Lessinger - Wishing You a Happy Thanksgiving

Bob &amp; Diane Peterson - Should You Sell Your House Over the Holidays?

Dan Ihara - We’re thankful for you

Sharon Stevens - A Quick Stucco Tutorial

Charlotte Mabry - We’ve Got an Opportunity for Agents Looking to Grow

Ed Pluchar - If You’re Under Contract, Is It Too Late to Back Out?

Leslie Carver - Happy Thanksgiving From Team Carver!

Clint Stitser - How Land is Stolen

Paul Brouillette - What Preliminary Steps Should You Take Before Buying a New Home?

Scott Hardesty - A quick real estate update

Jason Wilson - Taking Time to Reflect This Thanksgiving

Brian Riolo - Happy Thanksgiving From Our Entire Team

Zach Wessolleck - A Great Thanksgiving Recipe to Try

O’Neill Team - BUILDING HOMES FOR THOSE IN NEED WITH SEA ISLAND HABITAT FOR HUMANITY

Anastasia Riley - Home Updates That Bring The Most Value

Clint Stitser - How Land is Stolen

Bo Winn - Looking for a home in 2018?

Chad Hauer - 4 Unexpected Costs First-Time Homebuyers Should Watch out for

Ashley Carter - Plain Text

David Rosen - I Went to War for One of My Clients, and We Won—Here’s How

Jerimiah Taylor - Red light, Green light, and your budget

Sean Hellmann - To Our Friends, Family, and Clients: Thank You

Sandie Hea - Do You Know the Answers to These Common Appraisal Questions?

Chris Heller - 5 ways to add value to your home

Jacob Laffoon - A few Thanksgiving tips

Bryan &amp; Scott Colemere - Listing MistakesYou Should Always Avoid

Gene Agustin - Mortgage do’s and don’ts

Shawn Luong - Plain Text

Max Folkers - What will happen to the housing market?

Jose Morales - Another agent success

Kevin Hudoba - Happy Thanksgiving From My Family to Yours

Dave Silva - What Do Rising Interest Rates Mean for You?

Christy Kimbrel - Should You Hire a Buyer’s Agent to Help You Buy a Home?

Ryan Smith - 6 Tips to Get Your Home Ready for the Holidays

Delane Rouse - Budget season is here

Dave Knight - What Is a 1031 Exchange?

GoVig 1 - How are dating and interviewing similar?

Jason Huerkamp - The 4 Most Important Factors in Buying or Selling a Home

Monica Benevides - Plain Text

Jason Penrose - October 2017 market update

Angel Garcia - Making Your Offer More Attractive

Tiffany Holtz - Should You Put Your Home on the Market This Winter?

Kodi Riddle - Why are homebuyers suddenly so optimistic?

Jan Leasure - How Gratitude Helps Your Business

Alan Kushmakov - What Does The Market Have in Store for Those Who List Now

Earron Shields - What Should Buyers Expect to Pay at the Closing Table?

Charlotte Mabry - Do You Have a Problem With Your Foundation?

John West - Get the best deal for your home now - don’t wait until spring to list

Ferzoco Group - How to Celebrate the Holidays Here on the Jersey Shore

Tim Majka - Imagine Realty Wishes You Happy Thanksgiving

Victoria Sandoval - 3 Key Benefits to Homeownership

Maggie Harris - Plain Text

Jesse Myles - 3 Tips to Increase Your Home Value

Kevin Langan - It’s Time to Reflect on Our Blessings

Joe Mendoza - Thank You All for Your Support

Brent Dildine - Wishing You All a Happy Thanksgiving

Jason Daniels - You Could Afford a Home for Less Down Than You Think

Lisa Blake - What’s the Latest News From Our Denver Market?

Deepak Gupta - Happy Holidays From the Dee Team

Blake Sloan - Your November real estate market update

Dar Walden - Winter is officially here

Jon Carbutti - Plain Text

Tracy Venturi - Don’t Buy a Home Without a Realtor

Mike Quail - 5 ways to add value to your home

Chris Watters - Optimistic Homebuyers Plain Text

Shane Neal - The holidays are a great time to list

Mindy Robbins - How will the Fed’s new move impact real estate?

Shane Roxburgh - This listing method could cost you big time

Kevin Clancy - Could a common, deadly gas be in your home?

Lee Tessier - What Do You Need to Know About Short Sales?

Peter MacIntyre - Toys for Tots

Clayton Gits - Plain Text

Ron Cedillo - Why an Agent Is a Homebuyer’s Best Friend
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Patricia Kiteke, Tracy Wilson, Clint Stitser, Seth & Alyce Dailey, and Kevin & Amy Smitz</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Patricia Kiteke, Tracy Wilson, Clint Stitser, Seth & Alyce Dailey, and Kevin & Amy Smitz</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Week of 11/13/17</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/week-of-111317.html</link>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2017-11-13 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>John Carr and Rosalin Smith Carr - What’s the Latest From Our Toronto Market?

Ryan Anderson - Thanksgiving Pie Party

Scott Hollinger - Advice for the off-season

Kodi Riddle - Reserve your pumpkin or apple pie

Rob Kittle - Let Us Add Something Sweet to Your Table This Thanksgiving

Amy Smits / Kevin Smits - Our holiday season pie giveaway is here

Will Cook - 	What’s Going on in Our Market Today?

Joe Sabato - The disappearing deal: foreclosure sales are gone

Sandy King - Are You Interested in Being a Service Technician at Symbiont Service?

Jinger Cutting - Prescott real estate market update

Bob Sokoler - Plain Text

Kari Kohler - 2 Market Secrets to Be Thankful for This Holiday Season

Jennie Wolek - How do you treat your buyer listings?

Tyler Goff - Which home improvements are worth it?

Lisa Sisko - A Day in the Life of Our Administrative Staff

Duke Kimhan - Why Is Loss of Rent Coverage Important for Homeowners?

Becky Ivins - Let us provide the pie this Thanksgiving

Angie Travis Roberts - Beware - I got hacked

Zach Sikes - What We’re Thankful for This Thanksgiving

Jeff Green - Interview With Economist Brian Wesbury: Part 1

John Head - Home inspections vs. appraisals

Ashley Carter - How Short-Term Rentals Can Boost Your Real Estate Investment Strategy

Nathan Abbott - Sitting Down With Mike Ragsdale of 30A.com

Ryan Butler - Trump Tax (All-text)

Dave Nimick - Short-term rental properties

Bill White - How to Prepare Your Home to List This Fall

Kyle Fernandez - Which home repairs actually matter?

Brett Sikora - What Steps Do You Need to Take to Buy a Home in 2018?

Ryan Hummel - Nutrition Talk and Holiday Hours

Rick Carson &amp; Chuck Korger - How Are You Planning for Retirement?

John Schuster - Is Zillow an Accurate Way to Get a Home Value?

Rodney &amp; Jenn Wallner - Holiday Events

Alfie McFadden - Orange County market report

Kevin McCarthy - The Latest Developments From the Sea Casa

Gary Raze - 6 Tips for Homebuyers in 2018

John Mikesh - Watch: How much home can you afford?

Craig Barton - Homebuyers Are Feeling Optimistic

Gerald Durham - Summer Isn’t the Only Good Time to List

Robert Mack - 	November Newsletter

Bob Guest - Our Special Offer Can Set You Up for a Huge Home Sale in 2018

Troy Copeland - Watch: A word about insurance

Lindsey Gudger - The Cost of Waiting

Debbie Spaulder - 	Can You Trust “We Pay Cash for Houses” Signs?

Joe DeSane - Is it possible to juggle 2 transactions?

Dave Hooke - The 3 Steps to Buying and Selling at the Same Time

Darin Triolo - Watch: Is a homeowners association a good fit?

Sandy Blanton - 5 Inexpensive Things You Can Do to Maximize Your Home’s Value

Jeremy Larkin - Help us feed all 265 families!

REOP - Tips for Purchasing a Home During the Holidays

Susanne Casey - Plain Text

Mark Brace - 4 reasons to find a home this fall

Tom Daves - Come Join Us for Music, Fun, and Free Pie

Brad Atkins - Help Others in Burbank Celebrate Thanksgiving

Daniel Dixon - 5 improvement mistakes

Jesse Herfel &amp; Loretta - Three Reasons To Sell Your Home During The Holidays

Dan Jones - Watch: Charlotte’s 4th quarter market update

Ernie Dill - Think You’ve Missed Your Best Chance to Sell Your Home This Year?

Sarita Dua - Are You Asking Agents the Right Questions?

Clifton Sanders - 2 Programs to Help in the Wake of Hurricane Harvey

Scott Lander - What I’m Thankful for This Thanksgiving

Nick Good - School districts and your home price

Kris Miller - How healthy are your spending habits?

Greater Toronto Group (Dijana) - 3 Mistakes to Avoid When Selling Your Home

Aaron Wittenstein - What Low Inventory Means for Our Current Market

Dan Ellison - What Happens During the Inspection Contingency?

Wes Peters - How Does the Cool Kids Campaign Help Children With Cancer?

Dan Hamilton - 	Hot Carolina Neighborhoods

Anthony Boatner - 5 Surprising Benefits of Selling in the Winter

Mary Peacock - 	4 Energy-Efficient Tips for the Winter

Scott English - Happy Holidays From the English Real Estate Group

Shawn Culhane - Why It Makes Sense to List During the Fall

Lenny LaRocca//Tony Cangas - Explaining the Difference Between FHA and Conventional Loans

Christine Browning - How A Home Warranty Will Benefit You

Greater Calgary Group - 4 Tips for Buying in a Seller’s Market

Spalding Pyron - Should You Order a Pre-Listing Inspection?

Andrew Ford - Handling 2 Real Estate Transactions at the Same Time

Sohail Salahuddin - I’d Love to Have Your Help in Growing My Business

Larry Martin - Why Are Homebuyers Feeling Optimistic?

JP Pirtle - Watch: Don’t let hidden contingencies slip by

Marti Hampton - 	How hard is it to get into a home?

Rita Driver - Have a Real Estate Problem? We Can Help

Kathy Toth - Are You Interested in a Career in Real Estate?

Hunter Reynolds - Homebuyers Are Feeling Optimistic
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by John Carr and Rosalin Smith Carr, Ryan Anderson, Scott Hollinger, Kodi Riddle and Rob Kittle</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by John Carr and Rosalin Smith Carr, Ryan Anderson, Scott Hollinger, Kodi Riddle and Rob Kittle</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Week of 11/06/17</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/week-of-11617.html</link>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2017-11-06 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Haro Setian - You’re Invited to Our Annual Cheesecake Giveaway

Seth &amp; Alyce Dailey - Why It Isn’t Too Late to Buy or Sell

Cristina Dougherty - It’s Almost Time for Our Pie Giveaway

Holly Mabery - Buy in the fall

Brian Lessinger - New vs. Existing Homes

Jason Daniels - We Want to Thank You for Giving Us Five-Star Reviews

John Simmonds - Don’t Miss Our 3rd Annual Great American Pie Giveaway

Patricia Kiteke - How Will New Mortgage Rules Impact You?

O’Neill Team - LIST WITH MATT O’NEILL FOR OPTIMAL RESULTS

Gillies Team - 	 A word about the Fed’s recent announcement

Brian Hammond - When Is Reselling a Good Idea?

Marcus Green - A True Story of How Keller Williams Can Transform Brokerages

Alex Mont-Ros - How Does the Development Sector of Real Estate Work?

Tracy Wilson - Is your home wasting energy?

Diva Team - Is Your 2018 Business Plan Ready?

Jessica Sanders - Where Do We Get Our List to Call?

Richard Witt - How Much Does It Cost to Close With Me?

Tom White - San Antonio snapshot

Brian Riolo - What Qualities Do All Great Listing Agents Share?

Anastasia Riley - Listing your home in the fall or winter?

Stephanie Crawford - Knowing the Basics of Title Insurance

Aaron Hendon - The Amazing Story of the Burton Inn

Justin Woodall - What happened to foreclosure deals?

Scott Himelstein - Interest rates

Gary Raze - The Pros and Cons of Buying a New Home

Michael Vernamonti - Home Flipping Tips You Won’t Want to Miss

Mike Roth - Common Basement Concerns for Homebuyers &amp; Homeowners

Angela Fox - Staging your home this fall &amp; winter

Dave Silva - Be Sure to Ask an Agent These Questions

Jon DeHart - Why Fall 2017 Is a Great Time to Buy a Home

Shawn Anderson - The Best Restaurants in Idaho Falls

Andrew Kronenberg - New housing development in Carlisle

David Rosen - Questions You Should Ask Potential Brokers

Rob Spring - What Income Is Considered When Qualifying for a Mortgage?

Kevin Hudoba - How Will the Fed’s Recent Decision Affect You?

Patrick Fitzgerald - What You Need to Know About Property Surveys

Travis Chatwin - 6 ways to build your wealth

Sherry &amp; Angela - 	Don’t Forget to Reserve Your Pie From Us

Jody Donaldson - The 8 Most Common Homebuyer Questions

Jerry Land - What Is Our Approach to Recruiting?

Janice Overbeck - Cobb County market update

Bo Winn - Top 10 reasons to list during the fall

Enrique Medellin - 	5 Questions to Ask Before Moving Into a Homeowners Association

Josh Lioce - What 5 Expenses Do First-Time Homebuyers Often Forget?

Jeremy Larkin - Nominate Families to Receive Thanksgiving NOW!

Melissa Thompson - You’re Invited to Our Annual Pie Giveaway

Dave Knight - What Do Current LA Market Conditions Mean for You?

Gregory Taylo - 	Moving tips Victoria Sandoval	4 Reasons Pre-Approvals Are Essential

Blaine Moore - Things to Know as a Move-Up Buyer

Bryan &amp; Scott Colemere	8 Things You Must Not Overlook When Buying a Home

Don Williams - Busting the Myth That Fall Isn’t a Good Time to Sell

Angel Garcia - The Garcia Team Is Hiring Exceptional Agents

Mike Gray - 	How is our post-Harvey market?

Adam Cohn - Plain text

Nate Martinez - Is Moving Up Right for You?

Rob Ellis - Focus Fridays

Ferzoco Group - A Jersey Shore Market Update

Jan Leasure - How Will the Fed’s New Announcement Impact Your Real Estate Plans?

Patrick O’Sullivan - Sell in the fall

Brian Beatty - What Makes Fall a Great Time to Buy?

Kwasi Bowie - Not all renovations are worth it

Tim Majka - What Does the Fed’s Latest Announcement Mean for You?

Jason Huerkamp - How HOA Homes Can Be Beneficial

Erik Winegarden - Should you list now or wait?

Tiffany Holtz - Is Your Home the Right Size for You?

Christal Johnson - Three Ways to Get Your Offer Accepted in Today’s Competitive Market

Damon Gettier - How to Actively Seek New Business in Real Estate

Jason Penrose - Is the market going to crash?

Jodie Osofsky - What You Should Know About Your Property Taxes

Jesse Myles - 2 Ways You Can Successfully Buy and Sell a Home Simultaneously

Deepak Gupta - Is It a Better Idea to Buy Now or Later?

Jeremy Sisemore - Don’t Make These Mistakes If You’re Hiring During the Holiday Season

Jacob Laffoon - Should you list over the holidays?

Chris Watters - We’re Saying Thanks…With Pie

Craig &amp; Stacey Akers - 5 Ways to Invest in Real Estate

Jason McIntosh - Selling in the off-season

Josh Cooley - Is it too late to list?

Adrienne Lally - Real Estate Agent Gets Surprise Pie In The Face

Matt &amp; Jenn Freda - Meet the Members of teamFREDA

Ana Sarabia - What Makes Fall Such a Great Time to List?

Brent Dildine - The Truth About Zillow’s Estimates

Josh Heneveld - How to Handle Multiple Offer Situations as a Seller

Amy Smits / Kevin Smits - Airbnb Properties vs. Long-Term Rental Properties

Lance Woodley - Plain Text

Patrick Collins - Did You Know That Overpricing Can Reduce Your Home’s Value?

Denise Swick - Shouldn’t wait to list home

Tom Nickley - How Has Our Orlando Market Recovered Since Hurricane Irma?

Deja Lett - How Will the Fed’s Recent Decision Influence the Market?

Goran &amp; Lisa Forss - When to hire a realtor

Brent Drowning - Open House

Joy Daniels - Line your pockets with investment properties

Jack Lehr - How Seller’s Help Affects Buyers and Sellers

Dar Walden - Why fall is a great time to purchase a home

Dave Friedman - The latest in Charleston real estate

Kevin Clancy - How serious is mold?

Julie Baldino - Enter Our Pumpkin Pie Giveaway

Bret Johnson - 	Staging: Get the Most Bang for Your Buck

Jeff Latham - A dream come true: How I learned to fly

Joe Mendoza - How to Have a Major Breakthrough in Real Estate Investing

Deuce Kirk - The Unexpected Costs of Purchasing a Lexington Home

Brian Gubernick - How Do School Districts Impact Your Home’s Value?

Bob Sokoler - A Market Update and a Walk for a Great Cause

Chase Craig - How Can You Win in a Multiple Offer Situation?

Andrew Duncan - Is Your Agent as Good as They Say?
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Hero Setian, Seth & Alyce Dailey, Cristina Dougherty, Holly Mabery and Brian Lessinger</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Hero Setian, Seth & Alyce Dailey, Cristina Dougherty, Holly Mabery and Brian Lessinger</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Week of 10/30/17</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/week-of-103017.html</link>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-30 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Karlyn Ellis - Have you been to Thatcher?

Damon Gettier - Special Announcement for Local Agents

Sandy King - Let Us Help You Inspect Your Damaged Pool Heating Equipment

Janet Gresh - What the Fed’s new move means for you

Bob &amp; Diane Peterson - Learn how to make an offer that stands out

Eric Mortimer - 5 Ways to Avoid Buyer’s Remorse

Mario Gigant - Learn how to transition your portfolio for retirement

Wade Betz - 4 Reasons Why Your Lender Matters

Barbara Radke - Why are there so few homes for sale?

Valerie Van de Zilver - Vacation homes and short-term rentals

Chris Hauck - A guide to getting full-price offers

Scott Himelstein - Don’t Miss out

Joe DiRaffaele - Take Time to Enjoy All That Las Vegas Offers

Marcus Green - Teaching the Importance of Managing Money

Duke Kimhan - Did the Recent Equifax Breach Impact Your Credit?

Ed Pluchar - What Are the True Benefits of Buying and Selling in the Fall?

Jason Baker - Can You Take Advantage of Our Current Market?

Kristin Jamieson - How Much Money Down Is Too Much?

Chad Hauer - The Latest News and Numbers for Pierce County

Scott Hardesty - Were you affected by the Equifax hack?

Jerry Land - Are Human Recruiters Being Replaced?

Melinda Elmer - 5 projects that maximize home value

David Rosen - How I Helped Jim Sell His Home for a Record Price

Paul Brouillette - A Few Things Massachusetts Home Sellers Should Know

Nate Martinez  -  Recruiting	We Want to Teach You How to Build Your Wealth

Black Clover Fitness - Low Calorie Drink Options

Sharon Stevens - Where Is the Best Ice Cream in St. Augustine?

Martin Millner - What’s Going on in the Real Estate World of Bucks County?

Sandie Hea - A 3rd Quarter Update for the St. Louis Metro Market

Dave Hooke Recruiting - The 7 Habits of Highly Effective Real Estate Agents

Cristina Dougherty - 3 Home Improvements to Consider When Selling Your Home

Nathan Abbott - What Can the Tortoise Clinic Do for You?

Jay Heidel - Our market is constantly changing

Jason Wilson - 3 Strategies for the Move-Up Buyer

Nate Martinez - Is It Time for You to Downsize?

Adam Butler - Why I Love Arbor Masters

Don Williams - Is Your Home Ready for Trick-or-Treaters?

Sandy Eagon - How You Can Be a Hero Around the Holiday Dinner Table

John West - Which homes have increased in value the most?

Brandon Montemayor - Are Your Affairs in Order?

Doug Leugers - Need Dinner Reservations? Try La Corte Bistro in Cape Coral

Joe DeSane - Big changes are coming to the economy

Lance Woodley - How Your Property Taxes Can Cost You Extra

Dale Downing - Can Buyers or Sellers Cancel the Purchase Agreement Once in Escrow?

Lorie Gould - Plain Text

Monique Walker - Are Cash Offers Always the Best Option?

Leigh Marcus - How we help homebuyers find their dream home

Marcus Vanzant - How Will the Fed’s Recent Decision Influence the Market?

Kevin Hudoba  - Is This Autumn the Time to Sell Your Carmel Home?

Chase Craig - How Can You Win in a Multiple Offer Situation?

Chris Gorman - The hidden benefits of listing in fall

Jesse Herfel &amp; Loretta - What’s the key to a successful listing?

Sandy Blanton - 3 strategies for juggling transactions

Dave Hooke - Should I Buy or Rent?

Greg McDaniel  - Why I chose Real Estate

Blake Sloan - Your October real estate market update

Robert Mack  - What Should Buyers and Sellers Do as We Approach the Holiday Market?

Sean Zanganeh - Don’t Overlook TheseCritical Property Features

Aaron Wittenstein - You’re Invited to Our Next Networking Event

Caleb Pearson - Carleston Events

Brayden Bengtzen - If You’re Thinking of Buying, Now Is the Time

Jana and Jason DeLong - Halloween Safety Tips

Rick Sadle - How Will the Fed Reducing their Balance Sheet Affect Buyers and Sellers?

Sarita Dua - The Inspection Process Is All About Give and Take

Andrew Kent - A Look at Our Market and a Great Local Vendor

Anthony Boatner - 5 Tips to Entice Buyers &amp; Sell Your Home in Record Time

Haro Setian - Prepare for Our Annual Cheesecake Party

Shawn Kriewaldt - 5 Tips for a Safe and Happy Halloween

Ryan Smith - 6 Things to Never Do During the Home Buying Process

Dan Jones - List in the fall

Clifton Sanders - How to Maintain Your Home’s Value

Alan Kushmakov - Plain Text

Pazi D - Can You Qualify for 100% Financing?

Scott English - 4 Reasons to Never List Without an Agent

Mary Peacock  - Watch to learn about unexpected costs

Spalding Pyron - How Important Is the Final Walkthrough of a Home Sale?

Lee Tessier - We Appreciate Your Support, and Now We Need Your Help

Greg Tran - Which improvements aren’t worth it?

Michael Perna - Winter is Coming . . . . don’t get left in the cold!

Clayton Gits - Top 5 Reasons for the Dip in Inventory

Andy Richardson - How to Avoid Getting Spooked on Your Next Home Purchase

Jeff Smith - What’s Been Happening in Our Denver Market Lately?

Thom Dallman Core Group Realty - 6 ways to prepare your home for winter

Gillies Team  -  A word about the Fed’s recent announcement

Spencer Hasch - Answering All the Questions You’re Afraid to Ask During a Home Tour

Diva Team - A Fall Market Update

Ruby Miranda - Why Do Some Agents Ask for Exclusivity?

Julie Baldino - Don’t Let These Extra Costs Surprise You

Justin Udy - Looking for a home? It just got easier

Kevin Yoder - Sell with confidence

Ron Cedillo - 3 Tips for Selling Your House

Andrew Duncan - When Is the Best Time to Put Your Home on the Market?

Debbie Spaulder  -  2 great destinations for fall fun

Zach Wessolleck - 3 Keys to Selling Your Home if You Have Pets

Chad Schwendeman - 7 Reasons to Buy a Home During Fall
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Karlyn Ellis, Damon Gettier, Sandy King, Janet Gresh, and Bob & Diane Peterson</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Karlyn Ellis, Damon Gettier, Sandy King, Janet Gresh, and Bob & Diane Peterson</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Week of 10/23/17</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/week-of-102317.html</link>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-23 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Scott Hollinger - Is history repeating itself in our market?

Greg Flaherty - Is It a Good Time to Buy in San Diego? 

Holly Mabery - Home inspections

Nancy Seraphin - How The Wilstein Team Uses Leverage

Sandy King - A Message Regarding Hurricane Preparation

Richard Witt - Should You Expect a Secondary Inspection?

Brian Lessinger - Is Your Home Covered if Disaster Strikes?

Jared Chamberlain (Chamberlain Group) - Watch: How to pull off two transactions at once

Justin Woodall - What people forget about downsizing

Brian Riolo - What Should You Expect From Closing Costs?

Leslie Carver - Is Las Vegas Still in a Seller’s Market?

Kari Kohler - Why You Should Consider Buying a New Construction Home

Michael Vernamonti - Snowbird Season Is Upon Us

Angela Fox - A different kind of ghost

Kyle Fernandez - Fall 2017 St. Louis housing update

Jeff Cook - Save the Date for Pie Day!

Anastasia Riley - What will you pay in closing costs?

Gary Raze - All Your Real Estate Questions Answered

Sharon Stevens - Have You Heard of the ZIP System?

Rick Carson &amp; Chuck Korger - Do You Have Enough Saved for Retirement? 71% of Americans Don’t

Chris Heller - Market update for San Diego

Marjorie Dick Stuart - Backup contracts

Bob Guest - October Market Update for the Austin Area

Jody Donaldson - Winter Is Coming. Is Your Home Prepared?

David Rosen - How I Helped Jim Sell His Home for a Record Price

Josh Heneveld - Fall 2017 Salem housing update

Kevin McCarthy - 1031 Exchanges: The Basics

Brandon Brittingham - We’re making property management easy

Daniel Dixon - Meet agent Heather Sowa

Doug Herdahl - Why are there so few homes for sale?

Dave Silva - How to Sell Your Home the Right Way

Josh Pemberton (DiBello Group) - 5 home maintenance tasks to tackle this October

Jon DeHart - Watch to see if Zillow’s Zestimates are accurate

Jennie Wolek - Giving back feels great

Enrique Medellin - 	Buying a Home? Don’t Forget to Budget for These 4 Costs

Jason Daniels Training - What’s the Key to a Successful Open House?

Bryan David - 3 critical home search mistakes

Sean Hellmann - Why Sellers Should Be Excited About Our Current Market

Josh Lioce - 5 Tips for Energy Efficiency in Fall and Winter

Darin Triolo - Watch: How does our market look right now?

Andrew Kronenberg - Fall 2017 Central Pennsylvania housing update

REOP - How Do You Make an Offer in a Competitive Market?

Sherry &amp; Angela - 	Why is Now a Great Time to Sell?

Melissa Thompson - How Can You Protect Yourself Against the Equifax Breach?

Gerald Durham - Home Improvements to Make Before Selling

Sarah/Marty McKay - What Half of Americans Don’t Realize About Purchasing a Home

Susan Heller - Have Storms Affected Our Southwest Florida Market?

Ferzoco Group - What Do the Different Markets Around the Jersey Shore Look Like?

Adam Cohn - Getting a New Home Is Possible, Even With Limited Funds

Rex Jarnagin - Unsure About the Buying Process? We’re Here to Help

Zach Sikes - What Type of Home Is Right for You?

John Schuster - Why home inspections are so crucial

Aaron &amp; Kelly Allen - Recapping the 3rd Quarter of Our East Cobb Market

Mike Duggal - The Controversy of Stigmatized Properties

Shawna Brooks - When and How Do Sellers Pay for Closing Costs?

Bret Johnson - What’s the Latest Word From Our Phoenix Market?

Nick Good - Avoid these 3 home upgrades

Robert &amp; Shannon Rollings - 	October events in CRSA

Delane Rouse - LET US HELP YOU PHOTOGRAPH YOUR OFFICE SPACE

Charlotte Mabry - What Not to Do When Buying a Home

Jeremy Sisemore - What Are Some Common Mistakes Made in the Interview Process?

Ernie Dill - What Does It Actually Cost to Close?

Deepak Gupta - 5 Reasons Now Is the Time to Sell Your Home in Central Florida

Kodi Riddle - Do you know the signs of wire fraud?

Jeff Cook - Is Now a Good Time to Sell in Our Charleston Market?

Shawna Brooks - An Important Reminder in Light of Breast Cancer Awareness Month

Dar Walden - WATCH: Energy efficiencies in your home

Joe Mendoza - What Are the 7 Keys to Investing in Rental Property?

Jason Daniels - Overpricing Your Home Is a Critical Mistake

Josh Cooley - How to list your home for the most money

Matt Templeton - Watch: How to expose your home to millennials

Brent Dildine - Why Are Buyer’s Agents Useful?

SAUL ZENKEVICIUS - Watch: Thoughts about the flipping craze

Rita Driver - What’s the Latest News From Our Memphis Market?

Kevin Smith - Renovations Loans, Explained

Kevin Yoder - Watch: Do relatives and real estate mix?

Wes Peters - My Team Is Putting Our Money Where Our Mouth Is for Our Sellers

Brian Gubernick - 5 Top Tips for Fall and Winter Listings

Hunter Reynolds - Is Fall a Good Time to Put Your Home on the Market?

Kevin Clancy - Our approach to real estate

Jack Lehr - Home Renovation Mortgage

Diva Team - It’s Time for a Look at Our Blooper Reel

Andrew Ford - 3 FAQs About Property Taxes Answered

Kathy Toth - How Do Absorption Rates Impact You?

Matt Barker - Why Green Photos Can Make Or Break A Winter Listing

Damon Gettier - What’s the First Step to Take When Selling Your Home?
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Scott Hollinger, Greg Flaherty, Holly Mabery, Nancy Seraphin and Sandy King</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Scott Hollinger, Greg Flaherty, Holly Mabery, Nancy Seraphin and Sandy King</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Week of 10/16/17</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/week-of-101617.html</link>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-16 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Karlyn Ellis - Fall 2017 Buda/Kyle Texas housing update

Seth &amp; Alyce Dailey - 5 Home Staging Tips That Will Have You Cashing in on Your Home Sale

Earron Shields - You’re Invited to Our Fall Client Appreciation Event

Gretchen Karr - Is Fall a Good Time to Put Your Home on the Market?

Leslie Carver - Don’t Sell Your Home in Nevada Without Making These Disclosures

John Simmonds - How to Maintain Your Pool During the Hurricane

Eric Mortimer - You Latest Calgary Market Snapshot

Mindy Robbins - Fall 2017 Dallas/Ft Worth housing update

Paul Brouillette - Smoke and Carbon Monoxide Requirements When Selling a Home

Dave Nimick - Condo Owner Must Knows

Janet Gresh - Fall 2017 DC Metro area housing update

Alex Lam - 	How was our market this September?

Brian Lessinger - 2 Helpful Books to Jump-Start Your Financial Success

Jessica Sanders - How We Keep Remote Employees Accountable

Philipp Fries - Tour our newest listing

Ed Pluchar - A Quick Tip for Selling Your Home in Today’s Market

Jennie Wolek - How to handle lower offers

Patrick Fitzgerald - Is Using an IRRL a Smart Move for You?

Brian Beatty - Should You Sell in the Fall?

Tim Riordan - Fall 2017 Buffalo Northtowns housing update

Aaron Hendon - A Great New Community Venue Is Coming Soon to Vashon

Alex Mont-Ros - A Conversation With Lloyd Ball of Anomaly Commercial

The Consigliori - The Missing Key Revealed

Spencer Janke - What happened in this bathroom?

Brandon Montemayor - What Does a Recent Change in the Lending World Mean for You?

Jeff Green - Don’t Let Small Obstacles Eclipse Your Long-Term Goals

Sherry &amp; Angela - 	How Does Our 5-Step Buyer System Work?

Clifton Sanders - Work With A Mortgage Team That Truly Cares

Melinda Elmer - Were you impacted by the Equifax data breach?

Lisa Sisko - What Are Your Mortgage and Credit Options?

David Rosen - Property Tax Problems Explained

Ryan Hummel - How to Keep From Getting “Text Neck”

Bill Burns - A Pre-Approval Can Bulk Up Your Offer

Dave Hooke - How Has Our Local Market Changed Since 2016?

Jack Barry - Fall 2017 Philadelphia housing update

Matt Templeton - How Do We Handle a Shifting Market

Adam Bailey - 4 Helpful Halloween Home Tips

Andrew Lamb - Fall 2017 Vacaville housing update

Kwasi Bowie - The myth about down payments debunked

Don Williams - How to Stage Your Home for Success

Christal Johnson - Why Do I Need a Realtor If I Buy New Construction?

Pazi D - You Won’t Believe What’s Possible With Our New Loan Program

Tad Wicker - What makes us stand out compared to other agents?

Jason Bramblett - Fall 2017 Triad Area housing update

Kevin Langan - We’re Bringing Even More Value to Real Estate

Scott Fuller - Watch: What not to overlook when purchasing a home

Patrick O’Sullivan - 3 Reasons You Must Have Professional Photography When Selling

Ferzoco Group - How Are Appraisal Costs Calculated?

Heather Upton - 3 Questions to Ask When Interviewing Listing Agents

Joe Mendoza - Surprise guest for Saturday’s training event

Todd Martin - Fall 2017 Louisville housing update

Don Mowery - How will the Fed’s new move impact real estate? PLAIN TXT

Joy Daniels - Fall 2017 Central Pennsylvania housing update

Clayton Gits - When Are You Committed to a Real Estate Agent?

Jeff Ryder - Why home inspections matter so much

Diane Cardano-Casacio - Homeownership rates are increasing

Kelly Cook - Watch: Should you rent or own a home?

Abel Tejeda - 3 Tips for a Better Credit Score

Aaron Wittenstein - Selling Your Own Home? Take Advantage of the Smart Seller Program

Chris Colgan - How will the Fed’s new move impact real estate?

Jason Mitchell - 5 Things Potential Homebuyers Should Know

Dan Rochon - YOU’RE INVITED TO MY UPCOMING BUSINESS PLANNING CLINIC

JP Pirtle - Watch: We are hiring

Jeff Latham - Fall 2017 Washington housing update

Andrew Duncan - How Irma Affected the Tampa Real Estate Market

Rick Sadle - What Can Staging Do for Your Home?

Joshua Stern  - Market Update

Eric Burch - What to Expect From the Fourth Quarter Real Estate Market

Rob Cedillo - Why Are Pre-Approvals So Important?

Ruby Henderson - Master the Art of Negotiating as a Home Seller

(ASI) Aesthetic Surgical Images - Don’t miss this scary good deal

Robert Mack  - October Newsletter

Delane Rouse - Converting Color Photos to Black &amp; White Is Easy for Us

Chad Schwendeman - These 3 Seller Mistakes Are More Common Than You Think

David Humes - October Market Update

Brent Downing - The basics of working with an agent
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Karlyn Ellis, Seth & Alyce Dailey, Earron Shields, Gretchen Karr, and Leslie Carver</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Karlyn Ellis, Seth & Alyce Dailey, Earron Shields, Gretchen Karr, and Leslie Carver</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Week of 10/9/17</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/weekof10917.html</link>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-09 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Jeffrey Cohn - How Can You Know What Your Home Will Sell for in Omaha?

Scott Hollinger - 3rd Quarter 2017 Waterfront Report

Holly Mabery - Smart home

Joe Coimbra - Attorney Newsletter

Dan &amp; Connie Couse - Plain Text

Marcus Green - Meet Carolyn Chavez

O’Neill Team - Good Marketing Can Maximize Your Home’s Appeal

John Simmonds - How to Maintain Your Pool During the Hurricane

Richard Wit - 	Are There Any Costs or Obligations to Previewing Your Home?

Duke Kimhan - Owners, Rejoice: We’re Here to Help

Jason Wilson - Reserve Your Spot for Our Pie Giveaway!

Andrew Lamb - What Is an Expansion Team

Scott Himelstein - Market update

Jeremy Qualley - Buyer specialist

Melinda Elmer - What does “pre-foreclosure” mean on Zillow?

Marjorie Dick Stuart - Price reduction

Ashley Carter - You’re Invited to Our Free Pumpkin Giveaway!

Joe Richardson - Ask Joe: Answering Your Real Estate Questions

Chris Colgan - The top 4 negotiation tactics

Shane Neal - Looking for talented individuals

Anastasia Riley - What is a home warranty?

Gary Raze - These Missed Details Could Give You Buyer’s Remorse

Ron Margolis - The only way to get an accurate home value

Brett Sikora - 5 Costs That Shock First-Time Homebuyers

Rob Kittle - Plain Text

Nathan Abbott - Have You Been to the Sunset Bay Cafe?

Daniel Dixon - Appraisal questions and answers

Jeremy Sisemore - 10 Hottest I.T. Skills

Lindsey Gudger - What 4 Tips Can Make or Break Your Listing?

Becky Ivins - Do professional photos matter?

Sandy Eagon - 3 Common Misunderstandings Smart Sellers Still Have

Gillies Team - 	Why is a team better than just 1 agent?

Troy Copeland - List in the fall

Josh Lioce - 8 Tips to Prevent Flood Damage

Anthony Boatner - Why You Should Consider a Backup Offer

Bo Winn - Should you list or remodel your home?

David Rosen - Property Tax Problems Explained

Andrew Kronenberg - I am thinking about selling. Now what?

Bryan David - Why order an inspection before listing?

Jon &amp; Patty Hampton - Feds Plain Text

Jennifer Niederbrach - Can you trust online home value tools?

Melissa Thompson - A Look at Our Market: 2016 vs. Now

Chip Hodgkins - 	You must do this as soon as possible

Nate Martinez - Why Hasn’t Your Home Sold Yet?

Shawn Kriewaldt - Fall 2017 Housing Update

GoVig 1 - Becoming a better leader

Monique Walker - Support The Guerrant Foundation’s Worthwhile Cause

Bob Little - Why hire an agent

Sarah/Marty McKay - 4 Tips to Prepare Your Home to Sell in the Fall &amp; Winter

Aaron &amp; Kelly Allen - The Key to Listing in a Shifting Market

Mike Gray - 	How smart is your home?

Jennifer Smith - List in the fall

Zach Wessolleck - What’s the Best Way to Price Your Home?

Mike Duggal - A Guide to Selling Your Home in the Fall

Ryan Smith - How to Speed up the Selling Process

Mike Tchobanian - When Is the Best Time for Homeownership?

Kevin Clancy - Are you moving forward purposefully?

Dar Walden - Anchorage market overview

Kodi Riddle - Fall 2017 Greater Phoenix housing update

Andrew Kent - Is Fall a Good Time to Sell in Salt Lake City?

Greg Tran - Is the Austin market headed for a bubble?

Jeff Adler - Stand out offer

Rick Sadle - Fall 2017 Portland/Vancouver housing update

Kyle Lancashire - Join Us in Welcoming Brandon to Our Team

Chad Smith - Entice homebuyers

Kris Miller - Our group coaching could unlock your success

Leigh Marcus - Winter is coming! Take your outdoor photos now!

Adrienne Lally - Team Lally Supports Pearlside Boxing

Victoria Sandoval - A Fall Market Update for San Diego Real Estate

Dave Friedman - It’s the great pumpkin giveaway

Jodie Osofsky - Disc golf

Andy Mulholland - What kind of value is most important?

Greater Toronto Group (Dijana) - Don’t Hire an Agent Before Asking Them These 10 Questions First

Durwin Cheung - Why Include a “Love Letter” in Your Offer?

Chris Watters - Fall 2017 Austin housing update

Jerimiah Taylor - Upcoming Market Trends in  Tucson

Bret Johnson - What Happens If You’re Not Happy With Your Home Purchase?

Brandon Brittingham - Help Us Contribute to Breast Cancer Awareness

Saul Zenkevicius - Market update

Brian Gubernick - What Are You Required to Disclose About Your Home?

Spalding Pyron - Can an Agent Help You Purchase a For Sale By Owner Home?

Brent Dildine - Why Listing This Fall Could Be the Right Move for You

Jeff Cook - Rent Holy City

Wes Peters - How Has Technology Changed the World of Lending?

Marti Hampton - 	Fall 2017 Triangle Area housing update

JP Pirtle - Plumber wanted

Greater Calgary Group - A Way to Obtain the Best Rates &amp; Lowest Closing Costs

Maggie Harris - 5 Ways to Invest in Real Estate

Tom Nickley - What’s the Best Way to Stage Your Home?

Spencer Hasch - 8 Things to Avoid After Buying a New Home

Valerie Hunter-Kelly - Why Do You Need a Buyer’s Partner Representing You?

Dan Ellison - 3 Key Tips to Selling Your Home in the Fall

Diva Team - How to Get Your Home Ready Before Winter Strikes

Curtis Johnson - 5 ways to invest in real estate

Misty Soldwisch - We’ve cooked up a fun prize for you
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Jeffrey Cohn, Scott Hollinger, Holly Mabery, Joe Coimbra, and Dan & Connie Couse</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Jeffrey Cohn, Scott Hollinger, Holly Mabery, Joe Coimbra, and Dan & Connie Couse</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Week of 10/2/17</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/week-of-10217.html</link>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-02 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Tracy Wilson - How to purchase a home for next to nothing

Karlyn Ellis - New construction seekers need agents, too

Wade Betz - Things to Know About Flood Insurance

Kari Kohler - St. Charles Has Something for Everyone

Alex Lam - What could happen if your deal collapses

John Simmonds - How to Maintain Your Pool During the Hurricane

Janet Gresh - Real estate’s first cryptocurrencies

Max Folkers - Introducing Myself

Jason Daniels - TrainingThe Secret to Organizing Your Database

Casey Cooke - How Does Our Market Look as We Enter Fall?

Chris Hauck - What’s happening in St. Cloud’s market?

Kelly Fischer - Is It Time for You to Downsize?

Kyle Fernandez - You can make a difference for kids in need

Cristina Dougherty - 5 Upgrades That May Not Add Value to Your Home

Ed Pluchar - Answering Your Questions About Homebuyer Etiquette During Showings

Jared Chamberlain (Chamberlain Group) - How Can You Make Your Property Stand out in Today’s Market?

Joe DiRaffaele - How Kindness Can Help Us and Our City Move Forward

Sharon Stevens - My favorite farmer’s market in St. Augustine

Spencer Janke - Are rates changing soon?

Lisa Sisko - Everything You Should Know About Radon

Dave Nimick - How to Navigate Simultaneously Buying and Selling

Mike Roth - Plain Text

Jeff Green - Dealing With the Aftermath of Hurricane Harvey

Joe DeSane - The problem with Zillow’s Zestimates

Karen &amp; Joe Donovan (Long Island) - The Path to Orchestrating Your Own Home Sale

Sandie Hea - These 3 Inspections Could Save You a Lot of Trouble Later On

Adam Bailey - Got Questions You’re Afraid to Ask Your Agent? I’ve Got Answers

Andy Stavros - We’re Excited To Join Forces With Douglas Elliman

Blaine Moore - Plain Text

Mark Gellman - What Should You Do to Prepare Your Home for the Market?

Rex Jarnagin - What You Should Know About Zillow

Chip Hodgkins - Real estate’s first cryptocurrencies

Jason Baker - What’s Wrong With Listing Without an Agent?

Susan Heller - An Update on Southwest Florida’s Hurricane Recovery

Dave Hooke - 3 Reasons Your Home Isn’t Selling

Dave Knight - How to Fix Up Your Home Prior to Selling It

Mark Brace - Can you be exempt from capital gains?

Earron Shields - You’re Invited to Our Fall Client Appreciation Event

Mario Romero - Should you list your home this fall?

Brad Korb - What’s Our Fall Market Outlook?

Mike Quail - September Market Update

Shawn Luong - Plain Text

Lance Woodley - How Being Local Makes a Difference in Real Estate

Jesse Myles - Plain Text

Thom Dallman - Core Group RealtyThe fall Parade of Homes is happening now

Anne Stewart - Our market is changing

Dan Jones - Thinking of Listing on Your Own? You May Want to Reconsider

Matt Templeton - What 3 Challenges Do Homebuyers Most Commonly Face?

Joe Coimbra - How Do I Destroy, Erase or Improve My Criminal Record?

Lisa Blake - What Trends Are Happening in the Market?

GoVig 3 - A 90-day transition plan

Ana Sarabia - The Problem With Zestimates

Haro Setian - Plain Text

John Mikesh - Pick the patch

GoVig 2 - Looking to stand out as a job candidate?

Brayden Bengtzen - What’s Happening in the Salt Lake County Real Estate Market?

Dave Nabity/ Rob - The True Value of Entrepreneurship

Billy/Heidi Phong - What Do You Need to Know About Closing Costs?

Tom Daves - 4 Options for Buying and Selling at the Same Time

David Huffaker - 3 Topics to Consider When Building a New Home

Kodi Riddle - Tips for purchasing new construction

Jason Penrose - Which is the wiser investment?

Joy Daniels - What is Homes for Heroes?

Jason Daniels - Buying a Home for the First Time? Here’s How to Stay Protected

Sarita Dua - 2 Reasons to Get Pre-Approved Before You Look at Homes

Julie Baldino - 5 Unique Home Selling Tips for Fall and Winter

Aaron Wittenstein - 7 Questions to Ask Before Hiring a Listing Agent

Ruby Henderson - What Does Listing For Sale by Owner Truly Cost?

Damon Gettier - Unexpected Costs Could Leave You Reeling

Andrew Ford - The Best Home Search Website Out There

Danny Burks/Ashlee Branch - What Can You Do to Make Your Move as Smooth as Possible?

Bob Sokoler - Plain Text

Kathy Toth - What Is the Homes Sold Guarantee?
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Tracy Wilson, Karlyn Ellis, Wade Betz, Kari Kohler, and Alex Lam</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Tracy Wilson, Karlyn Ellis, Wade Betz, Kari Kohler, and Alex Lam</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Week of 9/25/17</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/week-of-92517.html</link>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2017-09-25 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Seth &amp; Alyce Dailey - Helping Those Impacted by Harvey

Breanne Steen - Questions - Plain Text

Justin Udy - 3 Questions to Ask Yourself Before Joining a Team

Scott Hollinger - Hesitating on the right home can be a mistake

Melida Potts - Questions - Plain Text

Melinda Elmer - 5 ways to invest in real estate

David Shutler - Debunking 2 major fitness myths

John Simmonds - How to Maintain Your Pool During the Hurricane

Anne-Marie McCormick - Market Update

Jeremy Larkin - Career Opportunity with The Larkin Group!

Jay White - Market update

Gene Agustin - The difference between pre-approval and pre-qualification

Mike Roth - Should You Trust Zillow With Your Home’s Value?

Blaine Moore - Buying New Home Construction? Beware of These Agent Tricks

Dan Ihara - Helping Those Impacted by Harvey

Bill Black - 770 Acre Dam Site

Aaron Hendon - Is Seattle in a Bubble? Part II

Karen &amp; Joe Donovan (Tampa Bay)

Monique Walker - A New Arcadia-Lite Listing!

David Rosen - What Are the Most Important Elements in a Property?

Christal Johnson - The Tale of 2 Home Inspections

Rodney &amp; Jenn Wallner - Fall/Winter Preperations

Chase Craig - Reconnect - Plain Text

O.K Hogan - What Makes Today’s Market So Great to List In?

Chad Smith - 4 Things to Consider When Buying New Construction

Shannon Rollings - Humanitree Juice Bar

Thom Dallman - Core Group RealtyDon’t miss these fall listing tips

Jesse Myles - Don’t Trust a Zestimate

Tim Majka - 5 Ways to Surge Ahead of Competitors in this Hot Market

Lee Tessier - How Can Renovations Affect Your Home Value?

Chip Glennon - Market Update

Christine Browning - The Role of Appraisals in Home Selling

Jon Carbutti - Don’t Start Your Home Search Without Meeting With a Buyer’s Agent First

Jodie Osofsky - Rounding Out the Top 10 Trends at Salt Lake Creative Homes

Shawn Culhane - The Loan Officer Is Key to Closing on Your Home

Todd Martin - Back-up Offers

(ASI) Aesthetic Surgical Images - Strech marks

Kelly Cook - 5 Ways You Can Invest in Real Estate

Caleb Pearson - 5 Real Estate Investments

Michael Perna - Harvey and Irma Victims still need us!!

Bob Sokoler - How Did Our Market Fare in the Month of August?

Jennifer Niederbrach - Zillow Lawsuit

Jennie Wolek - Grogg’s Green Barn

Christy Morrison - 5 reasons to list your home this fall

Travis Chatwin - Will changes in our local market affect you?

Becky Ivins - Getting your offer accepted

Josh Heneveld - Trusting Zillow could be a mistake

Dave Heeter - Market Update

Philipp Fries - Think twice before skipping flood insurance

Ryan Hummel - Alleviate lower back pain

Erik Winegarden - Who pays the commission?

Jack Barry - Will we see you at any of these events?

Shane Neal - Our Red Relief program is here to help

Art Lickunas - What an agent truly earns

Jason McIntosh - For Sale By Owner

Randy Plaice - Fall is a great time to sell your home

Greg &amp; Wendy Kime - Renting a home vs. owning one

Greg Ismay - The new place you can find our newsletter

Jason Morris - Do you need flood insurance?
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Seth & Alice Dailey, Breanne Steen, Justin Udy, Scott Hollinger, and Melida Potts</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Seth & Alice Dailey, Breanne Steen, Justin Udy, Scott Hollinger, and Melida Potts</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Week of 9/18/17</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/week-of-91817.html</link>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2017-09-18 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Tracy Wilson -	Northern Colorado market insights

Rob Kittle -	Listing Flyer

Dan Ihara -	Millionaire Listing

Dave Knight -	Questions Plain Text

Chad Huebener -	New inspection contingency changes

Hal Sweasey - 	Meet the Team

John Simmonds -	How to Maintain Your Pool During the Hurricane

Rob Spring -	How Much Do You Really Need for a Down Payment?

Charleston Homes -	Fall home preparation alert

Greg McDaniel - 	Commission Deal

Bo Winn -	Watch to find out the latest market trends

Joe DiRaffaele -	It’s Time for the 3rd Annual Sip, Sail, and Savor

Alfie McFadden -	What’s it like working with us?

Mike Lafido -	2 record-breaking home sales

Dave Friedman -	My recent visit to Real Estate Uncensored

Tina Caul -	5 Ways to Invest in Real Estate

Renae Gibson -	Red Relief—Helping Those Impacted by Harvey and Irma

Ashley Carter -	Helping Those Impacted by Harvey

Jason Shinpaugh -	Hurricane Recovery

Chris Snow -	Praying for Jacksonville

Dave Knight -	What Is the Mills Act?

Dave Nimick -	Local Lender vs Online Mortgage Provider

Jay White -	Is your home priced correctly for the market?

Rob Ellis -	Investing in Columbus

Gloria Buck -	Red Relief—Helping Those Impacted by Harvey and Irma

Lee Tessier -	Questions Plain Text

Lance Woodley -	Happy Fall Plain Text

Lance Woodley -	Recruiting Email

Anastasia Riley -	Interest Rates

Ryan Butler -	Real estate investing all text

Ian Lobas -	The importance of home staging

Mark Brace -	September Market Update

Lisa Treu - 	The victims of Hurricane Irma need our help

Anne-Marie McCormick -	Keep up with San Diego real estate news

Anne Stewart -	An emerging challenge in our market

Ryan Anderson -	How We Make Dreams Come True

Amanda Howard -	Investing in your kid’s college crib

Robert &amp; Shannon Rollings - 	Pricing for new construction &amp; resale homes

Jeff Ryder -	The right color can add thousands in value

Shawn Culhane -	Hurricane Harvey - Plain Text

Jan Leasure -	5 Ways to Invest in Real Estate

Kris Miller -	Where Do I Start My Day?

Jason Penrose -	What made our August market so different?

Jason Bramblett -	Our listing guarantee

(ASI) Aesthetic Surgical Images -	Recovering from a tummy tuck

Ana Sarabia -	Avoid These 5 Listing Mistakes

Diane Cardano-Casacio -	3 tips you’ll learn at my upcoming seminar

Haro Setian -	Red Relief—Helping Those Impacted by Harvey and Irma

Paul Herrick -	Real Estate Myth Busting: Part 2

Monica Benevides -	6 Tips for Successfully Staging Your Kitchen

Greg Tran -	What will the Houston market look like now?

Amy Smits / Kevin Smits -	This new program allows you to refinance quickly

John Hatch - 	Important stats from the Portland market

Peter MacIntyre -	5 Ways to Invest In Real Estate

Curtis Johnson -	3 facts you need to know about the home-flipping craze

Kwasi Bowie -	Is it possible to predict market changes?

Jeff Latham -	My key to financial freedom

Alex Lam - 	How interest rate increases affect you
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Tracy Wilson, Rob Kittle, Dan Ihara, Dave Knight, and Chad Huebener</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Tracy Wilson, Rob Kittle, Dan Ihara, Dave Knight, and Chad Huebener</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Week of 9/11/17</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/week-of-91117.html</link>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2017-09-11 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Tracy Wilson - Costly Mistakes

Scott Hollinger - Wildfire Season

Dan Ihara - Do You Have Any Questions?

Eric Vallee - Questions Plain Text

John Head - Answering 2 Questions

Breanne Steen - Are your property taxes going up?

Joe DiRaffaele - Harvey’s Impact on the Las Vegas Market

Christal Johnson - One success story from our mentoring program

Haro Setian - Questions - Plain Text

Aaron Hendon - Is Our Seattle Market in a Bubble?

Brian Hammond - Red Relief—Helping Those Impacted by Harvey and Irma

Michael Kaim - Could things fall apart before closing?

Roshena Chada - Reconnect Plain Text

Melida Potts - What Do You Have to Do to Sell Your Estate Sale?

Mike Roth - 7 Keys to Winning a Multiple Offer Situation in Our Market

Blaine Moore - Is the Fall a Good Time to Buy or Sell a Home?

Gene Agustin - How Divorce Impacts My Current Mortgage

Lee Tessier - Questions Plain Text

Lance Woodley - Plain Text

O.K Hogan - How to prepare for a hurricane

Rob Kittle - Appraisal vs. Inspection: What’s the Difference?

Thom Dallman -Core Group Realty - Mesa Listing

Seth &amp; Alyce Dailey - Why You Should Think Twice Before Trusting a Zestimate

Amy Smits / Kevin Smits - An Exciting New Venture

Greg McDaniel - 	You won’t want to miss our next event

Nick Good - Short Sales

Kevin Clancy - How Does My Team Sell So Many Homes?

Andy Sachs - Your latest fall market update

Amanda Howard - Market Update

Doug Herdahl - Vetting Buyers and Offers

Denise Swick - 5 ways to invest in real estate

Bill Black - Try the Fat Mo challenge

Chip Hodgkins - The best place to get meat in Manlius

Heather Upton - Red Relief—Helping Those Impacted by Harvey and Irma

Shawn Luong - A Look at Our Market From Last Year to Now

Caleb Pearson -  Are you on the fence about moving?

Maggie Harris - Providing disaster relief for hurricane victims

Diane Cardano-Casacio - Market Update

Chad Raney - Red Relief—Helping Those Impacted by Harvey and Irma

Tyler Goff - Is Fall a Good Time to Sell

Kwasi Bowie - Listing in the Fall

Jeffrey Cohn - What Things Need to Change When Transitioning Into a New Home?

Peter Dellane - Enhancing your credit

Chris Gorman - Video guide to a secret real estate resource

Bob Sokoler - A Market Update and Disaster Insurance Tips

David Robinson - New Study

Christy Morrison - Your latest Tahoe-Truckee summer market update

Ron Margolis - Kauai real estate’s latest news

Shane Neal - Could you be our next team member?

Jason Delatte - Are you making any of these mistakes?

Erik Winegarden - Closing cost questions?

Zach Behr - 3 Beautiful Homes That Haven’t Hit the Market Yet

Greg &amp; Wendy Kime - What’s happening with home prices right now?

Jose Morales - Good deals are always out there

Andy Mulholland - Appraisal problem help

Glen Gayden - Hurricane Harvey relief info

Art Lickunas - Can you overcome this real estate disaster?

GoVig 2 - The power of interview scheduling

Dave Friedman - We’ve been noticing some odd changes

Randy Plaice - The latest smart home tech

Greg Ismay - Don’t go into new construction alone

Jerimiah Taylor - The latest numbers from the Tucson market

Jason Morris - The best indicators of our market’s health

David Humes - Monthly Rector-Hayden Market Report
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Tracy Wilson, Scott Hollinger, Dan Ihara, Eric Vallee, and John Head</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Tracy Wilson, Scott Hollinger, Dan Ihara, Eric Vallee, and John Head</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Week of 9/04/17</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/week-of-90417.html</link>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2017-09-04 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Hunter Reynolds  - What Are the Best Benefits of Homeownership?

Charlotte Mabry - How to Sell Your Home—Agent Secrets Revealed

Canady and Chase - Earnest Money Explained in Under 90 Seconds

Clayton Gits - The Best Way to Choose a Realtor

Jody Donaldson - Which Home Upgrades Aren’t Worth Making?

Robert Little - 5 Ways to Add Value to Your Home

Clifton Saunders - 8 Common Myths About Veteran Financing

Mary Peacock - How to Prepare Your Home for the Market

Paul Brouillette - How Can a Digital Tour of Your Home Attract Buyers?

Vergis Eiland - How to Find the Right Lender

Bill White - Why Can’t You Trust Zillow to Calculate Your Home’s Value?

Christy Kimbrel - What Is Your Home Worth in This Crazy Market?

Will Cook - 6 Types of Disclosures in California

Angel Garcia - Don’t Make These Mistakes When Buying a Home

Mike Tchobanian - Think You Need 20% Down? Not With These Assistance Programs

Bob &amp; Diane Peterson - Reconnect Email

Andrew Ford - Credit Repair Advice From an Expert

Alan Kushmakov - Where Can You Find Properties Besides the MLS?

Paul Herrick - Myth-Busting a Common Real Estate Agent Claim

Ernie Dill - Are You Serious About Buying a Home?

Brayden Bengtzen - To Buy or Not to Buy—That Is the Question

Wes Peters - Great News About Our Zillow Reviews and a Quick Market Update

Matt Fetick - Why a Buyer’s Agent Is So Valuable

Kevin Yoder - Which Role Is Best for You—Buyer’s Agent or Seller’s Agent?

Nick Kellar  - How This Academy Is Using Jiu-Jitsu to Bring Confidence to a Community

Sarita Dua - Why We Don’t Mind Breaking the Deal

Don Vallee - The Best Ways to Make Your Home More Energy Efficient

Tom Nickley - You’re Invited to Pumpkin Chuckin’ with The Nickley Group

Deja Lett - Busting 3 Common Home Buying Myths

Sean Zanganeh - Is It a Wise Move to Invest in an Airbnb Property?

Jana &amp; Jason DeLong - A Few Common Appraisal Questions Answered

Anastasia Riley - How Can You Lessen the Stress &amp; Costs Involved in Your Move?

John Simmonds - How to Maintain Your Pool During the Hurricane
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Hunter Reynolds, Charlotte Mabry, Clayton Gits, Robert Little, and Clifton Saunders.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>This week's Top Performing Emails were sent by Hunter Reynolds, Charlotte Mabry, Clayton Gits, Robert Little, and Clifton Saunders.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright></copyright>
    <media:credit role="author"></media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Vyral Marketing - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
