<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>http://www.danjonescoaching.com</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://www.danjonescoaching.com"/>
    <description></description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor></managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2017-08-18 14:45:26 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright></media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://www.danjonescoaching.com"/>
    <media:keywords></media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd"></media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Sold@MyHomeCarolinas.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name></itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author></itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://www.danjonescoaching.com"/>
    <itunes:keywords></itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle></itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text=""/>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are We in a Bubble?</title>
        <link>http://www.danjonescoaching.com/are-we-in-bubble.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-11 14:41:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/2017/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+Is+Charlotte+in+a+Real+Estate+Bubble%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

A lot of people are asking if we’re in a bubble. To figure that out, the first place we should look is at the numbers themselves.

A lot of people have been asking if right now is a good time to buy or sell. But, another broader question I’m hearing a lot is, “Are we in a bubble?”

To figure that out, I think it’s important to look at the numbers. Over the last three years, **the market has seen consistent growth and the interest rates have generally stayed low. **

We can see from this that there isn’t a very high likelihood that the Feds will be raising interest rates in a significant way. In fact, some people are saying interest rates could even drop.

The lower interest rates are, the more people can afford. This is especially important since the somewhat drastic increases we’ve seen in prices over the last two to three years. Right now in our area, we’re starting to see prices similar to those we saw in 2006, 2007, and 2008.

Though interest rates typically rise along with price, this isn’t a trend we’re currently seeing. We can expect prices to continue to rise.

**We’re also seeing homes spending fewer days on market, as well as lower inventory overall. **

“IF YOU’RE THINKING OF BUYING, NOW IS STILL A GOOD TIME.”

However, if you’re thinking of buying, now is still a good time.

If you’re considering selling, the most important thing is to pay attention to supply and demand within the market.

Overall, I’d have to say that most people would not agree that we’re in a bubble.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/2017/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+Is+Charlotte+in+a+Real+Estate+Bubble%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.danjonescoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/2017/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+Is+Charlotte+in+a+Real+Estate+Bubble%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

A lot of people are asking if we’re in a bubble. To figure that out, the first place we should look is at the numbers themselves.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

A lot of people are asking if we’re in a bubble. To figure that out, the first place we should look is at the numbers themselves.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords></itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Do You Choose a Quality Agent?</title>
        <link>http://www.danjonescoaching.com/how-do-you-choose-quality-agent.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-27 13:02:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/2017/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+How+to+find+a+good+agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When you are looking for an agent to help with your real estate transaction, how can you know if they will do a good job?

With the recent influx of agents into our area’s market, a lot of people have come to me asking, “How do I find the right agent?”

The answer depends on what kind of real estate transaction you’re about to undertake. If you are in the market to purchase a home you should be looking for a lender.

But don’t settle for your first encounter, be sure to shop around to get the best rates and the best terms and conditions on your mortgage. You should also get a buyer’s roadmap. A buyer’s roadmap will show you how we get priority access to all the best deals on the market.

This will help you win out against the competition. Having the roadmap will be your guide to success as a buyer, but you’ll still need a quality agent. When looking for the right agent, be sure to ask how many homes they sell per year, how well they know the area, and how well they know financing.

Sellers will need a game plan, as well. Having a selling guide and using high-quality marketing will be key. **My team and I offer a 151-step marketing guide that can help you have as smooth and successful a transaction as possible. **

“VERY FEW OTHER AGENTS, OR TEAMS OF AGENTS, CAN DO WHAT WE CAN.”

Full-disclosure, full-detail marketing strategies are also something we do. From 3D tours to aerial drone shots and more, we have all the resources to help our sellers make their listing as attractive as possible. We also offer a 75-point photography checklist designed to ensure that your home is being presented in the best light.

Very few other agents, or teams of agents, can do what we can—let alone at such a high level.

To find out if an agent will be able to get you top dollar, there are a few questions you should ask as a seller. How many homes have they sold this year? Do they have a resume?

With as many agents as are coming in our area, we’re seeing a few of them underpricing homes and therefore only selling between two to four properties a year. Selling quickly isn’t worth it if an agent is undercutting their client’s profit by thousands.

One of the things that sets my team apart is that we only accept full price offers for our clients. You need an agent who has a game plan for getting you at or above list price.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/2017/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+How+to+find+a+good+agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.danjonescoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/2017/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+How+to+find+a+good+agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

When you are looking for an agent to help with your real estate transaction, how can you know if they will do a good job?

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

When you are looking for an agent to help with your real estate transaction, how can you know if they will do a good job?

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords></itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Who Can You Trust to Sell Your Rental Property?</title>
        <link>http://www.danjonescoaching.com/who-can-you-trust-to-sell-your-rental.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-26 13:57:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/2017/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+Who+Can+You+Trust+to+Sell+Your+Rental+Property%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you want to sell your home that’s currently being rented, should you try to sell it through the leasing company? Here’s why I advise against it.

There are a few common questions I’ve received in recent weeks that I wanted to address for you.

Q: Is there any benefit to choosing a team of real estate agents versus a leasing company?

A: A client had a home rented and was looking to sell it. The people leasing the home really wanted to list the house. I told them that the problem was that they wanted to list the house—not try to find a buyer and sell it in a reasonable amount of time for top dollar.

“DON’T ASK SOMEONE TO SELL YOUR HOME UNLESS THEY SELL HOMES REGULARLY AT A HIGH LEVEL.”

Someone once told me that when you ask someone to do something they don’t normally do at a very high level, you probably won’t get the best results. Just like you wouldn’t call your kids’ orthodontist for a root canal, you shouldn’t call your leasing company to sell your house.

If you have a home that’s rented that you’re looking to sell, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I’d be happy to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/2017/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+Who+Can+You+Trust+to+Sell+Your+Rental+Property%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.danjonescoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/2017/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+Who+Can+You+Trust+to+Sell+Your+Rental+Property%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you want to sell your home that’s currently being rented, should you try to sell it through the leasing company? Here’s why I advise against it.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you want to sell your home that’s currently being rented, should you try to sell it through the leasing company? Here’s why I advise against it.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords></itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Few Things to Know Before Buying New Construction</title>
        <link>http://www.danjonescoaching.com/a-few-things-to-know-before-buying-new.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-26 16:52:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/2017/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+New+construction+Edited.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Whatever you do, don’t start the new home building process without an agent’s help. You could be setting yourself up for failure without even trying.

We’ve been noticing that a lot of our clients over the years have misconceptions about how buying new construction homes work. We wanted to go through the process and clarify any questions you may have today.

If you’re considering building a new home, it’s always best to go into the process with an agent who has experience working with and negotiating these kinds of deals. You might think that you could save some money as a buyer by not using an agent, but you would be completely wrong.

If a builder knows you don’t have representation, they are going to run you over and you will end up overpaying for a property. Until you have an agent who knows what they’re doing when it comes to negotiating with these builders, you won’t have as successful of a home purchase as you could have had.

“AN AGENT CAN HELP YOU GET A LOWER INTEREST RATE AND BETTER UPGRADES.”

By working with an agent, you can get a lower interest rate, better upgrades, and other discounts that you wouldn’t be able to get on your own. The expertise of an agent really pays off in situations like this. If you’re working with one of our buyer’s agents here at the Dan Jones Team, let them know if you’re interested in this kind of property.

Speaking of our great agents, let me give a shout out to one of our new agents, Karen, who has been doing fantastic as of late putting homes under contract and is working with several new construction buyers right now.

In the meantime, if you have any questions for us, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/2017/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+New+construction+Edited.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.danjonescoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/2017/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+New+construction+Edited.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Whatever you do, don’t start the new home building process without an agent’s help. You could be setting yourself up for failure without even trying.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Whatever you do, don’t start the new home building process without an agent’s help. You could be setting yourself up for failure without even trying.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords></itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Latest News From the Charlotte Real Estate Market</title>
        <link>http://www.danjonescoaching.com/the-latest-news-from-charlotte-real.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-16 13:37:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/2017/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+Market+Update.mp4</guid>
        <description>

It’s not summer yet, but the Charlotte real estate market is the hottest market we have ever seen. I’ll go over more details for you today.

If you are thinking about selling a home in the next three to six months, you should know that **the real estate market is on fire right now. **

This is the hottest market that we’ve seen. Homes are selling after 30 to 40 days on the market; some homes are selling in 60 to 70 days. This is a much faster pace than the usual 130 to 140 days.

“ON AVERAGE, HOMES ARE SELLING IN 30 TO 40 DAYS.”

If you are thinking of buying or selling a home, we would love to show you what we do differently to help you reach your real estate goals. We can sell houses in half of the average days on market; in other words, **we can sell your home in 15 to 20 days. **

One marketing tool we like to implement is our “Full Price Offers Only” sign that we put on each of our listings.

For buyers, interest rates are still incredibly low, but they are starting to creep up a bit. Now is a great time to jump into the market while rates are still low.

If you have any questions about navigating our current market, give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/2017/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+Market+Update.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.danjonescoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/2017/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+Market+Update.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

It’s not summer yet, but the Charlotte real estate market is the hottest market we have ever seen. I’ll go over more details for you today.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

It’s not summer yet, but the Charlotte real estate market is the hottest market we have ever seen. I’ll go over more details for you today.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords></itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why You Should Hire Us to Sell Your House</title>
        <link>http://www.danjonescoaching.com/why-you-should-hire-us-to-sell-your.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-11 15:28:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/2017/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+Are+You+Thinking+About+Selling+Your+Home+This+Year%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’re thinking about selling your house this year, you need to reach out to us. Allow me to explain why.

If you’re thinking about selling your house this year, you need to reach out to our company.

We do a lot of things to sell your house quickly and for top dollar, including our VIP Seller Program. This is a ‘coming soon’ type of program that markets your home to thousands of people before it even hits the market. Our average days on market has been cut in half simply because of this program.

It could be the difference in you needing to make an extra mortgage payment or two on your home while you sell, and that’s huge.

We also offer a 151-step marketing tool, which we’ll happily send you. Whether you’ve sold a home recently or not, you’d be surprised at all the things we do to sell your house for top dollar every time.

We’d also be happy to send you our 2016 resume. **We sold more than 200 homes last year, and we’re well on our way to 250 to 300 sales this year. **

“WE SOLD MORE THAN 200 HOMES IN 2016 AND WE’RE WELL ON OUR WAY TO 250 THIS YEAR.”

When you sell your house, most agents will come out for a comparative market analysis (CMA) based on square footage, but it’s impossible to know the exact condition that every single home sold under. It could have been the result of a divorce, an estate sale, or a short sale, to name a few.

We do a full equity evaluation based on a market absorption sheet. We’ll look at everything that’s happened in the last 12 to 24 months to figure out where we need to be and what we need to do to sell your house for top dollar.

If you’re thinking about selling, it’s a must. Just give us a call or send us an email if you’re thinking about selling, we’d love to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/2017/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+Are+You+Thinking+About+Selling+Your+Home+This+Year%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.danjonescoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/2017/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+Are+You+Thinking+About+Selling+Your+Home+This+Year%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you’re thinking about selling your house this year, you need to reach out to us. Allow me to explain why.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you’re thinking about selling your house this year, you need to reach out to us. Allow me to explain why.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords></itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Stand out on the Market By Doing These 4 Things</title>
        <link>http://www.danjonescoaching.com/stand-out-on-market-by-doing-these-4.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-28 16:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/2017/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+Affordable+Ways+to+Get+Your+Home+Ready+for+the+Market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I’m going to go over some great, affordable ways to prepare your home for the spring market.

If you’re thinking about selling your home this spring, there are some great affordable ways you can prepare to ensure you get top dollar.

“DOING THE BASICS IS GOING TO GET YOU THE BIGGEST RETURN.”


  
    Declutter. Box up all of the items you don’t need and put them in a storage unit. Decluttering ensures your home feels cozy, and buyers are more likely to see the value in a decluttered home.
  
  
    Repaint the doors. Adding a fresh coat of paint to the doors will make them feel and look new. Buyers will take notice and really appreciate that detail.
  
  
    Repaint the trim. You don’t need to paint every bit of trim in the house, but make sure you hit the main walking areas, bathrooms, hallways, and the kitchen.
  
  
    Spruce up the landscaping. Get some mulch and freshen things up. Also, make sure two days before you get pictures taken you mow the grass and clear the driveway off.
Assuming there are no major issues with your carpet or flooring, hitting the basics is going to get you the biggest return. By doing so, your home will be 75% more likely to sell than other homes. Just remember not to over improve your home by taking on huge projects like the ones on HGTV. Those projects won’t always get you the best return.
  


If you have any other questions, please feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/2017/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+Affordable+Ways+to+Get+Your+Home+Ready+for+the+Market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.danjonescoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/2017/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+Affordable+Ways+to+Get+Your+Home+Ready+for+the+Market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today I’m going to go over some great, affordable ways to prepare your home for the spring market.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today I’m going to go over some great, affordable ways to prepare your home for the spring market.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords></itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Work With One of Our Buyer Specialists?</title>
        <link>http://www.danjonescoaching.com/why-work-with-one-of-our-buyer.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-10 15:42:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/2017/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+What+Makes+Our+Buyer+Specialists+Different.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Our market moves fast, especially for buyers. You can gain an advantage on your competition by hiring the right people to help you.

What makes our buyer specialists different from the rest? There are a lot of things, actually. If you’ve spoken to one of them already, you have an idea of what we’re all about. However, there are a lot of specific advantages to using our services over other firms out there.

There are so many real estate agents out there, but not many of them specialize in getting their clients priority access to all the best deals on the market. If you’ve been looking for a home lately, you already know how fast the market moves. That’s why we prioritize getting our clients a backstage pass to the MLS so they are aware of homes that match their criteria as soon as they hit the market, sometimes even before.

“WE GIVE OUR CLIENTS A BACKSTAGE PASS TO THE MLS.”

Another unique advantage our team offers is that we are coached at a very high level. This means we are more in-tune with the market, have better negotiating skills, and know how to handle stressful situations better than most agents.

The average agent sells five homes per year and doesn’t know how to get their buyers the best deal possible. With our unique training and experience, we do. If you have any questions for us or would like to work with one of our expert buyer specialists, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/2017/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+What+Makes+Our+Buyer+Specialists+Different.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.danjonescoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/2017/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+What+Makes+Our+Buyer+Specialists+Different.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Our market moves fast, especially for buyers. You can gain an advantage on your competition by hiring the right people to help you.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Our market moves fast, especially for buyers. You can gain an advantage on your competition by hiring the right people to help you.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords></itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Whats Going on in the Charlotte Market?</title>
        <link>http://www.danjonescoaching.com/whats-going-on-in-charlotte-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-27 11:46:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/2017/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+The+Charlotte+Market+is+On+Fire.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The Charlotte market is on fire right now! I’ll go over what’s making our real estate market so hot today.

The Charlotte real estate market is on fire right now, so I wanted to give you a rundown on what’s happening.

Many people thought home prices would come down as interest rates increased, but that hasn’t been the case so far. However, **price per square foot is expected to decrease as interest rates continue to rise in 2017. **

So, if you’re thinking about selling your home or investment property this year, now is the time. In fact, some people are saying that this year will be the best year ever to sell an investment property.

“2017 COULD BE THE BEST YEAR EVER TO SELL INVESTMENT PROPERTY.”

If you’re looking to make a move, whether you are downsizing or upgrading to a larger home, right now is the best time to take advantage of a low interest rate and secure the most profit from your current home sale.

All in all, right now is a great time to buy or sell real estate. Also, if you have been thinking about buying new construction, I know **a lot of builders have been accepting contingency offers, so make sure you keep that in mind. **

If you have any further questions or want to discuss how you can take advantage of Charlotte’s hot market, please feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/2017/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+The+Charlotte+Market+is+On+Fire.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.danjonescoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/2017/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+The+Charlotte+Market+is+On+Fire.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

The Charlotte market is on fire right now! I’ll go over what’s making our real estate market so hot today.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

The Charlotte market is on fire right now! I’ll go over what’s making our real estate market so hot today.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords></itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Great News for North Carolina Home Buyers </title>
        <link>http://www.danjonescoaching.com/great-news-for-north-carolina-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-25 13:26:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+%252415K+Grant+Program+is+back.mp4</guid>
        <description>

North Carolina recently brought back its $15,000 grant program. This is a great program for first-time home buyers. I’ll go over a few important details for you today.

Today I have some great news for North Carolina home buyers: the $15,000 grant program is back!

If you’re a first-time home buyer or if you haven’t owned a home in the last three years, you may be eligible for this program.

Basically, the state will give you $15,000 towards down payment assistance, closing costs, and/or buying the loan amount down.

There are a few requirements that you have to meet in order to qualify for this program.

First of all, you cannot make over a certain amount of money. Check in with your lender for the details. Secondly, you have to buy a home in the $240,000 to $245,000 price range.

“THE STATE WILL GIVE YOU $15,000 TOWARDS DOWN PAYMENT ASSISTANCE.”

This is a great program for first-time home buyers. I certainly wish it was around back when I bought my home!

If you are working with one of our agents already, they know tons about this program. Make sure you ask them about it.

If you’re not a first-time home buyer but you know someone who is, make sure that they are looking in Mecklenburg or Cabarrus County in order to qualify for this program.

Last October, 3,000 grants were issued to home buyers. There are not many left today. Get in touch with us to take advantage of this great loan program. We would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+%252415K+Grant+Program+is+back.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.danjonescoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+%252415K+Grant+Program+is+back.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

North Carolina recently brought back its $15,000 grant program. This is a great program for first-time home buyers. I’ll go over a few important details for you today.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

North Carolina recently brought back its $15,000 grant program. This is a great program for first-time home buyers. I’ll go over a few important details for you today.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords></itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Is Now a Great Time to List Your Home?</title>
        <link>http://www.danjonescoaching.com/why-is-now-great-time-to-list-your-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-11 11:04:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+Hiring+Buyer+Agents.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There are a lot of serious buyers out in the market right now. Here’s why listing now will help you capture this segment of buyers.

There are some great benefits to be had by getting your home on the market during this time of year. A lot of people tell us they are waiting until next month to get their home on the market, but we have been advising them to move up their timeline. Why?

Well, if you look at the numbers and how many homes are on the market versus what actually sells and closes, the percentage is ridiculously high. In February and March, the same number of buyers are out there, but inventory doubles or triples.

“YOU MIGHT NOT GET AS MANY SHOWINGS, BUT YOU WILL MOSTLY DEAL WITH SERIOUS BUYERS.”

Right now, the only buyers out there are serious ones. This is because they may have had a shift in income or a job change. Whatever their reason, they need to close on a home quickly. You might not get as many showings right now as you would during the rest of the year, but the people looking will always be serious buyers.

If you’ve been thinking about selling, get a time set up with one of our listing specialists to get a full equity evaluation on your property to see what’s going on in the market in your area and what your competition is trying to sell for. Then we can determine whether it makes sense for you to sell your home now or if you should wait.

As always, if you have any questions, we would be glad to answer them. Just give us a call or send us an email. We can’t wait to hear from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+Hiring+Buyer+Agents.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.danjonescoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+Hiring+Buyer+Agents.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

There are a lot of serious buyers out in the market right now. Here’s why listing now will help you capture this segment of buyers.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

There are a lot of serious buyers out in the market right now. Here’s why listing now will help you capture this segment of buyers.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords></itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Makes Zestimates Inaccurate?</title>
        <link>http://www.danjonescoaching.com/dan-jones-home-selling-team-perils-of.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2016-08-09 13:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+Why+Zillow+Zestimates+Are+So+Off.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I’ve gotten a lot of questions recently about Zestimates, and I’m going to address them today. A Zestimate is just what its name implies - an estimate of your home’s value. An estimate is a reasonable approach to value in regard to real estate, but an estimate is, by definition, inexact. Enjoy using a Zestimate as a tool, but don’t be surprised by the inaccurate information that you receive from it.

Why are Zillow’s Zestimates so inaccurate? There are a few reasons. First off, Zillow doesn’t look at supply and demand. They look at recent comps, but not recent appraisals. They also pull from tax records, which can be extremely inaccurate as well. If you use that data, you could be misrepresenting your home’s value by as much as $60,000 or $70,000. Tax records aren’t a good tool for estimating a home’s value.

“Your home could be worth $60,000 or $70,000 more than you think.”

Another thing Zillow’s Zestimate doesn’t take into account is location. Your home may have five or six different good comparables, but Zillow won’t be able to determine whether you live in a location that would boost your home’s value. If you live on a golf course, cul-de-sac, or a wooded lot, Zillow would not factor that in.

Finally, Zestimates don’t take upgrades and updates into account. Your home’s value will be determined in the same way whether you have a fully remodeled kitchen, bathroom, or basement. Assigning a list price to your home based on a Zestimate could be hugely detrimental to your sale.

I have a rental property that Zillow recently told me is worth $80,000 more than it really is. If anyone out there would like to buy the home for the Zestimate price, let me know and we’ll get a contract written up. Otherwise, if you have any other questions or want to know what the true market value of your home is, give us a call. We would be happy to do an equity evaluation for you and give you a professional opinion on how much your home should sell for.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+Why+Zillow+Zestimates+Are+So+Off.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.danjonescoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+Why+Zillow+Zestimates+Are+So+Off.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

I’ve gotten a lot of questions recently about Zestimates, and I’m going to address them today. A Zestimate is just what its name implies - an estimate of your home’s value. An estimate is a reasonable approach to value in regard to real estate, but an estimate is, by definition, inexact. Enjoy using a Zestimate as a tool, but don’t be surprised by the inaccurate information that you receive from it.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

I’ve gotten a lot of questions recently about Zestimates, and I’m going to address them today. A Zestimate is just what its name implies - an estimate of your home’s value. An estimate is a reasonable approach to value in regard to real estate, but an estimate is, by definition, inexact. Enjoy using a Zestimate as a tool, but don’t be surprised by the inaccurate information that you receive from it.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords></itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Are Some of the Hidden Costs of Selling a House?</title>
        <link>http://www.danjonescoaching.com/dan-jones-home-selling-team-hidden.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2016-08-01 10:05:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+The+Hidden+Costs+of+Selling+a+House.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There are several hidden costs of selling a house people usually don’t find out about until they get to the closing table. What I want to talk about today are some of those major expenses.

First of all, if you haven’t lived in your house for very long, there is a good chance you’re going to be paying a capital gains tax. It’s a good idea to speak with your accountant to confer over this.

Next are the seller closing costs. A lot of agents like to beat around the bush about who pays what, but it’s important to know this up front when you’re deciding who you’re going to sell your home to and at what price. Closing costs consist of attorney’s fees and deed stamps.

“It’s important to know your closing costs up front.”

Repairs to the house is another cost to consider. They might be simple, or they might be complicated, but almost all homes end up having repairs. Just getting an electrician through the door can cost as much as $150. A lot of buyers also like to ask for a home warranty. We don’t encourage our sellers to buy those up front because we’d rather wait for the buyer to negotiate that in and move up the asking price of the home.

Finally, you have costs like additional repairs or attorney’s fees. If there are any title issues, we strongly suggest that you clear them up beforehand.

Be sure you’re aware of these omissions when it’s your time to sell so you’re prepared for the process. If you have any questions, please send me an email or give me a call. As always, I look forward to your referrals and talking to you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+The+Hidden+Costs+of+Selling+a+House.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.danjonescoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+The+Hidden+Costs+of+Selling+a+House.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

There are several hidden costs of selling a house people usually don’t find out about until they get to the closing table. What I want to talk about today are some of those major expenses.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

There are several hidden costs of selling a house people usually don’t find out about until they get to the closing table. What I want to talk about today are some of those major expenses.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords></itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Pricing Errors that Cost Carolina Home Sellers Thousands</title>
        <link>http://www.danjonescoaching.com/dan-jones-home-selling-team-avoid-these.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2016-07-20 11:57:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+The+Top+Reasons+Sellers+Lose+Thousands+of+Dollars+When+Selling.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Homeowners can lose thousands of dollars when they sell their house for a number of reasons. How is it possible to lose money when selling, you ask?

In Carolina, we’re probably in one of the best seller’s markets we’ve seen in a decade. We have great comps to get homes sold, but when people are valuing their home, they aren’t doing a full equity evaluation and really understanding what the market can absorb. Many people are simply getting a comparative market analysis (or CMA) and underpricing the home, only to see it sell in a few days for up to 6% less than they should have.

If your home is worth around $300,000 or more, that’s a lot of money to leave on the table.

“Pricing a home too high or too low will cost you in the long run.”

Secondly, overpricing is a way people are throwing away money. I have people tell me they want to start their home priced $30,000 above what it should be. The downside is that the home’s going to sit on the market for a long time, and even if you find a buyer, the home probably won’t appraise for that price. If a home sits on the market, you’ll have to lower the price. By the time the price comes down to where it should be, buyers will think there is something wrong with the house and they won’t even come view it.

What you end up with is a house that sat on the market for around 200 days that ends up selling for up to 15% less than it should have if it was priced appropriately.

Finally, choosing the wrong agent can cause you to lose tens of thousands of dollars. You want to make sure the agent you hire has a full marketing budget to get your house proper exposure. There are a lot of new agents out there who just don’t know the market. If you’re not selling a lot of homes, they may end up underpricing and losing you money.

Let me know of any questions you have about pricing your home, or if you’re considering buying or selling a home. I look forward to speaking with you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+The+Top+Reasons+Sellers+Lose+Thousands+of+Dollars+When+Selling.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.danjonescoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+The+Top+Reasons+Sellers+Lose+Thousands+of+Dollars+When+Selling.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Homeowners can lose thousands of dollars when they sell their house for a number of reasons. How is it possible to lose money when selling, you ask?

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Homeowners can lose thousands of dollars when they sell their house for a number of reasons. How is it possible to lose money when selling, you ask?

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords></itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Is the Carolina Market So Hot? </title>
        <link>http://www.danjonescoaching.com/dan-jones-home-selling-team-carolina.html</link>
        
          <category>North Carolina Market Update</category>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2016-07-06 13:11:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+Why+is+the+Market+So+Hot%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Now is a great time to sell your house. In the last three to six months, we’ve had a lot of problems getting homes appraised because the market jumped up so quickly. However, now there are plenty of comparable sales to support those increases, and the market is on fire.

Why is the market so hot? The main reason is we have very low supply and very high demand right now. We are shifting into a seller’s market as there are not a lot of homes to choose from. Properties that are prepared properly and positioned well in the market sell pretty quickly and for top dollar.

Secondly, interest rates are very low. Two or three years ago, many people suspected we would see 5.5% interest rates in 2016, but rates have held consistently over the last year or so. In fact, rates have actually come down a little bit. These low rates mean it is still very affordable for you to buy a slightly bigger home or even build a house.

“Do not underprice your home in this hot market.”

If you are thinking of selling in this market, I have one warning: Do not underprice your home. Since the real estate market is picking up, there are a lot of newer agents getting their licenses and diving into the market. These agents don’t necessarily know how to price your property for this market. You could lose 5% to 10% of your true home value when you underprice your property.

If you are thinking about selling, give us a call or send us an email. We will do a full equity evaluation of your property so you don’t leave a lot of money on the table. We look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+Why+is+the+Market+So+Hot%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.danjonescoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+Why+is+the+Market+So+Hot%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Now is a great time to sell your house. In the last three to six months, we’ve had a lot of problems getting homes appraised because the market jumped up so quickly. However, now there are plenty of comparable sales to support those increases, and the market is on fire.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Now is a great time to sell your house. In the last three to six months, we’ve had a lot of problems getting homes appraised because the market jumped up so quickly. However, now there are plenty of comparable sales to support those increases, and the market is on fire.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords></itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Dont Make This Common Buyer Mistake in Charlotte</title>
        <link>http://www.danjonescoaching.com/dan-jones-home-selling-team-hiring.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2016-06-01 14:33:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+The+Biggest+Buyer+Mistakes.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There are unfortunately a lot of mistakes that buyers can make in the Charlotte market. Most of the time, it comes down to choosing the wrong agent.

Our team of agents here at Carolina Real Estate Experts have professional coaching and they’re full-time agents who really know and understand today’s market. There are too many agents out there who went out and got a real estate license a few years ago when the market got hot, and don’t truly understand what the market was and where it is today. They really don’t care about you getting the best price, terms, and conditions, because they’re really just interested in getting a check at the end of the day.

It’s very important to us at Carolina Real Estate Experts that you get the best price, terms, and conditions on your property and that we do a great job for you from start to finish.

“Ask good questions when hiring an agent.”

Make sure that if you’re going to work with someone, you don’t make the mistake of working with an agent who has a license but doesn’t have proper training yet. Be careful about asking good questions, because seeing two or three properties with an agent doesn’t exactly mean you’re “working with an agent.” Interview a few agents to make sure they’ll get you the best conditions.

If you or your friends, family or co-workers have questions or real estate needs, reach out to us. I’d love to speak with you and help you with your real estate needs.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+The+Biggest+Buyer+Mistakes.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.danjonescoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+The+Biggest+Buyer+Mistakes.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

There are unfortunately a lot of mistakes that buyers can make in the Charlotte market. Most of the time, it comes down to choosing the wrong agent.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

There are unfortunately a lot of mistakes that buyers can make in the Charlotte market. Most of the time, it comes down to choosing the wrong agent.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords></itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Avoid the Pitfalls of Hiring the Wrong Carolina Buyers Agent </title>
        <link>http://www.danjonescoaching.com/dan-jones-home-selling-team-wrong.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author></author>
        <pubDate>2016-05-13 11:09:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+The+Potential+Pitfalls+of+Choosing+the+Wrong+Buyer%2527s+Agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Purchasing a home is not as easy as people think. Most of the time, a buyer will go look at homes and actually purchase a home through the first agent they speak to. That’s probably the worst way to go about purchasing a home.

You really need to talk to an agent and figure out what they do. Do they work with a team? What kind of support staff do they have? You need the answers to these questions so you hire an agent who will make sure you get the best price, terms, and conditions when it comes to negotiating and understanding the market.

The last thing you want to do is walk into a transaction with someone who just got their license or only sells two homes a year. That agent really just doesn’t know what’s going on with the market. They won’t know what it will be like for you to sell that property again in the next five to 20 years.

“Interview more than one real estate agent.”

Think twice about what agent you’re using. Interview more than one agent. Make sure you work with someone who really knows the market. You need someone from the area, who sells 30 homes a year, and works on a team of agents that can get you the best price, terms, and conditions.

My team and I can get you to the closing process with the least amount of trouble. We can make this a very easy experience for you. If you have any questions, just give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+The+Potential+Pitfalls+of+Choosing+the+Wrong+Buyer%2527s+Agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.danjonescoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dan+Jones/Dan+Jones+Home+Selling+Team-+The+Potential+Pitfalls+of+Choosing+the+Wrong+Buyer%2527s+Agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author></itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords></itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright></copyright>
    <media:credit role="author"></media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain"></media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
