Each year during the holiday season, my team and I participate in something we believe to be a truly worthy cause: Toys for Tots. 

Many of you are probably already familiar with this program. But if you aren’t, allow me to explain.

Toys for Tots is a program put on by the United States Marine Corps Reserve designed to collect and distribute toys to less fortunate children. 

My team and I want to make it easy for you to help. So if you’d like to contribute, all you have to do is collect a new, unwrapped toy and bring it by our office. We can even pick it up from you, if you like. This program is a great way to give back.

However, the deadline is Friday, December 15. If you’d like to participate with us, please bring your toys by the office by either Wednesday, December 13 or Thursday, December 14 at the latest.

In the past, we’ve collected hundreds of toys. We’d like to beat that number this year. With your help, we’d like to make this holiday season bright for some less fortunate children.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
